AII right, hold on.
I got the turn up here.
(WHOOPING)
Oh! How cool was that?
That was way cool!
My turn. Sorry, that's
not allowed.
I just signed
15 pages of forms saying
you gotta ride
on the back of that thing.
I don't see
any Iawyers around.
You know
that's not the point.
No.
You just wanna keep
all the fun to yourself.
Come on, Dad!
You go over 15,
we're pulling over, all right?
I mean it.
You're the best.
AII right, get on there.
Put on your goggles.
Okay.
Ready?
Got the clutch in?
AII right, that's my boy.
(WHOOPING)
Adam, you're going too fast,
slow it down!
I mean it,
you're going too fast.
SIow down!
Adam!
Let go of the throttle!
Adam! No!
PARAMEDIC: What've you got?
Sixteen-year-old, status post,
ATV crash,
40% burns on his body.
Nasotracheal intubation.
Start a bag
of Iactated Ringer's,
wide open...
Will he be okay?
We'II be with you when we can.
Get him out!
Wait, wait, wait!
NURSE: I'II start fluids.
Let's go get him hooked up.
SURGEON: Watch the Iine.
(READING HINDI)
Been Iooking for you.
Been avoiding you.
Burn Unit can handle it.
If they could handle it,
they wouldn't
be asking for you.
Is that a journal?
Friend wrote an article.
In Hindi?
They have a cutting-edge
neuroscience program in India.
It says so right on the cover.
Kid's heart rate's messed.
Tachycardia
can be explained by the burn.
I assume
the Burn Unit knew that.
His potassium's Iow.
Which can also be explained
by the burn.
Except I'm sure
the Burn Unit's
pumping him with fluids
which means his potassium
should be going up, not down.
Could be amphetamines.
Or bacteria
Iunching on his heart.
Or cardiomyopathy,
or some other very bad thing.
HOUSE: He needs an EKG.
(EXCLAIMING)
Okay, no skin, no EKG.
CHASE: Is he even
gonna survive the burn?
What, you got
a date or something?
Forty percent of his body.
If the Burns Unit
can prevent an infection,
his body will regenerate
maybe 10%,
surgeons will do
20 or so grafts,
six months in this room,
he'II end up
with a series of nasty scars,
maybe some pain,
but he'II Iive.
Unless his heart shuts down
'cause we can't figure out
what's causing the
Iow potassium and tachycardia.
We need help
from a Belgian doc
named Einthoven.
He's dead.
While he was alive,
he invented a Iittle dittie
called the Galvanometer.
Where do we get one?
Go to any electronics store
that's been open
since before 1905.
There's a good chance
they've got one
in a corner in the basement.
BRENDA: We need
an audio-visual setup
for the Iecture hall.
What for?
For the Iecture.
What Iecture?
Dr. Weber's Iecture.
Who is Dr. Weber?
A neurologist, I think.
The memo was from you.
Where is my assistant?
She Ieft.
When?
Wednesday.
Seriously?
Well, the temp agency
sent someone,
but she got Iost.
Well, when she gets here,
fire her.
Oh, yeah.
Did you issue this memo?
Look at that.
Congratulations.
The patient
that has been in a coma
for two years and counting
is still in a coma.
This is not my signature.
I don't know
anything about this guy.
I'm supposed to introduce him?
Have Iunch?
The coma patient
has a migraine?
Oh, no, no, no.
No, I gave him medication
to prevent a migraine.
That's a migraine.
Increased flow velocity
in his cerebral arteries.
I did subsequently
give him nitroglycerin,
which could possibly...
You induced
a migraine headache
in a coma patient?
I gave him a Iittle headache,
similar to the one
you're giving me now.
Have you even read
an ethical guideline?
Well, it would be wrong
to try out a new
migraine prevention medication
on someone
who can actually feel pain.
Did you sign this?
Yeah.
We can talk Iater about
the appropriate discipline.
CAMERON: Because of the burn,
we can't perform
any of our normal tests
to see what's wrong.
So we're going to try
a Galvanometer.
It picks up a pulse
in the wrists and the ankles.
Hopefully it'II tell us
why his heart rhythm
is abnormal.
What have I done to him? I...
It was an accident.
AII right? So...
He's got all these burns
and now
there's something wrong
with his heart?
We're trying to figure out
if the two
are somehow connected.
Had he been sick Iately?
No, nothing.
Anything unusual
with his behavior?
Had he been tired a Iot?
Nothing.
He was great, he was happy,
he was just having
a great time, and then...
If he was experimenting
with amphetamines
or cocaine...
No.
We gave him some pot
about a year ago, to try...
It was just once.
We thought
if we took the mystery
out of drugs and alcohol,
the Iess he'd experiment.
We'II know more
after the tests.
It Iooks Iike
they're gonna electrocute him.
PIug it in.
You plug it in.
Fine. Give me the cord.
Works.
Prominent U waves.
No inverted T wave.
No ischemia.
Q wave normal.
That's not good.
Okay, turn it off.
Turn it off!
What's happening?
What is that?
CHASE: The seizure's
getting...
Can't you stop that?
Who electrocuted my patient?
He had a seizure.
CAMERON: He wasn't
electrocuted.
What does the seizure tell us?
Move.
What are you Iooking for?
Same as you are, Iove,
acceptance,
solid return on an investment.
Differential diagnosis. Go.
Could be epilepsy
or seizure disorder.
Not with the tachycardia.
It could be
a virus in his brain.
Your specificity's impressive.
Adrenoleukodystrophy.
Could be MS.
The seizures could be caused
by plaques
and Iesions on the brain.
Well, Iet's find out which.
Get him an MRI.
No nuclear imaging!
He wouldn't survive
the move to Radiology.
MRI and CT scan are both out.
Okay, Iumbar puncture
will tell us
if his proteins are elevated,
at Ieast we can exclude MS.
We can't do
a Iumbar puncture either.
You're cramping my exits.
Don't tell me,
no skin on his spine.
We'd be inserting a needle
into an area
that's teeming with bacteria.
If he doesn't have
a brain infection already,
we'd give him one for sure.
There's no other way
to Iook at a brain.
Transcranial
Doppler Sonography.
She said "brain,"
not "pregnant woman's uterus."
They do sound alike.
I used one to Iook at a brain
this morning.
Why didn't you take
the patient to Radiology,
get an MRA?
Obviously
I was doing something illegal.
Using nuclear imaging
would have raised questions.
You're not gonna get
a diagnosis of MS
from a sonogram.
Not definitively,
but patients with MS
have more reactive neurons
in their occipital cortex.
Okay then.
Thank you for all coming
to today's Iecture
by Dr. Phillip Weber,
who is our guest today
at our hospital
to talk about headaches.
Dr. Weber is at
the Weber Center for Pain,
that makes sense.
Weber, Weber.
So please welcome Dr. Weber!
Thank you Dr. Cuddy.
(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
I suppose I should tell you
a Iittle bit more
about myself.
I went to school in Virginia.
You've never been
to one of these things
in your Iife.
Who is this guy?
No idea.
What's with the outfit?
Sudden chills
and Iight sensitivity.
Inexplicable.
I received my medical degree
at Johns Hopkins University,
where I studied under
Brightman and Gilmar...
Hmm. He must be good.
You went to Hopkins,
and studied
under Brightman and Gilmar.
Shh.
...helped me win
the Doyle Internship
at the Mayo CIinic.
You were supposed
to get the Doyle Internship.
This guy's Von Lieberman?
The guy who got you
thrown out for cheating?
The dean threw me out.
Von Lieberman
just ratted on me.
This guy's name is Weber,
not Von Lieberman.
I call Weber Von Lieberman,
way eviler.
Shh.
...1 D receptors have improved
the acute treatment
of migraines,
to this point...
So what's the plan?
You gonna wait
until he bends over
and make a fart sound?
I'm not here about the past.
He's a bad scientist.
Well, you cheated off him,
how bad can he be?
He got the answer wrong.
DOUG: Are they trying
to wake him up?
They can't do that, right?
He'II be in too much pain.
Don't worry, he's still under.
But the brain
never completely sleeps,
it's always working.
Controlling your heart rate,
breathing, temperature.
The eyes
respond to visual stimuli.
BIood flow increases
in certain areas of the brain
and we can track that
with a sonogram.
With MS, blood vessels
are more reactive,
so flow is faster.
If Adam has an infection,
there'd be swelling,
which would
constrict the arteries.
And the flow would be slower.
Chase.
Near the subarachnoid space.
WEBER: Data from
control subjects were analyzed
of a two-way ANOVA
with status and side
as within-subject factors.
You stalked this guy
for 20 years just for
this shot to humiliate him?
I'm trying to Iearn.
...vessels without
significant rebound...
He doesn't even know
what that means.
You're gonna interrupt him,
aren't you?
If I have a question.
And what's that
gonna accomplish?
Why can't you just enjoy this?
Why can't you just
be happy for me?
You have got to find
Iess debilitating outlets
than humiliating people.
I hear bowling is more fun
than stalking.
But I'm better at this.
...if "P" is Iess than
point-zero...
BIow a ton of money
on a plasma TV.
We found a subarachnoid bleed.
BIeed in the head
isn't causing seizures.
It could be. 10% with damage
to cerebral cortex
have a seizure.
Or bacterial meningitis.
Viral encephalitis?
There's no way
to tell without...
Shut up!
Excuse me.
Not you.
You know, if my Iecture
is interrupting your meeting,
I can wait.
(SPEAKING HINDI)
As your people say in India.
Appreciate it.
We'II figure out why Iater.
Fix the bleed or he dies.
Talk to you in a couple hours.
(SPEAKING HINDI)
I'm in the subarachnoid space.
Can you get it?
Think so.
Put the probe
back where it was
so I can see the wire!
We're Iooking for the bleed
in...
Look when I get there,
I'm flying blind
without a contrast CT here!
...and with a p-value
of Iess than 0.001,
we have strong statistical
evidence that this drug
prevents migraine headaches
without daily administration.
Excuse me, Doctor.
He knows his field
better than you do.
It's always been
my understanding that, unless
you follow a daily regimen,
no drug
can prevent a migraine.
That's why they call it
a breakthrough.
That's why
you call it a breakthrough.
No, the pharmaceutical company
sponsoring my clinical trials
also hails it
as a breakthrough.
I'm sure your wife
and Iawyer do, too.
Is there anybody
who doesn't stand
to make a fortune from it
calling it a breakthrough?
Who are you?
Just a Iunatic
who desperately needs a hobby.
How exactly
do these studies work?
Do you give this drug
to a bunch of people,
and if they don't
get a migraine, you go,
"Voila, my drug works"?
Excuse me, miss?
Do you have cancer?
Wow! Mango juice
prevents cancer.
Perhaps I should have
taken my medication
before this Iecture.
WEBER: We had
a very specific control group,
chronic migraine sufferers.
I don't have time
to go through
all the math right now,
but the incidence
was dramatically...
Sure, in India.
Two plus two
equals five there, right?
Do I know you?
I know your math skills.
They blow.
Touche.
You sound very familiar.
Why did you publish it
in an obscure journal
in India?
Why not publish it
in really, really cool
head cases of South Philly?
Neuroscience New Delhi
is a respected journal.
Yeah.
The guy running SIurp N' Gulp
tells me it's one of the best.
Get a hooker, anything.
See, I'm thinking
that publishing studies
is probably the easiest way
to get
a pharmaceutical company
to give you a reach-around.
And choosing a journal
that no one can actually read,
well, that's...
That's shrewd.
I know I know you.
Sure you do, Dick.
The name's Philip.
My bad. Something to do
with your face.
I always think
your name is Dick.
House?
Here.
Medical school
was 20 years ago.
Give it a rest. Grow up.
Yeah. You were always
the grown-up. Do the
responsible thing, tattletale!
You cheated!
I cheated then,
you're cheating now!
Your drug doesn't work.
Oh, yes, you would Iike to
believe that because it plays
right into your fantasy...
I tested it.
Oh, really?
What are your parameters?
Where's your study?
Room 2134.
One patient?
The coma patient?
You haven't changed a bit.
You took shortcuts
in med school,
you're taking shortcuts now.
You cannot test this
on an abnormal brain.
That's so close-minded.
He's not abnormal,
he's special.
Cerebral cortex
atrophies in coma patients.
You need Iive,
conscious people.
You don't know everything,
House!
FOREMAN: Something
that disrupts brain function.
PIaques are perfect.
Interrupt
neuronal communication.
MS?
No, MS is complicated.
I think this is more basic.
It's just tachycardia
and seizures.
How much Ionger
the Burn Unit guys
gonna keep him in that thing?
Lecture's over, Iet's go.
House wants to...
Adam's waking up.
Get the anesthesiologist
in here now.
CAMERON: He's in pain.
That's not pain.
Need some help in here!
Adam had an orgasm.
What? You mean,
while he was sedated...
(HOUSE EXCLAIMING)
What's wrong?
I'm having a migraine.
Are you okay?
Yes.
I was right.
(GROANING)
I'm gonna knock you out
for a couple of hours.
No, I got work to do.
Just give me sumatriptan
for the pain
and verapamil
so it doesn't recur.
I heard the patient had fun
in the hyperbaric chamber.
Yeah.
Gotta schedule me
some time in there.
Weber's meds
aren't even Iegal in the U.S.
It's Iegal in India.
I was disoriented.
Moving around is a bad idea.
Hey, if you feel chest pain,
you need to Iet me know.
Verapamil can cause
congestive heart failure.
Nothing can hurt my heart.
Hey, you're gonna feel
some dizziness. Definitely
gonna be constipated.
Differential diagnosis
for getting off.
Is he gonna be okay?
No. Something's
seriously wrong with him.
Differential diagnosis
for ejaculation.
Don't make me say it again.
We're not stalling,
we just don't know.
Then guess.
Could pain medication
cause an orgasm?
I wish.
Maybe pain caused the orgasm.
You get a tattoo,
the brain releases endorphins
which create pleasure.
Most people don't orgasm
from a needle prick.
HOUSE: Well,
Chase has a point.
The brain
is Iike a huge train station,
if the switches...
(GROANING)
You're the neurologist,
talk for me.
If sensory information
got misinterpreted by
the medial forebrain bundle,
it's possible
for bad to feel good,
and good to feel bad.
He's a Iucky kid.
Let's not fix him
until the burns heal.
So what attacks
the medial forebrain bundle?
Infective neuropathies,
vasculitic neuropathies...
Krabbe's disease,
metachromatic Ieukodystrophy.
HOUSE: AII very bad things.
No way to Iook for any of them
in his condition.
Could be an infection.
I said infection
about eight seconds ago.
You Iisted
some brain infections.
But what if it's just
a regular old infection
festering in the burned skin?
Pus on his arm
isn't causing problems
in the forebrain.
He's on
20 different medications
to manage his pain, his heart,
how often he urinates.
His brain is Iike a waiter
that's got too many...
Hey, hey. I do the metaphors.
The brain is stressed.
An infection elsewhere
could put it over the edge.
So we just wait
for his burns to heal
to see if you're right?
If you're wrong,
he doesn't have
that kind of time.
Dominic Larrey.
He another dead doctor?
He's Napoleon's
Surgeon in Chief.
CIeaned
a Iot of battle wounds.
By amputating Iegs.
And with bugs.
CAMERON: Maggots are implanted
directly into Adam's burns.
Maggots, they eat dead people,
I...
Maggots eat dead flesh.
Only dead flesh.
So they're perfectly suited
to clean wounds.
They also kill the bacteria
that thrive
in injured tissues.
(EXCLAIMING)
Dr. Jekyll, I presume.
They found a half-eaten sheep
in the zoo. The police
wanna ask you a few questions.
I need something
to wash it down.
Coffee? Bad idea.
You're better off with water!
Coffee's closer.
Foolproof plan, by the way.
Either his meds would work,
and you'd be in psychic pain
because Von Evil
is gonna be rich.
Or they wouldn't,
and you get
to be in agony all day.
Perfect Iose-Iose situation.
Very you.
I had to prove...
You've proved nothing.
Right. This isn't a migraine.
Yeah. "Dear New England
Journal of Medicine,
"I took this guy's drug
and still got a headache.
"Thus, scientifically proving
that my arch enemy
is an idiot."
You just wanted the pain.
Meds are supposed
to prevent migraine.
You get distracted by pain.
Leaves Iess room
for the things
you don't wanna think about.
Like the FIyers sucking,
or the price of gas,
or the fact that you pushed
the Iove of your Iife
out of your Iife.
God, I wish the pain
would go away.
Next time you need
to get your mind off her,
stick a needle in your eye.
It's Iess annoying
to the rest of us
when you can still walk.
CAMERON: Did you sleep here?
Lower.
Do you want a pillow?
Not softer, Iower.
Frequency of your voice
is grating.
You should've been better
by now.
I'm super.
Patient?
The maggots
did great for the burn.
But the brain waves
are still all over the map.
Which means your regular
old infection isn't causing
his brain dysfunction.
Which means there's
an underlying condition,
which means
we've gotta get
inside his head.
Do a Iumbar puncture.
We've already established
that we can't get a Iumbar...
C2, C3.
No. No. No way.
I only saw
a cervical tap once,
and that guy got paralyzed.
Ask the parents if they prefer
to have their son
in a wheelchair or dead.
Something's causing his brain
to Iose control.
Eventually it'II shut off.
We need to do
a Iumbar puncture
to get some of the fluid
in his spine
so we can test it.
You need us to sign a consent?
I have to warn you.
There's a serious risk
of paralysis or death.
Are you saying
we shouldn't do this?
You have to do this.
Then why are you telling us
what can go wrong?
I just think
you should know...
Either you're cruel
or this clipboard is a way
for you to cover your ass,
in case you cripple our son.
This isn't his fault.
No, it's not.
It's yours, that's what
you keep telling me.
My son is Iying in there
half-dead,
I am just trying to find a way
to get through this.
I'm sorry.
Yeah, I know.
(MONITOR BEEPING)
Needle.
It's not going in.
Don't force it.
I'm going one space higher.
It's too close
to his brain stem,
it'II herniate.
You're gonna paralyze him.
You're not helping.
His blood pressure's spiking,
stop.
I can get it.
(MONITOR BEEPING RAPIDLY)
He's 180 over 1 20,
he's gonna stroke.
I'm in the space.
Give me the vial.
(MONITOR BEEPING RHYTHMICALLY)
He doesn't have MS
or an infection.
His proteins aren't elevated?
Wrong protein. IgM, not IgG.
EIevation was probably caused
by the bleed.
What if there was tingling
in his extremities
prior to the crash?
How can you still be on MS?
I gotta be on something.
Something's interrupting
his neurons' chitchat,
Iike Iesions.
We can't scan for them.
The only test we can do,
we just did
and it was negative.
He has no tingling,
no numbness.
And you read his history,
parents didn't say
anything about...
What about Adam?
We can't Iook into his brain,
but you want us
to read his mind?
Good point.
(DOOR OPENING)
Yeah, you can finish
the sponge bath in a minute.
They're just
re-doing his dressings.
He's out, he's fine.
I didn't page you
to put him out.
I paged you to wake him up.
Why are these Iights
so damn bright?
Thank you.
Come on,
I need to talk to him.
House, you can't wake up
a burn victim
to play twenty questions.
It's torture.
He won't remember.
He's gonna be
in extraordinary...
God, you're good!
You're putting me to sleep.
I know he's gonna be in pain,
I know you disapprove.
I'm his attending.
Wake him up.
(GASPING)
Oh, my God!
I'm Dr. House.
It hurts!
It's gonna get a Iot worse,
so answer fast.
Before the accident, did you
experience any numbness
or tingling in your fingers?
You got burned, it's healing,
I need an answer.
It really hurts!
Any tingling
in your arms or Iegs?
You gotta do something,
I can't...
Adam, you gotta Iisten to me,
did you feel anything?
(CRYING IN PAIN)
I pissed in my pants
and then I don't remember...
(SCREAMING IN PAIN)
Was he okay?
Get everyone in my office.
Where you going?
Kid's screaming
gave me a headache.
I gotta take an aspirin.
House, you okay?
We've been waiting for you.
I'm hallucinating.
Hallucinations with migraines
are pretty uncommon.
What did you see?
I saw music.
Sensory deception
makes no sense.
You took something.
The kid's
fighting for his Iife.
Hey, you find him?
He was hallucinating
in the Iocker room.
He okay?
He's feeling no pain,
he's high.
Vicodin high?
Past that. He's seeing sounds.
Took something.
Why is it so dark in here?
It's a beautiful day outside.
Open the shades,
Iet the sun shine in.
It's nighttime.
It's still Tuesday, right?
You Iook better.
I took something.
Mind if I ask what?
Little of this,
Iittle of that.
I know
what's wrong with our patient.
He's depressed.
He told you that
when you woke him up?
Nope.
He told me he pissed his pants
and blacked out.
That's not diagnostic of
depression. Lack of appetite,
isolating yourself.
Uncontrollable urination
and blacking out
are good predictors of what?
Seizure.
Which means the seizure he had
when you tested his heart
was at Ieast
his second seizure.
So what?
Depression and seizures
aren't correlated.
No, but you know what is?
Depression
and anti-depression medicine.
Tox screen was clean.
Yeah, but you know
how much crap
he's got in his system
for dealing with those burns.
The guy could have
the Spanish Armada floating
through his bloodstream
and we wouldn't know about it,
till they started
firing cannons.
Antidepressants have been
known to cause seizures
in kids, but not orgasms.
This is a brain in trouble.
This is a brain
with too much serotonin.
Serotonin affects mood,
appetite, it doesn't cause
the brain to shut down.
Antidepressants fake brains
into thinking
they have more serotonin
than they actually do.
Every ten million or so cases
sets off a chain reaction.
Produces too much,
enough to fry itself.
If Adam has Serotonin Storm,
it's deadly.
But treatable. Cyproheptadine.
Unless he doesn't have
Serotonin Storm.
He could just as easily have
too much dopamine
as serotonin,
but if it's dopamine,
the cyproheptadine
will kill him.
Where are you going?
Gonna talk to the kid again,
he seems nice.
You can't.
Why? Did he say
he doesn't Iike me?
Anesthesiologist
told the parents what you did.
Everyone's a tattletale.
Is your son depressed?
No. Who are you?
I'm Dr. House.
Oh, you're the idiot
who thought...
I heard him screaming
all the way down the hallway.
If I didn't wake him up,
I wouldn't have Iearned
what caused the crash.
He had a seizure.
This wasn't my fault?
Well, if he hadn't
had the brain problem,
he wouldn't have the burns.
On the other hand,
if you hadn't put him
on the ATV,
he also
wouldn't have the burns.
You can debate
your personal responsibility
after I Ieave.
I need to wake him up again.
I need to know if
he's taking antidepressants.
He's not.
He's the happiest kid I know.
But you don't know, do you?
He's my son.
That's sort of my point.
At 16,
they'II tell anyone anything,
except their parents.
Adam talks to us
about everything.
Yeah, I know
about the pot and the cocaine.
There was never... Cocaine.
What...
Are you sure?
Are you having him followed?
He told us
when he got drunk at a party.
when he started having sex.
At 16? Way to go.
He told us
when he cheated
on a math test.
He told us
when his girlfriend
cheated on him.
He doesn't hide
anything from us.
But if he was depressed?
He'd tell us.
We don't judge,
he's not depressed,
we're sure.
"Bet his Iife on it" sure?
Just hypothetically.
Yeah.
Okay.
Kid's happy.
Happy, happy, happy.
Then we're back
to where we started.
Seizure disorders.
Seizure disorders
aren't causing orgasms.
Vascular malformations?
Would've seen it
on the sonogram.
Hepatic encephalopathy?
Liver enzyme tests
were normal.
Where are you going?
Take a Ieak.
What are you doing?
You can't come in here,
you're not sterile.
Don't touch our son,
we told you...
Seriously,
millions of bacteria,
microbes on you.
He'II die of sepsis.
If you go in there...
I think
he's gonna wake him up again.
I know he is.
House, you can't do this.
Oh, if I had a nickel
for every time
I've heard that. Relax.
Are they gonna sue us?
If I'm right, I save his Iife.
If I'm wrong,
he's dead no matter what I do.
Either way, how much
have I really hurt them?
Leave him alone!
You're not sterile.
Do you wanna kill the kid?
Give me the syringe.
No pain, no gain.
Hey, you gotta stop this.
They're right.
He's not depressed.
FOREMAN: Yeah, sure.
I'm not Ietting you go
till you give me that syringe.
What's that on his wrist?
A burn.
Why on his wrist?
Why not on his wrist?
His back, his torso,
everything's a mess.
His forearms are clean.
Except right there.
So what?
It's a perfect circle.
So a drop of burning gasoline
fell on his wrist,
a screw from the ATV.
Maybe.
Why are you torturing him?
Does your son smoke?
I'd kill him.
So, he can talk to you
about sex, crack,
anything except cigarettes.
He has a cigarette burn
on his wrist.
AIso a fading nicotine stain
between two fingers.
Bad news,
your son has a filthy,
unhealthy habit.
Good news,
he's trying to quit.
Bad news,
the quitting's killing him.
Good news,
I can cure him. Bad news...
Nope, that's the end of it.
Quitting smoking can kill?
No-smoke meds
are antidepressants.
The crappy ones
you get over the Internet
are Ioaded
with whatever antidepressants
they can get cheap.
And since Mommy and Daddy
obviously didn't take him
to a pediatrician...
Sorry, I was wrong
about him being depressed.
Treat him.
(DOOR OPENING)
CUDDY: Hey!
Did you drop acid?
Why would I do that?
To annoy me.
Or maybe because
you're miserable,
or because
you want to self-destruct.
Pick one.
How about because LSD
acts on serotonin receptors
in the brain,
which can stop
a migraine in its tracks.
I'm just saying
that's also a possibility.
How did you know about it?
Cameron is worried about you.
I told her that LSD Iasts
up to 1 2 hours, if you were
functional, she must be wrong.
Either that or I also took
a whole bunch
of antidepressants,
which short-circuited the LSD.
I'm just saying
that would also explain it.
Thank you for ruining
my clinical trials.
Pharmaceutical company's
shutting me down.
You're kidding. Really?
How could that surprise you?
You sent them an email
complaining about my math,
telling them about your stunt.
I didn't know
people actually read emails.
Delete button's
so conveniently Iocated.
So what's next?
You gonna follow me
my whole Iife?
Torture me?
Why would I do that?
You waited 20 years
to do this. What's next?
Break up my marriage?
No. We're even.
Right.
Oh, thanks for setting me up.
Eye for an eye,
LSD and antidepressants.
Everything in balance.
Buddhists call it Karma.
Christians call it
the Golden Rule.
Jews call it...
I don't know,
Rabbi Hillel
said something poignant.
Universe
always settles the score.
Does it?
No.
But it should.
Do you think you'II ever
be able to Iook at him
and not blame me?
Yeah. Will you?
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
PAULA: I'm Paula.
Hey, Paula.
How you doing?
You work over at the college,
or are you full-time
over at the...
I'm Iooking for a distraction.
You don't need to talk
to do that, do you?