Try not to be scared
when you see him, okay?
Mom, I've seen him sick.
I'm not scared.
This time's different.
The doctors gave him
an extra course of
radiation and chemo...
I know.
And you understand
how proud we are of you,
right?
Gloves, mask.
Matty, you said you wanted
to see your brother
before the procedure.
I know I look like an alien,
but I promise not to eat
your brain.
(CHUCKLES)
When this is done,
will you be able to
play out back with me?
I'll rip anything you
put near the strike zone.
Let your brother rest up,
while we take
some of your marrow.
You don't need to be
in an isolation room,
but I pulled some strings
so you could be next door
to your brother.
How many games will I miss?
Well, you only have to
be here overnight,
but you do have to
take it easy for a little bit.
I already missed two.
Matty...
I know. It's okay.
It must have been a drag.
We just had to make sure
you weren't exposed
to any bugs,
because your healthy bone
marrow is what's gonna cure
your brother's leukemia.
(GROWLS)
Go on.
(BARKING)
CHASE: He sneezed.
Maybe it's just an allergy.
Not with an enlarged spleen
and a fever.
WILSON: He's got one of 10,000
possible infections,
even if it's just the common
cold, I do the transplant,
he kills his brother.
How long do we have?
Radiation obliterated
his immune system.
Even in a clean room,
he's got four, maybe five,
days left.
No way we can solve this
that fast. You need to find
another donor.
They're African American.
It makes it nearly impossible
to find a full match.
Tell me about it.
I can't even find the one
I've got working for me.
Where is Foreman?
Nothing like a dead patient
to send you back
to your choir boy roots.
Hey, you're not gonna
believe what happened.
Wilson just killed a kid
same way you did.
He's not dead.
Five days are gonna fly by.
He didn't look both ways
before he nuked.
You done talking to
your imaginary friend?
Because I thought, maybe,
you could do
your job and just...
Start the donor brother
on broad-spectrum antibiotics.
Great idea,
if you're looking to
save exactly one kid.
Broad-spec will take
at least a week to work.
We need narrow-spec.
How old is Hector?
Our patient's name is Matty.
His brother's Nick.
Hector's my dog.
He's about 17?
Seventeen? That's, like,
a 119 in human years.
Why is he still alive?
Five days minus 20 seconds
talking about Wilson's dog.
We need to start testing.
Stool samples for parasites,
antibody tests...
Blood panel was negative
for all the usual suspects.
That's because the
infection is too small.
We start testing now,
it's like looking for
a needle in a haystack.
We draw blood odds are
we're just gonna
come up with hay.
We need to
grow more needles.
Okay, that probably needs
further explanation.
We make the donor kid sicker.
We freeze him, we soak him,
break down his immune system.
Suddenly we're looking at
some needle that a camel
can pass through the eye of.
Making him sicker risks
spreading the infection
all throughout his body.
True, but who cares?
Once we know what
the infection is, we'll know
exactly how to treat it.
As long as he isn't dead yet,
we're cool.
We should do
what we normally do.
Go to the kid's house,
check for sources
of the infection.
Waste of time.
You think it's in the house.
I know it's in the patient.
Safer than
intentionally making
the kid sicker.
Fine, go.
So exactly how sick
are you gonna make Matty?
He could get quite ill.
It certainly won't be a
pleasant experience for
anyone, but it's our only...
Ever get caught in the rain
without an umbrella?
That's all we're
talking about here.
Sign the form.
It's a little more complicated
than that. We'll also be
doing leukopheresis.
We run Matty's blood through
a machine that filters out
his white blood cells.
But without his white cells,
how could he get better
in time?
We'll pump the white
blood cells back as soon as
we have a diagnosis.
Then we should be able to cure
the infection in time
to do the transplant.
But you can't guarantee?
We're not GM.
No recalls, no rebates.
Anymore questions
while your son's life
slips away?
You really think
we should do this?
Yes.
Sorry. Your patient,
you tell them.
This is your family.
It needs to be your decision.
All you had to do was
say, "Yes, I do."
God knows it's a phrase
that you've used
often enough in your life.
It was a mistake every time.
Give it a break.
They said yes.
That's not enough for you.
You need them to feel good
about saying yes.
I treat patients for months,
maybe years,
not weeks, like you.
I'm taller.
If they don't trust me,
I can't do my job.
The only value of that trust
is that you can
manipulate them.
You should write
greeting cards.
Giving the parents a chance
to make a bad choice
was a bad choice.
At least it would have
been their choice.
One they'd regret
at their son's funeral.
Kitchen and bathrooms were
immaculate. Whatever the kid's
got, he didn't get here.
No, whatever the kid got,
he didn't get from
the kitchen or the bathroom.
Nobody cleans swing sets.
Yeah, because their kid's 10
and hasn't used it
since he was six.
You obviously think your time
could be better spent.
Why'd you come along?
You feel bad about
what happened last week.
I'm handling it.
Think the family's gonna sue?
She only had her grandparents,
and they weren't close.
Well, that's good.
For you, I mean.
A lawsuit makes it even harder
to put behind you.
You put yours behind you?
Nope.
When I woke up
this morning I...
I couldn't remember
what she was wearing
when I admitted her.
Memories fade.
I killed her a week ago and
I can't remember what color
top she was wearing.
I was grateful when
I could wake up
not thinking about her.
I'm not like you.
Your patient died because
you were distracted
over the death of your dad.
I made a calculated decision.
You acted like a human being.
I acted like House.
Could be Mucor or
Strongyloides in this dirt.
No pulmonary symptoms,
setting well,
breathing easily.
Mom, I'm freezing.
How long do I have to wait?
Matty, we found
an old water pump
in your backyard.
You ever drink from it?
Yeah it was gross.
We gotta test
for Mycobacteria,
leptospirosis.
When did you drink the water?
Last summer?
You sure?
You haven't even taken
a sip to cool off?
It was really gross.
My shoulder's bugging me.
Does that matter?
It could. Did you
do anything to hurt it?
Just threw the ball around
the other day,
for a couple hours.
It's probably just
a muscle ache.
Let us know if it gets worse.
So soreness and stuff,
that's not 'cause I'm sick?
Is something else bugging you?
Sort of.
He has acute scrotum.
Adorable.
Please, I thought you
were dignified.
Come on,
how am I not supposed to
make that joke?
Best thing about big,
honking gonads, well,
one of the best things,
is that there's only
a few infections
that could cause it.
Do urinalysis and cultures for
E. Coli, Klebsiella,
TB, and Brucella.
Blood tests
for enteroviruses
and adenoviruses.
Hopefully, the needles
have grown as fast as
his sack, and we can find it.
Can Chase and Cameron
cover that?
Mind if I ask why?
I want to recheck the
National Marrow registry
for an alternate donor.
In case we're wrong?
It's been known to happen.
Fine, go.
Negative for E. Coli and TB.
Why is House taking
it easy on Foreman?
He deserves a break.
Yeah, House is all about
giving breaks to people
in need.
No on Klebsiella.
And it's Tuesday.
It's got nothing to do with
Foreman or House. It's just...
It's the day I remind you
I like you, and I want us
to be together.
Thank you, I'd forgotten.
No on Brucella
and both viral antibodies.
You're really gonna
do this every Tuesday?
You take the day off,
I'll pick it up on Wednesday.
What if we're looking for
the wrong thing?
These are the only infections
that cause swollen testicles.
Why don't you just say it
four times now and leave me
alone for a month?
Well, what if it's
not an infection?
His temperature's through
the roof. There's mucous
pouring out of him.
I know he has an infection,
but what if it didn't directly
cause the scrotum issue?
What if it just caused
the thing that caused
the scrotum issue?
CK-MB is elevated.
Slightly.
There's nothing wrong with...
Indicates cardiac injury.
We stuck him in that room, put
his stupid, little runny-nose
infection into hyperdrive.
What if it went to his heart?
CHASE: Pulmonary valve
looks clean.
Wait. Stop. Mitral valve,
there's a growth.
He'll need a month
of antibiotics to clear that.
His brother only has
four days to live.
The infection in Matty's
mitral valve rules him out
as a donor.
This is perfect.
We drove the infection
into his heart.
Okay, perfect is too strong
of a word, but it's very,
very good.
Now we know
where the infection is.
All we've got to do is remove
the valve, ID the infection,
target and destroy it.
Remove the valve?
He'll be fine on antibiotics.
He doesn't need open-heart
surgery.
He'll be heartbroken,
on account of
his dead brother.
Either way he's got a dead
brother. The infection
isn't just in the valve.
Even with targeted medication,
there's no way
we can clear his system
in time.
We don't have to.
We have to clear his marrow.
After the surgery,
we harvest the marrow,
marinate it in the targeted
antibiotic, simmer and serve.
Could work.
It's insane.
It is better than
a dead brother.
I'm running this by Cuddy.
Fine. Go.
In fact, let's all go.
This surgery is dangerous
and life-altering,
and clearly not in
the interest of our patient.
It is, if he
likes his brother.
We have a conflict
of interests.
WILSON: The parents don't.
FOREMAN: Of course they do.
They already sacrificed
Matty's health to benefit
his brother once.
They made his cold worse.
We screwed up his heart valve
by making his cold worse.
Do you have anything
to add to this debate?
Wilson's right.
Foreman's wrong.
Your shirt is way too
revealing for the office.
What do you want me to do?
We should call child services
and have them appoint
a guardian for Matty.
No.
Go explain the choices
to the parents, and don't
let House bully them.
House.
Did he really think
I was gonna do that?
I didn't.
Then, why did you let him...
I'm trying to
cut him some slack.
Nice of you.
I think he's got the yips.
Steve Blass, Scott Norwood,
David Duval all got the yips.
Great athletes, lost their
confidence and immediately
started sucking.
And you're giving him time
to work through it?
Four days, and he's fired.
You don't get better
from the yips.
Open-heart surgery?
If you want both kids to live,
it's the only choice.
Due to the valve replacement.
Matty will have to be
on blood thinners
to prevent potential clots.
For how long?
Forever.
He couldn't participate
in contact sports, because of
the risk of hemorrhage.
What about the
marrow registry?
Maybe they'll find a match.
Maybe they'll ride it here
on a unicorn.
I'm afraid finding
a viable new donor
isn't something we can
realistically depend on.
Either we cripple one son,
or kill the other.
He won't be able to play
baseball. That doesn't
make him a cripple.
What should we do?
You should protect
your family as a whole.
You should do the surgery.
That was awesome.
Shut up.
I gotta start
pretending to care.
I did exactly what
Cuddy told us not to do.
No you didn't.
You did exactly what
she told me not to do.
You're completely
in the clear.
Oh, you've got to be
kidding me.
You're actually upset.
You just said
what you believed.
I also believe in patients
making their own choices.
Because it lessens your guilt
if things go wrong.
You're not protecting
their choices. You're
soothing your conscience.
By that logic, a sociopath
would make the best patient
advocate in the world.
Am I blushing?
You ready?
Yeah.
Thanks.
You'd do the same for me.
Don't worry. You'll be fine.
You think I'll be
better in time to pitch
in the playoffs?
Maybe next season.
We should have told him.
He loves his brother,
but if he understood what
we were asking of him...
He loves his brother more than
he loves baseball.
You did the right thing.
Putting any part
of this decision on him...
It's impossible for you guys
to deal with this.
How's a 10-year-old
supposed to do it?
Canula in place.
Sutures are holding.
We're all set to go.
Switch him over to bypass.
(WOMAN CHATTERING ON TV)
(PHONE RINGING)
Yeah?
I didn't do the surgery.
You woke me up
to tell me that you're lazy?
We biopsied a piece
before we started cutting.
I'm tired. Get to the point.
We didn't replace the valve
because the growth
was fibrous tissue.
It wasn't infectious.
We've got to be wrong about...
Oh, God.
What?
You know what's wrong
with Matty?
I think Hector's
committed suicide.
What are you talking about?
He took some pills.
Is he alive?
He ate half my stash.
Of course he's...
(GRUNTS)
He's stoned. I'll be right in.
We cut all the way
into this kid's heart,
and all we got was this lousy,
non-infectious fibrous tissue.
How did we miss this?
Matty had a fever.
He got sicker when we
suppressed his immune system.
That all points to infection.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Not our fault. Fibrous tissue.
Something is turning
his healthy heart valve
into gristle.
Fibrous tissue,
enlarged spleen, fever...
Could mean autoimmune.
Autoimmune diseases
aren't passed along
in bone marrow.
He can still donate.
We confirm, I do the surgery.
Lupus and Behçet's are
our best bet.
Do an ANA and pathergy test.
Or it could be infection.
My memory's not
what it used to be,
but didn't we just
rule that out
eight seconds ago?
Just because it's not
what screwed up his valve,
it doesn't mean
it's not in his system.
Uh-huh, and has the obvious
advantage of making us right
all along.
Little disadvantage
of making big brother dead.
That's your argument?
A better outcome?
It fits.
The family has one kid
with leukemia
and one with autoimmune.
I wouldn't stand next to them
in a rain storm.
That's your argument?
It sucks for them?
It fits, and we can
still help big brother.
National Marrow Registry
came up with four
out of six donors.
Six out of six is two better
than four out of six, right?
I mean, I know two
is so small,
but since it means that
he's gonna get
Graft-Versus-Host Disease,
the marrow will
attack his body, and he'll
die a painful death.
Find out what
autoimmune it is.
Is this autoimmune
better or worse than
the new heart valve?
It depends on which autoimmune
it is. With early detection,
most are manageable.
How long will testing take?
That's the other good thing
about this.
There's literally
thousands of
possible infections,
but only a handful of
autoimmune conditions.
We'll have the answer
in a few hours.
NICK: Hey, Doctor?
Is this bad?
Wanna catch a movie?
It's one in the morning.
I know a place.
Although, I wouldn't recommend
wearing those shoes.
How exactly does a dog
unscrew a bottle of pills?
Is that a riddle?
It requires
an opposable thumb.
I must have left it off.
On the floor?
I think he hopped up
onto the bathroom counter.
He has arthritis.
Not me this time.
No! It's your damn dog.
He chews everything.
I was missing a file.
Found paper in his stool.
An original Sun Record 78
Elvis recording, gone.
Who the hell chews vinyl?
He's vindictive.
He's had a good, long life.
It's his time.
Are you okay?
I just tripped over
Wilson's self-righteousness.
What do you got?
Matty's negative
for everything.
It's not autoimmune.
So, we're back to infection.
Nick's starting to deteriorate
fast. He's got bruising
all over his arms.
His capillaries
are leaking blood.
If it happens in his brain,
he's dead.
We've got to go
with the four-out-of-six
donor.
Did I mention my concerns
about four being less
than six?
Wilson's first wife
ignored a similar issue.
Of course, that time,
it was only fatal
to their marriage.
It's either that, or we start
randomly testing Matty
for infections.
I know how you hate
the word "random."
Do it alphabetically.
We're not doing
that damn transplant.
Where's Foreman?
We've found a donor.
It's not an ideal match,
but four out of six
still gives Nick a chance.
A partial match transplant
is extremely dangerous.
Doctor Foreman explained...
Did he also explain
what sort of pain
your son will experience
if he gets
Graft-Versus-Host Disease?
Yes.
Apparently,
he didn't explain it
vividly enough.
Let me give it a whack...
He also explained that if we
did nothing, Nick could start
bleeding into his brain.
Matty is a perfect match.
Just give us a little more
time to figure out...
How much time?
Doctor House is
the best diagnostician...
How much time?
I don't know.
And Nick can start
bleeding into his brain
without any warning?
Yes, but the chances of
complications from
a mismatch are...
My boys have suffered enough.
Get Matty better,
and give Nick the transplant
from the new donor.
Foreman screwed us.
No, you screwed us.
What is the point
in being able to
control people
if you won't actually do it?
It's like training a dog and
letting him go on your rug,
which, by the way...
Once Foreman got his mitts
on them, well,
there was no way...
You don't explain chances
and probabilities,
you lie to them.
You tell them Foreman's
a moron, which isn't even
much of a lie right now.
You've got to talk to him.
I've got no problem
with what Foreman did.
He undercut us,
and he may have cost
that kid his life.
Foreman did what he thought
was right. You, on the
other hand, sucked out.
When the decision
really mattered,
you didn't have the guts
to tell them what to do.
If that kid dies,
it's because Foreman
was wrong,
and because you're a coward.
Oh, goodness,
I've left my door open.
My poor dog must have
run away and been hit by
a car or a truck or a train.
Or an anvil.
(HECTOR PANTING)
Thank God, you're still here.
He's still here!
Where's my stereo?
(HECTOR YELPS)
How are you feeling?
A little itchy.
It's weird, huh?
You still have no idea
what's wrong with me,
but those meds will
make me better.
We put you on a variety
of medications that will fight
all kinds of infections.
Nick, you know exactly
what's wrong with him,
but maybe he's gonna die,
anyway.
Hopefully,
the new marrow will...
I can't go in there, can I?
Your infection would kill him.
So, I won't be able to
be with him when he dies?
You'll be able to be with him
when he gets better.
What's wrong?
It really itches.
Hello?
Why am I meeting you here?
You're paying for my new cane.
It was your dog.
So, that's it?
You call me a coward,
life goes on?
Apparently. You showed up.
Hey.
I'm sorry.
(BELL DINGING)
You're pathetic.
I didn't actually mean that.
Yes, you did.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
No, I didn't to infinity.
Yes, you did.
You're pathetic.
Yeah?
When?
What did the labs say?
Why don't you buy your cane
at a medical supply store
like a normal cripple?
Fewer bitching choices.
Okay. What do you got
in bitching?
Right this way.
That was Cameron.
The kid that wasn't all that
sick is now all that sick.
He's bleeding out of his ears.
Blood counts?
Down.
Schistocytes on the smear?
His body's not making
new blood cells.
His bone marrow's crashing.
This is
one of our top sellers.
It's a little too
Marilyn Manson
in a retirement home.
The meds are suppressing
his bone marrow.
Or the infection's doing it.
Pretty cool.
Genuine bull penis,
stretched over a metal rod.
Penis canes are murder.
Right.
Let me see the one on the end.
You got it.
We need to stop Matty's meds.
If the marrow rebounds,
it's the meds. If it doesn't,
it's an infection.
And if it's the infection?
Maybe I was wrong
about which kid's gonna die.
Bitching.
Flames?
It makes it look like
I'm going fast.
Now, how's our dying kids?
Nick's developed blisters
all over his feet and legs.
He's got grade four
Graft-Versus-Host.
Increase his dosage
of methylprednisolone.
Already did. It's not working.
Feeling guilty?
I did the right thing.
Always a comfort.
Okay, what's
the other kid's status?
We're done with Nick?
God is done with Nick.
We know what he has.
We know how to treat it.
We're doing it,
it's not working.
Life is for the living.
Matty's been off his meds
for a few hours, but his
blood count's still tanking.
Means the meds
aren't to blame.
It's the infection.
If we don't get this
under control, his blood will
literally turn into water.
Cultures still
aren't growing anything.
Why not?
Because you did the
right thing. Convinced
the parents to treat the kid.
All you did
was yank the weed
out of the ground.
Its roots are still killing
their beautiful lawn.
We just can't see it.
If we can't see it,
we don't know what it is.
If we don't know what it is,
we can't kill it.
So we got to wait for it
to grow back again.
Now, the soil is arid.
So with he and his brother
we'll be dead by the time...
What if the dandelion
was in fertile soil?
What if we take the roots
from Matty,
and put them in Nick?
Turn the kid into
a petri dish, only better.
A petri dish can't
tell you when it hurts.
You want to give him
his brother's infection?
The very thing we've been
trying to avoid
since the brother sneezed?
Leukemia kid's
got no defenses.
Which is why he'll die.
But before he does,
the infection
will spread fast.
Fast enough to tell us
what it is, in time to
save his brother.
Do you see any other way?
WILSON: The infection
is decimating
Matty's bone marrow.
But if we give that marrow
to Nick, his symptoms
could let us diagnose Matty.
But, it'll kill Nick.
Yes.
You're...
You're saying we should
kill one son to
save the other?
Nick is gonna die either way.
You don't know that.
I mean, he's in pain
right now, but...
Nick's Graft-Versus-Host
is not responding
to medication.
That can change.
Maybe he... He'll rally.
Hey, my Nick is a fighter.
Graft-Versus-Host
isn't gonna go away
because of Nick's sunny smile
and positive outlook.
Nick has survived
three reoccurrences
of his leukemia.
He's being torn apart
from the inside out.
His pain's gonna get worse
and worse, until he dies.
You're just dragging it out.
You have only
one decision to make.
You can leave here
with one dead son, or two.
Tell them.
You should let us do this.
No!
We're not giving up on Nick.
Not!
The patient's parents
apparently don't want to be
parents anymore.
You're a sneaky bastard.
Any ideas how
we get around this?
Court order?
It's hardly sneaky.
We can still save Matty.
Run more tests,
find out what infection
is destroying his marrow.
Ten-thousand possible
infections at least
20 minutes per test
it'll take you
approximately eight years.
Actually, four months,
assuming the last one I test
is the right one,
and, if it's the first,
it will take me approximately
20 minutes.
He's right. It's worth a shot.
He's timid.
Testing blindly is not
gonna save this kid.
But standing around here will.
(NICK GROANING)
Wow, he sure is hurting.
The nurses say he maxed out
on his pain meds.
If I had a nickel for
every time I heard that...
Pharmacy's
on the ground floor.
I'm gonna go get you
some more pain medication,
okay?
Thank you.
It's not gonna help.
You're dying.
Nothing's gonna change that.
These drugs will just
make you go easier.
I know.
Fourteen years on the planet,
most of them spent suffering.
Dying before you even
got to drive a car,
take off a girl's bra,
drink a beer.
Believe me, there's plenty
you haven't done.
Really good stuff.
Must make it hard
to believe in God,
or fairness, larger purpose.
But your life
doesn't have to be
meaningless.
You can save your brother.
How?
FOREMAN: Negative for CMV.
WILSON: Negative for amoebas.
House called you timid.
He's called me a lot worse.
To him, there is
nothing worse.
He's gonna fire you.
Even if we run 100 tests,
that only gives us
a one percent chance
of saving these kids.
Better than zero.
You don't care
if you get fired?
I don't know.
There's got to be a way to
better our odds from
a 99-percent chance of death.
You've got to know.
It's not food-borne,
because no one else
in the family is sick.
You either care about
your job, or you don't.
And Matty's the only one
who drank from that water
pump in the back yard,
and we eliminated Pseudomonas
and cholera.
If you care,
you fight to keep it.
If you don't, you quit.
I thought they lived
in the suburbs.
They do. Why?
And they've got a water pump?
NICK: Please, I...
I want to do it.
No, Nicky,
it's not your decision.
I'm dying.
There's nothing that's
gonna change that.
Hey, hey, hey.
Don't say that. Okay?
You can't give up.
It's time for me to go, Dad.
You got to let me go.
No.
Please, son.
I can't... I can't...
I can't!
Let me do it for Matty.
Let me do it for you guys.
So you won't be alone.
Are you sure?
No, but he is.
Get Nick back
to the clean room.
The parents agreed
to infect him.
We figured out
what's wrong with Matty,
histoplasmosis.
Well, what is that?
I mean, why did it...
Fungal infection.
It grows in chicken feces.
The dirt that Matty used
to build his pitcher's mound
must have sat under
a chicken coop.
Your whole neighborhood
was built on top of farmland.
We didn't test for it earlier,
because we didn't...
Can you fix him?
Full course of amphotericin
and he should be fine.
And Nick?
I mean, can you clean
Matty's marrow?
Just like you were talking
about doing it, but do it
fast, and get it into Nick.
I'm sorry, the reason
Matty is so sick is
because the infection
is attacking his marrow.
He doesn't have enough left
to safely take from him
and give to his brother.
I'm gonna get better now?
That's it?
That's it.
And what about Nick?
Your brother was willing
to risk his life to save you.
Are you willing to
do that for him?
I can't sedate you.
You're too sick.
(SCREAMING)
Please, please stop. Please.
Please. You're done, right?
Sorry, I need a lot more.
No, stop! Stop!
How much heat are you taking
from the parents?
They're calming down.
I think it has something to do
with both their kids being
alive, awake, and eating.
The marrow transplant took.
Welcome back, Foreman.
You should talk to him.
Tell him how proud I am?
Hey, if you're ashamed of him,
tell him that.
Pride and shame only apply
to people we have a vested
interest in, not employees.
How many hours a day
do you have to spend
with someone
before they're
basically family?
Good point.
But, first, I've got to tell
Cameron and Chase that
they're violating God's will.
I'm just asking you to have
an adult conversation
to let him know...
That he did a good job?
He knows it.
Adults don't need adult
conversations, just like I
don't need this conversation.
Have you killed Hector yet?
Obviously not.
Oh. He's quiet. He's...
Is that my stethoscope?
Bad dog.
Listen...
Bonnie joined her homeowner's
association and staged a coup.
Pets are now allowed.
Oh.
If you want to keep him,
she wants a new puppy anyway.
She'll understand.
Why would I want to keep him?
You're sure?
Come on, boy.
Accidents happen.
Candy?
Good boy.
You did good.
I did what you would have.
Well, maybe I'm biased, but...
I tortured the kid.
Because you knew it was right.
You knew you were
saving his brother.
I know.
I don't like that I know.
I hate that I can listen
to a kid screaming in pain
and not even take a moment
to question whether I'm
doing the right thing.
I hate that in order
to be like you, as a doctor,
I have to be like you
as a human being.
I don't want to turn into you.
You're not.
You've been like me
since you were
eight-years-old.
You'll save more people
than I will.
But I'll settle for
killing less.
Consider this my
two weeks notice.