NARRATOR: Previously on House.
You high, popo?
HOUSE: A cop
with a sense of humor.
You check the cop car.
AIso check his personal car,
work, home.
Foreman, get out!
Am I the only one
who finds this funny?
You stole my article.
I wouldn't do that.
We're not friends.
We're colleagues.
(EXCLAIMS) Son of a bitch!
Now we're both exposed.
In 10 minutes time...
You die, I die.
It's not gonna happen.
Time of death.
1 2:26 p.m.
I need a bone saw.
I'm sorry. I wish I could.
They said you won't...
I just want a Iittle
tiny slice
of this guy's brain.
That's all I need,
just enough to tell me
what's killing Foreman.
A thin slice of Joe's brain
could also cause
a public health crisis.
It's not a good idea
to scream "fire" every time
somebody Iights a match.
Don't downplay this, House.
You put both of them
in isolation for a reason.
Joe's death elevates
this situation
to a Biosafety Level 3.
Level 3.
Did you call Jack Bauer?
I called the CDC.
Well, tell them I'II be
really, really careful.
We don't have the proper
equipment for you to be
really, really careful.
You can do whatever you want
to Foreman, but the CDC
will do this autopsy.
Whatever. The point is,
we'II be Iucky to get results
in three days.
I told them
how urgent this is.
And they told you...
"We'II have the results
in three days."
Oh, that's a shame.
Because Foreman
will never get to know
what it was.
He'II be dead in 36 hours.
Maybe this is a toxin.
Maybe it's not contagious
at all.
You're killing Foreman
because of a "maybe."
Well, you have 36 hours
to figure out which one it is.
Foreman. Come here, fast.
What's going on?
When are they doing
the autopsy?
You're doing it, now.
You ever studied
how they used to do
ice pick Iobotomies?
I read about it in med school.
Why would I...
Shove an ice pick
into the eye socket
just above the tear duct,
bang it a couple times
with a hammer,
get a sample.
What's going on, House?
Foreman, you can't do it!
You'd be in violation of...
Can't do the time
if you're not alive.
CUDDY: You! I need you
to suit up.
Get that equipment
away from Dr. Foreman.
Take your time, guys.
Just tell them to go slow.
It won't be your fault.
Foreman, we don't even know
what kind of contagion
we're dealing with.
Which is why we need
to chop into the guy's head!
It's dangerous.
Not to you, Foreman!
There are other ways
to diagnose you.
Yeah? You have the answer?
Foreman, do it now!
I am warning you! Do not...
What are you doing?
That didn't feel right.
He's blind.
But he thinks he can see.
Same as the cop.
We need something
to bag the sample.
Forget it.
You just biopsied a mattress.
No, no, no. I'm fine.
House, there's the sample.
Get it, test it!
You got to test that sample!
Apparently I was optimistic
about the 36 hours.
Intractable,
unbearable pain is up next.
Sure you don't wanna
reconsider that whole
autopsy thing?
Physically, his eyes are fine.
The problem's isolated
to his brain.
Damage to the occipital Iobe
extends from
the primary visual cortex...
We should retest him
for bacterial meningitis.
If it was meningitis,
we'd all be sick.
His CSF might show signs...
LP's pointless.
We already did
a brain biopsy.
It was negative.
Toxic mold.
If it was toxic mold,
I'd be sick.
How do we know
you're not sick?
Do I seem happy to you?
Never.
(SCOFFS)
It was funny.
Well, Iet's assume it's not
blood-borne.
If you start cracking jokes,
we can reassess.
In the meantime, stay away
from people and animals
that you care about.
Guillain Barré.
Neither of them had
any sort of paralysis.
Joe could have died
before the paralysis
had a chance to present.
What about arbovirus?
Start treatment.
For arbovirus?
You think our Jersey beat cop
has been spending
a Iot of time
exploring deep, dark Africa?
Treatment for everything,
Iikely or unlikely.
If you can think of it,
treat for it.
Mixing that many meds
will create all sorts of
toxic interactions.
We'II box his Iiver, trash
his kidneys. There's got to be
a better way.
Of course
there's a better way!
It's that body sitting
in the room with him
that Cuddy won't Iet us touch!
Bacterials, virals, toxins,
fungals, parasites,
it's got to be one of them.
Where are you going?
See if I can find
another brain to biopsy.
They're gonna Iock Joe up
downstairs until
the CDC gets here.
Foreman, you can't see.
Right.
House wants to start you
on some meds.
They're in the air Iock.
For what?
Leading candidate
is toxic mold.
Is Cameron sick?
I'm fine, thanks for asking.
You're casting your net
a Iittle wider than
toxic mold, aren't you?
Guillain Barré
is also on the table.
This is an oval shape.
That's either an "L" or a "7."
I'm guessing an "L."
Levofloxacin, because
you can't rule out bacteria.
8-0-0. That's the dosage
for acyclovir
in case it's viral.
Square.
No, more Iike a rhombus.
That's fluconazole for fungus.
There's about
eight others here.
You're treating me
for everything.
You have no idea
what I've got.
House thinks this is
the best course of action.
House is desperate.
House is never desperate.
Something we give you
will work.
Yeah, we should start treating
all patients this way.
When they get sick,
they just take everything.
It's better
than doing nothing.
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello?
I'm at the cop's place.
I need to retrace your steps.
You don't think the "treat him
for everything" approach
is enough?
Where did you
start your search?
The kitchen.
Okay, well, tell me
everything you did,
everything you touched.
If you went to the john,
I want to know when and why.
It started with samples
from the mold in his sink.
What next?
That's it. Then I Ieft.
What do we do now?
Wait for Steve McQueen
to get giddy.
Excellent plan.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Hey, Dad, it's Eric.
I'm not doing too good.
(GRUNTS)
How's Foreman?
You're accessing a webcam?
Cuddy's shower.
Are you a fan
of the Brazilian? I...
Is that your kitchen?
Well, obviously
I couldn't bring him here.
He's been exposed
to whatever Foreman's got.
You infected Steve?
Why didn't you just get
a rat from the pet store?
Because I needed one
with a clean medical history.
Who knows
what kind of antibiotics
they gave those rats?
So this is your plan,
just sit here
and watch your rat all day?
It shouldn't take Iong.
I've got the AC blasting,
I soaked the floor
of his cage.
As soon as he gets sick,
I do an autopsy.
As soon as he's dead.
Right after he gets sick,
there's a good chance
he'II get hit in the head
with a cane-shaped object.
Normally you just use
your patients as Iab rats.
It's a nice change.
First symptom is euphoria.
Well, how do you know
if a rat's euphoric?
He doesn't usually climb
on his water bottle Iike that,
does he?
The seizures
only seem to happen
when she's in her car seat.
She starts to rock and grunt.
Is she responsive?
No, no.
It's Iike she's in a zone
and her abdominal muscles
become dystonic.
Big word. Someone's been
on the Interweb.
I Iooked up a few articles
on epilepsy.
You know, there's actually
some really great
youth soccer Ieagues
that would cater specifically
to her special needs,
and I think it might explain
why she's been having
a hard time in preschool.
Well, Iet's confirm
your diagnosis
before you have her held back.
Strobing Iights
and high-pitched sounds
can provoke a seizure.
(WHOOPING)
You're a goof.
Takes one to know one, Ioser.
Wait, that means I'm a Ioser.
Scratch that.
These episodes,
she gets sweaty afterwards?
Soaking wet.
And does she seem upset
by them or just tired?
No. She kind of thinks
it's funny.
You mix rocking, grunting,
sweating and dystonia
with concerned parents
and you get
an amateur diagnosis
of epilepsy.
In actuality,
all your Iittle girl is doing
is saying
"yoo-hoo to the hoo-hoo."
She's what?
Marching the penguin.
Ya-ya-ing the sisterhood.
Finding Nemo.
(GIGGLES)
That was funny.
It's called
"gratification disorder."
Sort of a misnomer.
If one was unable
to gratify oneself,
that would be a disorder.
Are you saying
she's masturbating?
I was trying to be discreet.
There's a child in the room.
This is horrifying.
Epilepsy is horrifying.
Teach your girl about privacy
and she'II be fine.
There you go.
Thank you.
One afternoon,
and you're on pace
to set the record
for most patients
seen in a month.
You're upset
that I'm doing clinic hours?
Wow, that is so Iike
rain on your wedding day.
For the past three hours,
I have been on the phone
with the CDC while you are...
How's that going, by the way?
They promised to expedite...
Tough to do an autopsy
when they haven't even
picked up the body.
It's tough to treat
your patient when you're not
even on the same floor.
Go. CIinic is covered.
I go watch the meds
drip into his IV,
you think that'II make
the treatment work faster?
Go to your office, play with
your ball, write on your
white board, insult your team.
Do whatever it is that you do
to figure things out.
Feeling guilty?
It's not too Iate
to change your mind.
Go call the CDC,
tell them
you were just joshing.
Keep avoiding Foreman's case
until he dies.
Then I'II drown in guilt.
CAMERON: Feeling any better?
How are you doing?
I'm not the patient.
Is your sed rate elevated?
No. So far,
it Iooks Iike I Iucked out.
Cameron, it Iooks Iike
you Ieft the tourniquet
on the bed.
You can see again?
The treatment's working.
The question is,
which treatment?
We'II start weaning him off
one at a time.
Which one do we start with?
I don't care
if you do it alphabetically.
Just stay on top
of his vision.
First sign of regression
means we've taken him off
the wrong one.
Latest blood work.
Foreman's amylase and Iipase
Ievels are three times normal.
The pancreas is failing.
A toxic side effect
of his meds.
Philosophical question:
How do you wanna die?
OId age.
Your choice is currently
between 4 hours from now
and 14 hours from now.
So I'm assuming that means
you want the Iatter.
The cocktail's working.
My vision's almost
completely restored.
The meds are curing what's in
your head, but they're
trashing your pancreas.
That's why you're puking
and you can't stand up
without screaming.
So Iower the dosages.
Less stress on my pancreas,
still battle the infection.
Lower dosages
will still be toxic.
I don't care!
I can handle the pain
of the pancreatitis.
I don't think
you can handle Iife
without a pancreas.
If we keep you on these meds,
you'II spend the Iast
four hours of your Iife
being able to see.
We take you off,
you'II go blind again.
But it'II give us time
to figure out
what's eating your brain.
(INHALING)
Fine. What do we do next?
MAN: Eric?
Dad?
Yeah, you two can get
caught up Iater. Sir,
I need you to come with me.
House, what is this?
He's not a "what,"
he's a "who." They even have
the right to vote now.
Rodney Foreman, Cuddy.
Cuddy, Rodney Foreman.
Nice to meet you, ma'am.
This is Foreman's dad.
Yeah, I got that.
And Dr. Cuddy here
is the Dean of Medicine.
Remember that cool autopsy
I was telling you about,
the one that would save
your son's Iife?
She's the one who can give us
the green Iight to do it.
I understand
you don't want them to do it.
Dr. House
didn't seem to know why.
Mr. Foreman,
I am doing everything I can
to get the CDC...
Won't be soon enough.
...and my decision to follow
public health
safety protocols...
Oh, don't blame the rules.
Don't hang this on policy
and protocol.
I'm well aware
that it may cost
your son his Iife,
just as I am well aware that
my decision has a devastating
effect on family and friends,
without having them paraded
in front of me.
Your son has an unknown,
contagious, deadly infection.
If we don't contain it here,
even more people
could be at risk.
And I am capable
of empathizing
with those people too,
without having them
paraded in front of me.
I understand.
What's wrong with your hand?
It's called
a muscle contracture.
I thought this thing
was in your brain.
It is. It just means
the infection's moved
to the primary motor cortex,
which controls the muscles.
Aren't you glad
you sent me to med school?
Does it hurt?
No.
Is it gonna?
The other guy,
he didn't seem to suffer
too much.
He just went in his sleep.
Steve's still acting normal.
No sign of contractures.
They got the cop's body
in a Iocked, airtight bag.
And a guard on the door.
Those feds
are seriously paranoid.
He hasn't gotten up
to pee in hours. He's due.
You haven't sprinkled
Senokot granules on his donut?
His bowels would open up
Iike the Red Sea.
He wouldn't eat the donut.
Have you seriously
been down here for hours?
No.
I had to pee a couple times.
You've got to stop
blaming Cuddy for this.
Given that it is her fault,
that seems appropriate.
That part is her fault.
The part
where somebody wasted his time
in the basement
plotting the overthrow of
a government agency,
that one's on you.
Only thing I can do is think.
You can pretty much
do that anywhere.
As Iong as
no one's bugging me.
RODNEY: Did you call
your brother?
No.
Did you?
It's not a big deal.
I sure would have Iiked
to see Mom, though.
You know
she can't travel anymore.
You tell her?
Why?
Just upset her for a while.
Then she wouldn't remember
for a while.
She should know.
She's Iost a Iot
of who she was.
She can't deal with something
Iike this.
And you can?
I still know
you're going
to a better place.
It's easy for you, isn't it?
As Iong as you believe
I'm going to a better place,
dying ain't so bad.
I don't want you to be afraid.
If I'm not afraid of dying,
what the hell
should I be afraid of, Dad?
I thought you believed.
I did.
I'm not so sure anymore.
I'm going to pray
for you, Son.
I suggest you do the same.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
CHASE: Field of vision is
regressing and he's reached
an eight on the pain scale.
The disease pattern
is following the exact course
as Joe's.
Only it's moving much faster
in Foreman.
Good. It's an anomaly.
Anomalies tell us things.
Why would this go faster
in Foreman? What's different?
Could be a different strain
of the same disease?
Right! We were wasting
all this time Iooking
for an unknown disease.
We should have be Iooking for
a different strain
of an unknown disease.
Joe's a cop.
He's into physical fitness.
He could have had
a more powerful immune system,
stronger metabolism.
Foreman's black.
What?
How Iong have you been sitting
on this information?
Lupus, gout, glaucoma,
osteoarthritis, hypertension,
diabetes, stop me anytime,
they all affect black people
more than whites.
Check everything.
Bacterials, fungals,
toxins, parasites.
Look for anything
with a documented
racial disparity.
Wait.
The rat's showing symptoms?
No.
He's completely healthy.
Maybe that's the difference
between Foreman and the cop.
How you feeling?
Why are you here?
Because you're a friend,
and I should be here.
I'm sorry House used my dad
to try and manipulate you.
You've got integrity.
You aren't going to change
your mind just because you're
confronted by my father.
Thank you.
Just Iike
I'm not gonna forgive you,
just because you come by here
and ask how I'm feeling.
You know I've had no choice.
Of course you had a choice!
Regulations are clear.
And the punishment
for violating
those regulations,
is it death?
Because frankly, I'm okay
if you get a fine,
a suspension...
Hell, you can spend
a couple years in jail
if it saves my Iife!
(POUNDING)
You're dying too fast.
Couldn't agree more.
Hey, Cuddy.
Having a nice visit?
What's that?
Legionella...
Legionella pneumophilia.
And why are you
carrying a vial of it
around with you?
Foreman was perfectly healthy
before he got this infection,
but our cop wasn't.
He had Legionnaire's disease,
and our cop didn't turn into
brain food until we cured
the Legionella.
The Legionella
slowed down the disease.
Why would that happen?
No idea.
I just know that it did.
So you want to infect Foreman?
You gonna tattle to the CDC?
The meds can't help me,
but a disease can?
Forget it.
Just take the pain away.
Put me under.
If I put you under,
I can't monitor your pain.
If I can't monitor your pain,
I won't know
if the Legionella's working.
I'm not consenting
to you giving me...
What was that?
Wish there could have been
a puff of smoke or something.
Would have been
much more dramatic.
Keep your slippers on.
Wouldn't want you
to cut your foot.
You feeling any better?
I can't breathe.
I'm dizzy
and I can barely hear anything
over the sounds
of my Iungs crackling.
That's the Legionella.
Oh, you figured that out from
the symptoms or from the vial
of stuff tossed in my room?
I'm trying to be professional
here, and there's no reason
to be nasty.
I'm in pain.
So is House.
And he's a delight.
He doesn't try to kill
his colleagues.
(BEEPING)
You can remove
the thermometer now.
It's down almost
a whole degree.
How's the pain?
Great. It's the good kind.
How bad is it
compared to an hour ago?
No worse.
WILSON:
Is the Legionella helping?
Yeah.
Good.
But not great.
It didn't fix anything,
it just slowed it down.
The whole point
was to give Steve a Iittle
more time to get sick.
What are you gonna do
if he never gets sick?
Brilliant.
Cameron, what type
of illnesses
affect humans but not rats?
Why are you asking me that?
Because I'm sure
that you spent the first
1 2 years of your Iife
dreaming of being a vet.
The rat is not getting sick.
Cameron is not getting sick.
Sorry.
It's okay,
it's not your fault.
Presumably, you're still
healthy because whatever
it is, it's not blood-borne.
Steve has no excuse.
He did everything
that Foreman did.
Some bacterial infections
don't affect rats.
Foreman tested negative
for every bacterial infection
that would affect his brain.
And what infections could
he be positive for
but test negative for?
When we test for infections,
we Iook for antibodies.
Now, what if the patient
is infected
but has no antibodies?
What if the body
is not fighting the infection?
Why would...
I asked first.
Let's start with the "what."
We'II deal with
the "why" Iater.
If the body doesn't recognize
the infection,
our tests come back negative,
and the disease
rampages through
the body unstopped.
Exactly Iike the cop
and exactly Iike Foreman.
Now, what if the patient
was then exposed
to a second infection,
Iike Legionella?
The body would recognize
that infection,
increase the white count,
send in the troops
to start fighting,
and the initial infection
would get caught
in the crossfire.
So the question becomes
what type of bacterial
infection affects humans
but not rats,
and the human body
would be unlikely
to recognize?
HOUSE: The answer is Iisteria.
I'm starting you on
amp and gent.
So, you're basing this theory
on the tests being negative
and your rat being healthy?
And the fact that
Legionnaire's is helping you.
But the medicine
you want to give me
will put an end to that.
Yeah.
And if it's not Iisteria,
all the gent will do is
cure the Legionnaire's disease
and put whatever is killing me
back into overdrive.
Stop asking me questions
based on the premise
that I'm wrong.
The antibiotics
are in the airlock.
I think the first biopsy
didn't give us the answer
because you didn't go
deep enough.
I want you to do
a white matter brain biopsy.
Absolutely. Don't blame you.
The world is such
a complicated place if you've
got higher reasoning skills.
I'm often jealous
of small animals
and retarded children.
Take the antibiotics.
There can be minimal damage
if it's done right,
if the surgeons drill
where I tell them to drill.
One slip, you could spend
the rest of your Iife
not being able
to keep your drool
in your mouth.
I'd rather be disabled
than dead.
Sure! I make it Iook
oh-so-sexy.
It's actually not as glamorous
as you might think.
The biopsy
will tell us for sure
what's wrong.
The antibiotics
could do the same thing!
"Could," not "will."
We try it, we see.
The antibiotics
will bring back the pain!
Pain makes us
make bad decisions.
Fear of pain
is almost as big a motivator.
Look, we still have time.
I will do that biopsy
if I have to.
But not a moment before.
Start Foreman
on IV antibiotics.
Where's his dad?
Where you're supposed to be
when your son is dying.
He's not with him.
He's in the chapel.
Oh, man...
I started your son
on a new course of treatment.
If it works, he'II get better.
If it doesn't, he won't.
While he's not getting better,
he's going to experience
so much pain
that we'II have to put him
in a chemically-induced coma
while we figure out
what to do next.
My son says
you're a manipulative bastard.
It's a pet name.
I call him "Dr. BIing."
I assume you're here
for a reason.
What do you want from me?
When your son is in a coma,
you're the one who's gonna
have to make
the medical decisions for him.
Whatever you decide is fine.
You don't care what I do?
I'm not a doctor.
What do I know,
except what Eric tells me?
He says you're the best doctor
he's ever worked with.
I need your help.
There's nothing I can give you
for the pain.
I want to be put out.
I can have a nurse in here
in five minutes.
No.
Once I'm out,
I might not come back.
I've never done a will.
I'II call a Iawyer for you.
I want you to be
my medical proxy.
AII the things
that piss me off
about you in House's office,
you're too emotional and
too caring, too cautious...
They're all good things
on this floor.
Your dad is...
No.
He cares about you.
So do you.
I can't do this.
We expect family members
to make decisions
about their Ioved ones
after a 10-minute briefing,
that we're agonizing over
even with years
of medical experience.
That's from my article.
I'm sorry, AIIison.
I shouldn't have stolen
your article.
I shouldn't have exposed you.
You were a friend.
I need to know
that we're okay.
No.
I'II be your proxy,
but we're not okay.
You're scared you're dying
and it's the only reason
you want to set things right.
We're gonna get you better
first and then,
if you still wanna apologize,
I'II be around.
I'II call that Iawyer.
Any improvements?
No.
As far as we can tell, the
only thing the antibiotics are
treating is the Legionella.
I think we need to consider
alternate theories.
Like what?
We do the biopsy. We...
Give the antibiotics
more time.
There is no more time.
The pain
is almost unbearable already.
So he's almost
in unbearable pain.
He's not almost dead!
Which means we have more time.
Mr. Foreman?
We need to put your son
in a coma.
You should be there.
It's a medical procedure,
right?
Yeah.
But once we put him out,
if we don't solve this,
he won't wake up.
What should I say?
Should I talk to him
Iike it's going to be okay?
Or should I be saying goodbye?
I need to know
what people say when...
Just tell him you Iove him.
Hey, Son.
Hey, Dad.
It's going to be okay.
You don't know that.
I know.
You don't.
I don't wanna miss you.
I Iove you too, Dad.
Hey,
it's gonna be okay.
Can we do this now?
Yeah, of course.
I accept your apology.
Why weren't you with Foreman?
I hang out in the basement,
you rag on me. I stay in my
office, you rag on me.
Honky just can't buy a break.
Do the biopsy.
Based on the cop's
progression, I figure he's got
about another four hours...
You figure?
You're playing
Russian roulette,
but the gun's pointed at him.
No. Cutting open his head
is what's dangerous.
Oh, it's dangerous.
Well, what would people think?
The reason
you don't see patients
is because if you know them,
you'II give a crap about them.
I know you.
If you give a crap,
you stop making
outrageous calls.
If this was any other patient,
you'd have damned the risk
and cut their head open
a Iong time ago.
He's out. The EEG shows
he's still in pain.
The antibiotics have had
more than enough time.
We're doing the brain biopsy.
Not unless you people can't
come up with something clever
in the next three hours.
Now. We're doing it now.
Well, who died
and made you boss?
Foreman.
It's Iegal.
He's out of his mind.
Yesterday he was giggling
about a hole in a guy's head.
Then hire a Iawyer
and challenge it. In the
meantime, Cameron's in charge.
Why would he sign that?
It's nothing personal,
Mr. Foreman.
My son doesn't trust me.
How exactly
is that not personal?
I'm sorry.
You're sorry?
You're talking about
this man's son!
You're denying him
the right to be a part...
Oh, shut up, House.
If you want to do the biopsy,
do the biopsy.
If House tries to interfere,
Iet me know
and I will take care of it.
Yeah, you're a hero.
If it wasn't for you, we'd be
cutting into a dead guy's head
instead of Foreman's.
Sorry.
Thanks.
That was great!
It was rude and unnecessary.
Yeah.
Go away.
Give me time.
We're out of time.
An hour.
What does "out of time" mean?
His O2 sats
are at 94 right now.
As Iong as they're above 90,
danger of fatal arrhythmia
doesn't increase.
So what?
There's no point in waiting.
You were right.
We should be cutting into
a corpse's head.
Yeah, we should be,
except the CDC's
got the cop's body under...
There's got to be
other bodies.
You think this thing
has killed other people?
No.
That apartment was a dump.
Just because Steve McQueen
didn't get sick doesn't mean
some other vermin didn't.
You give me an hour,
I go back there,
I find a dead animal,
I cut its head open
instead of Foreman's.
Foreman's already on
100% oxygen.
Once his O2 sats hit 90,
I can't wait any Ionger.
Where's your suit?
Either you'II find the answer
or I'II find the answer.
It doesn't matter.
CHASE: Prep the drill.
We've got to be ready
to go if we get the signal.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Ninety-two.
I found a blind bird.
Great. How fast
can you get it in here?
I'II know in about 30 seconds.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
You better have the bird.
The surgical team's in place.
I screwed up.
How can you not capture
a blind bird?
That's not what I meant.
I screwed up the first time
through this place.
Foreman told you
everywhere he went.
It's not "where, " it's "when. "
He came here early afternoon.
Me and Steve came through
two hours too Iate.
You were six hours early.
It's the water.
The irrigation system
only pumps at...
House! I tested the water!
The water's clean.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
House.
We tested the wrong water.
He stole cable,
he stole fertilizer
and he stole water.
It's riddled with Naegleria.
I know.
You already did the biopsy.
I thought I had no choice.
How's my son?
He has primary
amoebic meningoencephalitis.
It's a parasite
that goes through the nose
and migrates into the brain,
where it feeds on brain cells.
The Legionella attacked
the parasite. That's why
the disease slowed down.
Is it treatable?
We started him
on an antiparasitic
and the amoebas
will clear out of his system.
And he'II be okay?
Then we'II wean him
out of the coma...
Will he be okay?
There'II be no Iasting damage
from the parasite.
But the surgery?
We don't know.
Up and at 'em.
How you feeling?
Can you talk?
I don't feel anything.
Are you numb?
No, I mean,
I don't feel any pain.
Keep your head still.
Follow my finger.
I'm okay.
Your breath stinks,
and you're peeing into a bag.
What are our names?
You did the biopsy?
Thank you.
Names?
Cameron,
my dad
and the manipulative bastard.
You remembered.
(LAUGHS)
How you doing, Dad?
Great.
Relieved. Great.
What did I have?
Naegleria.
Biopsy showed the amoeba,
the CDC autopsy
eventually found the amoeba,
and House found it
in the water
on the cop's roof.
Wiggle your Ieft toes.
Wait. What?
You went back
and she did the biopsy?
Your Ieft toes, Foreman.
I just did.
No, you didn't.
He can't move his toes.
He can move them.
Raise your right arm.
What?