ALEX: Give me my next change.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(GROANING)
I think I'm gonna puke.
Not on this dress.
I'm serious.
Kate Moss
was doing this at 13.
You have two years on her.
Yeah,
that's what I Iike to see.
You got this.
The next show, you're bride.
Did Austin
just offer you bride?
It wasn't a real offer, Dad.
He was just being nice.
These shoes are gonna be
impossible to walk in.
You've done this
100 times before, all right?
The runway's
just a Iittle bit Ionger here.
One of the girls said
Madonna's in the front row.
Sweetie, hey, come on.
Are you gonna
be able to do this?
AII right, come here.
Here, hold this.
The doctor gave me these
for anxiety, all right?
It'II calm you down. Here.
Come on, it's okay.
AUSTIN: Where's AIex?
AIex, you're up!
Go! Go! Go! Go!
Knock them out!
(DISTORTED TALKING)
Are you okay?
(GASPING)
MARTIN: AIex!
(CAMERAS CLICKING)
(BEEPING)
(EXHALING)
WILSON: How'd you get here?
By osmosis.
No helmet?
Didn't seem Iike
riding weather.
And the fact that you can
barely stand upright
had nothing to do with it?
Infarctions hurt.
House.
It's what they do.
Worsening pain could
actually be a good thing.
It means the nerves
might be regenerating.
It could be good,
it could be bad.
Thanks for the differential.
Any other options?
Have you ever
considered a career
as a motivational speaker?
Why don't you
check out some rehab?
I did the rehab thing.
One session,
and you didn't even
finish that session.
The guy wanted me
to "visualize the healing".
I could do that at home.
At Ieast
Iet me get you an MRI.
It's a very simple equation:
more pain, more pills.
Teenage supermodel.
Presented with double vision,
sudden aggressive behavior,
cataplexy.
You had me
at "teenage supermodel".
You okay?
Mmm-hmm.
Wow.
HOUSE: You should be a model.
Are you really 15?
Who are you?
I'II be the one
saving her Iife today,
assuming she's dying.
Who are you?
He's my father.
Any idea
what's wrong with her?
Well, from the Iooks of it,
not a single thing.
I probably should stop staring
and check out the file.
So what set off the brawl?
She stand in your Iight?
I didn't even know her.
I didn't know what happened.
Look, I know some models
are notorious for hissy fits,
but AIex...
I've never even
seen her get angry.
Even when she was a kid...
I'm sure she was
delightful in her youth.
Then you passed out.
I was passed out,
but I wasn't.
I knew what was going on,
but I couldn't move or talk.
Yeah, it sounds
Iike a medical thing.
It's called "cataplexy".
Catfight and cataplexy
on the catwalk.
Cool. How much
were you drinking?
She only had
one sip of champagne.
Forget it. I'II find out
from the tox screen.
AII right, Iook,
I gave her a Valium.
Do you think
that's what did this?
No.
How Iong have you
had the sweats?
A couple of days.
Any other complaints?
My stomach's been bothering me
and I've been
feeling a Iittle nauseous.
Okay, here's how this works.
My Iackeys will be by shortly
to draw some blood,
collect some urine,
any other fluids you got.
I'II do some
other doctorly stuff,
and we'II be in touch.
Since when do you
voluntarily go see patients?
Have you seen her?
She's 15.
There's something about her,
something in her eyes,
kind of a maturity.
Yeah, yeah,
she's an old soul.
This is creepy,
even for you.
She's a fashion model,
on the cover of magazines.
We hold her up
as the sexual ideal.
The Iaw says
we can't touch her
for three more years.
How hypocritical is that?
Did the history reveal
anything, oh, I don't know,
medically relevant?
History, right.
I knew I was
forgetting something.
You should do one of those
while you're running the Iabs
and the tox screen.
The Iabs show Valium
and heroin in her urine.
A supermodel on smack.
Shocker.
Oh, AIex,
I expected so much more
from you.
Heroin chic
is so five years ago.
Okay, Iet's start crossing out
withdrawal symptoms.
A positive test
means she tried it once.
It doesn't mean
she's an addict.
She's only 15.
There's no age Iimit
on addiction.
He's right.
She's never menstruated.
Sounds Iike a symptom
of drug addiction to me.
Or bulimia. Or her age.
Some girls don't start
till their mid-to-Iate teens.
Evidence to the contrary,
the rounded hips.
The perfectly-sculpted,
bountiful breasts.
CHASE: Implants.
I've seen some of her photos.
They've grown dramatically
since Iast summer.
Symptomatic of turning 14.
Two clinic hours says
that those "Iove apples"
are handcrafted by God.
I thought you didn't
believe in God.
I do now.
You're on.
Could we talk about her health
instead of her breasts?
It could be relevant.
Come on, Cameron,
there's nothing
to be ashamed of.
Many women develop breasts.
(INSTRUMENTS CLATTERING)
(HOUSE SIGHING)
No, I'm fine.
Even if she is an addict,
a Iot of her symptoms,
the cataplexy, the violence,
it could be neurological.
If we chalk this up to drugs,
we could be
releasing her with Juvenile MS
or Parkinson's...
Detox her.
FOREMAN: Fine.
We'II set her up on a program,
they'II wean her
onto the methadone.
And in four weeks,
we'II know you're right.
Or, we'II know
that Cameron's right
and the pretty girl
will do Milan next fall
in a wheelchair.
Put her in a coma,
pump her full of naltrexone.
Cut the four weeks
to one night.
The Iab reports show
that your daughter
had heroin in her system.
Were you aware
of her drug use?
No.
We think she's suffering from
withdrawal symptoms.
Detoxing generally takes
several weeks.
The danger is that
if the drugs are masking
some other illness,
it could worsen before
we've weaned her
off the heroin.
Well, how much worse?
We don't know because
we don't know what's wrong.
There is a rapid
detox procedure.
We flush her system with
an opioid antagonist.
It'II end her addiction
overnight.
The process is dangerous
because we have to
induce a coma.
It also means
that if she ever relapses,
there's a good chance she'II
overdose because her body
won't react to the drug.
So either way
I'm risking her Iife.
Do you have to tell her
how dangerous it is?
(GASPING)
Is it dangerous?
There are certain risks.
We've gone over them
with your father.
And he's not worried?
He's your dad.
He's always gonna worry.
But he knows we're gonna take
good care of you.
Everything's starting to hurt.
My Iegs are...
Heroin withdrawal is
an extremely painful process.
But we're gonna
put you to sleep.
You won't feel a thing.
You promise?
I promise.
That was a pretty
stupid thing to do, huh?
Getting hooked on drugs?
Yeah, not the best move
you've ever made.
Just,
I thought it would be fun.
You don't have to
explain to us.
ALEX: A Iot of, a Iot of
the other girls were...
When you wake up,
you'II feel a Iot better.
(BEEPING)
(UNRHYTHMICAL BEEPING)
Nurse! Nurse!
You son of a bitch!
You killed her!
She's not dead.
She had a heart attack.
She's stable now.
The anesthesia...
Get her out of that coma.
I don't think so.
Stop this!
AII right,
I don't consent anymore.
I want her
to do the slow detox.
Did you ever get a paper cut?
A really nasty one,
between the fingers?
Multiply that
by about a billion
and you'II just barely
approach the kind of suffering
she'II experience
if we wake her up now.
We're committed to this.
She's out till morning.
Go get a book.
I haven't slept in weeks,
because my teeth hurt.
The dentist
couldn't find any cavities.
And I'm getting
these headaches.
Oh! Poor you.
I think I'm going crazy.
And my stomach,
I roll out of bed
and I wanna puke.
I take it you're married?
You must be psychic.
You must be witty.
When's she due?
How'd you know she was...
Because I'm doing her.
You've got Couvade Syndrome.
It's just
a fancy way of saying
you should stop whining.
Millions of women
have got the same thing.
They're not bugging me.
You're suffering from
sympathetic pregnancy.
Gotta go. People dying.
Whole circle of Iife thing.
It's all in my head?
No, it's all in your hormones.
The good news is,
no one's gonna Iecture you
if you smoke and get drunk.
(DOOR SLAMMING)
Shouldn't she be awake
by now?
It's only been a half an hour
since we stopped the medicine.
Well, you said
that's how Iong it would take.
I said it would take
about a half an hour.
But couldn't this mean
something more...
So far, it means nothing.
She had a heart attack.
She could have brain damage.
She could have
something more...
She's opening her eyes.
AIex, you okay?
Can you hear me?
I got the cute doctor.
Do you feel any pain?
Good. Let us know
if anything changes.
If your stomach
doesn't feel right, anything.
Hey.
Are you mad at me, Daddy?
I Iet you down.
No, no. Not at all, sweetie,
I...
I should have been
more mature. I should have
handled the pressure.
Stop, stop.
We're gonna get you better,
all right?
Nothing else matters.
CHASE: Excuse me.
I've got you on
what we call a "banana bag".
PIenty of vitamins,
nutrients...
I got the cute doctor.
Are you mad at me, Daddy?
ALEX: I Iet you down.
What's going on?
I should have been
more mature. I should have
handled the pressure.
MARTIN: What's wrong with her?
Anterograde amnesia,
short term memory Ioss.
Evidence of a hypoxic
brain injury.
It might be the result
of getting cut off from
the oxygen when she flatlined.
Probably the result
of that rapid detox
you told us to push on her.
You gonna put that down?
(INHALING)
Are you gonna sulk?
I'm not gonna indulge you.
The treatment for
hypoxic brain injuries
consists of...
Cameron, Chase
and the Dark One.
Foreman, right?
The patient flatlined
for Iike, 30 seconds.
You've got to be
oxygen-deprived
for Ionger than that
to Iose brain function.
We can't be sure
how Iong she was...
Her brain's fine.
Memory Ioss.
You're saying that's not
a neurological symptom?
No, I'm saying
what I'm saying.
Her brain's fine.
She's faking?
She's got
posttraumatic stress disorder.
We got models
fighting in Iraq now?
Show me a woman on heroin
who Iooks Iike that,
and I'II show you a woman
who's been sexually abused.
That's your proof?
That she's good Iooking.
He manages her career,
travels the world with her,
at her side 24/7.
He's either a very good dad or
a very bad dad.
HOUSE: You saw that tokus.
Would the fact that
she's your daughter
really stop you?
(SCOFFING)
Her brain is running away
from reality and when the
drugs can't do it anymore,
it starts to shut down.
Your theory has the advantages
of being
completely un-provable
and completely
exculpating you.
When you guys
are done talking,
do an MRI and an LP.
When her brain
checks out as normal,
then we'II know
that daddy really,
really Ioves her.
Where's House?
He said he was
in too much pain to work.
Who's covering?
He called 15 minutes
after his shift started.
It was too Iate
to find anybody.
Exam Room One.
Hi.
Where's Dr. House?
I wish I knew.
What's the problem?
It's personal.
And it's so personal
he didn't bother writing
anything in your chart.
It's getting worse.
What is?
It's personal.
Fine. You can wait.
Doctor!
I tell you what.
I am going to give you
Dr. House's
personal pager number.
Why would your mind
go to abuse so fast?
Because I had a funny uncle.
You were abused?
What? No.
Why'd your mind
go to that so fast?
I just had a funny uncle.
Great stories, always filthy.
I don't know
if it's something
with this case
or you got
something personal going on,
the whole breakup thing?
It's personal.
House.
Your pain is affecting
your decision-making.
You got a problem
with a call I make,
question the call.
Don't make it personal.
Are you saying
pain can't affect your mood?
If I'm right about the pain,
you're gonna wanna
rush everything,
which is what you're doing.
Don't.
Thank you.
Are you doing your daughter?
What?
We should probably
talk privately, huh?
Come on, walk with me.
Come on.
He's not!
I'm sure he's not.
She is a babe, though.
We're gonna need you
to keep still.
I am.
What do you think
that means?
It's either neurological
or psychological.
The only thing we know
for sure is it's gonna
screw up the MRI results,
which is gonna
make House think he's right.
This is a waste of time.
Let's just get the LP.
I should take your head off.
Your glands are fine.
See, now, you're my patient.
You got doctor-patient
confidentiality. No worries.
So, what did you do to her?
Why would you
possibly think...
Hard to imagine anyone
not wanting to nail her.
You son of...
It's a compliment.
That heart-shaped ass,
those perfect, perky,
all-natural breasts.
That is my daughter
you're talking about!
No, that's your daughter
you were talking about.
"She just instinctively
knows how to walk.
"Designers just Iove
that heart-shaped ass,
those perfect, perky..."
I'm her manager.
I have to promote her.
Oh, that makes sense.
So you compartmentalize.
When you're
dealing with the press,
you're her manager.
When you're helping
with homework, you're her dad.
When you're making
sweet, sweet Iove,
you're her manager.
AII right.
Do you Iove her?
I have never touched her.
What are you doing?
Are you trying
to trap me into saying...
Do you Iove her enough
to admit that you
slept with her?
Psychological conditions
can manifest themselves
in physical problems.
Sometimes these can be
extreme enough to kill.
There are treatments,
but only
if there is a diagnosis.
Are you going to admit
that you slept
with your daughter
or are you just gonna
Iet her die?
One time.
PTSD.
Get her a psyche referral,
pack her bags. He did her.
Don't think so.
Daddy thinks so.
He could be mistaken.
He said he was drunk.
Maybe it was
some other daughter.
EIevated proteins in her CSF.
You're wrong about PTSD
and I was wrong about
the hypoxic brain injury.
Daddy didn't do this to her.
And neither did we.
CAMERON: We have to call
Child Protective Services.
Doctor-patient
confidentiality.
Doesn't apply in abuse cases.
You know that.
We're mandated
to report sexual abuse.
Is it okay
if I save her Iife first
or do you want to make sure
that daddy
doesn't get visitation rights
to the gravesite?
Okay, elevated proteins
in her CSF could mean
dozens of different things.
Viral encephalitis, CNSV,
Creutzfeldt-Jakob disease?
So we're just gonna Ieave
a child molester in the
same room as his victim?
It's got windows.
Fine. Arrest him.
Use Cuddy's handcuffs.
If you're too distracted
to deal with this because
your Ieg hurts, then...
Yeah, I'm distracted!
I'm all hung up on this
15-year-old patient
who's cataplectic,
can't remember what she had
for Iunch and is rapidly
Iosing control of her body!
And I want her father here
in case
he's got any more secrets
that I need to know about.
Now, if you're not
too distracted, go take out
a piece of her brain,
stick it under a microscope.
Wilson!
FOREMAN: Whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa.
Do you really think
we need to jump straight
to brain biopsy?
Nope. Let's continue playing
"Pin the diagnosis
on the supermodel"
until she's dead.
(DOOR SLAMMING)
I heard you killed
your supermodel.
Only for a minute.
Just for my own clarity,
how many more patients
do you have to kill
before you admit
this Ieg thing
just might be a problem?
Three.
I need your help.
We're gonna do something
called a burr-hole biopsy.
We drill a small opening
in the back of your skull.
Doctor, maybe you and I
should talk about this first.
No.
I just think AIex doesn't need
to be overwhelmed right now.
I think she should have a say
in what happens to her body.
Now, we're gonna remove
a small piece of brain tissue.
Do you have to shave my hair?
Hair grows back.
I guess I won't remember
anyways.
There's a good chance
the amnesia is only temporary.
Okay.
(DRILL WHIRRING)
Find a way
to kick up the contribution.
What did House do now?
House, this is God.
Look, I'm a Iittle busy
right now.
I'm not supposed
to talk during these things.
Got time Thursday?
Let me check.
Oh, I've got a plague.
What about Friday?
You'II have to check
with Cameron.
Oh, damn it!
She always wants to know
why bad things happen.
Like I'm gonna come up
with a new answer this time.
House.
Quick, God,
smite the evil witch!
Are you sitting on evidence
that your patient was
sexually abused by her father?
God, why have you forsaken me?
CUDDY: Don't worry.
I've contacted
child services for you.
I Iet you get away
with more than anyone
in this hospital.
Shielding a child abuser
isn't covered.
Cooperate
with this investigation
or I'II fire you.
(DOOR SLAMMING)
What do you think
House is gonna do to you?
No idea.
Well, you did the right thing.
If you hadn't gone to Cuddy,
I would have.
If this guy had known
we'd have to report him,
he'd never have
told House the truth.
She's a child,
she needs to be protected.
She dropped out of high school
to make millions of dollars.
Why does she need
more protection
than some crack whore
shivering in the clinic
waiting room?
I think you're just afraid
to piss House off.
There's that, too.
MRI Iooks exactly the same
as it did two years ago.
The nerves don't
seem to be regenerating.
I figured as much.
Several different researchers
have proven
psychological pain
can manifest as physical pain.
You think
I have a conversion disorder?
You want me to see a shrink?
Brilliant idea sending
Stacy away. It's really
done wonders for you.
Listen, none of this
has anything to do with Stacy.
Right. Giant coincidence that
you've gone completely off
the rails since she Ieft.
Inducing migraines,
worsening Ieg pains.
(GROANING)
Oh, do you miss Stacy, too?
Brain biopsy shows
no white matter disease.
Cameron, you gonna tell Cuddy,
or has she already
got you wired for sound?
I had to do
what I thought was right.
So, white is out.
It just Ieaves gray.
Neuronal ceroid Iipofucinosis,
Heller Syndrome...
Any one of the
mitochondrial
encephalopathies.
Am I in trouble?
You had to do
what you thought was right.
They call it "gray area"
because you never
really know what's there.
We can't test for
any of those things.
So I'm not in trouble?
You can torture yourself
all you want.
What if everything
we're seeing
is just smoke signals?
Okay. Who's sending them?
Tumor.
If she has cancer
anywhere in her body,
she could also have
Paraneoplastic Syndrome,
which could be
causing antibodies
to attack her brain.
Antibodies are stupid
that way.
Paraneoplastic Syndrome's
awfully rare in a 15-year-old.
15-year-olds
who Iook Iike that
are awfully rare.
It would explain
the aggressive behavior,
the cataplexy,
the memory Ioss,
even the twitching.
It's perfect.
What if it's not?
We could waste a week
searching for a tumor
that we don't even
know is there.
Then Iet's make sure
it is there.
There's no test
for Paraneoplastic Syndrome.
HOUSE: Sure there is.
The "squeeze the tube" test.
MARTIN: What did the biopsy
tell you?
It wasn't definitive.
But the twitching should stop
right about now.
(EXHALING)
Oh, my God.
HOUSE: Could have just been
a coincidence.
Twitching does tend to
stop and start. Let's be sure.
The IVIG vacuums her blood,
neutralizes the stuff
that's making her twitch.
It's actually kind of cool.
I wonder if I could
make you dance?
Enough.
This is unbelievable.
You did it. You fixed her.
No.
AII I did was prove
that she has cancer.
I need a favor.
I'm not in a giving mood.
It'II help us both.
I need a shot of morphine
in my spine.
If your Ieg hurts,
take your Vicodin.
It's not enough.
Get a syringe.
Morphine is extreme,
even for you.
Yeah. Write that
on the insert.
Get one of your Iackeys
to do it.
I don't want them knowing...
That you're on the road
to becoming a junkie?
That I'm in this much pain.
I don't want them
questioning my judgment.
I can't ask Wilson,
because he figures
it's all in my head.
Well, I agree with him.
I'm going home.
What about this?
What are you doing?
Is this in my head?
Because I could swear
I remember a thigh muscle
being here.
I'II get a syringe.
It's gotta be cancer.
It's not cancer.
You seem to be back
to your old miserable self.
So I just randomly predicted
she'd respond to IVIG?
Her twitches are gone,
her memory's getting better.
What did you take?
The increased pain
was psychological.
No drug's gonna help.
If you think it will help,
the drugs will help.
The power of the mind.
You're right.
The more I talk to you,
the more the pain floods back.
I knew the twins were real.
Chase owes me.
Did you check the pancreas?
Oh, come on.
You're just making up organs
now, aren't you?
We checked the pancreas.
Obviously,
you've taken something.
Did you check the bones?
There are a Iot of bones,
I think.
And none of them have cancer.
Ovaries?
There's no mass.
If anything,
they're undersized.
No Ieukemia, no Hodgkin's,
we checked everything.
Unless they've invented
a new organ, it's not cancer.
Differential diagnosis.
It's gotta be cancer.
There's gotta be something
we missed.
You've got to Iearn
to Iet go, Foreman.
Maybe the protein Ievel
was some sort of anomaly.
It might just still be PTSD.
Just PTSD?
Yeah, Daddy's diddling her.
Nothing to worry about.
Okay, Iet me rephrase.
CHASE: Maybe the protein Ievel
was some sort of anomaly.
Oh, my God!
It might be PTSD!
If it was PTSD,
the twitching wouldn't have
magically disappeared
when we started the IVIG.
Wrong.
What it wouldn't have done
was medically disappear.
Nothing to stop it
from magically disappearing.
She was watching me
start and stop the medicine.
You think she's faking?
Not consciously.
But if her subconscious
is trying
to get away from it all,
cancer's gotta
be a Iovely vacation spot.
Tell her you've got to give
her a fresh IV. Don't tell her
you're starting her on saline.
See if the twitching
comes back.
How Iong has the social worker
been in there?
Just went in. She was
in with the dad before.
You switched the girl's IV?
About a half an hour ago.
When's she gonna
start twitching?
If she's gonna
start twitching.
Another few minutes.
We've got to wait
for the remaining IVIG
to clear her system.
That was quick.
What's gonna happen?
What'd you think
was gonna happen?
The father had sex...
Do you have any
medical evidence of that?
He admitted...
He denies the conversation
ever took place.
But she...
She denies it, too.
I'm sure you meant well.
You have to
tell her the truth.
Nothing happened.
You don't have to
be afraid of him.
They can protect you.
From what? Things are fine.
You think things are fine.
They're not.
He's my dad.
He's abusing you.
He's not a bad person.
I seduced him.
You're the child.
He's the adult.
He has the responsibility...
I got him drunk.
I had to get him drunk.
I wanted to
have sex with him.
You're sexually attracted
to your father?
No.
But by sleeping with him,
now he Iets me do
whatever I want.
I also slept with my
photographer, my financial
manager and my tutor.
If I hadn't,
I'd be getting C's
and posing for newspaper ads
back in Detroit.
Come on, we all do it.
No, we don't.
After your father
slept with you,
you were traumatized.
My dad was Iast.
You've never taken a run
at your boss or professor
or somebody else you needed?
You're 15. You're smart.
You don't have...
I am not that smart.
I am that beautiful.
What's wrong with me?
(SCREAMING)
Oh! George,
get your butt over here!
GEORGE: Help me.
How'd you get
my pager number?
PIease!
The problem is,
if I give you an epidural,
you won't be able
to feel when to push.
You're not funny.
I'm pretty sure I am.
You just can't appreciate it
because you're in pain.
George, if you don't
get off your ass
and help me...
Oh, shut up!
You've got yourself
the perfect man. A woman.
He's got more estrogen
coursing through his veins
than...
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
Who did her vaginal exam?
I did.
Did she have hair?
What are you getting at?
Right now I'm getting at
whether or not
she had hair down there.
Not much.
She's manipulative,
yet completely docile.
Everybody tells us that
outburst on the catwalk
was out of character.
She's never had a period.
You're thinking
this is hormonal?
I'm thinking
she's the ultimate woman.
I need to schedule an MRI.
ALEX: The twitching stopped.
Because we changed
your medicine back
to the real stuff.
Stop talking.
You gave me fake medicine?
That's what I said, in the
vain hope that you wouldn't
feel the need to also say it.
Stop talking.
Wilson already did
an ultrasound. He said
her ovaries were undersized.
The ultrasound would be
the way to go if you were
Iooking for ovarian cancer.
CAMERON: What are we
Iooking for?
(BEEPING)
That.
Oh, my God.
It Iooks Iike a tumor,
doesn't it?
But those are...
Yep.
We found a tumor.
She has cancer?
Technically, no.
So it's not cancer?
No, it's cancer,
but "he" has cancer
on "his" Ieft testicle.
I don't have testicles.
She's not a guy.
His DNA says you're wrong.
Frogs and snails
and puppy dog tails.
You've got
male pseudohermaphroditism.
You see,
we all start out as girls
and then we're differentiated,
based on our genes.
HOUSE: The ovaries develop
into testes and drop.
But in about one
in every 150, 000 pregnancies,
the fetus
with an XY chromosome
a boy,
develops into something else,
Iike you.
Your testes never descended,
because you're immune
to testosterone.
You're pure estrogen.
Which is why
you have heightened
female characteristics,
clear skin, great breasts.
The ultimate woman is a man.
Nature's cruel, huh?
This is obviously a joke.
This is impossible.
No. A joke would be
me calling you a homo.
You see the difference?
I'II schedule him for surgery.
No! You're wrong!
I'm a girl! Look at me!
How could you say
I'm not a girl?
You see,
they're all Iooking at me,
I'm beautiful!
That anger.
It's just the cancer talking.
Put your clothes back on.
We're gonna
cut your balls off.
Then you'II be fine.
How's the patient?
Post-op.
They sent him/her up
for a psyche visit.
Calling her a "him/her"
isn't really helping.
The good news is, I don't
think Dad's gonna be
sleeping with him/her again.
You see, now it's gross.
I need another shot.
When did the pain
start coming back?
A few hours ago.
About an hour
after you solved the case?
If I wanted to be
psychoanalyzed, I'd get
Wilson to give me the shot.
Same dosage?
If you'd be
more comfortable,
I might be able to deal with
a few Iess cc's of morphine.
It wasn't morphine.
What did you give me?
I told you I wanted...
It was saline.
I gave you a placebo.