My offer's withdrawn.
You can walk to work.
Got it.
You're morally outraged.
Now, can we
get through this part?
'Cause the next
part's awesome.
How do you rationalize
something like this?
You broke into
Stacy's therapist's office.
Borrowed a key.
And stole her
treatment notes.
Nope. I made copies.
(GROANS)
"Mark is," and I quote...
"...withdrawn,
passive aggressive,
won't communicate,
"like he resents me
because I can walk."
I don't wanna hear this.
"Dishes in the sink,
toilet seat up."
Meanwhile, she can't
stop thinking about...
I can't read that,
is she obsessed
with a gray horse or me?
It says she thinks
you're an annoying jerk.
It's a pet name.
Here's the kicker.
They're not having sex?
HOUSE: Doctor cleared him,
but no lift-off.
She's frustrated,
so she's doc-blocking me.
Paperwork, seminars,
meddling with my patients.
But now you've got
the proof you need,
just take those
personal psych records
to Cuddy,
and that'll show her
Stacy's out of control.
You ignoring me?
While looking
for my newspaper.
Efficient, huh?
KALVlN: Over here.
(SlGHlNG)
Dr. Wilson, I want you
to meet my stalker.
Your waiting room sucks.
I am not treating you.
Because you're a closet case?
We're not together.
He is so self-loathing.
But we gotta go now.
So, maybe see you after work.
No, no, no, no.
Nobody can figure out
what's wrong with me.
Well, your shirt is
gaping at the collar.
That means you've lost weight.
You're flushed, that's fever,
and you're short of breath.
And finally, there's
the KS lesion on your face.
It means you're HlV positive,
and you've progressed
to full-blown AlDS.
So you're sick because
your immune system is shot
and someone sneezed on you.
May I be excused now?
Brilliant,
but my immune system is fine.
Your concentration-camp
physique begs to differ.
Get your T-cell count
re-checked.
I've already done that.
They test for
T-cell lymphoma?
It was negative.
All of this
will be fascinating
to an HlV specialist.
Now let go of my cane
before it becomes
your new boyfriend.
Honey, I will marry it
if you will look at my file.
Congress says you can't,
so...
(BOTH GRUNTlNG)
(GROANS)
(CAR ALARM BLARlNG)
(GASPlNG)
I didn't touch him.
He's going into
anaphylactic shock.
Go see Stacy.
We gave him epi. He's fine.
You need a lawyer.
Go see Stacy.
You hit a patient.
Four words, two mistakes.
He's not a patient,
and I didn't hit him.
Of course you didn't.
Go see Stacy.
I didn't cause
the anaphylaxis.
It's probably
one of his HlV meds.
Abacavir.
I'll pass that along,
make sure the ER
takes him off it.
Go see Stacy.
You have to treat him.
Medically,
this case is a snooze-fest.
AlDS plus infection.
You don't treat him,
he charges you with assault.
Just 'cause he says I hit him,
doesn't make it true.
Watch, I am surrounded
by naked cheerleaders.
See?
Although, I like my chances
of some action this morning.
I forgot Wednesday
was hooker day.
This could have waited.
You make me meet you
at your house.
Your husband is
conveniently absent.
Mark's at physio.
I'm stuck waiting
for the exterminator.
I saw a rat last night.
Well, I'm surprised your feet
are touching the floor.
I barely slept.
What was Mark up to?
If memory serves,
a quick climb
up Mount Gregory,
and you'd doze
through a seal hunt.
Clubbing, shrieking.
What're you doing?
Sorry, it was just
driving me nuts.
You hate washing dishes.
People change.
(SCRUBBlNG DlSHES)
I could make sure
you'd sleep like
a baby tonight.
Rather take care of it
myself.
I was referring to the rat.
Trenton Pest
is sending a guy.
MARK: What's going on?
It's not what you think.
I know it looks like
we're cleaning dishes,
but actually we're having sex.
We're working.
Wow, wish I had
become a doctor.
Place would be spotless.
Take 10 minutes,
cure the guy,
and stop whining.
I give you Kalvin Ryan,
so flamboyant in person,
so boring on paper.
Obviously got
an opportunistic infection,
probably TB or PCP.
Have you read his file?
I started,
but I found the characters
two-dimensional.
He went to an HlV clinic
last week.
Tested negative
for TB, PCP, MAC, CMV, HSV.
It's not an infection.
HlV clinic.
So few patients,
so much money.
Redo the tests.
The results make sense.
Kalvin's T-cells are at 200.
That's strong enough
to fight infection.
Fine, parasite.
Nope. The stool sample
was negative.
Two months ago,
he was down to 30 T-cells.
Then he changed his meds,
his immune system rebounds,
his viral load drops,
everything's getting better,
but he's getting sicker.
Face it. This might be
an interesting case.
What if his immune system
is too strong?
An auto-immune disease?
With HlV, that's impossible.
His new HlV meds
kicked his system
out of a sound sleep.
It wakes up hungry, cranky,
spoiling for a fight.
And when it doesn't find
an active infection,
it starts attacking
the harmless remnants
of old infections.
Immune reconstitution
syndrome.
His meds made him
so much better,
he made himself sick?
Sounds pretty...
Boring!
This is so not interesting.
Chest x-ray to find
the old infection
and start him on steroids.
If you're wrong, the steroids
will tank his immune system.
He'll get worse.
Now that would
be interesting.
Where's the Coumadin?
If your patient's
got a blood problem,
then blood thinners
aren't exactly...
It's for Stacy's rat.
Death by anticoagulation.
Trying to win Stacy back
by killing an animal.
Very caveman.
I don't want her back.
I just want her to
admit her feelings for me.
I go to Cuddy,
Cuddy fires her
or reassigns her.
Either way, I'm happy.
If you want her back,
either tell her
or, better yet,
shut up and cry yourself
to sleep like everybody else.
Hi, this is, Mark Warner,
1724 Spring Street.
Listen, you don't
need to send that guy down.
We caught him.
No, you should
send the bill to
Princeton-Plainsboro Hospital,
attention Dr. James Wilson.
Yeah.
Your lymph nodes
aren't swollen, that's good.
KALVlN:
Maybe Dr. Chase should check.
Sorry, mate, hands full.
He's too pretty
to be straight.
You ever done any modeling?
Does anyone actually
fall for that line?
Every day.
Why do you think
I became a photographer?
I'm guessing you guys
didn't think about dating
on career day.
I love my job.
Really?
You seem more the "find it
exceptionally satisfying"
type.
I'm not sure
there's a difference.
Your mom died of diabetes.
How's your dad's health?
Last I heard,
he had cirrhosis.
Love is love.
Satisfying is
"social validation,
fun can wait."
I have fun.
Yeah, she's got some
scheduled for February.
Last you heard, your father?
He threw me out
when I was 16.
It's just as well.
I got tired of getting
BB guns for my birthday
when I'd asked for a Barbie.
Dads can be
real sweethearts.
Sensitive and cute.
He's cute.
He ran into that
heating vent, right there.
Hopefully, Mark's anger
will go away eventually.
He's not angry,
he just doesn't like you.
Nothing unique there.
Didn't seem real wild
about you, either.
He's fine with me.
He's angry.
Said so in group.
Of course he's angry.
He's looking at
months of painful physio.
He's mad at you.
There's no way he said that.
(SlGHlNG)
No.
But it's true.
He resents you
for being able to walk.
Been there.
I resented you
for a hell of a long time.
Past tense?
(CELL PHONE RlNGlNG)
Might be the hospital.
What?
Bad time? Where are you?
HOUSE:
At your girlfriend's place.
Ignore the moaning
and squeaking.
His lungs are too scarred to
tell which infection triggered
the immune reconstitution.
He a smoker?
CAMERON: Yes, and possibly
more than cigarettes.
His tox screen
came back positive
for recreational drugs.
HOUSE: Not surprising,
not medically relevant.
His heart looks
a little enlarged.
That's a typical
side effect of AZT.
What are Kalvin's
most recent infections?
T oxo, CMV,
and PCP.
(RAT SQUEAKlNG)
(WHlSPERlNG)
Well, let's assume
it's one of those.
Give him ganciclovir
for the CMV.
We can hardly hear you.
Where are you?
In a closet.
Your girlfriend's
other boyfriend showed up.
Ganciclovir for the CMV.
Sulfadiazine for the toxo,
Bactrim for PCP.
Gotta go. It's killing time.
CAMERON: Your tox screen
came back positive for...
Crystal meth and ecstasy.
Recreational drugs are
dangerous to begin with,
but for someone with HlV...
I didn't mistake them
for vitamins.
I'm a PNP boy.
Party and Play.
Drugs and sex.
(COUGHlNG)
You don't approve?
Does the sex include condoms?
If he's negative, sure.
If he's positive...
Why put on a raincoat
if you're already wet?
You could get hepatitis,
or another strain of HlV.
Or I could get hit by a bus.
AlDS isn't a death
sentence anymore.
I don't wanna
have any regrets.
(COUGHlNG)
How long have
you been coughing?
(SlGHlNG)
About an hour or so.
Try to take a deep breath.
What is it?
I think it's blood.
I recommend
post-exposure prophylaxis.
Your chances of
conversion are slim,
but I'd like to
put you on three
anti-viral medications.
Nelfinavir,
zidovudine, and lamivudine.
There are side effects,
headache, nausea,
vivid dreaming.
You'll be tested
for HlV at six weeks,
three months, six months.
Very interesting.
He coughs infected blood
in Cameron's eyes and mouth,
that's interesting?
The "coughing" part,
not the "in Cameron" part.
New symptom, blood vessel
ruptured in his lung.
I closed the tear.
Well, it takes
immune reconstitution
off the table.
What's it put on the table?
It's okay, she's not here,
you can skip
the nice-guy acts.
You know,
some human beings are actually
capable of human feelings.
My giving a damn or not
is not gonna
change what happened.
Could be
Goodpasture's syndrome.
No edema, no bloody urine.
Well, KS on his face could
mean KS in his lungs, with
bleeding from the lesions.
I would have seen them
when I repaired
the tear in his lung.
Wegener's granulomatosis?
Wegener's would have
responded to steroids.
Maybe you should go home,
take the rest of the day.
I'm fine.
Well, this is good.
He's pretending to care,
you're pretending not to.
I think we should
reconsider drugs.
Kalvin uses crystal meth.
Concerned enough
about his health
to stalk me,
while indulging in
deadly street drugs.
A study in contradictions.
Interesting, but still
not medically relevant.
It could be,
if his drugs were tainted.
They cook meth
with battery acid,
lye, lantern fuel...
Find Kalvin's pills,
test for toxins.
Foreman, you're with me.
I need a consult
on another case.
We have another case?
It's a hip-pocket deal.
Patient presents with
a distinct neck tilt.
Wry neck. Is he an athlete?
He's a regular runner.
Any pain
associated with movement?
None that
he's complained of.
Best-case scenario,
an infection
in the ear or lungs.
Worst case, brain-stem tumor.
You should do an MRl,
CAT Scan, full work up.
I don't think so.
No insurance.
No drugs in here.
I'll take the bathroom.
How about a drink after work?
Take your mind
off what happened.
Cameron?
I might have HlV,
a drink's not gonna
wash it away.
There's like zero chance
of you contracting the virus.
Big difference between
"like zero" and "zero."
What did the infection
control guy tell you?
He was very reassuring.
Kept reminding me
that the hospital covers
all my medical costs.
Apparently forgot to mention
that if I do test positive,
that they'll pass it on
to legal, and legal will
dig up any dirt they can,
trying to prove that
I'm a drug user or tramp,
and that's why I have HlV.
It's not like they're gonna
find anything, right?
Right.
Check this out.
CHASE:
Kalvin's a photographer.
The broken bulbs were props.
The glass is from
1930s fluorescents.
Some of the bulbs
are date-stamped.
Pre-World War ll,
fluorescent bulbs
contained large amounts
of beryllium.
Beryllium dust
inflames the lungs,
they get rigid,
patient can't breathe.
My father co-authored
a paper on acute berylliosis.
Phew!
For a moment there,
I thought you were smart.
Cameron, get a biopsy
of Kalvin's lung tissue,
run a spectrographic analysis.
I can handle it.
No reason to risk
exposing the entire team.
Then who would I torment?
I'm sorry.
About what happened.
It's best not to talk.
You're gonna feel
a sharp pinch.
This actually is gonna grab
a piece of your lung.
What were you guys
looking for at my hotel?
Your drugs.
We thought maybe
you'd used toxic meth.
We'll know if you were
exposed to beryllium
in a few hours.
Well,
if you're still curious,
it's in my bag over there
on the chair.
You brought drugs
into the hospital?
Glad I wasted my time
at your hotel.
KALVlN: I told you I used,
you didn't ask me
for a sample.
You're not pissed about this,
you're mad because
I coughed blood on you.
That was an accident.
Would you stop being nice?
It's useless,
and worse, it's boring.
Get angry!
I had one stupid night,
I end up with HlV.
Do you have any idea
how pissed off I was?
This wasn't your fault.
(WHlSTLlNG)
You broke into my house?
Well, I had to,
Mark isn't here.
He has physio.
Oh, really?
How's he doing?
What happened
with all the cheese?
Well, I had to get rid of it
before Steve McQueen
ate any Coumadin.
I named your rat.
Steve's tilting his head.
Any neurologist will tell you
that suggests an infection
or a brain-stem tumor.
Death cures
both those things.
We can't kill him.
If it's an infection,
it could be caused
by something in your house.
Something that could
affect you guys.
Smell this.
Does it smell like urine?
You missing any asparagus?
Okay, stuff these.
If he doesn't get better,
then it's a tumor.
Then what, chemo?
Steve McQueen without hair?
It's a blessing
he died young.
(CELL PHONE RlNGlNG)
Hello.
Hi, honey.
I'm sorry I missed you, yeah.
I came home.
All right, I'll see you
in a few minutes.
Okay.
Bye, hon.
Chest hurts.
Heart rate's a 100
and climbing, could be
an allergic reaction.
Neck veins are up.
Must be pericardial effusion.
There's no wheezing.
The tear in his lungs
must have reopened.
Kalvin?
You're bleeding into the area
around your heart.
(GASPlNG)
I can't breathe.
The blood's
crushing your heart.
Once we remove it,
you'll be fine.
If I die,
please tell my dad...
You're not going to die.
Tell him sorry.
(CARDlOGRAPH BEEPlNG RAPlDLY)
Where's the blood?
It's clear.
Only one other thing
could cause this.
A tumor in his heart.
WlLSON: CT confirmed
a mass in Kalvin's heart,
and several smaller ones
in his lungs.
That's why his heart's
enlarged, not the AZT.
You okay?
She's fine,
probably getting bored
with the question.
Masses in the heart and lungs,
what kind of cancer
are we looking at?
They may not be cancerous.
This is classic
Non-Hodgkin's lymphoma.
HlV-positive patient
with a primary heart mass?
It could be sarcoidosis.
His lung tissue was negative.
Lymphoma's a death sentence,
sarcoidosis is treatable.
So is an ear infection,
but since he didn't test
positive for that either...
I want to do
the Kveim-Siltzbach test.
Do you have any idea
how much paperwork
Cuddy's gonna need signed?
Do it.
So...
How's the patient's father?
"Tell my dad I'm sorry"?
Might as well have waved
a red flag at a bull.
He's not coming.
Well, it's not a tragedy.
Dad doesn't wanna see him,
he doesn't wanna see the dad.
You're the only one
who wants them together.
He asked.
He thought he was dying.
Dying people lie, too.
Wish they'd worked less,
they'd been nicer,
they'd opened
orphanages for kittens.
If you really wanna
do something, you do it,
you don't save it
for a sound bite.
What did you say
when you thought
you were dying?
On the other hand...
His dad tossed him out.
So what's our guy
wanna apologize for?
Everybody has regrets.
If the growths in your lungs
and heart are sarcoid,
your body will recognize
this material,
and we'll see
a reaction on your arm.
Did you really wanna
see your dad?
You called him?
Thanks.
He would've come,
tried to straighten me out.
How are you holding up?
I'm fine.
Convincing.
What did you do
with my drugs?
The lab disposes of them
after analysis.
Too bad.
They could've
done you some good.
Not really my thing.
You know, I hope
you don't have it, but...
Getting HlV might have been
the best thing that
ever happened to me.
I used to be a good boy.
Never wanted to
piss anybody off.
Playing by the rules
makes everybody else happy.
Now I'm happy.
So you just show up
every time he's at physio?
Of course not.
Also when
he's at group therapy
or out for dinner
with friends.
And when she happens
to mention to Mark
that you dropped by...
You tell your wife
everything?
It's a process.
But Stacy doesn't have
any reason to hide this
from Mark.
As far as she knows,
Mark's okay with you
being there.
My bet is
she mentions me to Mark
as little as possible.
Because she thinks
that he thinks
that she still
has feelings for me.
You know
why she thinks that?
Because she still
has feelings for you?
If you're right,
she did tell him
and I don't get through
the door tonight.
If I'm right...
So how long do we stay here?
Until something happens.
He's not gonna come out
with us right here.
We are downwind,
and he seems to
have hearing loss.
He's not blind.
Steve McQueen does not
run from danger.
Antibiotics,
on the other hand...
He ate around the pill?
Smart.
Admit it, you like him.
He's all right. For a rat.
You wanna know
how cool he is?
His urine showed traces
of hydrogen cyanide,
formaldehyde, lead.
He's a smoker.
Your husband's
been lighting up,
which is particularly stupid,
given that it could
cause his AlP...
Okay, I blow my smoke
into the vent
so Mark doesn't know.
I always knew.
Bluffing.
You started two weeks
after my surgery.
Menthols,
then lights after a month.
Why didn't you say anything?
'Cause it helped me monitor
your misery level.
One trip outside
was a good day,
and upwards of six,
you were in hell.
You could have
asked me how I was.
I already knew.
I'm sorry you were miserable.
Sorry I caused you
so much pain.
(METAL CAGE RATTLlNG)
Glad you changed your mind
about that drink.
Come on in.
You should get changed,
there's this new place
on campus that looks...
Are you high?
Uh-huh.
I thought the lab
disposed of the drugs.
Not all of it.
Slow down.
Your pupils are dilated.
You're not...
Come on, Chase,
don't turn into
a good guy on me now.
You're late.
And hung over.
Or maybe not.
Why do you have a rat?
Jealous?
(ELEVATOR BELL DlNGS)
KALVlN: Get out of my room!
MlCHAEL: Don't you dare
put this on me!
I'm not gonna grovel, Dad!
That's not
what I'm asking for!
Like hell it isn't!
You said you didn't call.
Well...
Don't mind me,
just here for the show.
Yeah, well,
there's not gonna be any.
What happened
to the big apology?
Yesterday he was all,
"Daddy, I'm so sowwy."
This is none of
your business.
Well, you should've
thought of that
before you stalked me.
Now I'm interested.
So what's he got
to apologize for?
You're the one
who tossed him out.
Now why would I do that?
I don't know,
because it's tough
to brag to
your hunting buddies
that your son knows
all the words to The Wiz.
That's a lie.
42nd Street?
(LAUGHS) No.
Much easier just to
get drunk and beat him.
Explains his hating you,
and also your cirrhosis.
Also, why the more I talk,
the more you sweat.
What it doesn't explain,
is why he's got to
apologize to you.
Residual guilt for
sharing your special toy
with other boys?
Just leave it alone.
You just wanna leave
the bigot with some peace
of mind after you're gone?
Look, this has got nothing,
and I mean nothing,
to do with him being gay.
Now Kal brought this
on himself
with what he did
to his mother.
He steal her signature look?
No.
No, he killed her.
Kalvin lied!
Yeah.
That certainly is shocking.
Mom's kidneys were failing,
she needed a transplant,
they tested Kalvin,
he was a match,
he was also positive for HlV.
Mom never found
a qualified donor, she dies.
HOUSE: Tragic tale.
Undercut slightly
by the rapid-fire delivery
and constant movement.
Too much coffee this morning?
He didn't kill her.
Our bodies aren't
donor farms for our parents.
It's not 1980.
We know how HlV
is transmitted.
If Kalvin got HlV through
unprotected sex, dad has
every right to be pissed.
So you always use a condom?
Yeah.
Brothers on
the down-low got to.
I'm not ready for any
Foreman Juniors yet.
You?
Working girls are sticklers.
You're not gonna poll Chase?
I'm not an idiot.
Obviously not.
Who doesn't sleep with
a drugged-out colleague
when they have a chance?
Where's Wilson?
We got the result
of the Kveim test.
But so...
I have cancer?
In all likelihood, yeah.
Non-Hodgkin's lymphoma.
And I am
dying?
We need to biopsy the tumor.
It's near your aorta,
so getting that sample
carries serious risks.
Is my dad still here?
He hasn't been in?
We'll inject a dye around
your heart to make the tumor
visible on the CT.
WlLSON: Then a surgeon
inserts a guide wire,
runs it up into your heart,
where he takes a small piece
of that tumor so we can look
at it under the microscope.
Ativan.
It' ll help
settle you down.
Why are you so calm?
Not coming off meth helps.
Last night probably
shouldn't happen again.
Do you think I want it to?
When two people have had sex,
unless it sucks,
if they can do it again,
they're gonna do it again.
And that's when
things get complicated.
And it didn't suck.
So now you've gotta drum up
another excuse to be around
the love of your life.
Could hit another patient.
Yeah, don't like
to repeat myself.
People will say
I'm formulaic.
Well, that rules out
letting the rat go
so you can catch him again.
I can't do that.
Steve needs two weeks'
antibiotics and
a smoke-free environment.
Cigarettes aggravated
his infection.
The rat is actually sick?
That thing could infect
the entire hospital.
Steve's infection is not
contagious to humans.
I'm an idiot.
How do I miss mycoplasmosis?
Was that the kid's father?
Yeah.
Remember the Black Death?
It started with rats.
Well, what's he doing
in the hallway?
Is the kid getting
his biopsy already?
He just won't
go in the room.
Who knows what else he has,
parasites,
bacterial infection?
The kid doesn't
have parasites.
Not the kid, the rat.
Was he still sweating?
Rats only sweat
through their tails.
Not the rat, the dad!
Where are they from?
Montana. What's going on?
You were right,
it's a parasite.
Cancel the biopsy,
it'll kill him.
Hey, Daddy, come with me.
Yeah, I'm not going in there.
(SlGHS)
Your son asked to talk to you.
Why is he here?
He wanted to talk to you.
Did you two
used to hunt together?
Foxes? Did you kill foxes?
It's Montana.
Those masses in your chest
are not tumors.
They're parasitic cysts from
a bug called echinococcus.
Touch a dead fox,
they jump aboard,
they can hunker down
for decades.
Growing, spawning, shopping,
putting on plays.
I've been tested
for parasites.
Okay, it's cancer. You happy?
The cysts isolate
the parasites,
keeping them from showing up
in stool samples. Even in
blood tests, cardiac...
All right,
you don't need me for this.
But you've got
the same things
in your liver.
I have cirrhosis.
Liver cysts have
identical symptoms,
with one addition, fever.
And liver cysts
we can test for.
Your diagnosis
could confirm Kalvin's.
So, option A,
we draw some blood...
No, no, no.
Look, you're not touching me.
Well, you see,
this is why I need you here.
I want you to tell your son
that you won't take a simple,
painless blood test
to save his life.
You
never expressed
a shred of regret
for what happened
to your mother.
Jeez, Dad.
MlCHAEL: If you'd have
worn a damn rubber,
you'd have been fine.
You could have
saved her life.
You wouldn't be lying here.
HOUSE:
Yeah, yeah, yeah, I get it!
You're really mad at him
for killing himself,
and for destroying
everything you love.
I don't have time for this.
Are you gonna apologize?
I'm living my life
the way I want.
Are you gonna
give me some blood?
Look,
if he doesn't give a damn,
then neither do l.
Okay, option B.
Why did your wife
kill herself?
Did she hate you?
She was a diabetic!
You know, you don't know
a thing about my Susan.
Either Susan wanted to die,
or she was both
fat and stupid.
Used a Twinkie
instead of a gun.
And girls with big appetites,
well, they just can't get
enough of anything.
Shut up!
Probably nibbled on
every Devil Dog in the county!
Shut up!
Just in case I'm not
making myself clear,
I don't mean
the delicious snack.
You son of a bitch!
Yeah? Come on!
Thank you.
Means I can do this.
(GROANS)
We're gonna need
some epi in here, stat!
Are you out of your mind?
You said you didn't care.
(CHOKlNG)
Notice how you can't breathe?
Now,
either that's the cane
or, I just ruptured
one of those liver cysts
we were chatting about,
and you've gone into
anaphylactic shock.
Exactly the same way
your son did
when he accidentally tripped
against my friend's car.
I'm just so excited
to find out which.
(GRUNTlNG)
I'm gonna schedule
the surgery.
WOMAN: Clamp.
MAN: Pressure's holding.
(SURGEONS CHATTERlNG)
Give me the syringe.
WOMAN: Clamps...
Two successful surgeries,
two lives saved.
I'm over my quota.
Can I have next week off?
Two family members assaulted.
It was self-defense.
You baited him.
You're right,
I was asking for it.
The low-cut blouse,
the do-me pumps.
You flooded his gut
with a parasite.
He could sue.
Go see Stacy.
Okay.
That's it, "okay"?
No name-calling? No squawking,
no rending of garments?
I like this t-shirt.
You lied to me.
If this is
about my mom, l...
This is about your lonely,
miserable life.
I'm not miserable.
And as long as
there's a gay bar around,
I'm never lonely.
You haven't had
a single visitor
except for your dad.
Drugs are great,
HlV freed you,
your dad hates you,
you're so happy.
Everything's a lie.
You blame yourself
for your mom's death.
You're not trying
to have fun, you're trying
to self-destruct.
You wanna kill yourself,
fine, but stop recruiting!
Heard you hit
another patient.
Yeah, sure, why not?
He hit me first.
Cuddy didn't mention that.
Let me see.
I'm the doctor.
My concern is purely legal.
Looks okay. Does it hurt?
A little.
You need some ice.
There's no way
that Mark doesn't know.
About the smoking.
He would have said something.
Then he hasn't been
near you in months.
We're fine.
Can't be easy.
Stop squirming.
Why would you
lie about this?
I'm not lying.
I don't care if you're
sleeping with him or not,
but you're not, so...
I am.
You're lying.
You know when I have sex?
You can smell that on me, too?
The only people who know
about what's going on
with me and Mark,
are me and Mark.
Well, I just know you.
And I know you.
You're confident, arrogant,
but you're never certain
unless there's a reason
to be certain.
One other person knew.
I told you I was
seeing Dr. Harper,
you can easily
get into her office.
You read my file.
The dishes, the concern,
the acting like
a human being.
You have...
This whole time,
you've been manipulating me.
You knew that I had
an angle the moment
I poured soap
onto a scrub brush.
You could have thrown me out
or ignored me
or found another exterminator.
You didn't even tell Mark
that I kept coming by.
You let this happen
because you wanna be with me.
I don't anymore.
Get out.
I'm sorry.