It's almost 11:00.
She needs a lot of sleepthese days.
Please, Mrs. Bardach.
I haven't seen her for a week.
I'll see how she's feeling.
- Thank you.
- You know what to do.
Bardach: All done?
- Yeah.
I, uh, scrubbed
for 45 seconds,
did the nails,
all the way downthe elbows,
the whole deal.
[Sneezes]
- Are you sick?
- No, no, no.
- Cough, sore throat?
- No, no.
I just--Sometimes I sneeze
when I look at lights.
I always have.
I'm sorry. You better--
I would never get her sick.
Please.
A mask.
Got me by the bouncer.
She's crazy.
She's let me out like six times
in the last two months.
Every time it's just
to go to the hospital.
I'm a prisoner.
Aw, it's okay.
- It's ugly.
- No.
I wasn't looking
at the scar anyways.
Take off your mask.
Uh...If your mom
comes in here, she--
Hey, give me a kiss
or I'll kill you.
Your skin.
Are you okay?
[Wheezes]
Augh.
Melinda, can you--
What's wrong? What's wrong?
Can you breathe?
What's wrong?
Is it your heart?
Mrs. Bardach!
Melinda, I don't know how to use this.
I've never used one of these before.
[Choking]
[Catches her wind]
What did you do to her?
2X16 - Safe
Original Airdate (FOX): 4 APR-2006
Cuddy called.
I know.
Saw the caller ID.
Young girl,
anaphylactic shock.
You answered?
Turns out that's
what stops the ringing.
It's a weird case.
I thought you did
the dishes last night.
It was your day.
I did. Those are new.
Midnight snack.
For a midnight snack,
you made a pot roast.
The same pot roast
I made last night.
Yeah. Actually,
it was after midnight.
Today is your day, right?
You want me out of here.
I get it.
No, it's fine if you stay.
The place I was gonna move,
the guy never called.
- Otherwise, I'll already be there.
- I said it's fine if you stay.
Yeah. That's why you're
making me miserable.
Maybe I just want to make sure
you do your fair share around here.
Tha--
What's weird about it?
The girl with the allergies.
Yeah.
- She's immunocompromised.
- What are you doing?
What? You asked me--
You knew that I was interested.
That gives you
a valuable bargaining chip.
You could've had me
doing dishes for a week.
Okay.
The allergic reaction happened
while she was in a clean room.
Why does she have
a clean room in her home?
Heart transplant.
Immune system's in the toilet.
Mommy builds her little angel
a John Travolta-quality bubble.
Six months after the transplant,
she doesn't need to be
confined to a clean room.
Six months without putting out,
Dr. Cuddy doesn't need
to wear thong panties, but
it's not our call.
I was wondering when
you'd get around to my panties.
She's had four days of workups.
They've tested everyone who
came anywhere near that room,
everything in the room.
It's like an Agatha Christie mystery.
Maybe it's not what was there.
It's what she was doing.
Exercise allergy.
Love it.
What sort of exercise could
a strapping young man and
a nubile teenage nymphet possibly--
Mom  was in the room
within seconds.
So the boyfriend brought in
an allergen and is lying about it.
Or the girl snuck out and
she's lying about that.
Or the parents are lying
about the room being clean.
These are your big ideas?
Somebody's lying?
Hasn't let me down yet.
Recheck Mom, Dad, the girl,
the boy, the room, and the home.
Any of you have a new soap,
detergent, perfume?
No. Barbara's really
careful about that stuff.
And you haven't been
outside recently?
How could I?
I'm trapped up there.
You're not trapped.
It's just safe--
They won't even
tell me the alarm code.
Just tell her I can
go back to school.
Till we clear this up.
Fine.
Find out what I'm allergic to,
and I'll stay away from it.
Then I can go back to school, right?
It's up to your parents.
But medically,
there's no reason--
Told you.
Could I speak to you outside
for a second, please?
You know, this is hard enough
without you in there giving--
She asked my opinion.
She is 16 years old.
Lie to her.
When I was eight,
my mom, she hated--
I know.
I-I need to loosen up.
I'm overprotective.
I saw Finding Nemo. I get it.
I don't need another story.
But you're not just
being overprotective.
You're  one of the most
overprotective parents
I've ever seen.
She has the best private tutors.
I let her friends visit.
I'm not going to apologize.
Just  giving you my thoughts.
She almost died three times
during her childhood.
Penicillin,
bee stings, peanuts.
I've seen her file.
Six month ago,
we leave her home alone
for the first time on a weekend.
She goes out,
buys one chocolate chip cookie.
Peanut butter in the dough.
She's forgotten her epi pen,
she drives to the hospital,
passes out, has an accident.
Steering wheel
crushed her chest.
She ended up losing her heart.
So when you say to me
that I'm one of the most
overprotective parents
you've seen, please...
please introduce me to the ones
who were more protective
so that I can find out
what they're doing right.
She's allergic to having
a sucky social life.
Give the parents a break.
They're just trying
to keep her healthy.
Everything in here's
labeled "hypoallergenic."
Check it anyway.
Cameron.
This place is cleaner
than her hospital room.
No alarm on this window.
It's 20-foot drop.
You can get to the tree from here.
There's some bark scraped off.
Sure. Heart-transplant girl
swung down there on a vine.
Maybe she was hooking up
with Tarzan and Cheetah
down by the elephant graveyard.
Or...Jane stayed in the tree house
and Tarzan came up.
Okay. Um, I spent
most of the night Friday.
But if her mom finds out
about that, she will totally freak.
You guys had sex?
Yeah, but, you know,
I did everything I could
to make sure she wouldn't get sick.
A latex allergy?
What do you mean,
like a condom? We didn't--
You had unsafe sex?
The whole unsafe thing
didn't tell you something?
Yeah, but we didn't like
plan on it, you know? It just--
I don't know. We're in love.
We've been dating for two years.
Practically a lifetime.
How about a semen allergy?
We're gonna need
a semen sample.
You can use
the bathroom over there.
Right. Uh, how do I...
Aim and shoot.
No thinking about Dr. Cameron.
We'll know.
We should tell her parents.
Why stop there?
Call the cops.
Melinda's a minor.
And if we nip it in the bud here,
teenagers will never again have sex.
The parents will find out
when they get the bill anyway.
Oh, so you're fine with them
finding out as long as you don't
have to tell them personally?
Pretty much.
Too bad it's not you
giving the sample.
We'd be done by now.
Test was negative.
No semen allergy.
Boyfriend sneaks in to get his freak
on the night before the anaphylaxis.
I don't buy that it's unrelated.
He loves her.
Did everything he could
to make sure she wouldn't get sick.
What does that mean?
Love is an emotion
certain people experience,
similar to happiness.
No. Maybe I should give
a more relatable example.
Oh, snap!
What did he do to protect her?
Brillo-pad his privates?
- I assumed he washed and he--
- Oh, good work.
Assumptions are so much
faster than actual questions.
House:
You the boyfriend?
Need to borrow you.
What is going on?
Don't worry. I'll return him
in roughly the same condition.
Do you take anything
to stay healthy?
Something stronger
than an apple a day?
Is he okay?
He's just tired...
from being in a coma so long.
What'd you take?
Don't worry.
He can keep a secret.
Antibiotics?
Penicillin?
Any of those names ring a bell?
Yeah, uh...my friend Elliot,
his dad had, like, a whole bottle
that he hadn't finished, so...
I swiped it and took a bunch
for, like, a week.
There's no way I was gonna risk
breathing germs on Melinda.
This is the one downside
of teenage sex:
You're idiots.
You almost killed
your girlfriend.
She's allergic to penicillin.
What, do you think there was
still some on my lips?
I brushed my teeth.
Think lower and more fun.
I mean, it can--
It can go through your stuff?
Totally, dude.
There's this administrator here,
whenever she gets sick,
she just gives me the prescription.
But you know, they tested Melinda,
they said...she wasn't allergic to my stuff.
Yeah, four days later.
By that time, the penicillin
was crusting up a sock
at the bottom of your hamper.
Do you have to tell her
it was my fault?
No.
Great part of being a grownup,
you never have to do anything.
You're releasing her?
What happened?
What did you find out?
Tests on your house ruled out
any environmental allergens.
Yeah, but what caused this?
We believe it's highly unlikely that
this set of circumstances will repeat itself.
What set of circumstances?
It's good news.
She's healthy.
- But you might want to talk--
- Cameron!
- I can't breathe.
- Getting the epi.
Lewis: Give her the shot!
- No murmurs, no friction rubs.
- What are you waiting for?
- Quiet.
She's coughing up white sputum.
Crackling two-thirds
of the way up.
Look at her neck.
Please. She is vomiting.
Would you give her the shot?
It's not an allergy.
It's her heart.
What's the good news?
What's the bad news?
Congestive heart failure.
Is which?
- Good news.
- Why?
I don't know.
It just sounded like you.
New puzzle piece.
Always good news.
What's the bad news?
We've got two puzzle pieces
from two different puzzles.
Seems that way.
What if her anaphylaxis
wasn't anaphylaxis?
Toxicity from the anti-rejection meds could
cause a seizure and then heart failure.
And get cured by
a mommy-wielded epi pen?
It's anaphylaxis. What else?
What if they really are two puzzles?
You think she had two unrelated
rare conditions in one week?
- We explained the anaphylaxis.
- What do you mean, we? I did!
At least I thought I did.
Maybe I didn't.
Still, it was all me.
Heart problems aren't so rare for
someone who's had a heart transplant.
I say we assume House was
right about the anaphylaxis.
It is tempting.
Heart failure could be either infection,
coronary disease, or rejection.
Sorry. There's a reason
they call it the white board.
It's not my rule.
What ties both
these conditions together?
Okay, we can all stare at each other,
or we can investigate
what caused the heart failure.
Just the heart failure.
You wanna give me
that black marker?
There's no fever,
so it's probably not infection.
Or no fever because she's been
on immunosuppressants
for the last six months.
Let's do a C.T.,
get a heart biopsy
and redo the blood work.
- Anything?
- Not yet.
So I hear you don't want
teenagers having sex.
Teen suicide rate isn't
high enough for you already?
I just think
those two are brats.
The girl undercuts her mother
any chance she gets.
Yeah, it's the daughter's fault.
Has nothing to do with
mom infantilizing her.
Good point.
Explains why parents
who don't pay attention get
such nice, well-adjusted children.
What's this?
Think it's vegetation?
Yeah.
The kind made of muscle
that opens your heart valves.
It's nothing.
She's clean.
It's good news.
You don't show any signs
of coronary artery disease.
So what's next?
Well, blood work
to rule out infection,
and  then a heart surgical biopsy
to rule out rejection.
But you don't think you're gonna
rule out both things, do you?
No.
I'm gonna lose this heart, right?
Hopefully we'll find
the problem and fix it.
You'll keep
your heart a long time.
How long?
Well, there could be
drug breakthroughs that allow you
to keep it for decades more.
[Chuckles] Yeah.
That's the answer
my cardiologist always gives me.
I looked it up on the web.
It's like five or ten years, right?
That's about the average.
That's why I need to have a life.
Why can't you convince my mom
to let me go back to school?
M elinda,
you've got bigger worries
right now than missing school.
Until we figure out
what's wrong with your heart,
the safest place for you to be is right here.
"Pain in My Heart"
by Otis's Reddings
# Pain in my heart #
# Is treating me poor #
# Where can my baby be #
# Lord, no one knows #
# Pain in my heart #
#  Just won't let me sleep #
# Where can my baby be? #
# Lord, where can she be? #
# And now the days #
# Has begin to get tough #
# Said I want you to come back #
# Come back, come back, baby #
# I've had enough, oh-oh...#
Where's...
the hooker, I assume?
Right up here, buddy.
You said
you'd hang the stethoscope
if you were having sex.
I didn't say it had to be
with another person.
Can you think of anything
that would tie together
anaphylaxis and heart failure?
No.
I was waiting
out there for hours!
I need a lot of foreplay.
And then there's
the cuddling afterwards.
Any way that
anaphylaxis isn't anaphylaxis
even it responds to epi?
No. Oh, no wonder
you were in the mood.
This month's
New Jersey Journal of Cardiology.
Have you seen the centerfold?
There's no way
those valves are real.
Any chance that the heart failure
could be unrelated to--
No. If you need
time alone to work,
you just have to say so.
You don't have to lie about it.
- Lying's more fun.
- Being lied to, not as much fun.
Please have an answer
to this question:
What's for dinner?
Wilson:
You still haven't done the dishes?
You want one of these?
I think I got a couple of blueberries.
Nope. Sorry. Just one.
Oh, don't look all weepy.
You got a problem with me,
deal with it.
Short my sheets or something.
[Sighs]
[Wilson does the dishes]
Biopsy was negative for rejection.
Thank God.
And what about the blood tests?
Showed no infection.
So we still don't know
what caused her heart failure.
Let's just be happy
she doesn't need a new heart.
Mrs. Bardach, it could have
just been a one-time thing.
So she has
an allergic reaction
and heart failure,
and neither of them
can be explained.
Are they doing
any more tests on her?
- No.
- She's not here.
Notify local hospitals, cab companies,
the state troopers, and local cops.
Any security officers off duty
are back on duty.
Woman:
We're on it.
And I'm going to need some pictures.
And go through those drawers.
And I want at least two people
going over the surveillance tapes.
That work?
Are those all her clothes?
Uh, yeah.
She's obviously
still in the building.
So where did she go?
What does she want?
See her boyfriend?
She didn't take her phone.
She wants to be outside.
If you're trying to
scare your parents, great job.
Can we go back now?
I hate her.
When I was eight years old,
I was sick.
- Not really sick,
but the point is, my mom, she--
- She was like this before.
Home by 9:00 every night.
Can't go out on the weekends.
Can't do sports.
- Transplant just gave her
what she always wanted.
- Melinda...
You had heart failure.
This is kind of an insane time
to be criticizing your mom
about being overprotective.
I know. I mean, this is
what makes it even worse.
All of her craziness, it just...
It makes sense now.
Everything's gonna be all right.
I didn't even try to get outside.
I was too scared.
Come on.
Whoa, whoa. Melinda,
please walk back towards me.
Why?
Please?
It feels kind of weird.
It's called steppage gait.
Lewis:
Is it serious?
No, not necessarily.
All right,
stick your leg out, hold it up.
She was under anesthesia
for the biopsy. If she lost oxygen--
C.T. ruled out brain damage.
Put your leg down.
Relax.
Why is her leg
twitching like that?
Fasciculation.
Is that serious?
It's paralysis,
and it's ascending.
She's going to
lose the use of her legs?
To start with.
It's ascending fast.
She can hardly extend her leg now.
At this rate, it'll be up to
her lungs in a matter of days.
So, anaphylaxis,
heart failure, paralysis.
Couldn't put the first two together.
I'm guessing we can't put all three together.
Tick paralysis?
Could also explain the anaphylaxis,
maybe even the--
Penicillin allergy explains
the allergic reaction much better.
Particularly
because tick paralysis is
usually accompanied by a tick.
We did
two comprehensive physicals
looking for insect bites.
Can we put any two
of those together?
How about we stipulate?
You argued that there must be
something to connect all three symptoms,
you mocked us for not figuring it out,
and finally you let us discuss the paralysis
on its own because
it's what's gonna kill her.
Now, it's ascending.
Her MRIs are clean,
so rule out stroke or aneurysm.
- ALS? MS?
- Progression's too quick.
- Spinal lesion from leukemia?
- Too slow.
It's most likely
Guillain-Barre.
She's immunosuppressed.
What about botulism?
Not unless she's been
walking around on her hands
the last couple of days.
Botulism paralysis is
descending, not ascending.
Could be a virus.
West Nile, even polio
with her immune system shot.
Get an LP and
do PCRs for the viruses.
And get an EMG
to check for Guillain-Barre.
Foreman's right. We gotta
find out why she's paralyzed.
But not before staring at me
dumbly for a few seconds.
Foreman:
We ran more tests
on your daughter.
We took a lumbar puncture,
got some spinal fluid.
Then we brought her to the lab
to look for infections that
could be affecting her brain.
We also did an EMG to check
how her muscles and nerves are
responding to electrical impulses.
Unfortunately, her muscles are showing
increased weakness above the knee.
You mean she's getting worse?
The LP and PCRs ruled out
polio and West Nile.
We think it's Guillain-Barre.
The body's immune response
goes haywire and starts
attacking the peripheral nerves.
It causes
muscle weakness and paralysis.
How bad is it?
It's serious, but
Guillain-Barre usually responds
very well to plasmapheresis.
Foreman:
You see, the plasma,
the clear liquid part of her blood,
contains most of the antibodies,
which are overreacting and
attacking her nervous system.
The machine spins her blood
in a centrifuge and separates parts
of the blood based on weight.
White blood cells are the heaviest,
then the red cells, then platelets and plasma.
We discard the stuff that's causing
all the trouble and return the good blood cells
back to her body in a replacement fluid.
If it works, we'll see results
in a couple of days.
You didn't get any messages
for me last week, did you?
Nope.
That's funny.
The guy finally called back.
The place I lost?
He said he left
three voice mails.
Gotta pee.
Which I never got,
if that wasn't clear.
He must be lying.
You wouldn't want
to live with a liar.
- You erased my messages?
- Yup.
Decided I wanted you to stay.
Told you that, didn't I?
You're...miserable, and you're lonely, and
you're gonna trap me here to keep me
every bit as miserable and lonely, too.
- Yeah, and you're
happy, happy, happy.
- Okay.
Hey, I'm obviously going
through a rough patch here.
Wife leaves, tends
to bum somebody out.
Do you know
where my pee went?
You're missing some?
No. Came out of me and
went right into the toilet.
Now, why would that be?
You're William Tell.
You could pick an apple
off someone's head?
No, it's because there was
no clear plastic wrap over the toilet.
Stuff's in the kitchen.
You have plenty of time.
All that was missing was the will.
This isn't a college dorm.
It could be.
We're not 18!
So what?
What did I do to you?
I scammed you into doing the dishes,
I made you sit on the steps.
I didn't kill your puppy.
I did not make you miserable.
Oh, so this is therapy?
No. It's just...
makes me smile.
All right, I'm finding
a new place tomorrow.
Right, but not tonight.
[Pops cork]
Well, I figure you wanna shave
my eyebrows while I'm asleep.
I wouldn't wanna
deprive you of that last smile.
You're not going anywhere.
You're gonna sit on my couch,
and depress us both,
because you just can't admit
that it's over with your wife.
That's right.
I'm here on vacation.
Have you gotten a lawyer yet?
- That's--That's not...
- You even called one?
As long as you're here,
it's just a fight.
As soon as you get a place,
then it's a divorce.
Everything sucks.
Might as well find
something to smile about.
Reflexes are
marginally weaker.
The paralysis is getting worse?
Sometimes it takes a few treatments
for the plasmapheresis to work.
Why do these things
keep happening to me?
Dan's back.
Hey, baby, did you hear that?
Dan's here.
I don't want to see him.
I'll tell him
to come back later.
No.
Mommy, stay here, please.
Of course.
...
Is she okay?
She's sleeping.
I'm sure she's exhausted.
Mood swings are common
with the anti-rejection meds.
No. She's had mood swings.
This isn't it. This is--
She's given up.
I know you think I'm--
This isn't what I wanted.
She's always fought with me.
Ever since she was a baby,
she was so damn stubborn.
But I never
wanted her like this.
I just wanted her safe.
Doctor! Doctor!
[Beeping]
She can't breathe!
She couldn't get
a whole sentence out.
She's using accessory muscles.
- 02 sat's down to 90. Lungs clear?
- Yeah.
Does your tongue feel
swollen? Is it itchy?
No hives.
It's not an allergy.
Lips are cyanotic.
We got to intubate.
What are you doing?
Pushing lorazepam.
She's not getting enough oxygen.
We've got to assist her breathing.
What was that?
Was that a reaction
to the treatment?
It's the paralysis.
It's reaching her lungs.
Chase:
Melinda's dying.
We're all dying.
How fast?
Too fast for Guillain-Barre.
Cuddy wants to get her an MRI
to rule out a spinal lesion.
Cuddy?
What's shedoing on this?
The family lost confidence in us.
I don't blame them.
I'll be right in.
It's like she got poisoned
with a nerve agent.
Glue inhalation. Would explain
why she hasn't admitted it.
Tox screen was clear for pot.
Middle-class heart transplant
patient's gonna huff glue?
Pesticides?
Cameron:
This time of year,
they're not spraying.
This girl's tough.
She gets what she wants.
She's deprived of human contact,
she gets herself a backdoor man.
Or in her case, a side window boy.
What else has she been deprived of?
She's on a special diet
because of her allergies.
The boyfriend brings the hot beef.
He also brings a side dish: botulism.
This is paralysis is
ascending, remember?
Not if the heart problem's
really a paralytic problem.
Why would she admit the sex
and not the food?
She didn't admit anything.
He admitted the sex, and
we didn't ask him about food.
Get me a rat.
- You have a rat.
- What?
I'm not gonna kill Steve.
Only way to confirm this...
inject the rat with her blood and wait
for it to get all botulistic on your ass.
In the meantime,
I'm going downstairs to browbeat
a scared, dying teenage girl until she...
breaks down like
a scared, dying teenage girl.
- You're up early.
- Cuddy needed a consult.
We're checking for
spinal lesions from leukemia.
Yeah, I know.
Fits perfectly.
Unless this is the patient with
the anaphylaxis, the heart failure,
and the paralysis, in which case,
you're wasting your time.
We wanted a second opinion.
Second? We must have
given you at least eight.
Okay, well here's nine.
Botulism.
Listen to me.
Have you eaten anything abnormal?
- Any canned foods?
- No.
You sure? Lying to your parents is
usually the right thing to do, but
there is an impending death exception.
Don't talk to her like that.
You're right. She never lies.
I was being rude.
When your boyfriend
snuck in on Friday night--
surprise--
perhaps he got you some
sexy little treats, huh?
Some honey or some edible underwear,
some massage oils. Come on, anything.
[Gags]
We didn't--
Yeah, yeah,
we know about the sex.
Turns out that Danny's
little Danny is full of penicillin.
That's what caused
your anaphylactic shock.
You didn't tell us that's what--
It was--
He took clindamycin.
What I use.
He said he was on penicillin.
I saw the bottle.
It's a non-penicillin antibiotic.
If the antibiotics didn't
cause the anaphylaxis...
It's still on the table.
Everything is connected.
What did we discuss?
What was the differential?
Cameron said...
When Dan came to your house that night,
did he go through any tall grass?
Climbed a fence.
What are you doing?
Your daughter had
two visitors on Friday night.
One of them is still in the room.
She has tick paralysis.
Dan tracked a tick onto his jeans,
which wouldn't be a problem.
But being a teenager,
Dan couldn't keep
his tick in his pants.
Foreman:
We already checked her.
Now I'm checking her.
Tick bites don't ordinarily
cause anaphylactic shock.
This girl's allergies
are not ordinary.
House, get out of here.
We have to re-intubate her,
get her into the MRI.
The time course is perfect.
The bite itself sets off
an allergic reaction.
Venom takes four days to kick in,
heart's vulnerable, hits that first,
and a day later sets off
the ascending paralysis.
Except that ticks
aren't usually invisible.
They are until you find them.
Oh no, that's dandruff.
That wasn't nearly
as dramatic as I'd hoped.
Just means the next time
it'll be even better.
[Monitors start beeping]
What's happening?
That's the tick venom ascending.
That or you stressed her
into heart failure. BP's dropping.
- Heart rate, 47.
- I'm administering atropine.
She's going to need
a transvenous pacing wire.
Okay, magical tick hunt is over.
Only real doctor stuff now.
This is just gonna get worse.
Ticks produce more toxins
the longer they feed.
She's gonna be dead in an hour
even if you pump her heartfull of jet fuel,
unless you let me find the tick.
Could he be right?
The only thing I know for sure is
that your daughter's heart won't last
another 20 minutes without treatment.
Okay, I just need
one final instruction.
When I find the tick on the autopsy,
do you want to know?
I'm thinking not.
Probably make the coping easier.
Stop talking to them!
Page Borsisky in cardiology.
Get her team down here stat.
Get them out of here.
Get House out of here, too.
Dr. Wilson, I could use your help.
Well, I don't know
if the dopamine's enough.
She may need
inamrinone lactate.
Why? What's that?
She doesn't--
She might need stronger pressors.
They don't have any in radiology.
Inamrinone can cause
arrhythmia and thrombocytopenia.
Not inamrinone could cause death.
Death's worse.
We have to get her up to the ICU.
Sorry.
Little crowded here.
House, get out of the elevator.
You're welcome
to wait for the next one.
You got her?
Got her.
[Stops the elevator]
[Alarm goes off]
Well, as long as we're stuck here,
this might be a good time
to look for that tick.
Turn the elevator back on.
Just be a minute, honey.
[Beeping]
[Chokes]
Atropine's wearing off.
- So inject her again.
- That's just temporary.
Temporary's fine.
We're not hanging wallpaper.
We've got to get her upstairs
and put her on norepinephrine.
It wasn't penicillin.
You still think
the symptoms are unconnected?
We've got to take care
of her heart before--
You wake up in the morning,
your paint's peeling,
your curtains are gone,
and the water's boiling.
Which problem do you deal with first?
- House--
- None of them!
The building's on fire!
We treat her symptoms, she dies.
We find the cause, she lives.
That tick is an I.V. drip of poison.
We unhook it, she'll be fine.
It's my last atropine.
Last us about three minutes.
Let's get her gown up.
[Starts breathing]
Her heart rate falls below 35,
we're getting her to the ICU.
I'm not gonna let her die
in this elevator.
[Elevator dings]
Where are they?
Get maintenance
up here right away.
Ear canal's clean.
Left foot's clean.
If it's not here,
we've only got--
[Beeping]
- Heart rate's 46.
- It's here.
Looks like a mole or a freckle.
Something we missed.
Check the armpits.
[Wheezes]
Dr. Foreman's an excellent doctor.
He'll be able to handle it.
Yeah? You know that
from experience?
You lose a lot of patients
on elevators?
The maintenance guy said
it didn't just stop on its own, that
they hit the emergency stop button.
Well, I'm sure
he must be mistaken.
- Perineum.
- We checked it.
- If we get her upstairs--
- Maxilla.
- Checked.
Down to 38.
We don't have a lot of time.
Eyebrows, eardrums,
pubic hair.
Checked, checked, checked.
We checked everywhere!
It's not--
[beeping]
35. We got to get her to the ICU.
We haven't found the tick yet.
We already kidnapped her!
You want to add murder?
We've looked over every inch of skin on her body, House!
It's over.
Hey, is that the first time
you had sex?
With all the other stuff
going on down there,
she might not have realized.
Oh...
[Elevator dings]
You sick, miserable--
- What are you doing?
- Oh, my God!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
See? Told you it'd be
even more dramatic.
Push norepinephrine.
Get her heart back to normal.
She'll be completely cured by tomorrow.
Foreman, let's get her into the ICU.
Inamrinone was a stupid idea,
unless you wanted me
to get that girl on the elevator.
Oh, I wouldn't do that.
Wouldn't respect you
if you did.
Wow. Looks like somebody filed
halfway through your cane
while you were sleeping.
Reflexes back to normal.
Heart's looking good, too.
I'll send in the nurse,
we'll get you transferred out of ICU,
you'll be discharged in the morning.
Thank God.
I just want to get home.
And back to school
on Monday.
I'm-I'm not ready.
You're ready.
I'm sick, Mom.
You're not sick.
You're gonna go to class,
and you're gonna see your friends
and your boyfriend.
[James Stewart on TV]
What's this doohickey?
Barbara Bel Geddes:
It's a brassiere.
Bel Geddes:
You know about those things.
You're a big boy now.
James:
Well, I've never across one like that.
Bel Geddes:
It's brand new. Revolutionary uplift.
I've explained to you--
Stewart:
I know, I know. I have acrophobia,
which gives me vertigo. And I get dizzy.
Stewart:
What a moment to find out I had it.
Bel Geddes:
You've got it, and there's no losing it.
And there's no one to blame. So why quit?
Stewart:
You mean, and sit behind a desk,
chair-borne?
Bel Geddes:
Where you belong.
Stewart:
What about my acrophobia?
I called a divorce lawyer today.
Does that mean you're leaving?
At some point.
You might not
wanna sit exactly there.