No, No, No, No.
Lilith is trying
to break the 66 seals
To free, Lucifer from hell.
Lucifer will bring
the apocalypse.
#I was caught in the middle
of a railroad track#
#Thunder#
#I looked 'round, and I knew
there was no turnin' back#
#Thunder#
#My mind raced, and I thought,
"what could I do?"#
You're possessing
some poor bastard?
This is... a vessel.
I had to give my consent
to invite him in.
#You've been thunderstruck#
#I was shakin' at the knees#
Chuck Shurley?
We have a life. You've been
using it to write your books.
Dean, let him go.
This man is to be protected.
- Why?
- He's a prophet of the lord.
- Who are you?
- I'm Zachariah. I'm, Castiel's superior.
- And how am I gonna ice Lilith?
- You're not.
Lilith's going to break
the final seal.
You don't want to stop it,
do you?
You are chosen.
You will stop it.
Just... not Lilith
or the apocalypse, that's all.
#Thunderstruck#
#Ah ah ah ah ah#
#You've been thunderstruck#
I'm sorry.
- Sammy, let's go.
- Dean...
He's coming.
Come on.
Dean!
What the devil
is your name?
Sa... s-s...
Uh... s... s...
yo-Sam-ity, Sam!
Yo-Sam-ity, Sam?
Hmm, let's see.
Sam...
Ah, here it is.
What the hell?
I don't know.
Folks, quick word
from the flight deck.
We're just passing over
Ilchester, then Ellicott city,
on our initial descent
into Baltimore...
Ilchester? Weren't we just there?
So if you'd like
to stretch your legs...
now would be a good time to.
Holy crap!
Aaaah!
And governor, O'malley urged calm,
saying it's very unlikely
an abandoned convent
would be a target
for terrorists,
- either foreign or homegrown.
- Change the station.
Hurricane Kinley,
unexpectedly slamming into
the Galveston area...
...announced a successful test
of the, North Korean nuclear...
- ...baffled...
- ...swine flu...
Dean look...
Don't. Don't say anything.
It's okay.
We just got to
keep our heads down
And hash this out. All right?
Yeah, okay.
All right, well, first things first.
How did we end up
on "soul plane"?
Angels, maybe?
I mean, you know,
beaming us out of harm's way?
Well, whatever.
It's the least of our worries.
We need to find, Cass.
Oh!
Geez! Ow!
Sam.
- Yeah!
- Hey, Chuck.
So... you're okay?
Well, my head hurts.
No, I mean... I mean,
my... My last vision.
You went, like,
full-On, Vader.
Your body temperature was 150.
Your heart rate was 200.
Your eyes were black.
Your eyes went black?
I didn't know.
Where's, Cass?
He's dead.
Or gone.
The, archangel smote the crap out of him.
- I'm sorry.
- You're sure?
I mean, maybe he just vanished
into the light or something.
Oh, no. He, like, exploded.
Like a water balloon
of, chunky soup.
You got a...
Uh... right here?
Uh, the...
Oh.
Oh, god.
Is that a molar?
Do I have a molar in my hair?
This has been
a really stressful day.
Cass, you stupid bastard.
Stupid? He was trying to help us.
Yeah, exactly.
- So, what now?
- I don't know.
Oh, crap.
What?
I can feel them.
Thought we'd find you here.
Playtime's over, Dean.
Time to come with us.
You just keep
your distance, ass-hat.
You're upset.
Yeah. A little.
You sons of bitches
jump-started judgment day!
Maybe we let it happen.
We didn't start anything.
Right, Sammy?
You had a chance to stop
your brother, and you couldn't.
So let's not quibble
over who started what.
Let's just say it was
all our faults and move on.
'Cause like it or not...
...it's apocalypse now.
And we're back
on the same team again.
Is that so?
You want to kill the devil.
We want you to kill the devil.
It's... Synergy.
And I'm just
supposed to trust you?
Cram it with walnuts, ugly.
This isn't a game, son.
Lucifer is powerful
in ways that defy description.
We need to strike now,
hard and fast.
Before he finds his vessel.
His vessel?
Lucifer needs a meat suit?
He is an angel.
Them's the rules.
And when he touches down,
We're talking four horsemen,
red oceans, fiery skies...
The greatest hits.
You can stop him, Dean.
But you need our help.
You listen to me,
you two-faced douche...
After what you did, I don't want
jack squat from you!
You listen to me, boy!
You think you can rebel against us?
As, Lucifer did?
You're bleeding.
Oh, yeah.
A little insurance policy
in case you dicks showed up.
No!
Learned that from my friend
Cass, you son of a bitch.
This sucks ass.
- Hey.
Uh... Here.
Hex bags. No way the angels
will find us with those.
Demons, either, for that matter.
- Where'd you get it?
- I made it.
How?
I... I learned it from, Ruby.
Speaking of...
How you doing?
Are you jonesing for another hit
of, bitch blood or what?
I... It's weird.
Uh, tell you the truth, I'm fine.
No shakes, no fever.
It's like whoever... put me on that plane
cleaned me right up.
Supernatural methadone.
Yeah, I guess.
- Dean...
- Sam.
It's okay. You don't
have to say anything.
Well, that's good.
Because, what can I even say?
"I'm sorry"?
"I screwed up"?
Doesn't really do it justice, you know?
Look, there's nothing
I can do or say,
that will ever make this right...
So why do you keep
bringing it up?!
Look, all I'm saying is,
Why do we have to put this
under a microscope?
We made a mess.
We clean it up. That's it.
All right, so,
say this is just any other hunt.
You know, what do we do first?
We'd, uh, figure out
where the thing is.
All right.
So we just got to find...
The devil.
All right, keep it together.
Keep it together, man.
Aaah!
It's you, Nick.
You're special.
You're chosen.
"And then, Sam touched".
No.
"...Caressed, Dean's clavicle.
"'This is wrong'. Said, Dean.
"'then I don't want to be right,'
replied, Sam. In a husky voice."
Oh... My god.
You.
- You're...
- Carver Edlund, yeah. Hi, Becky.
You got my letters.
And my marzipan.
Yeah, yeah.
Um... yummy.
But, uh...
I am your number-one fan.
You know, I'm samlicker81.
I'm sorry. You're... You're what?
Web-mistress, at more than brothers. Net?
Oh, yeah. No, yeah.
You're my... number one fan.
That's why I contacted you.
You're the only one
who will believe me.
Are you all right?
No.
I'm being watched.
Okay, not now. At least, I don't think so.
But I don't have much time.
I need your help.
You need my help?
That's right.
I need you to get a message,
to, Sam and Dean.
Okay.
Look, Mr. Edlund...
Yes, I'm a fan, but I really
don't appreciate being mocked.
I know that "Supernaturals"
just a book, okay?
I know the difference
between fantasy and reality.
Becky, it's all real.
I knew it!
But then how would
you explain an earthquake,
A hurricane, and multiple tornadoes.
All at the same time,
all around the globe?
Two words. Carbon emissions.
Yeah, right, wavy gravy.
You okay, lady?
Sam... is it really you?
And you're so firm.
Do I know you?
No. But I know you.
You're, Sam Winchester.
And you're...
...not what I pictured.
I'm, Becky.
I read all about you guys.
And I've even written a few...
Anyway...
Mr. Edlund told me where you were.
Chuck?
He's got a message,
but he's being watched.
Angels.
Nice change-up to the mythology,
by the way.
The demon stuff
was getting kind of old.
Right. Just, um...
what's the message?
He had a vision.
"The, Michael sword is on earth.
The angels lost it."
The, Michael sword?
Becky, does he know where it is?
In a castle, on a hill made of 42 dogs.
42 dogs?
Are... you sure
you got that right?
It doesn't make sense,
but that's what he said.
I memorized every word...
For you.
Um...
Becky, uh, can you...
quit touching me?
No.
Hey, Bobby.
Good to see you boys
all in one piece.
You weren't followed, were you?
You mean by angels,
demons, or Sam's new super-fan?
You heard.
I heard, romeo.
So... sword of, Michael, huh?
You think we're talking
about the actual sword
From the actual, archangel?
You better friggin' hope so.
That's, Michael.
Toughest sum-bitch they got.
You kidding me? Tough?
That guy looks like, Cate Blanchett.
Well, I wouldn't want to meet him in a dark
alley, believe me.
He commands the heavenly host.
During the last
big dust-up upstairs,
He's the one who booted,
Lucifer's ass to the basement.
Did it with that sword.
So if we can find it...
We can kick the devil's ass
all over again.
All right. So, where do we start?
Divvy up, and start reading...
Try and make sense
of, Chuck's nonsense.
Kid?
You all right?
No, actually.
Bobby, this is all my fault.
I'm sorry.
Sam...
Lilith did not break
the final seal.
Lilith was the final seal.
Sam, stop it.
I killed her,
and I set, Lucifer free.
You what?!
You guys warned me
about, Ruby.
The demon blood,
but I didn't listen.
I brought this on.
You're damn right
you didn't listen.
You were reckless and selfish
and arrogant.
I'm sorry.
Oh, yeah?
You're sorry you started, Armageddon?
This kind of thing
don't get forgiven, boy.
If, by some miracle,
we pull this off...
I want you to lose my number.
You understand me?
There's an old church nearby.
Maybe I'll go read
some of the lore books there.
Yeah.
You do that.
I never would have guessed
that your daddy was right.
About what?
About your brother.
What, John said...
You save, Sam or kill him.
Maybe...
Maybe what?
Maybe we shouldn't have tried
so hard to save him.
Bobby.
He ended the world, Dean.
And you and I weren't strong
enough to stop him proper.
That's on us. I'm just saying.
Your dad was right.
Dad.
It's got to be in here somewhere.
What the hell
are you talking about?
Here.
I don't believe it.
What the hell is it?
It's a card for my dad's lockup
in upstate New York.
Read it.
"Castle storage, 42 rover hill."
Castle on a hill of 42 dogs.
So you think your dad had the,
Michael sword all this time?
I don't know. I'm not sure what else,
Chuck could have meant.
Yeah.
Okay.
It's good enough for me.
I always knew you were
a big, dumb, slow,
dim pain in the ass, Dean.
But I never dreamt
you were so V.I.P.
I mean, you're gonna ice the devil?
You?
If I'd have known that,
I'd have ripped your pretty,
pretty face off ages ago.
Ruby.
Try again. Go back further.
Meg?
Hi.
These are the days
of miracle and wonder, Dean.
Our father's among us.
You know, we're all dreaming again
For the first time
since we were human?
It's heaven on earth.
Or hell.
We really owe your brother
a fruit basket.
My god, you like the sound
of your own voice.
But you, on the other hand,
You're the only bump in the road.
So every demon...
Every single one...
Is just dying for a piece of you.
Get in line.
Oh, I'm in the front
of the line, baby.
Let's ride.
What is that? Peanut butter?
You know, your surrogate
daddy's still awake.
Screaming in there.
And I want him to know how it feels
Slicing the life out of you.
Bobby...
Bobby!
No!
Now!
Aaaah!
No!
Heya, Sammy.
You miss me? 'Cause I sure missed you.
Meg?
It's not so easy without those
super-special demon powers,
Huh, Sammy?
Aaaaaaaaaah!
No!
N-No!
No, god, no!
Need some help here!
What happened?
He was stabbed.
Can we get a gurney?
Just wait here.
No, no, we... We can't
just leave him!
Just don't move.
I've got questions.
- Sammy, we got to go.
- No. no way, Dean.
The demons heard
where the sword is.
We got to get to it
before they do,
If we're not too late already.
Come on!
I see you told the demons
where the sword is.
Oh, thank god.
The angels are here.
And to think...
They could have grabbed it
any time they wanted.
It was right in front of them.
What do you mean?
We may have planted that
particular piece of prophecy
Inside, Chuck's skull,
but it happened to be true.
We did lose the, Michael sword.
We truly couldn't find it.
Until now. You've just
hand-delivered it to us.
We don't have anything.
It's you, chuckle-head.
You're the, Michael sword.
What, you thought you
could actually, kill, Lucifer?
You simpering wad of insecurity
and self-loathing?
No.
You're just a human, Dean.
And not much of one.
What do you mean,
I'm the sword?
You're, Michael's weapon.
Or, rather, his... receptacle.
I'm a vessel?
You're the vessel.
Michael's vessel.
How? Why... Why me?
Because you're chosen!
It's a great honor, Dean.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, life as an angel condom.
That's real fun.
I think I'll pass, thanks.
Joking. Always joking.
Well... no more jokes.
Bang.
God!
You son of a bitch!
Keep mouthing off, I'll
break more than his legs.
I am completely and utterly
through, screwing around.
The war has begun.
We don't have our general.
That's bad.
Now, Michael is going
to take his vessel,
and lead the final charge
against the adversary.
You understand me?
How many humans die
in the crossfire, huh?
A million? 5, 10?
Probably more.
If, Lucifer goes unchecked,
you know how many die?
All of them. He'll roast the planet alive.
There's a reason
you're telling me this.
Instead of just nabbing me.
You need my consent.
Michael needs my say-so
to ride around in my skin.
Unfortunately, yes.
Well, there's got to be another way.
There is no other way.
There must be a battle.
Michael must defeat the serpent.
It is written.
Yeah, maybe.
But, on the other hand...
Eat me.
The answer's, no.
Okay.
How about this?
Your friend Bobby...
We know he's gravely injured.
Uh, say yes, and we'll heal him.
Say no, he'll never walk again.
No.
Then how about
we heal you from...
Stage-4 stomach cancer?
No.
Then let's get really creative.
Uh, let's see how...
Sam does without his lungs.
Are we having fun yet?
You're going to say yes, Dean.
Just kill us.
Kill you?
Oh, no.
I'm just getting started.
How are you...
Alive?
That's a good question.
How did these two
end up on that airplane?
Another good question.
'Cause the, angels didn't do it.
I think we both know
the answer, don't we?
No.
That's not possible.
It scares you.
Well, it should.
Now, put these boys
back together and go.
I won't ask twice.
You two need to be more careful.
Yeah, I'm starting to get that.
Your frat brothers are
bigger dicks than I thought.
I don't mean the, angels.
Lucifer is circling his vessel.
And once he takes it,
Those hex bags won't be
enough to protect you.
What the hell was that?
An, enochian sigil.
It'll hide you from every angel in creation,
Including, Lucifer.
What, you just brand us with it?
No. I carved it, into your ribs.
Hey, Cass. Were you really dead?
Yes.
Then how are you back?
Nick.
You're dreaming, Nick.
But it doesn't mean this isn't real.
Sarah?
I'm not your wife, Nick.
I'm an, angel.
An, angel?
My name is, Lucifer.
Sure.
Naturally.
Um...
Could you do me
a favor there, Satan,
And remind me to quit drinking
before I go to bed?
I'm here because you're special, Nick.
There's very, very few people like you.
Is that so?
You're a vessel. A very powerful vessel.
Meaning what, exactly?
I need to take control
of your mind and your body.
To be honest...
It'll probably be unpleasant for you.
But it is necessary.
Okay, look...
If it's just the same to you,
I think I'd like to wake up now.
I told you. This is real.
Don't be afraid.
This is your choice.
You need to invite me in.
Even if this is real.
Which it's not,
but assuming it was...
Why the hell would I do
something like that?
You people misunderstand me.
You call me "Satan"
and "devil," but...
Do you know my crime?
I loved, god too much.
And for that, he betrayed me.
Punished me.
Just as he's punished you.
After all, how could, god stand idly by.
While that man, broke into your home,
and butchered your family in their beds?
There are only two rational answers, Nick.
Either he's sadistic...
Or he simply doesn't care.
You're angry.
You have every right to be angry.
I am angry, too.
That's why I want to find him...
Hold him accountable for his actions.
Just because he created us,
doesn't mean he can toy
with us, like play-things.
If I help you...
Can you bring back my family?
I'm sorry.
I can't.
But I can give you
the next best thing.
God did this to you, Nick.
And I can give you justice.
Peace.
How do I know
you're telling the truth?
Because, contrary to popular belief,
I don't lie.
I don't need to.
What I need...
Is you.
Nick, I need you, to say yes.
Then yes.
"unlikely to walk again"?!
Why, you snot-nosed
son of a bitch!
Wait till I get out of this bed!
I'll use my game leg
and kick your friggin' ass!
Yeah, you better run!
You believe that yahoo?
Screw him. You'll be fine.
So, let me ask the million-dollar question.
What do we do now?
Well...
We save as many as we can
for as long as we can, I guess.
It's bad.
Whoever wins, heaven
or hell, we're boned.
What if we win?
I'm serious.
I mean, screw the angels
and the demons,
and their crap apocalypse.
They want to fight a war,
they can find their own planet.
This one's ours, and I say
they get the hell off it.
We take 'em all on.
We kill the devil.
Hell, we even kill, Michael
if we have to.
But we do it our own damn selves.
And how are we supposed to
do all this, genius?
I got no idea.
But what I do have
is a G.E.D.
And a "give 'em hell" attitude,
and I'll figure it out.
You are nine kinds of crazy, boy.
It's been said.
Listen, you stay on the mend.
We'll see you in a bit.
Sam?
I was awake.
I know what I said back there.
I just want you
to know that...
That was the, demon talking.
I ain't cutting you out, boy.
Not ever.
Thanks, Bobby.
You're welcome.
I deserve a damn medal for this,
But... you're welcome.
You know, I was thinking, Dean...
Maybe we could
go after the colt.
Why? What difference
would that make?
Well, we could use it on, Lucifer.
I mean, you just said back there...
I just said a bunch of crap
for, Bobby's benefit.
I mean... I'll fight.
I'll fight till the last man,
but let's at least be honest.
I mean, we don't stand
a snowball's chance,
And you know that.
I mean, hell, you of
all people know that.
Dean...
Is there something
you want to say to me?
I tried, Sammy.
I mean, I really tried.
But I just can't keep pretending
that everything's all right.
Because it's not.
And it's never going to be.
You chose a demon
over your own brother,
And look what happened.
I would give anything... Anything
To take it all back.
I know you would.
And I know
how sorry you are. I do.
But, man...
You were the one
that I depended on the most.
And you let me down
in ways that I can't even...
I'm just...
I'm having a hard time
forgiving and forgetting here.
You know?
What can I do?
Honestly?
Nothing.
I just don't...
I don't think that we can
ever be what we were.
You know?
I just don't think that, I can trust you.
Sync by honeybunny
www.Addic7ed.Com
Edited by Scooby