Look, dad's gone now.
We have to carry out his legacy.
And that means hunting
down as many evil sons of
bitches as we possibly can.
- Lisa.
- Dean.
If you want to stick around
for a while,
You're welcome to stay.
I can't. I got a lot of work
to do, and it's not my life.
Bela talbot's her real name.
I procure unique items
for a select clientele.
A thief.
A great thief.
Sam, you want to break
Dean free of that demon deal,
You ain't gonna
find the answer in no book.
- Then where, Bobby?
- Kid, I wish I knew.
I've been busting my ass
trying to keep you alive, Dean,
And you act like
you couldn't care less.
I don't want you
to worry about me, Dean.
I want you
to worry about you.
I want you to give a crap
that you're dying.
Every damn demon,
they were all human once?
Every one I've ever met.
The answer is yes,
by the way -- The same
thing will happen to you.
There's no way of saving me
from the pit, is there?
No.
Oh. I'm sorry.
Sir?
Wake up.
Wake up! You hear me?
Wake up!
Sir, wake up!
Help!
I need some help in here!
* down around the corner
* half a mile from here
* you see them long trains
runnin' *
* and you watch them disappear
There you are.
What are you doing?
Having a drink.
It's 2:00 in the afternoon.
Drinking whiskey?
- I drink whiskey all the time.
- No, you don't.
What's the big deal?
You get sloppy in bars.
You hit on chicks all the time.
Why can't I?
It's kind of slim pickings
around here.
What's going on with you?
* she lost her home
and her family *
* and she won't be coming back
* without love
I tried, Dean.
To do what?
To save you.
Can I get a whiskey?
Double, neat.
- I'm serious, Dean.
- No, you're drunk.
I mean,
where you're going...
what you're gonna become.
I can't stop it.
I'm starting to think
maybe even ruby can't stop it.
But, really, the thing is,
no one can save you.
- What I've been telling you.
- No, that's not what I mean.
I mean, no one can
save you because you
don't want to be saved.
I mean, how can you care
so little about yourself?
What's wrong with you?
Hello?
Yes, this is
mr. Snyderson.
What?
Where?
So, what's
the diagnosis?
We've tested everything
we can think to test.
He seems
perfectly healthy.
Except that
he's comatose.
Mr. Snyderson,
you're his emergency contact.
Anything we should know?
Any illnesses?
No, he never gets sick.
I mean, he doesn't even
catch a cold.
Doctor, is there
anything you can do?
Look, I'm sorry,
But we don't know
what's causing it,
So we don't know
how to treat it.
He just...
went to sleep
and didn't wake up.
So, what was Bobby doing
in Pittsburgh?
I dunno, unless he's taking an extremely lame vacation
But he must've been working a job, right?
Well you'd think there must be
some sort of sign or something,
you know
Research
News clippings
A frigging pizza box or a beer can
How 'bout this?
Good old Bob, he always covered up his tracks
You make heads or tails of any of this?
"Silene capensis,"
Which, of course, means
absolutely nothing to me.
Here, obit
Dr. Walter gregg, 64,
university neurologist.
How'd he bite it?
Um, actually,
they don't know.
They say he just went to sleep
and didn't wake up.
That sound familiar
to you?
All right, um...
so, let's say Bobby was
looking into the doc's death,
- You know,hunting after something...
- that started hunting him.
Yeah.
All right, stay here.
See if you can make
heads or tails of this.
What are you gonna do?
I'm gonna look into
the good doctor myself.
So, you're
dr. Gregg's lab assistant.
That's right.
Well, his death must have
come as a shock to you.
Yeah, it did.
But, still,
go in your sleep, peaceful --
It's what you wish for,
right?
Yeah, right.
Dr. Gregg, uh,
studied sleeping disorders?
Dreams?
I don't understand.
I went over all of this
with the other detective.
You already spoke
to another detective?
Yes, a very nice older man
with a beard.
Well, I'd love to hear it again,
if you don't mind.
Thing is, I'm sort of busy.
Maybe we could do this later?
Sure. Yeah.
I'll just bring you down to
the station later this afternoon
And get your statement on tape,
do it all official-Like.
Look, okay, I didn't know about
dr. Gregg's experiments --
Not until I was
cleaning out his files.
His experiments -- The ones
he was conducting on sleeping?
No one knew, okay?
Not the university, not anybody.
I already spoke
with a lawyer,
And he told me that I can't
be held liable for anything.
T1maybe you couldn't,
But that was before
the new evidence came to light.
- New evidence?
- Mm-Hmm.
What n evidence?
I'm not at liberty
to say.
Look,
I'm just a grad student.
This was a gig
to cover tuition.
Maybe so, but, still,
this -- This --
This could go
on your permanent record.
Unless you hand over
the doctor's research to me --
All of it.
Look, I don't know
what the r.A. Said,
But, uh,
I was growing ferns.
Take it easy, phish.
That's not why I'm here.
Really?
Oh, thank god.
Okay.
I want to talk to you
about dr. Gregg's sleep study.
Yeah. Dr. Gregg
just died, right?
You were one of
his test subjects, right?
Yeah.
Ss you're on duty
or whatever.
I guess
I can make an exception.
Now, dr. Gregg
was testing treatments
For a charcot-Wilbrand
syndrome,
Which means...
um, I, uh,
I can't dream.
I had this bike accident
when I was a kid,
And I banged my head
pretty good,
And I haven't
had a dream since.
Till the study...
uh, sort of.
What'd the doc give you?
It's this yellow tea.
It smelled awful --
Tasted worse.
What did it do?
Just passed right out.
And I had the most vivid,
super-Intense dream.
Like a bad acid trip,
you know?
Totally.
I mean, no.
That was it.
I dropped out of his study
right after that.
I didn't...like it.
To tell you the truth...
it kind of scared me.
How is he?
No change.
What you got?
Well, considering
what you told me about
the doc's experiments,
Bobby's wall is
starting to make a hell
of a lot more sense.
How so?
This plant,
silene capensis,
Also known as
african dream root,
It's been used by shamen
and medicine men for centuries.
Let me guess -- They dose up,
bust out the didgeridoos,
And start kicking around
the hacky.
Not quite.
If you believe the legends,
it's used for dream-Walking.
I mean, entering
another person's dreams,
Poking around
in their heads.
- I take it we believe the legends.
- When don't we?
But dream-Walking is just
the tip of the iceberg.
- What do you mean?
- I mean, this dream root is some serious mojo.
You take enough of it,
with enough practice,
You can become
a regular freddy krueger.
You can control anything.
You could
turn bad dreams good.
turn good dreams bad.
And killing people
in their sleep.
For example.
So, let's say this doc
Was testing the stuff on
his patients tim leary-Style.
Somebody
gets pissed at him,
Decides to give him
a little dream visit,
He goes nighty-Night.
But what about Bobby?
I mean, if the killer
came after him,
How come
he's still alive?
I don't know.
Help me!
Somebody help me!
Help me!!
So, how do we find
our homicidal little sandman?
It could be anyone.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Anyone who knew the doctor,
had access to his dream shrooms.
Maybe one of his test subjects
or something?
Possible, but his research
is pretty sketchy.
I mean, we don't know
how many subjects he had
or who all of them were.
What?
In any other case,we'd be calling Bobby And asking him for help right now.
Know what?
You're right.
- What?
- Let's go talk to him.
Sure. I think we might
find the conversation
a bit one-Sided.
Not if we're tripping
on some dream root.
- What?
- You heard me.
You want to go dream-Walking
inside Bobby's head?
Yeah, why not?
Maybe we could help.
We have no idea what's
crawling around in there.
- How bad could it be?
- Bad.
Dude, it's Bobby.
Yeah, you're right.
One problem, though.We're fresh out of african dream root.
Unless you know someone
who can score some...
- Crap.
- What?
Bela.
Bela?
Crap.
You're actually suggesting
we ask her for a favor?
I'm feeling dirty just
thinking about it, but yeah.
Hey, Sam.
Bela.
I didn't think there was
a chance in hell you'd show up.
Well,
I'm full of surprises.
Though, truthfully,
you want to know why I'm here?
Okay.
Because of you.
Uh, what are you doing?
I can't stop
thinking about you.
What?
Are you sure?
Sam.
Sam. Oh.
Sam, wake up!
Dude, you were out.
And making
some serious happy noises.
Who were you
dreaming about?
- What?
- No one. Nothing.
Come on. You can tell me.
Angelina jolie?
No.
- Brad pitt?
- No!
No.
Dude, it doesn't matter.
- Whatever.
I called Bela.
Bela? Yeah?
W-What'd she, you know,
say?
She's...gonna...help us?
Shockingly, no, which puts us
back to square one.
I've been trying to decipher
the doctor's notes.
Unfortunately, he has
worse handwriting than you do.
You gonna come help me
with this stuff?
Yeah, yeah.
Just give me a sec.
Bela,
as I live and breathe.
You called me,
remember?
I remember
you turning me down.
Well, I'm just
full of surprises.
Hey, Bela.
What's going on?
I brought you
your african dream root.
Nasty stuff.
And not easy to come by.
Why the sudden
change of heart?
What, I can't do
you a little favor
every now and again?
No, you're not.
Now, come on. I want to
know what the strings are
before you attach 'em.
You said this was
for Bobby singer, right?
Well, I'm doing it for him,
not you.
Bobby?
Why?
He saved my life once...
in flagstaff.
I screwed up, and he saved me,
okay? Are you satisfied?
Maybe.
So, when do we go on this little
magical mystery tour?
Oh, you're
not going anywhere.
I don't trust you enough
to let you in my car,
Much less Bobby's head.
No offense.
None taken.
It's 2:00 a.M.
Where am I supposed to go?
Get a room.
Oh, they got
the magic fingers,
A little "casa erotica"
on pay-Per-View.
You'll love it.
You...
nice to -- S-Seeing you...
...Bela.
Well,
shall we dim t lights
And sync up "wizard of oz"
and "dark side of the moon"?
Why?
What did you do
during college?
Wait, wait, wait.
Whew.
Can't forget this.
Here.
What the hell is that?
Bobby's hair.
We have to drink
Bobby's hair?
That's how you control
whose dream you're entering.
You got to drink
some of their, uh...
some of their body.
Well, guess
the hair of the dog's
Better than
other parts of the body.
- Bottoms up.
- Yeah.
Feel anything?
No.
You feel anything?
Maybe we got
some bad schwag.
Hey, when did it
start raining?
When did it start raining
upside down?
Okay, I don't know
what's weirder --
The fact
that we're in Bobby's head
Or that he's dreaming
of better homes and gardens.
Wait.
Wait a second.
Imagine the place
without the paint job,
More cluttered, dusty,
books all over the place.
It's Bobby's house.
Yeah.
Bobby?
Dean.
I'm gonna go
look outside.
No, no, no.
Stay close.
Dude, I'll be fine.
Just look around in here.
Look,
we got to find him.
Don't do anything stupid.
Dean!
Bobby?
Bobby?!
Who's out there?
Bobby, you in there?
Dean?
Yeah, it's me.
Open up.
Hey.
How the hell
did you find me?
Sam and I got our hands on
some of that dream-Root stuff.
Drearoot? What?
Dr. Gregg --
The experiments?
What the hell
are you talking about?
Hurry.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.What's going on?
- She's coming.
Okay, you know
this is a dream, don't you?
W-Whate you crazy?
It's a dream, Bobby.
None of this is real.
Does that look made up?
No.
Bobby, who is that?
She's...
she's my wife.
Why, Bobby?
Why did you do this
to me?
I'd have rather died myself
than hurt you.
But you did hurt me.
You shoved that knife
into me...
again and again.
You watched me bleed...
watched me die.
Bobby, she's not real.
How could you?
You were possessed,
baby.
You were rabid.
And I didn't know
what I know now.
I didn't know
how to save you.
You're lying.
You wanted me dead.
If you'd loved me,
you would have found a way!!
- I'm sorry.
- Come on.
- Who are you?
You don't belong here.
You're one to talk.
You're in my friend's head.
Well, you got a poor choice
in friends.
This is self-Defense.
He came after me.
H-He wanted to hurt me.
That may be
because you're a killer.
You should be nicer
to me.
In here,
you're just an insect.
I'm a god.
I'm telling you -- All of it,
your house, your wife --
It's a nightmare.
I killed her.
Boby
This is a dream and you can wake up.
Hell,
you can do anything.
Just leave me alone.
Let her kill me already.
Look at me.
You got to
snap out of this now.
snap out of this now!
You're not gonna die.
I'm not gonna let you die.
I'm not gonna let nnu die.
You're like a father to me.
You've got to believe me.Please!
I'm dreaming?
Yes!
Now, take control of it!
I don't believe it.
Believe it.
Now,
would you please wake up?
Sweet dreams.
Hey, Bobby...
that, uh, that stuff --
All that stuff with your wife...
...that actually happen?
Everybody got into hunting
somehow.
I'm sorry.
Don't be sorry.
If it weren't for you,
I'd still be lost in there...
or dead.
Thank you.
So, uh, stoner boy
wasn't in his dorm.
My guess is
he's long gone by now.
He ain't
much of a stoner.
- No?
- No.
His name's jeremy frost --
Full-On genius -- 160 I.Q.
Which is saying something,
Considering his dad took
a baseball bat to his head.
Here's
father of the year.
He died
before jeremy was 10.
Looks like
a real sweetheart.
Injury gave him
charcot-Wilbrand.
He hasn't dreamt since.
Till he started
dosing the dream drug.
Yep.
yep.
How did he know how to
dig up your worst nightmare
and throw it at you?
Hey, he was rooting around
in my skull.
God knows
what he saw in there.
Yeah, how'd he get in there
in the first place?
Isn't he supposed to
have some of your hair,
your dna, or something?
- Yeah.
Before I knew it was him,
he offered me a beer.
I drank it.
Dumbest friggin' thing.
Oh, I don't know.
It wasn't that dumb.
Dean, you didn't.
I was thirsty.
That's great. Now he can
come after either one of you.
Well, now we just have to
find him first.
We better work fast...
and coffee up.
'Cause the one thing
we cannot do is fall asleep.
Two days later.
I mean, this jeremy guy's
not a friggin' ghost.
Where the hell
could he be?
Dean, you sure
you don't want me to drive?
You -- You seem
a little...caffeinated.
Well, thanks for
the news flash, edison!
Jeez.
Tell me
you got something!
- The strip club was a bust, huh?
- Yeah.
That was our last lead.
What the hell, Bobby?!
Don't yell at me, boy.
- I'm working my ass off here.
- Sorry. I'm sorry.
I'm just --
I'm -- I'm tired.
Well, who ain't?
What's Bela got?
What do you got, Bela?
Sorry.
Sometimes the spirit world's
in a chatty mood,
And sometimes it isn't.
- She's got nothing.
- Great!
Well, I'm just gonna go
blow my brains out now!
Gosh!
Let me ask you something.
What are you doing
helping us?
Bobby, I'm surprised
you don't remember.
Flagstaff?
Oh.
Yeah.
Right.
Flagstaff.
All right, that's it.
I'm done.
What are you doing?
Taking myself
a long-Overdue nap.
What? Dean,
jeremy can come after you.
That's the idea.
Excuse me?
Co on, man. We can't find him,
so let him come to me.
On his own turf --
Where he's basically a god?
I can handle it.
Not alone you can't.
Ow!
What are you doing?
Coming in with you.
- No, you're not.
- Why not?
At least then,
it'll be two against one.
'Cause I don't want you
digging around in my head.
Too bad.
Dean.
For the love of god.
What are we
still doing here?
I have no idea.
There's someone
out there.
* stars shining bright
above you *
* night breezes
seem to whisper "I love you" *
Hey.
You gonna sit down?
Come on.
We only have an hour
Before we have to pick ben up
from baseball.
* say nighty-Night and kiss me
I've never had this dream
before.
* just hold me tight
and tell me you'll miss me *
Stop looking at me
like that.
Sorry.
Dean.
I love you.
Where'd she go?
Dean.
Okay.
Dean?
Jeremy?
Hey, Dean.
Well, aren't you
a handsome son of a gun.
We need to talk.
I get it. I get it.
I'm my own
worst nightmare.
That it? Huh?
Like the "superman iii"
junkyard scene --
A little mano y mano
with myself?
Joke all you want,
smartass.
But you can't lie to me.
I know the truth.
I know how dead you are
inside...
how worthless
you feel.
I know how
you look into a mirror...
and hate what you see.
Sorry, pal.
It's not gonna work.
You're not real.
Sure I am.
I'm you.
I don't think so.
'Cause, see,
this is my siesta...
not yours.
All I got to do is snap
my fingers, and you go bye-Bye.
I'm not going anywhere.
Neither are you.
Like I said...
we need to talk.
Dean.
Hey.
Wake up.
Boy, you just don't know
When to leave well enough
alone, do you?
You're a psycho.
- You're wrong.
- Yeah?
Tell that to dr. Gregg.
The doc?
No, no, the doc's the one
who got me hooked on this stuff,
And then he took it away.
But I needed it,
And he wouldn't
let me have it.
So you killed him.
I can dream again.
You know what that's like --
Not to be able to dream?
Y-You never rest --
Not really.
I-It's like being awake
for 15 years.
And let me guess --
That makes you go crazy.
I just want
to be left alone.
I just want to dream.
Sorry.
Can't do that.
That's the wrong answer.
I'm getting better and better
at this --
Stronger and stronger
all the time.
But you
and your brother...
you're not waking up...
not this time.
I'm not gonna let you.
I mean,
you're going to hell,
And you won't lift a finger
to stop it.
Talk about low self-Esteem.
Then, again, I guess
it's not much of a life
worth saving, now, is it?
Come on, Dean.
Come on. Wake up.
I mean after all you got nothing outside the Sam.
You are nothing.
You're as mindless and obedient
as an attack dog.
- That's not true.
- No?
What are the things
that you want?
that you dream?
I mean, your car --
That's dad's.
Your favorite
leather jacket -- Dad's.
Your music -- Dad's.
Do you even have
an original thought?
No.
No, all there is
is "watch out for Sammy.
Look after
your little brother, boy."
You can still hear your dad's
voice in your head, can't you?
Clear as a bell.
Just shut up.
I mean, think about it.
All he ever d
was train you...
boss you around.
But Sam...
Sam, he doted on.
Sam, he loved.
I mean it.
I'm getting angry.
Dad knew
who you really were --
A good soldier
and nothing else.
Daddy's
blunt little instrument.
Your own father didn't care
whether you lived or died.
- Why should you?
- You son of a bitch!
My father
was an obsessed bastard!
All that crap he dumped on me
about protecting Sam --
That was his crap!
He's thalone who couldn
protect his family!
He's the one
who let mom die!
Who wasn't there for Sam!
I always was!
It wasn't fair!
I didn't deserve
what he put on me!
And I don't deserve
to go to hell!
You can't escape me, Dean.
You're gonna die.
And this -- This is
what you're gonna become.
You can't stop me.
There's nothing
I can't do in here.
Because of
the dream root.
That's right.
Yeah? Well,
you're forgetting something.
What's tha
I took the dream root,
too.
Jeremy?!
Jeremy!
No.
Dad?
You answer me
when I'm talking to you, boy!
You did a little dream-Weaving
of your own in there, huh?
Yeah, uh, I just
sort of concentrated,
And it happened,
you know?
Didn't have anything
to do with...
you know,
your psychic stuff?
No.
I mean,
I don't think so.
Good.
Hey,
you guys seen Bela?
She's not in her room.
She's not answering her phone.
She must have taken off
or something.
Just like that?
That's a little weird.
Well, if you ask me what's
weird, it's why she helped
us in the first place.
I thought
you saved her life.
What the hell
are you talking about?
The thing flagstaff.
That thing in flagstaff
was an amulet.
I gave her a good deal.
That's all.
Well, then, why did --
You boys better check
your pockets.
??
No, no, no, no, no, no.
The colt.
Bela stole the colt.
Damn it, boys!
Pack your crap.
Why?
Where are we going?
We're gonna go
hunt the bitch down.
Hey, Sam,
I was wondering --
When you were in my head,
what did you see?
Uh, just jeremy.
He kept me separated from you.
Easier to beat my brains out
that way, I guess.
What about you?
You never said.
Nothing. I was looking for you
the whole time.
Sam...
yeah?
I've been doing
some thinking.
And...
well, the thing is...
...I don't want to die.
I don't want
to go to hell.
All right, yeah.
We'll find a way
to save you.
Okay, good.
You n't escape me, Dean.
You're gonna die.
And this -- This is
what you're gonna become.