and the second you find
out this ruby chick is a demon,
you go for the holy water.
you don't chat.no one was chatting,dean.
then why didn't you send her ass back to hell?
she told me she could help you,okay?
she knows what your weakness is.it's me.
think something's wrong
with my brother?no. demons lie.
last i checked,dean's still going to hell.
everything in its own time,sam.
you're gonna have to do things
that go against that gentle nature of yours.
on the bright side,i'll be there with you --
that little fallen angel on your shoulder.
that was just a terrible,terrible party.
but there was this one really beautiful woman there.
you should have gone home
with her.
i did.
i need a few minutes.
all right.
there's a bottle of '89 in the fridge.
oh,god.
what the...
paul!
what is it? it's my teeth.
janet?!
help me!
i couldn't help. i couldn't do anything to stop it.
i-i've talked to the police
and i've talked to the medical examiner
and no one can explain it.
that's why they put the call into us,mr. dutton.
but the cdc --that's disease control,right?
w-what do you think it's some kind of virus?
we're not ruling out anything yet.
mr. dutton,did janet have
any enemies? i'm sorry?
anyone that had a reason to hurt her?
what are you saying that somebody poisoned her?
i'm just saying we have to cover
every base here.
i mean,what kind of poison?
you think a person could havedone this?
would anyone want to?
what? no.
no,there's no one that could have...
mr. dutton?
uh,everyone loved janet.
okay.thank you very much.
i think we got everything we need.
we'll be out of your way now.
that dude seem a little evasive to you?
i don't know.
i was under a sink...pulling this out.
hex bag.
ohh,gross.
yeah.
bird bones,rabbit's teeth.
this cloth was probably cut
from something janet dutton owned.
so we're thinking witch?
uh,yeah.
and not some new-age wiccan water douser,either.
this is old-world black magic,dean,
i mean,warts and all.
i hate witches.
they're always spewing
their bodily fluids everywhere.
pretty much.it's creepy.
it's downright unsanitary.
yeah,well,someone
definitely had it out for janet dutton.
yeah,someone who snuck
into that house and planted the bag.
so,what are we thinking?
looking for some craggy old blair bitch in the woods?
no,it could be anyone --
a neighbor,coworker,man,woman.
they're human.they're like everyone else.
how are we gonna find them?
this wasn't random.
someone in janet dutton's
life had an ugly ax to grind.
we find the motive...
we find the murderer.yeah.
amanda?
hey,amanda!
oh,elizabeth,hi.
sorry,i've got,like,a thousand things on my mind.
are you okay,sweetie?
you didn't come to book club last night.
yeah,sorry.i was gonna call.
i just --i got busy,you know?
but i'm fine,really.i am. thanks.
this dinner was cooked for you,paul arthur dutton.
now you're going to eat it.
got it!
you okay?
what the hell is happening to me?
someone murdered your wife.
now they're trying to kill you.
that's impossible.
there's no way --
if we hadn't been following you,you'd be a doornail.
now,who wants you dead?
i --come on,think.
there's a woman.
okay,a woman.
an affair,a-a mistake.
she was unbalanced.
she was blackmailing me.
i put an end to it a week ago.
what's her name? wha--
what could she have to do with what
paul,what is her name?
that's a curve-ball.
yeah.
three per wrist vertical.
she wasn't fooling around.
that's a curveball.
yeah.
three per wrist --vertical.
she wasn't fooling around.
yeah,looks like she was
working some heavyweight evil here.
yep.
freaking witches!seriously,man! come on!
guess we know where
she got the rabbit's teeth from.
paul knows how to pick 'em.
it's like "fatal attraction" all over again.
why's the rabbit always get screwed in the deal?
poor little guy.
you know what i don't get,dean?
if she was so bent on revenge,why do this?
well,she got janet dutton,
thought she finished off paul,
decided to cap herself
and make it a spurned lover's hat trick.
maybe.
this doesn't exactly look like a tv room
of a bright and stable person,you know?
no.
but then...
...there's this.
another hex bag? come on.
looks like we got a hit,huh?
a little witch-on-witch violence.
i guess.
i'd like to report a dead body at 309 mayfair circle.
my name? yeah,sure,my name is...
why are witches ganking each other?
i don't know,but i think maybe we got a coven on our hands.
all right,all right. i'm going.
i'm not fooled by your little book club,by the way.
i know what you ladies get up to when i'm gone.
it's all dish and gossip.
hi,ron.
oh,hello,elizabeth.
i mean,when's the last time
anyone actually brought a book?
good night,ron. good night,ron.
all right.
he doesn't know?you didn't tell him?
about amanda?
i think that's book club business,don't you?
thank you,tammi.
the police just took away her body,
and we're just gonna pretend it didn't happen?
he loved amanda.
it's true.
we know that she was a little...unstable.
also true.
and we have to face it --
she probably killed janet dutton.
people just don't spit out their teeth all of a sudden.
mnh-mnh.
we have to stop.
we have to stop book club.this has all gone too far.
elizabeth,just take a deep breath.
calm down.
we can't stop.
but people are dying.
amanda killed herself,yes.
and,yes,she killed janet.
awful,awful business,of course,
but that's all over now.
and think about what book club has gotten us,hmm?
your husband's promotion,
that little trip to hawaii that you won.
and what about me?
my home pottery business is finally taking off,
and you want to just stop?
do you want to stop?
okay. now,come on. we don't have much time.
ron gets back from his fantasy  football in an hour.
all: book of shadows,we kneel before you.
let us serve your master as you serve us.
book of shadows,we kneel before you.
let us serve your master...
sam: you must have a green thumb.
excuse me?
getting these herbs to grow out of season like this.
quite impressive.
i'm sorry. i should have introduced myself first.
i'm,uh,detective bachman,and this is detective turner.
hiya.
we're following up on amanda burns' death.
going around the neighborhood,talking to her neighbors.
but didn't she -- i mean,she killed herself,right?
maybe,maybe.we heard you
were friends with the deceased,right?
yeah,i guess so.
do you have any idea about her practices?
i'm sorry?what -- what kind of practices?
well,her house was
littered with satanic paraphernalia.
it was a regular black sabbath.
no,th--but she was an episcopalian.
well,then we're pretty sure
she was using the wrong bible.
renee: elizabeth.
are you all right?
i'm fine.uh,renee,these are detectives.
they say amanda was
--she was practicing --
sorry,detectives.
you can tell that elizabeth is a little upset.
of course,miss...
mrs.renee van allen.
would you like me to spell it for you?
i'll get by,thanks.
this amanda business has been hard for liz,
for all of us.
yeah,i mean,you think you know a person.
well,i guess we all have secrets,don't we?
well,thanks. um,we'll be in touch.
have a nice day.
bye.
well,i'm already sold on that elizabeth chick.
did you see that victory garden of hers?
belladonna,wolfsbane,mandrake.
not to mention that little flinch she threw
when we mentioned the occult.
well,she's definitely had a good run lately.
gone up a few tax brackets,
won almost too many raffles --
the kind of thing a little
black magic always helps with.
yeah.
i don't think she's alone,either.
it looks like mrs.renee van allen
has won almost every craft contest she's entered
in the past three months.
a regular martha stewart,huh?
except for the devil worship.
i'm thinking that was the coven we met back there,
minus one member.
amanda was clearly going off the reservation.
you think they killed her to keep up appearances?
seems like an appearance
kind of crowd,don't you think?
yeah.
if they killed a nut job,
should we thank them or what?
they work in black magic,too,dean.
they need to be stopped.
stopped,like stopped?
they're human,sam.
they're murderers.
burn,witch,burn.
ruby.
sam,listen to me. there's no time.
what are you talking about?
you have to get out of town.
so,this is ruby,huh?
never had the pleasure.
dean.i was hoping you'd show up again.
point that thing somewhere else.
ha ha ha ha.right.
sam,please. go.
get in the car and don't look back.
why? i don't understand.
hey,hot stuff,we can take care
of a few kitchen witches,thanks.
i'm not talking about witches,you jackass.
witches are whores.
i'm talking about who they serve.
demons.
they get their power from demons.
yeah.
and there's one here now.
oh,what,you mean besides you?
sam,it knows you're in town,
and it's gonna come after you,
and it's way more than you can handle.
oh,come on. what is this,huh?
please tell me you're not listening to this crap.
put a leash on your brother,
sam,if you want to keep him.
dean,just chill out.no! no!
she's messing with your head! god knows why.
that's who they are!
i'm telling you the truth.
i'm telling you to shut up,bitch!
i'm sorry. why are you
even a part of this conversation?
maybe because he's
my brother,you black-eyed skank!
oh,right,right.
and you care about your brother so much.
that's why you're checking out,
leaving him all alone.shut up.
let me try and save him
since you won't be here to do it anymore.
i said shut up!dean,no!
what the hell were you thinking?
what? what the hell was i thinking?
she's a demon,sam,period.all right?
they want us dead.we want them dead.
oh,that's funny.
i remember that demon chick in ohio --
casey -- you didn't want her dead.
well,she wasn't stringing me
along like a fish on a hook.
no one's stringing me along!
look,i know it's dangerous that she is dangerous
but like it or not,she's useful.
no! we kill her before she kills us.
kill her with what? the gun she fixed for us?
whatever works.
dean,if she wants us dead,
all she has to do is stop saving our lives.
look,we have to start
looking at the big picture,dean.
start thinking in strategies and and moves ahead.
it's not so simple.we're not just hunting anymore.
we're at war.
are you feeling okay?
why are you always asking me that?
because you're taking advice from a demon,for starters.
and,by the way,
you seem less and less worried about offing people.
it used to eat you up inside.
and what has that gotten me?
nothing,but it's just
want you're supposed to do,okay?
we're supposed to drive in the freaking car
and freaking argue about this stuff!
you go on about the sanctity
of life and all that crap.
wait,so you're mad
because i'm starting to agree with you?
no,i'm not mad!
i'm -- i'm...
i'm worried.
sam,i'm worried because
you're not acting like yourself.
yeah,you're right.i'm not.
i don't have a choice.
what is that supposed to mean?
look,dean,you're leaving,right?
and i got to stay here
in this crap hole of a world...
alone.
so,the way i see it,if i'm gonna make it,
if i'm gonna fight this war after you're gone,
then i got to change.
change into what?
into you.
i got to be more like you.
what's going on with you?
i don't know.
sam,something's wrong.
a bunch of knives inside of me.
dean? son of a bitch.
dean. ohh!
the coven,man.it's got to be the coven.
dean,i can't find it!
no.
sam,what are you doing?
sam!
oh,my god!
let him go.
let who go?what are you doing?
you're insane. get out!
look,if you know about me,
then you know about this gun.
you're killing my brother.now let him go.
get away from the altar.what?
now!
you want to kill me?get in line,bitch.
stop...calling me bitch.
go.
what? w-w-we weren't hurting anyone.
please,we don't even know your brother.
stop the spell or die.
five seconds.what?!
no,please.please don't kill us.
we were just getting
renee a lower mortgage rate.
next time you point that gun at me,
i'm not gonna just disappear,understand?
you...saved my life.
don't mention it.
what was that stuff?
god,it was ass.
it tasted like ass.
it's called witchcraft,short bus.
you're the short bus.
"short bus."
okay,maybe it's not you...
...or you.
maybe it's you.
i-i don't even know what he's talking about.
what are you even talking about?
i mean,all of you everyone in your little coven.
you've all had runs of good fortune --
newsworthy good fortune.
except for you,tammi.
now,tell me,why is that?
you didn't want anything for yourself,
or is it because you're
already getting what you wanted,
like these women's souls?
i can't -- i'm not --i-i-i don't...
nice dick work,magnum.
let...my brother...go.
what's wrong?couldn't find my hex bag?
sorry,sweetheart,
but your brother's lungs
should be on the floor by now.
you're in a lot of trouble,sam.
tammi,what's wrong with your eyes?
tammi,what are you doing?
renee,shut your painted hole.
what?
i-i will -- you can't --
not in my house,tammi benton.
look! you got me!
let the girl go.
wait your turn,young man.
ohh,god!
lizzy,it's okay.
you're not tammi?
I no. but i'm wearing her meat.
i had to break the ice with you girls somehow.
you killed renee.
renee,amanda.
that's what happens to
witches who get voted off the island.
who are you?
funny story,actually.
you remember all those dark,demonic forces
you prayed to when you swore your servitude?
just who did you think you were praying to?
this -- this isn't --it can't be.
what did you think it was?
make-believe,positive thinking,
the secret?
no. it was me.
you sold yourself to me,you pig.
all i had to do was
bring one good book to book club,
and you ladies lined up to kiss my ass.
no. no.we didn't know --
oh,yes,you did.
you knew every step of the way,
and now your ever-living souls are mine.
comments,questions?
sammy winchester,wow.
right here in our little town.
you know,my friends
and i we've been looking for you.
why?
oh,right,because i'm supposed
to lead some piss-poor demon army.
no,not at all.you're not our messiah.
we don't believe in you.
but there's a new leader rising in the west.
a real leader.
that's the horse to bet on,sam,
the one who's gonna tear this world apart.
thing is,this demon it doesn't like you very much.
it doesn't want the competition.
nothing personal.it's a p.r. thing.
so,bye-bye.
two for one.lovely.
wait.
please.
i just...came to talk.
you made it out of the gate.
impressive.
it was a bitch of a fight,wasn't it?
doors out of hell only open for so long.
what do you want,ruby?
i've been lost without you.
take me back.
that's why i led the winchesters here.
they're for you...as a gift.
really?
let me serve you again.
i've wanted it.
i've wanted you for so long.
you were one of my best.
but then again,you always were a lying whore.
tammi: you're really
telling me you threw in your chips
with abbott and costello here?
come on. get up.
i said get up!
we've been here before,haven't we?
she didn't tell you?
pretty mortifying,i guess.
she was one of mine.
i turned her out a long,long time ago.
ruby here was a witch.
of course,that was when you were human.
oh,didn't want your friends to know
that all those centuries back,you sold yourself to me?
embarrassing,i guess.
but don't worry,love.
no secrets where you're heading,remember?
go.
i'll clean up this mess.
come on.
go.
so,the devil may care after all.
is that what i'm supposed to believe?
i don't believe in the devil.
wacky night.
so,let me get this straight.
you were human once.
you died,you went to hell,and you became a...
yeah.
how long ago?
back when the plague was big.
so,all of them every damn demon
they were all human once?
everyone i've ever met.
well,they sure don't act like it.
most of them have forgotten what it means...
or even that they were.
that's what happens when you go to hell,dean.
that's what hell is --
forgetting what you are.
philosophy lesson from a demon.
i'll pass,thanks.
it's not philosophy. it's not a metaphor.
there's a real fire in the pit,
agonies you can't even imagine.
no,i saw "hellraiser." i get the gist.
actually,they got that pretty close...
except for all the custom leather.
the answer is yes,by the way.
sorry?
yes,the same thing will happen to you.
it might take centuries,
but sooner or later,
hell will burn away your humanity.
every hell-bound soul,
everyone,turns into something else.
turns you into us,so,yeah --
yeah,you can count on it.
there's no way of saving me from the pit,is there?
no.
why'd you tell sam that you could?
so he would talk to me.
you winchesters can be pretty bigoted,
and i needed something
to help him get past the --
the demon thing?
that's pretty hard to get past.
look at you...
trying to be all stoic.
my god,it's heartbreaking.
why are you telling me all this?
i need your help.
-help with what? -with sam.
the way you stuck that demon tonight
it was pretty tough.
sam's almost there,but not quite.
you need to help me get him ready...
for life without you.
to fight this war on his own.
ruby.
why do you want us to win?
isn't it obvious?
i'm not like them.
i don't know why.
i wish i was,but i'm not.
i remember what it's like.
what what's like?
being human.
Sub by : gagak_84
Download : subscene.com