Then
Good night, love
Sweet dreams, Sam.
Sammy, you're my favorite.
Does this mean
I have demon blood in me?
It's you.
Mary!
Look, our whole lives have been
searching for this demon.
That thing killed Jess!
That thing killed mom!
Sam...
I'm sorry.
For what?
- Who are you?
- Castiel.
I'm the one
who gripped you tight
And raised you
from perdition.
- I mean, what are you?
- I'm an angel of the lord.
Samuel colt made a special gun.
This gun can kill anything.
Why would an angel
rescue me from hell?
Because god commanded it.
Because we have work
for you.
Now
Ready?
Definitely.
Hello, Dean.
And what were you
dreaming about?
You get your freak on
by watching other people sleep?
What do you want?
Listen to me.
You have to stop it.
Stop what?
Move it, buddy.
You can't sleep here.
Okay.
Sleep where?
Anywhere but here.
Perfect.
Hey,
where the hell am I?
Jay bird's diner.
Yeah, thanks.
I mean, uh, city and state.
Lawrence, Kansas.
Lawrence.
Are you okay, buddy?
Yeah.
Tough night.
Hey, uh,
coffee here, reg.
Can you tell me where i can
get reception on this thing?
The U.S.S. Enterprise?
Thanks.
Nice threads.
You know sonny and cher
broke up, right?
Sonny and cher broke up?
Momdy, April, 1973
Hey, Winchester!
Son of a bitch!
How you doin', corporal?
Hey, mr. D.
I heard you were back.
Yeah,
a little while now.
Good to have you home,
John.. Damn good.
Dad?
- Say hello to your old man for me.
- You got it, mr. D.
Do we know each other?
I guess not.
Take it easy, pal.
Yeah.
www.1000fr.com presents
Capture:∑ÎŒµ
Sync:VinE ”Í‰Ï
S4E03
In The Beginning
What is this?
What does it look like?
- Is it real?
- Very.
Okay, so, what, angels got
their hands on some deloreans?
How did i get here?
Time is fluid, Dean.
It's not easy, but we can
bend it on occasion.
Well, bend it back. Or tell me
what the hell i'm doing here.
I told you.
You have to stop it.
Stop what? Huh?
What, is there something nasty
after my dad?
Come on.
What, are you allergic to straight
answers, you son of a bitch?!
Fine young man like yourself
just starting out.
How about i take off
another $250?
Let's do it.
I'll get the paperwork.
That's not the one
you want.
You following me?
No, no.
I was just passing by.
I never got to thank you for
that cup of coffee this morning.
I was
a little out of it.
More than a little.
Let me repay the favor.
This is the car you want.
Oh, yeah? You know
something about cars?
Yeah.
Yeah, my dad taught me
everything i know.
And this..
This is a great car.
327 four-barrel,
275 horses.
A little tlc,
this thing is cherry.
You know, man...
you're right.
What are you buying
that thing for?
Kind of promised someone
i would.
Over a '67 chevy?
I mean, come on.
This is the car of a lifetime.
Trust me, this thing's still
gonna be badass when it's 40.
John Winchester.
Thanks.
Dean Van Halen.
And thank you.
I was in pretty rough shape
this morning, huh?
No kidding.
I've been hung over before,
but, hey,
I was getting chills
in that diner.
You didn't feel any
of those cold spots, did you?
Nope.
No.
I swore I smelled something
weird, too, you know?
Like rotten eggs.
You didn't happen to smell
any sulfur, by chance?
No.
Have there been
any cattle mutilations in town?
Okay, mister, stop it.
Yeah.If only I knew
what to stop.
Listen, uh...
watch out for yourself, okay?
Yeah. Sure.
So?
I'll take this one.
What's this?
My car.
What happened
to the van?
Mary, this is better
than the van.
It's got a 327,
a 4-barrel carburetor.
Mom.
Sammy, wherever you are...
mom is a babe.
I'm going to hell.
Again.
I should
just talk to him.
My dad's being my dad, John.
It's not you.
How is it not me? He's been like this
for how many years?
He's just protective
over me, that's all.
He's doesn't want me to...
hook up with a mechanic
from a family of mechanics?
No.
Hey.
I love you
for exactly what you are.
I'll be right back.
Why are you
following us?
Are you crazy?
You've been trailing us
since my house.
- I don't know what you're talking about.
- Oh, really?
Okay, how about
we talk about this, huh?
Let me go!
Are you a hunter?
See you later?
If you're lucky.
Dean, right?
I'm not sure
you should come in.
You can trust me.
I mean, come on,
we're all hunters, right?
I mean, we're..
We're practically family.
The thing is, my dad,
he's a little, um...
oh, I got to meet him.
You've heard of him?
Clearly, not enough.
So, you're a hunter?
Well, tell me something,
Mr. Hunter..
You kill vampires
with wooden stakes or silver?
Neither.
You cut their heads off.
So, do I pass your test?
Yep.
- Now get out of my house.
- Dad!
I don't trust
other hunters, Dean.
Don't want their help.
Don't want them
around my family.
Knock it off,
Samuel.
He's a hunter.
Who passed
your little pop quiz,
And now I'm inviting him to dinner.
- You hungry?
- Starving.
Good.
I'm Deanna.
You've met my husband,
Samuel.
Now wash up.
Samuel and...Deanna?
Really?
First time
in Lawrence, Dean?
Well...
been a while.
Things sure have changed...
I think.
You working a job?
Yeah, maybe.
What's that mean?
It means I don't trust
other hunters either, Samuel.
Hey, um...
so, why were you
following me and John?
Mm.
I thought something was after
your.. Your boyfriend.
But, um,
I don't think that anymore.
John Winchester
mixing it up with spirits.
Can you imagine?
I saw that.
What?
That sour-lemon look.
Now, hold on.
John's a really,
really nice...
...naive civilian.
So, what, would you rather me be
with a guy like this?
What? No, no.
Mary, of course not.
It's just that I..
That's enough, both of you.
We have company.
So, what about you, Sam?
You, uh, working a job?
Might be.
He's working a job
on the Whitshire farm.
Whitshire.. Why does that name
sound familiar to me?
It's been all over the papers..
Tom Whitshire.
Got tangled up in a combine
a few towns over.
That kind of thing happens.
Except why was he on it
in the first place
When his crops
are all dead?
Demonic omens?
That's what
I got to find out.
What about
the rest of the town?
Did you find anything
on the web?
Of...information
that you have assembled?
Electrical storms,
maybe.
The weather service graphs
should be here on friday.
By mail?
No, we hired a jetliner
to fly them to us overnight.
You know,
it sounds to me
Like we might be hunting
the Same thing.
You know,
if we go in there in numbers,
We'll take care of this
real quick.
What part of "we work alone"
do you not understand, son?
And I'm here because...
family business, Mary.
Family.
What, you'd rather be waving
pom-poms at a bunch of dumb jocks?
Uh, where you going?
To do the job, dad.
Father.
I see you beat me here.
The lord is funny that way.
Beth Whitshire...
this is my associate,
Our senior senior priest,
father Cheney.
Please accept
our deepest condolences
On behalf of the county diocese.
Thank you.
Miss Whitshire was
just telling me all about tom
And how normal and ordinary
things were
On the day
before his death.
I see.
So you didn't notice
anything unusual, ma'am?
You mean like my husband's guts
fertilizing the back 40?
Excuse me.
Charlie, would you like
to tell the father here
What you just told me?
Dad drank sometimes.
Sometimes he got rough with mom.
And that's when the stranger came?
I just thought
he was some bible-thumper,
Like you-all.
He showed up
about a week ago.
Saying what?
Did I want the beatings to stop?
I just thought he was crazy.
I didn't think..
And the next thing I know,
dad's dead.
Am I going to jail?
You didn't do this,
Charlie.
Did the stranger
want something in return?
He didn't want anything.
Come on, Chuck. He wasn't just handing out
freebies, now, was he?
He did say something
about coming a-calling
10 years from now
And maybe he'd want something then.
Something like what?
I don't know, okay?
Look, I told you
he was nuts.
What do you think?
I think he just
pimped his soul to a demon,
And he doesn't even
know it.
Charlie, do you remember
what the stranger looked like?
Yeah, uh...
he's about 5'10"...
white.
He was kind of
normal-looking, really.
Anything else?
- There was one thing.
- What?
It's just, the light hit
his eyes in a weird way, and...
for a moment,
I could have sworn..
What, that they were black?
Or red, maybe?
No.
They were yellow.
Pale yellow.
What do you say we just slow down
and talk this thing through?
There's nothing
to talk about.
Except you're saying
there's a demon,
And none of us has ever heard
of demon with yellow eyes.
Yeah, well, I have.
This thing
killed my family.
- Just calm down, son.
- You don't get it, do you?
You are in danger.
We are all in danger.
In fact, you need to get
yourself someplace safe.
Not until we know
what we're dealing with here.
Sam's right, Dean..
It could be a demon,
It could be a shapeshifter,
any number of things.
I know what this thing is!
And I'm gonna kill it.
That's all the talking
I need to do.
You're gonna kill a demon?
How?
There's a hunter
named Daniel Elkins.
He lives in Colorado.
He has colt's gun.
The colt.
Yeah, I heard about the colt.
I used to tell it to Mary
as a bedtime story.
Well, it's real.
All right,
say that it is.
You got some kind
of a crystal ball
Telling you
where this demon's gonna be?
Yeah, maybe I do.
- What's this?
- It's a list.
Of what?
My dad wrote down anyone
he thought ever came in contact
With the yellow-eyed demon..
Who, where, and when.
Why?
'Cause the more he could learn
about the son of a bitch,
The more he could figure out
why it killed my mom.
Look.
Whitshire farm.
I told you
that name sounded familiar.
Whitshire farms..
That was two days ago.
How the hell
is that on your dad's list?
My dad could see
the future.
Look at this.. Says he's gonna
hit here tomorrow night.
Liddy Walsh?
Haleyville.
That's close.
Yeah, it's about 3 miles,
but...
I know
you guys think I'm crazy.
You seem like a really nice kid,
Dean, but, yeah, you're crazy.
Yeah, maybe.
But I know where
this bastard's gonna be.
And I'm gonna stop it...
once and for all.
I, uh,
I'm shoving off.
I just wanted
to say "bye."
Really?
So soon?
Yeah,
I have a job to do.
Hey,
I wanted to tell you,
You know,
for what it's worth, um...
It doesn't matter
what your dad thinks.
I like that John kid.
You do?
Yeah.
Yeah, I think
you two are meant to be.
Hell,
I'm depending on it.
- What?
- Nothing.
can I ask you
a question?
What's he like..
John?
Why do you ask?
Just curious.
I don't know.
he's sweet...
kind.
Even after the war,
after everything,
He still believes in
"happily ever after," you know?
He's everything
a hunter isn't.
No offense.
No, none taken.
Can I tell you
something?
He's gonna ask me
to marry him.
Tomorrow, I think.
Yeah?
Oh, dad's gonna explode.
But I don't care.
I'll run away
if I have to. I just...
I love John. And...
and what?
I want to get out.
This job, this life...
I hate it.
I want a family.
I want to be safe.
You know, the worst thing
I can think of...
the very worst thing...
Is for my children to be raised
into this, like I was.
Well,
I won't let it happen.
Yeah.
Hey.
You okay?
Yeah.
No, I'm.. I'm fine.
Hey, m-uh, Mary...
can I tell you
something?
Sure.
Even if this sounds
really weird,
Will you promise me
that you will remember?
Okay.
On november 2, 1983...
...don't get out of bed.
No matter what you hear
or what you see...
...promise me
you won't get out of bed.
Okay.
So, what, god's my co-pilot?
Is that it?
Oh, you're a regular
chatty cathy.
Tell me something..
Sam would have wanted in on this.
Why not bring him back?
You had to do this
alone, Dean.
And you don't care that he's tearing up
the future looking for me right now?
Sam's not looking for you.
All right,
if I do this,
Then the family curse
breaks, right?
Mom and dad live
happily ever after,
And Sam and I grow up
Playing little league
and chasing tail?
You realize
if you do alter the future,
Your father, you, Sam,
you'll never become hunters.
And all those people you saved,
they'll die.
I realize.
And you don't care?
Oh, I care.
I care a lot.
But these are
my parents.
I'm not gonna let them
die again.
I can't.
Not if I can stop it.
Hold it right there,
friend.
Drop the gun.
Be on your way.
Can't do it, daniel.
Who the hell are you?
A hunter,
just like yourself.
- "Thief" is more like it.
- I just need it for a few days.
Not happening, mister.
Look, I have a chance
to save my family's lives.
My family.
But I need this gun
to do it.
So if you want to stop me,
kill me.
There's some hunters
in Lawrence. The Campbells.
Never heard of them.
That's where she'll be.
Dean say
where he was going?
He said
he was gonna kill a demon.
Kill a demon?
That's impossible.
Yep.
Where?
Oh, I don't know..
Over in haleyville.
Uh, Walshes, maybe.
Oh, wait..
Not Liddy Walsh?
Well, yeah,
I.. I think so.
Dad,???
We got to help her.
What's wrong?
I'll be in the car.
Hey!
She wants to hunt,
she doesn't want to hunt.
Is this some female
"time of month" thing?
What?
I'm sorry, Liddy.
It's metastasized.
Where?
His liver, his lungs.
It's time we talked
about arrangements.
No, you have to do
something, Dr. Brown.
There is one way..
A cure, actually.
But I'll need your help.
- What do I have to do?
- Nothing.
Just in 10 years,
I'm going to come to you
And ask for something then.
What?
Nothing you'll miss.
- ????
- Hold that thought.
You son of a bitch.
Well, hello, there.
Where the hell
have they been hiding you?
I like you.
You got a lot of spunk.
You let her go!
Where'd you get that gun?
- Mary, what else did he say to you?
- I told you..
Just that he liked me.
What did he mean
by that?
Liddy's a strong kid. She'll be fine.
Are you okay?
No, dad, I'm pretty far
from okay. Can we go?
- Nice job in there.
- I missed the shot.
Take the compliment,
son.
I'm saying
that I was wrong about you.
We need to talk alone.
We have to kill this thing now,
or Mary dies.
What?
How do you know that?
I just do, okay?
When?
Well, maybe today,probably years from now.
But it's happening.. Trust me.
So, what, are you some kind
of a psychic now, too?
No.
All right,
listen to me.
Now, this is
gonna sound a little...
actually, it's gonna sound
massively, massively crazy.
Okay.
- Mary is my mother.
- Excuse me?
And I'm your grandson.
And I know what the hell
I'm talking about.
You want to run that
by me again, son?
My real name
is Dean Winchester.
I was born
january 24, 1979.
My parents are Mary and
John Winchester.
I don't have to listen
to this.
Mary gets killed
by a yellow-eyed demon in 1983.
Now, I think that this,
what happened tonight,
I think this is the moment
that he caught her scent.
Now, if we don't catch
this thing now and kill it
And it gets away...
then Mary dies.
So I'm asking you...
please.
Hey.
Y.. You okay?
You promised
you'd take me away.
Of course I did.
Do it now.
How did I know
about the colt, huh?
about the yellow-eyed demon
Or where it would be?
I'm not making this up,
Samuel.
Every bone in my body is aching to put you
six feet under, but...
there's something about you..
I can't shake it.
Now, I may be crazier than you,
son, but I believe you.
Thank you.
How do we find
this bastard?
Right here.. The list.
And with the colt?
Yeah.
Let me see it.
Sorry.
I don't let anybody hold it.
I'm your grandfather.
Nothing personal.
Sure it is.
Especially when it's me
you're trying to kill.
Future boy, huh?
I only know one thing that's got the juice
to swing something like that.
You must have friends
in high places.
So, I kill your mommy?
That's why you came all this way
to see little ol' me?
Oh, I came here
to kill you.
Hey.
Wait a minute.
If that slug marries
your mommy, are you..
Are you one of my psychic kids?
No.
Not you.
Maybe you got a sis.
Or a bro.
That's terrific.
That means
it all worked out.
After all,
it's why I'm here.
So that's what this is about..
These deals you're making.
You don't want
these people's souls.
No.
I just want
their children.
I'm here to choose
the perfect parents,
Like your mommy.
Why her?
Why any of them?
Because they're strong.
They're pure.
They eat their wheaties.
My own little master race.
They're ideal breeders.
Oh, get your mind
out of the gutter.
No one's breeding
with me.
Though Mary...
man, I'd like to make
an exception.
So far,
she's my favorite.
So, why make the deals?
I need permission.
I need to be invited
into their houses.
I know, I know.. The red tape
will drive you nuts.
But in 10 short years,
it'll all be worth it.
'Cause you know what
I'm gonna do to your sibling?
I'm gonna stand
over their crib,
And I'm gonna bleed
into their mouth.
Demon blood is better than
ovaltine, vitamins, minerals.
It makes you
big and strong!
For what?
So they can lead
your discount demon army?
- Is that your big plan?
- Please
My endgame's a hell of a lot
bigger than that, kid.
Endgame?
What endgame?
Like I'm gonna tell you.
Or those angels
sitting on your shoulder.
No.
I'm gonna
cover my tracks good.
You can cover
whatever the hell you want.
I'm still gonna kill you.
Right.
Now, that,
I'd like to see.
Maybe not today.
But you look into my eyes,
you son of a bitch.
'Cause I'm the one
that kills you.
So, you're gonna save everybody.
Is that right?
Is that it?
Well, I'll tell you one person
that you're not gonna save.
Your grandpappy.
No!
No
Mary,
Mary.
I guess it's no secret
Why I brought you way out here.
- John..
- Just...
just let me
get through this, okay?
Okay, wait.
There's things you don't
know about me, John.
So?
I will always love you
for exactly who you are.
- What did I tell you?
- Dad!
Sir, just listen!
Ow! dad!
Stay away from her!
You're hurting me!
Hey, take it easy!
No!
You killed him.
Oh, not just John,
sweetie pie.
Mommy and daddy, too.
They're all dead.
- No.
- Yep. 'Fraid so.
You're little
orphan Mary now.
You son of a bitch!
Oh, sticks and stones
may break my bones.
And they won't bring
your family back either.
I'll kill you.
I swear to god.
Oh, let's not get nasty.
Now, look, we both said
some things that we regret.
Let's, uh...
kiss and make up.
I'll tell you what..
I'll arrange to have lover boy
here brought back breathing.
My parents, too?
Nope.
Sorry, doll.
That's not on the table.
Think about it.
You could be done
with hunting forever.
The white picket fence,
Station wagon,
couple of kids.
No more monsters or fear.
I'll make sure of it.
What?
And all it costs is my soul?
Oh, no.You can keep your soul.
I just need permission.
For what?
In 10 years, I need to swing by your house
for a little something, that's all.
For...what?
Relax.
As long as I'm not interrupted,
Nobody gets hurt.
I promise.
Or you can spend
the rest of your life
Desperate and alone.
Mary?
It's a good deal.
So, what do you say?
No!
- Mary?
- John.
I couldn't stop
any of it.
She still made
the deal.
She still died in the nursery,
didn't she?
Don't be too hard
on yourself.
You couldn't have
stopped it.
What?
Destiny can't be changed,
Dean.
All roads lead
to the same destination.
Then why'd you send me back?
For the truth.
Now you know
everything we do.
What the hell
are you talking about?
Where's Sam?
We know what azazel did
to your brother.
What we don't know is why..
What his endgame is.
He went to great lengths
to cover that up.
Where's Sam?
425 Waterman.
Your brother is headed down
a dangerous road, Dean.
And we're not sure
where it leads.
So stop it.
Or we will.