so, you talk to angels?
i just overhear them.
now we know why the demons
want you so bad.
this is uriel, a specialist.
hello again, dean.
don't you recognize me?
but we were so close...
in hell.
alastair.
they're coming.
back room!
we're here for anna.
are you gonna help her?
she has to die.
you want anna?
why?
out of the way.
whoa, whoa, whoa.
okay, i know she's wiretapping
your angel chats or whatever,
but it's no reason
to gank her.
don't worry.
i'll kill her gentle.
you're some heartless sons
of bitches, you know that?
as a matter of fact,
we are.
and?
and anna's an innocent girl.
she is far from innocent.
what's that supposed
to mean?
it means she's worse
than this abomination
you've been screwing.
now give us the girl.
sorry.
get yourself another one.
try jdate.
who's gonna stop us?
you two?
or this demon whore?
cass, stop...please.
i've been waiting for this.
what the...
come on.
anna.
anna!
are they --
are they gone?
did you kill them?
no.
i sent them away...
far away.
you want to tell me how?
that just popped in my head.
i don't know how i did it.
i just did it.
so, what do you think?
i think anna's getting
more interesting by the second.
yeah, i agree.
and what did they mean by
"she's not innocent"?
it seems like
they want her bad,
and not just 'cause
of the angel radio thing.
i mean, that blood spell --
some serious crap, man.
something's going on
with her.
see what you can find out.
what are you gonna do?
anna may have sent the angels
to the outfield,
but, sooner or later,
they're gonna be back.
we got to get ourselves safe
now.
iron walls drenched in salt.
demons can't even touch
the joint.
which i find racist,
by the way.
write your congressman.
here.
x bags?
extra-crunchy.
they'll hide us from angels,
demons, all comers.
thanks, ruby.
don't lose this.
so, anna, what's playing
on angel radio?
anything useful?
it's quiet.
dead silence.
good.
that's not troubling
at all.
we're in trouble, huh?
you guys are scared?
nah.
sam: hey, dean!
just stay here, okay?
keep an eye on her.
dean: how's the car?
i got her.
she's fine.
where's bobby?
the dominican.
he said we break anything,
we buy it.
he's working a job?
god, i hope so.
otherwise, he's at hedonism
in a banana hammock
and a trucker cap.
now that's seared
in my brain.
what did you find on anna?
uh, not much.
her parents
were rich and amy milton --
a church deacon
and a housewife.
riveting.
yeah.
but there is something here
in the report.
turns out this latest psych
episode wasn't her first.
no?
when she was 2 1/2,
she'd get hysterical
any time her dad
got close.
she was convinced
that he wasn't her real daddy.
who was?
the plumber, hmm?
a little snaking
the pipes?
dude, you're confusing reality
with porn again.
look, anna didn't say.
she just kept repeating
that this real father of hers
was mad.
very mad --
like wanted-to-kill-her mad.
kind of heavy
for a 2-year-old.
well, she saw
a kid's shrink,
got better,
and grew up normal.
until now.
so, what's she hiding?
why don't you just ask me
to my face?
nice job watching her.
i'm watching her.
no, you're right, anna.
is there anything
you want to tell us?
about what?
the angels said
you were guilty of something.
why would they say that?
you tell me.
tell me why my life
has been leveled...
why my parents are dead.
i don't know.
i swear.
i would give anything
to know.
okay.
then let's find out.
how?
we're here!
sam: pamela. hey.
sam.
it's me. it's sam.
sam?
yeah.
sam, is that you?
i'm right here.
oh.
know how i can tell?
that perky little ass
of yours.
you could bounce a nickel
off that thing.
of course i know
it's you, grumpy.
same way i know
that's a demon,
and that poor girl's anna.
and that you've been eyeing
my rack.
don't sweat it, kiddo.
i still got more senses
than most.
got it.
hey, anna.
how are you?
i'm pamela.
hi.
dean told me
what's been going on.
i'm excited to help.
oh.
that's nice of you.
oh, well, not really.
any chance i can dick over
an angel, i'm taking it.
why?
they stole something from me.
demon-y, i know.
but they're just plastic.
good for business.
makes me look extra-psychic,
don't you think?
now...how about you tell me
what your deal is?
hmm?
don't you worry.
pamela: nice and relaxed.
now, i'm going to count down
from five to zero.
when we're at zero, you'll be
in a deep state of hypnosis.
as i count down,
just go deeper and deeper, okay?
5...
4...
3...
2...
1.
deep sleep.
every muscle
calm and relaxed.
can you hear me?
i can hear you.
now, anna, tell me...
how can you hear the angels?
how did you work that spell?
i don't know.
i just did.
your father...
what's his name?
rich milton.
all right.
but i want you
to look further back...
when you were very young...
just a couple of years old.
i don't want to.
it'll be okay.
anna, just one look --
that's all we need.
no.
what's your dad's name?
your real dad.
why is he angry at you?
no. no!
no.
no!
calm down.
he's gonna kill me!
anna, you're safe.
calm down.
he's gonna kill me!
anna?
dean, don't.
wake in 1, 2, 3, 4, 5.
anna...
you all right?
thank you, pamela.
that helped a lot.
i remember now.
remember what?
who i am.
i'll bite.
who are you?
i'm an angel.
very reassuring.
neither do i.
so...castiel, uriel --
they're the ones
that came for me?
sam: you know them?
we were kind of
in the same foxhole.
so, what, they're like
your bosses or something?
try the other way around.
look at you.
but now
they want to kill you?
orders are orders.
i'm sure i have
a death sentence on my head.
why?
i disobeyed...
which, for us, is about
the worst thing you can do.
i fell.
meaning?
she fell to earth,
became human.
wait a minute.
i don't understand.
so, angels
can just become human?
it kind of hurts.
try cutting your kidney out
with a butter knife.
that kind of hurt.
i ripped out my grace.
come again?
my grace.
it's...energy.
hacked it out and fell.
my mother, amy,
couldn't get pregnant.
always called me
her little miracle.
she had no idea
how right she was.
so, you just forgot
that you were god's
little power ranger?
the older i got,
the longer i was human, yeah.
i don't think you all appreciate
how completely screwed we are.
ruby's right.
heaven wants me dead.
and hell just wants her.
a flesh-and-blood angel
that you can question, torture,
that bleeds.
sister,
you're the stanley cup.
and sooner or later, heaven
or hell, they're gonna find you.
i know.
and that's
why i'm gonna get it back.
what?
my grace.
you can do that?
if i can find it.
so, what, you're just gonna take
some divine bong hit,
and, shazam,
you're roma downey?
something like that.
all right.
i like this plan.
so, where's this grace
of yours?
lost track.
i was falling about 10,000 miles
per hour at the time.
wait. you mean falling,
like, literally?
yes.
like the way
a human eye can see?
like a comet maybe
or a meteor?
why do you ask?
here. in march '85,
a meteorite
vanished in the night sky
over northwestern ohio.
it was sighted nine months
before anna was born,
and she was born
in that part of ohio.
you're pretty buff
for a nerd.
look, i think it was anna.
and here, same time --
another meteor over kentucky.
and that's her grace?
might be.
all right.
that just narrows it down
to an entire state.
look, it's a start.
sam...i'm sorry.
for what?
for bringing you this mess.
if i had known,
i would have kept my trap shut.
yeah, well,
we'll muddle through.
not this time.
you do not want to get
between these two armies.
it's godzilla and mothra.
if one side doesn't get us,
the other one will.
so, what do you want to do?
dump anna and run?
forget it.
look, i know
the angels freak you out.
forget the angels.
it's alastair i'm scared of.
alastair?
you met him in the church.
practically the grand inquisitor
downstairs.
picasso with a razor.
and?
and you should pull him out
and throw him
back in the pit...
if you weren't
so out of shape.
ruby...
no, your abilities --
you're getting flabby.
yeah, so how do i tone up?
you know how.
you know
what you got to do.
no, i'm not doing that
anymore.
well, then you better pray
that anna gets her groove back,
or we're all dead.
pamela get home okay?
yeah.
she said she was sorry.
it's just after last time,
she, uh...
this is just a little too rich
for her blood.
i don't blame her.
you guys should do the same.
well, we're not that smart.
can i ask you something?
what do they want me for?
why did they save me?
i'm sorry.
the angels
aren't talking about it.
and it was after i fell.
that's another question.
why would you fall?
why would you want to be
one of us?
you don't mean that.
i don't?
a bunch
of miserable bastards...
eating, crapping,
confused, afraid.
i don't know.
there's loyalty...
forgiveness...
love.
pain.
chocolate cake.
guilt.
sex.
yeah, you got me there.
i mean it.
every emotion, dean,
even the bad ones...
...it's why i fell.
it's why...
why i'd give anything
not to have to go back.
anything.
feelings are overrated,
if you ask me.
beats being an angel.
how's that possible?
you guys
are powerful and perfect.
you don't doubt yourselves
or god or anything.
perfect...
like a marble statue.
cold...
no choice...
only obedience.
dean, do you know
how many angels
have actually seen god?
seen his face?
all of you?
four angels.
four.
and i'm not one of them.
that's it?
well, then how do you
even know that there is a god?
we have to take it
on faith...
which we are killed
if we don't have.
huh.
i was stationed on earth
2,000 years.
just...watching...
silent...
invisible...
out on the road...
sick for home...
waiting on orders
from an unknowable father
i can't begin to understand.
so don't tell me that --
what is so funny?
what?
nothing. sorry.
it's just...
i can relate.
hey.
did you find something?
i think so.
union, kentucky.
found some accounts
of a local miracle.
yeah?
yeah.
in '85, there was
an empty field outside of town.
six months later,
there was a full-grown oak.
they say it looks a century old
at least.
anna,
what do you think?
the grace.
where it hit, it could have
done something like that, easy.
so grace ground zero --
it's not destruction.
it's...
pure creation.
what?
nothing.
it's just an angel and a demon
riding in the backseat.
it's like the setup
to a bad joke...
or a penthouse forum letter.
sam: dude...
reality...
porn.
you call this reality?
it's beautiful.
it's where the grace
touched down.
i can feel it.
you ready to do this?
not really.
anna, what are
we even looking for?
it doesn't matter.
it's not here.
not anymore.
someone took it.
i say we head back
to the panic room.
what, forever?
i'm just thinking
out loud!
oh, you call that
thinking?
hey! hey, hey, hey.
stop it.
anna's grace is gone.
you understand?
she can't angel up.
she can't protect us.
we can't fight
heaven and hell.
one side maybe, but not both.
not at once.
um...guys?
the angels
are talking again.
what are they saying?
it's weird...
like a recording...
a loop.
it says, "dean winchester
gives us anna
by midnight, or..."
or what?
"or we hurl him
back to damnation."
anna...
do you know of any weapon
that works on an angel?
to what?
to kill them?
nothing we could get to...
not right now.
okay, wait, wait.
i say we call bobby.
we get him back
from hedonism.
dean, what's he gonna tell us
that we don't already know?
i don't know, but we got to
think of something!
hey.
holding up okay?
trying.
yeah.
a little scared,
i guess.
so, um...
dean...
i just wanted to thank you.
for what?
everything.
you guys --
you didn't have to help me --
hey, let's can the "thanks
for trying" speech, you know?
participation trophies
suck ass.
i don't know.
maybe i don't deserve
to be saved.
don't talk like that.
i disobeyed.
lucifer disobeyed.
it's our murder one,
and i knew it.
maybe i got to pay.
yeah, well, we've all done
things we got to pay for.
i got to tell you something.
you're not gonna like it.
okay. what?
about a week ago,
i heard the angels talking...
about you...
what you did in hell.
dean, i know.
it wasn't your fault.
you should forgive yourself.
anna, i don't w-want to,
uh...
i don't want to...
i can't talk about that.
i know.
but when you can,
you have people
that want to help.
you are not alone.
that's all
i'm trying to say.
what was that for?
you know...
our last night on earth...
all that.
you're stealing
my best line.
* i'm walking down
this rocky road *
* wondering
where my life is leading *
* rolling on to the bitter end *
* i'm finding out
along the way *
* what it takes
to keep love living *
* you should know how it feels,
my friend *
* oooh *
* i want you to stay *
* i want you today *
* i'm ready for love *
* oh, baby, i'm ready for love *
* ready for love *
* yeah *
* oh-oh-oh *
* for your love *
hello, ruby.
alastair.
i have to say,
i'm surprised to find you
out in the open like this.
yeah?
desperate times.
that they are.
you looking for this?
your gawky human friend
gave it to me.
keep it.
i just came to talk.
about what?
about how a demon
is protecting an angel?
we really must revoke
your membership.
look, i know i'm not
employee of the month,
but this --
i never wanted to get
in the middle of this.
why are you here, ruby?
i'll give you the angel.
will you?
and in return?
i walk away.
me and the winchester boys,
both of them.
this angel business
is none of our business.
hmm.
you know...
i'd always heard
that you were a devious,
cowardly little slut.
you don't disappoint.
so, what do you say?
it's interesting...
prudent.
but, uh...
let me make you
a...counteroffer.
uriel: look at that.
it's so cute
when monkeys wear clothes.
i'm dreaming, aren't i?
it's the only way
we could chat...
since you're hiding
like cowards.
don't normally see you
off leash.
where's your boss?
castiel?
oh, he, uh...
he's not here.
see, he has this weakness.
he likes you.
time's up, boy.
we want the girl.
wouldn't try that
if i were you.
see, she got her grace back.
full-blown angel now.
that would be a neat trick,
considering...
...i have her grace
right here.
we can't let hell
get their hooks into her.
well, then why don't you just
give her back her angel juice?
she committed
a serious crime.
what?
thinking for herself?
this is our business,
not yours.
she's not even human...
not technically.
yeah, well, i guess i just like
being a pain in the pooper.
no.
there's more.
you cut yourself
a slice of...
angel food cake.
didn't you?
huh?
you did.
what do you care?
you're junkless
down there, right?
like a ken doll?
ooh.
well, it's your last chance.
give us the girl, or --
or what?
what, you're gonna toss me
back in the hole?
you're bluffing.
try me.
this is a whole lot bigger
than the plans
we got for you, dean.
you can be replaced.
what the hell?
go ahead and do it.
you're just crazy enough to go,
aren't you?
what can i say?
i don't break easy.
oh, yes...
...you do.
you just got to know where
to apply the right pressure.
alastair: you know the problem
with your generation?
instant gratification.
it's all now, now, now.
no patience,
no craftsmanship.
but i do have to say...
this knife of yours...
it's an exquisite piece.
you must tell me
where you found it.
you know...
i haven't been up here
since poland '43.
truth is, i loathe it.
it's chilly.
no stink of blood
or sizzle of flesh
or the wet flap
of flayed skin.
i don't know
how you stand it.
so, the sooner
you cooperate,
the sooner i can finish up
with this ghastly angel business
and return home
to my studies.
but no rush.
let's take our time...
relish the moment.
now,
i'm going to remove this,
but don't you go smoking
out of that meat.
you won't get very far.
oh!
now you tell me
where that angel is.
no.
no?
i tell you, you kill me.
but i'll show you.
i don't know, man.
where's ruby?
hey, she's your hell buddy.
little early for that,
isn't it?
it's 2:00 a.m. somewhere.
you okay?
yeah, of course.
hello, anna.
it's good to see you.
sam: how?
how did you find us?
dean?
i'm sorry.
why?
because they gave him
a choice.
they either kill me...
or kill you.
i know how their minds work.
you did
the best you could.
i forgive you.
okay.
no more tricks.
no more running.
i'm ready.
i'm sorry.
no. you're not.
not really.
you don't know the feeling.
still, we have a history.
it's just --
orders are orders.
i know.
just make it quick.
don't you touch a hair
on that poor girl's head.
how dare you
come in this room...
you pussing sore?
name-calling.
that hurt my feelings...
you sanctimonious,
fanatical prick.
turn around
and walk away now.
sure.
just give us the girl.
we'll make sure she gets
punished good and proper.
you know who we are
and what we will do.
i won't say it again.
leave now...
or we lay you to waste.
think i'll take my chances.
sorry, kiddo.
why don't you go run
to daddy?
aaaaahhhh!
potestas inferna,
me confirma.
potestas inferma,
me confirma!
dean, dean, dean...
i am so disappointed.
you had such promise.
no!
shut your eyes.
shut your eyes!
well, what are you guys
waiting for?
go get anna...
unless, of course,
you're scared.
this isn't over.
oh, it looks over to me,
junkless.
you okay?
not so much.
what took you so long
to get here?
sorry i'm late
with the demon delivery.
i was only being tortured.
i got to hand it to you,
sammy.
bringing them all together
all at once --
angels and demons.
it was a damn good plan.
yeah, well, when you got
godzilla and mothra on your ass,
best to get out of their way
and let them fight.
yeah,
now you're just bragging.
so, i guess she's
some big-time angel now, huh?
she must be happy...
wherever she is.
i doubt it.
i can't believe we made it out
of there - again.
i know you heard him.
who?
alastair.
what he said...
about how i had promise.
i heard him.
you're not curious?
dean, i'm damn curious.
but you're not talking
about hell,
and i'm not pushing.
it wasn't four months,
you know.
what?
it was four months up here,
but down there...
i don't know.
time's different.
it was more like 40 years.
oh, my god.
they, uh...
they sliced and carved
and tore at me
in ways that you...
...until
there was nothing left.
and then, suddenly...
i would be whole again...
like magic...
just so they could start in
all over.
and alastair...
at the end of every day...
every one...
he would come over.
and he would make me
an offer
to take me off the rack...
if i put souls on...
...if i started
the torturing.
and every day,
i told him to stick it
where the sun shines.
for 30 years, i told him.
but then i couldn't do it
anymore, sammy.
i couldn't.
and i got off that rack.
god help me,
i got right off it,
and i started
ripping them apart.
i lost count
of how many souls.
the --
the things
that i did to them.
dean...
dean, look,
you held out for 30 years.
that's longer
than anyone would have.
how i feel...
this...
inside me...
i wish
i couldn't feel anything, sammy.
i wish i couldn't feel
a damn thing.