I got a year to live,sam. I'd
like to make the most of it.
What do you say we kill some evil sons
of bitches and we raise a little high?
- You didn't tell,dean?
- Tell me what?
There's a big new up-And-Comer.
Her name is lilith.
She really,really wants
sam's intestines on a stick.
Let dean out of his deal right now.
I'm just a saleswoman. I
got a boss like everybody.
Who holds the contract?
I can't tell you.
Bela talbot's her real name.
The colt. Bela stole the colt.
I want it back,bela.
Your little pistol,
you mean? Sorry.
You understand how many people
gonna die if you do this?
Whatxactly is it that you
think i plan to do with?
Take the only weapon we have
against an army of demons
And sell it to the highest bidder.
You know nothing about me.
- Pack your crap.
- Why? Where are we going?
We're gonna go hunt the bitch down.
- I don't want to go to hell.
- We'll find a way to save you.
I'm scared,sam. I'm really scared.
And the only person that can
get me out of this thing is me.
And me.
Erie,pennsylvania
Up for a drink?
No,i can't. I got to
be up at the catwn.
Duty calls.
Boob job?
I wish.Nah,some crabby
old broad wants the works.
I need a forklift to
get it all back up.
All that work to have what?
15 minutes off her faces?
Staying young is a brutal business.
Hey!
Help!
??? Out of here!
Sir?
Please.
It's okay,sir. Let
me see what happened.
Don't you worry. There's
nothing i haven't seen.
No. No. No.
- Let me see.
- No
Supernatural s03e15
Stop!
You ready to talk?
I don't know.
I don't know anything!
Oh,hat,sam? He
doesn't know anything.
Yeah,i heard.
I'm telling you the truth.
Oh,you are?
My god,then i owe you an apology.
Allow me to make it up to you.
I'm gonna ask you
one last time --
Who holds my contract?!
Your mother.
Yeah,she,uh,showed it to me
right before i bent her over.
I want a name
- Or else
- Or what,hmm?
You're gonna squirt your
holy water in both ends?
Please.
Brother,that's like a fleabite
compared to what's coming to me
If i tell you jack.
Do what you want.
The only thing i'm scared is
the demon holding your ticket.
Exorcizamus te.
Omnis immundus spiritus.
How does that feel?
Does that feel good?
Go ahead.
Send me back to hell...
'Cause when you get there,
i'll be waiting for you...
With a few pals who are
dying for a nice little meet
And greet dean winchester.
Should i?
??? Him someplace he
can't hurt anyone else.
????
Omnis incursio
infernalis adversarii...
Omnis legio, omnis congregatio...
Et secta diabolica.
You ran the prints twice?
Are you sure?
Okay. Yeah,just chalk
it up to lab error.
Don't i know it.Okay.
Thanks. Yeah, i'll
tell the lieutenant.
Bury the body?
Yeah.???
Looks like these demons
ride 'em hard just for kicks.
What was the phone call about?
Remember that thing
in the paper yesterday?
"Stripper suffocates
dude with thighs"?
The other thing.
Right,the guy that
walks into the e.R. Out.
And kneels over
dead.His stomach's ripped
His liver,actually.Anyways,i
just found out
Something pretty damn interesting.
What?
The dead body covered
in bloody fingerprints --
Not the victim's.
Okay,great. My man dave caruso
will be stoked to hear it.
Those fingerprints match
a guy who died in 1981.
Really?
Urwhat are we lking?
Uh,walking dead?
Walking,killing dead?
Maybe.
Zombies do like the
other other white meat.
Speaking of, what do
you care about zombies?
What do you mean?
Well,you've been on soul-Saving
detail for months now.
And we're three weeks
out, and all of a sudden,
You're interested in
some hot zombie action?
Hey,man,you're the one who's
been all gung ho to hunt.
I just thought i'd
be doing you a favor.
Hey,no,no, no,no,no.
I didn't say i didn't
want to do it,okay.
I mean obviously i want
to hunt some zombies.
Okay,fine,whatever.
Yeah,the rest of
the body was intact.
The liver was the
only organ missing.
Now,where the liver was ripped out,
Did you happen to
notice any teeth marks?
Can i see your badges?
Of course,sure.
Fine. So you're cops and morons.
Excuse me? No,no. We're very smart.
The liver was not ripped out.
It was removed
-- Surgically --
By someone who knew their
way around a scalpel.
Didn't you read my report?
Of course we did.
Oh,it was riveting.
It was a real page-Turner,
just delightful.
- You done?
- I think so.
Please go away.
- Okay.
- Sure.
What?
Noing.
So,that kind of punches a
hole in ourombie theory,huh,
That scalpel thing?
Yeah,zombie with skills.
"Dr. Quinn,medicine zombie.
Maybe we're on the
wrong track,dean,
Looking for hacked-Up corpses.
What should we be looking for?
Survivors.
This isn't zombie lunch.
This is organ theft.
I told the cops all
of this yesterday.
I don't want to talk
about it anymore.
It's just a couple
of questions,sir.
Hey,man.
I just got my kidney stolen.
I'm tired.
We'll be out of here quick.
Don't you want to get the guy?
Will it get me back my kidney?
So what's the last
thing you remember?
Feeding my meter
He jumped from behind...
And then i wakenpped to a table.
And then the worst pain you
could possibly imagine,only worse.
And then i black out
again -- Thank god.
And then i wake up screaming
Ine no-Tell motel
In a bathtub full of ice.
Do you remember anything
about the surgery know,
What the guy looked like,
any details about the room?
Let me think about that.
Yeah...
One thing is coming back to me.
You know what i remember?
Getting my kidney
cut out of my body!
- So,i got a theory.
- Yeah?
Yeah,i talked to
mr. Giggle's doctor.
Turns out his incisions
were sewn up with silk.
- That's weird.
- Yeah,nowadays it is,
But silk used to be
the sututhf choice
Back in the ean y 19th century.
It was really problematic.
Patients would get
massive infections.
The death rate was insane.
- Good times.
- Right,
So doctors,they had to
do whatever they could
To keep infections from spreading.
- One way was maggots.
- Dude,i'm eating.
It actually kind of
worked because maggots --
They eat bad tissue, and
they leave good tissue.
And get this -- When
they found our guy,
His body cavity was
stuffed full of maggots.
Dude,i'm eating.
All righ let me get this straight.
- So,people are getting ganked,right?
- Yeah.
A little "antiques roadshow"
surgery,some organ theft.
But why does ty l sound familiar?
Because you
ard it before --
When you we a kid... from dad.
Doc benton -- Real-Life
doctor, lived in new hampshire.
Brilliant and
obsessed with alchemy,
Especially how to live forever.
So,in 1816,doc abandons
his practice and --
Right,yeah,nobody hears
from him for like 20 years,
And all of sudden, people
start showing up dead.
Dead or missing an organ ot a
hand or some other kind of part.
'Cause whatever he was
doing was actually working.
He just kept on ticking.
Parts would wear out,
he'd replace them.
But i thoughi dad hunted him
down and took his heart out.
Yeah,i guess doc must
have plugged in a new one.
All right, where's he doi the deed?
According to this, bes,ky
about where he sets up his lab.
He likes dense forest with
access to a river or stream
Or some kind of freshwater. Why?
Because that's where he
likes to dump the bile
And intestines and fecal matter.
Lost your appetite yet?
Maybe i can ??? You.
No please.
No
No no.
No solicitors.No asking
for donations.No selling???
So?
You called him this morning.
Uh,you told bobby
About a british chick
who made contact with you.
And so?
You know where she is?
Yeah.
Great. Could you tell me
where i could find her?
No.
Course not.
Look,rufus,man...
Look,let me point
something out to you.
You are knocking at my
door, so don't "look,man" me.
I'm not your man.
I'm sorry,sir.
All right,i'mght,you
a little story.
See,once upon a
time, bobby called me,
Asked me to call him if i got
a whiff of this bela talbot.
I got a whiff. I called. The end.
Okay,yeah,if you could
just tell me where she is,
I mean, that would be great.
- Dean winchester,right?
- Yeah.
Dean,do i look like
i'm here to help you?
I'm gonna say no.
Then get the hell of my property.
All right,fair enough.
I got one more
question for you,though.
See,i got this,uh
this bottle of scotch,
And...is this considered good?
Bottoms up.
You know,i don't
even bother drinking
Unless it's this stuff.
Nectar of the gods, m telling you.
Hey,it's a nice change, you know.
Most of my whiskey's
from a plastic jug.
So,bela was here because...
She wanted to buy
a couple of things,
Which is gonna take me
some time to round up.
Where is she now?
C-Can i ask you something?
Sure.
You got three weeks left.
Why are you wasting your time
Chasing after that skinny,
stuck-Up english girl?
How do you know about that?
Because i know things.
I know a lot of things
about a lot of people.
Is that so?
I know ain't no
peashooter gonna save you.
What makes you so sure?
'Cause that's the job,kid.
Even if you manage to
scrape out of this one,
There'just gonna be
something else down the road.
Folks like us...
There ain't no happy ending.
We all t coming.
Well,ain't you a
bucket of sunshine?
I'm what you've got to look
forward to if you survive.
But you won't.
So,bela...
Hotel canaan.
Room 39.
But watch your back.
I think i can handle bela.
Oh,don't be so sure about that.
There are things that
you don't kn about her.
Oh,and you do?
Right.
Because you know things.
Yep.
And let me guess -- You
lift her fingerprint?
Yep.
And that got you jack.
She bux@ed them off.
Probably years ago.
Yeah,so you're right ere we are.
Nope.
You do her ear?
Sorry?
Hey,man,i'll try anything
once,but i don't know.
That sounds uncomfortable.
Ears are as unre
to humanso as finge
No kidding.
Of course,that don't fly
in the courts over here,
But in england,
they're all over it.
A friend of a friend... of a friend
Faxed me 10 pages
of confidential files
Within a day.
All i had to send him
Was one clean shot off
the security camera.
Right.
One ean shot of her ear.
The so-Called bela talbot.
Shh! Shh! Shh!
It's okay. I'm here to help you.
I'm here to help you.
Pehere to help you.
Shh,shh,shh,shh, shh,shh,shh,shh...
Shh! I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Okay,here we go. Shh.
Shh,shh,shh.
Shh! Shh! Shh! Shh!
Ok,watch your head.
Sorry.
Try to get straight.
Where's the colt?
- Dean.
- No extra words.
It's long gone --
Across the world by now.
You're lying.
I'll call the buyer. Speak farsi?
Now,look
--
Don't flatter yourself.
- Don't move.
- I told you i don't have it.
Oh,yeah,i'm definitely
gonna take your word for it.
Don't move.
It's gone.
Get on a plane if you must.
Track down the buyer. You might
catch up to him eventually.
Are you going to kill me?
Oh,yeah.
You're not the cold-Blooded type.
You mean like you? That's true.
See,i couldn't imagine
killing my parents.
- I don't know what you're
talking -- - Yes,you do.
You were,what,14?
Folks died in some
shady car accident.
Police suspected a
slashed brake line,
But it was all too crispy to tell.
Cut to
little bela --
Ohi'm
sorry,abby --
Inheriting millions.
- How did you ev--
- Doesn't matter.
They were lovely people.
And i killed them.
And i got rich.
I can't be bothered to give a damn.
Just like i don't care
what happens to you.
You make me sick.
Likewise.
You're not worth it.
It worked.
He found me.
No,sam wasn't with him.
But i know where they are.
- Dean?
- Yeah.
- Did you get the colt?
- What do you think?
So,does that mean bela is...
No,no,she deserves to
die a dozen times over,
- But i couldn't do it.
- Dean.
I'm really screwed,sammy.
- No,you're just -
- But you were right.
Bela was a goose chase.
The colt's gone,and this
time i'm really screwed,sam.
Maybe not.
Look,i found benton's cabin.
- You okay?Was he there?
- Yeah.
- Did you kill him?
- No.
What do you mean,"no"?
Dean,please just
listen for a second.
I found his lab book,
and it has the formula.
- What, the live-Forever
formula? - Yeah.
Great,let me guess.
I got to drink blood
out of a baby's skull?
No,that's the thing --
It's not black magic.
There's no blood
sacrifice or anything.
It -- It's just
science,dean.
Very,very extremely
weird science,but...
Wait,wait,wait. What are
-- What are you saying?
You ink... dean,i think
it might be doable.
I mean,i know we've
hit a lot of walls,
But i-I think this formula
-- I think it might be it.
This could save you.
Okay,so,this formula...
Well,i mean,look,look,
we're not in the clear yet.
There are still things
that i don't get.
Sam?
Sammy!
You can relax.
It's all gonna be okay.
Ain't nothing gonna happen here
That you got to worry about,sammy.
Your chances of coming out
of this procedure alive --
Very,very high.
How do you know my name?
Oh...
I know.
You think i'm some kind
of monster,don't you?
Well,i got to tell you, i
have never done one thing
That i did not have to do.
This whole eternal-Life thing
is very high-Maintenance.
If something goes bad
-- Like my eyes here --
You got to replace them.
And sometimes things get damaged,
Like when your father
cut out my heart.
Now,that
--
That was very inconvenient.
So,i'm sure that you can understand
All the joy i felt
When i read all about
myself here in his journal.
Kind of makes this whole thing
Just feel like some kind
of family reunion,don't it?
Well,i guess it's about time
That we get this thing started.
Shoot all you want.
A knife?
What part of immortality
do you not understand?
Pity about the heart, though.
It was a brand-New one.
Good.
It should be pumping
nice and strong...
Sending this stuff
throughout your whole body.
See,i picked up your
little bottle upstairs
And dipped the knife in it.
Oh,hiya,doc.
Wakey,wakey, eggs and bac-Y.
- Please.
- Please what?
You've been killing poor
bastards for over 150 years
And now you got a request? Shut up.
No,you don't understand.
I can help you.
I know what you need.
We might have to cut
him up into little bits.
You know,this immortality
thing is a bitch.
I can read the formula for you.
The whole
immortality --
Forever young,never die.
Dean.
Sam.
What?
I mean,we're talking
hell in three weeks.
Or needing a new pancreas
in like half a century.
Yeah,well,you can't exactly
get those at a kwik-E-Mart.
It's not perfect, but
it buys us more time
To think of something better.
We just need time,dean.
I mean,please,just --
Just think about it.
No.
Dean,don't you want to live?
What he is isn't living.
Look,this is simple.
- Simple?
- To me it is,okay.
Black or white --
Human,not human.
See,what the doc is
is a freakin' monster.
I can't do it.
I would rather go to hell.
You don't understand.
I can help you!
Now,i'm gonna take care of him.
You can help me or
not. It's up to you.
No! No! No!
???
I can help you.No.
Enjoy forever in there,doc.
Let me out.
I can save you.
No.Don't.
No.
???
Hiya,bela.
Here's a fun fact
you may not know --
I felt your hand in my pocket
When you swiped that motel receipt.
You don't understand.
Oh,i'm pretty sure i
understand perfectly.
You see,i noticed something
interesting in your hotel room,
Something tucked above the door.
An herb --
Devil's shoestring.
Well,there's only
one use for that --
Holding hellhounds at bay.
So,you know what i did?I went back,and
i took another look at your folks' obit.
Turns out they died
10 years ago today.
You didn't kill them.
A demon did your dirty work.
You made a deal, didn't you,bela?
And it's come due.
I can take care of them for you.
And it won't even
cost you anything.
For 10 whole years.
Is that why you stole the colt,huh?
To try to wiggle out of your deal?
- Our gun for your soul?
- Yes.
But stealing the colt wasn't
quite enough,i'm guessing.
They changed the deal.
They wanted me to kill sam.
Really? Wow.
Demons
untrustworthy --
Shocker.
That's kind of a
tight deadline,too.
What time is it?
Oh,look at that. Almost midnight.
Dean,listen,i need help.
Sweetheart, we are weeks past help.
I know i don't deserve it.
You know what? You're
right. You don't.
But you know what the
bitch of the bunch is?
If you would have just come to
us sooner and asked for help,
We probably could have
taken the colt and saved you.
I know, and saved yourself.
I know about you dean.
And who told you that?
The demon that holds it.
She holds mine,too.
She says she holds every deal.
She?
Her name's lilith.
Lilith?
Why should i believe you?
You shouldn't, but it's the truth.
This can't help you,bela. Not now.
Why are you telling me this?
Because just maybe
you can kill the bitch.
I'll see you in hell.