Uh...can I help you?
Sure hope so. Agents deyoung and shaw.
Just need to ask you a few questions.
Notice anything strange in the
building, last couple of days?
Like what?
Well, some other tenants
anreported flickering lights.
I don't think so. Why?
What about noises?
Any tering in the
walls? Kind of like rats?
And the fbi is investigating
a rodent problem?
What about cold spots?
??? Sudden drops in romperature?
I know it
You guys are larping, aren't you???
- Excuse me?
- You're fans.
- Fans of what?
- What is "larping"?
Like you don't know.
Live-Action
role-Play
And pretty hardcore, too.
I'm sorry,e no idea what
you're talking about.
You're asking questions
like the building's haunted.
Like those guys from the books.
What are they called? Uh...
"Supernatural."
Two guys, use fake
I.D.S with rock aliases,
Hunt down ghosts, demons, vampires.
What are their names? Uh...
Steve and Dirk? Uh, Sal and Dane?
Sam and Dean?
That's it!
You're saying this is a book?
Books. It was a series.
Didn't sl a lot of copies, though.
Kind of had more of an
underground-Cult following.
Let's see. Um...
Ah. Yeah
That's the first one of them.
"Supernatural" by Carver Edlund.
"Along a lonely california highway, a mysterious
woman in white lures men to their deaths."
Give me that.
We're gonna need all the copies
of "supernatural" you've got.
www.1000fr.Com
presents
sync:misandry radorer mzinfo
Supernatural 418
The monster at the end of this book
This is freakin' insane.
How's this guy know all this stuff?
- You got me.
- Everything isin here. I mean everything.
From the racist truck
to -- to me having sex.
I'm full-Frontal in here, dude.
How come we haven't
heard of them before?
They're pretty obscure.
I mean, almost zero
circulation. Uh, started in '05.
The publisher put out a couple
dozen before going bankrupt.
And, uh, the last one --
"No rest for the wicked" --
Ends with you going to hell.
???Ate freaking insane
Check out. Actually fans.
??? T still. L.His?
Yeah.
Although for fans, they sure do
complain a lot. Listen to this --
Simpatico says "the
demon story line is trite,
Clich'd, and overall craptastic."
Yeah, well, screw you,
simpatico. We lived it.
Yeah. Well, keep on reading.
It gets better.
There are "Sam girls"
and "Dean girls" and --
What's a "slash fan"?
As in...
Sam-Slash-Dean.
Together.
Like, together together?
Yeah.
They do know we're brothers, right?
Doesn't seem to matter.
Oh, come on. That...
That's just sick.
We got to find this carver edlund.
- Ah, ht n easy.
- Not?
Los like "carveris a p no known address.
???
Somebody ??
So published the "supernatural" books?
Yep. Yeah. Gosh. These books...
You know, they never really
got the attention they deserved.
All anybody wants to readanymore I
You know -- "Doctor
sexy, m.D."? Please.
Right. Well, we're hoping
that our article can ...
Shine a light on an
underappreciated series.
Yeah, ye, because, you know,???
Then m-Maybe we could
start publishing again.
No, no, no god, no.
I mean, why -- Why would you want
to do that? You know, it's, uh,
Such a complete series,
What with Dean going to hell and all.
My god! That was one of my favorite
ones, because Dean was so...
Strong...
And sad and brave.
And Sam...
I mean, the best parts
are when they'd cry.
You know, like
in -- In "heart,"
When Sam had to kill Madison, the first
woman since Jessica he really loved.
And in "home," when
Dean had to call J	ohn
And ask him for help.
Gosh...
If only real men were so open and in-
In touchwith their feel???
Real men?
I mean, no offense.
How often do you cry like that, hmm?
Well, right now, I'm
crying on the inside.
Is that supposed to be funny?
Lady, this whole thing is funny.
How do I know you two are legit, hmm?
Oh, trust me. We, uh... we're legit.
Well, I don't want any smart-Ass
article making fun of my boys.
- No! R.No,
- No, that's...
We -- We are
actually, um...
...big fans.
Hmm. You've read the books?
Cover???
What's the year and model of the car?
1967 chevy impala.
- What's may 2nd?
- That's my -- Uh...
That's Sam's birthday.
January 24th is Dean's.
Sam's score on the lsat?
1...
74?
Dean's favorite song?
It's a tie.
Between zep's "ramble on" and
"traveling riverside blues."
O youwant to know?
Lund's real name?
Oh, no. 'T.
We jtalk to him.
Know, get the "supernatural"
story in his own words.
Very private. Like salinger.
Please.
Like I said --
We are, um...
...big...
...big fans.
Awesome.
You know what?
I got one, too.
Whoa. You are a fan.
Okay. His name's Chuck shurley.
And he's a genius,
so don't piss him off.
"Sam and Dean
Approached the run-Down..."
"...Approached the ramshackle
house with trepidation."
"Did they really want
to learn the secrets
"That lay beyond that door?
Sam and deantraded soulful lo
"Then,
With determination, "Dean
Pushed the doorbell with forceful...
Determination."
Ugh!
You Chuck shurley?
The Chuck shurley who wrote
the "supernatural" books?
Maybe why
I'm Dean. Sam.
The Dean and saming
you've been writing about.
Look, uh...
I appreciate your enthusiasm.
Really, I do. It's, uh, it's
always nice to hear from the fans.
But, uh, for your own good,
I strongly suggest you get a life.
See, here's the thing.
We have a life.
You've been using it
to write your books.
Now, wait a minute.
Now, this isn't funny.
Damn straight, it's not funny.
Look, we just want to
know how you're doing it.
I'm not doing anything.
- Are you a hunter?
- What?
No. I'm a writer.
Then how do you know
so much about demons
???
Is this some kind of "misery" thing?
Ah, it is, isn't it?
It's a "misery" thing!
It's not a "misery" thing.
Believe me, we are not fans.
Well, then, what do you want?!
I'm. And that's Dean.
Sam and Dean are fictional characters.
I made them up! They're not real!
- Are those real guns?
- Yup.
These are real rock salts
these are real fake ids
Well, I got to hand it to you guys.
You really are my number-One fans.
So, I-I think I've got
some posters in the house.
- Chuck, stop.
- Please wait.
- Please, don't hurt me.
- How much do you know?
Do you know about the angels?
Or Lilith breaking the seals?
Wait a minute. How do youbout that?
The question is how do you know.
Cause I wrote it?
You kept writing it
You know but after the publisher got
bankrupt, but those books never came out.????
Okay, wait a minute.
This is some kind of
joke, right? Did that --
Did phil put you up to this?
Well, nice to meet you. I'm Dean
winchester, and this is my brother, Sam.
The last names were never in the books.
I never told any about that.
I never even wrote that down.
Oh! Oh, you're still there.
Yup.
You're not ??Ion.
Nope.
Well, there's only one explanation.
Obviously I'm a god.
You're not a god.
How else do you explain it?
I write things and
then they come to life.
Yeah, no, I'm definitely a god.
A cruel, cruel, capricious god.
The things I put
you through --
The physical beatings alone.
Yeah, we're still in one piece.
I killed your father.
I burned your mother alive.
And then you had to go through the
whole horrific deal again with jessica.
- Chuck...
- All for what?
All for the sake of literary symmetry.
I toyed with your lives,
your emotions, for...
- ...Entertainment.
- You didn't toy with us, Chuck, okay?
You didn't create us.
Did you really have to
live through the bugs?
Yeah.
What about the ghost ship?
Yes, that too.
I am so sorry.
I mean, horror is one thing,
But to be forced to live bad writing...
If I would have known it was real,
I would have done another pass.
Chuck, you're not a god!
We think you're probably just psychic.
No.
If I were psychic, you
think I'd be writing?
Writing is hard.
It seems that somehow, you're just...
Focused on our lives.
Yeah, like laser-Focused.
Are you working on anything right now?
- Holy crap.
- What?
The er...??
It's, uh, it's kind of weird.
"Weird" how?
It's very vonnegut.
"Slaughterhouse-Five," vonnegut,
or "cat's cradle," vonnegut?
- What?
It's, uh, "kilgore trout," vonnegut.
I wrote myself into it.
I wrote myself, at my house...
Confronted by my characters.
"I was sitting in a laundromat,"
Reading about myself
sitting in a laundromat
-- My head hurts.
There's got to be something
this guy's not telling us.
"Sam tossed his gigantic
darks into the machine.
"He was starting to
have doubts about Chuck,
About whether he was
telling the whole truth.
- Stop it.
- "'Stop it,' Sam said."
Guess what you do next.
"Sam turned his back on Dean.
His face, brooding and pen."
I mean, I don't know how he's doing it,
But this guy is doing it.
I can't see your face,
but those are definitely
Your "brooding and pensive" shoulders.
You just thought I was a dick.
E guy's good.
So...
You wrote another chapter?
This was all so muchier
before you were real.
Can take just spit it out.
You especially are not gonna like this.
I didn't like hell.
It's Lilith.
She's coming for Sam.
Coming to get him?
When?
Tonight.
She's just gonna show up? Here?
Uh...
"Lilih patted the bed seductively.
"Unable to deny his
desire, Sam succumbed,
And they sank into the
throes fiery demonic passion."
You're kidding me, right?
- You think this is funny?
- You don't?
I mean, come on.
"Fiery demonic passion"?
It's just a first draft.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Lilith is a little girl.
No, uh, this
time she's a --
"Comely dental hygienist
ington, indiana."
Great. Perfect.
So what happens after the...
"Fiery demonic" whatever?
I don't know, that
hasn't come to me yet.
Dean, look, there's
nothing to worry about.
Lilith and me? In bed?
How does this whole
psychic thing of yours work?
You mean my process?
Yes, your "process."
Well, it usually starts with a headache.
A really bad headache.
Aspirin is useless, so...
I drink.
Until I fall asleep.
The first time it happened, I
thought it was just a crazy dream.
The first time you dreamt about us?
It flowed.
It just it it kept flo
Still does. I-I can't stop it, really.
You can't
seriously believe --
Humor me.
Look, why don't we, we just...
Take a look at these
and see what's what.
You
--
...knew you were gonna
ask for that. Yeah.
Dean, come on.
"The minivan accident wasn't that bad,
"But Dean was still seeing stars.
"He scratched absently at the
pink-Flower band-Aids on his face."
So?
So, I've seen you gushing blood.
You'd use duct tape and bar rags before
you'd put on a pink-Flower band-Aid.
- What's your point?
- My point is this --
All of this -- I-Is totally
implausible, it's nuts.
He's been right about everything so far.
You think he's just gonna
ground out at first now?
"Dean slid behind the
wheel of his beloved impala
"And drove off,
"The plastic tarp on the rear window
flapping like the wings of a crow."
A tarp?
Yeah. On the rear window.
And you drive it like that.
Well, he might be
wrong about the details,
But doesn't mean he's
wrong about the end result.
So we just got to run?
We are a rom?? Way...
From ready for a face-To-Face
death match with Lilith.
???
What seems to be the prm?
Bridge is out ahead.
We're just trying to get out of town.
Yeah, afraid not.
- Is there a detour?
- Nope.
There's not a side road
that takes us to the highway?
To get to the highway, you
have to cross that river.
To cross the river, you
have to take that bridge
- How deep's the river?
- Sorry.
Afraid you boys are gonna have
to spend the night in town.
Hey, this could be a good thing.
I mean, if this is what puts
us on the path to Lilith,
Then all we got to do
is get off the path.
How do you mean?
It's a blueprint of what not to do.
I mean, if the pages
say that we go left --
- Then we go right.
- Exactly.
We get off-Book.
We never make it to the end.
It's opposite day.
It says that we, uh,
we get into a fight,
So no fighting.
No research for you...
No bacon cheeseburger for you.
Yeah, no problem.
I'll just order something else.
Hi, uh, what's good?
Well, if you like burgers,
oprah's girlfriend said
We had the best bacon
cheeseburgers in the country.
Really?
I'll just have the cobb salad, please.
I'll have the... veggie tofu burger.
Thanks.
- This whole thing's ridiculous.
- Lilith is ridiculous?
The idea of me hooking up with her is.
Right.
'Cause something like
that can never happen.
Dean, for the first time,
We have warning that Lilith is close.
So?
So...
We've got the jump on her.
If we know when she's
coming, we know where she's --
This is an opportunity.
Are
you --
It frustrates me when you
say such reckless things.
Well, it frustrates me when
you'd rather hide that fight.
Cobb salad for you.
Ane tofu veggie burger for you.
Thank you.
It's not hiding. It's being smart.
It's picking your battles.
And is a battle that we
are not ready to fight.
Oh, my god.
This is delicious.
Tofu is amazing!
I am so sorry.
I gave you the bacon
cheeseburger by mistake.
Dude, this place charges by the hour.
Yeah, well, the book says Lilith
finds you at the red motel.
Hence, the uh, ???
It's opposite day, remember?
What are you doing?
Couple of x bags ought
to Lilith-Proof the room.
So, what? I'm supposed to
just hole up here all night?
That's exactly what
you're gonna do, okay?
And no research.
I don't care
what you do --
Use the magic fingers or, watch ???
??
Oh, dude, come on.
Oh dude. Com on
???
What you gonna do?
Well, the pages say that I spend
all day riding around in the impala.
So I'm gonna go park her.
Behave yourself, would you?
No homework.
Watch some porn.
Tureador
Re d
Hey!
- You wanted to see me?
- Yeah.
Thanks for coming.
Ah, sure.
Um...
I was just wondering
how much you know...
About me.
What do you mean?
Have you seen ons of me
When I'm not with Dean?
Oh...
You want to know if I
know about the demon blood.
You didn't tell Dean.
I didn't even write it into the books.
I was afraid it would make
you look unsympathetic.
Unsympathetic?
Yeah, come on, Sam.
I mean, sucking blood?
You got to know that's wrong.
It scares the hell out of me.
I mean, I feel it inside of me. I...
I wish to god I could stop.
But you keep going back.
What choice have I got?
If it helps me kill
Lilith op the apocalypse --
Ght that was Dean's job.
That's what the angels say, right?
De not...
...he's not Dean lately.
Ince he got out of hell.
He needs help.
So you got to carry the weight?
Well, he's looked
after me my whole life.
I can't return the favor?
Yeah, sure you can.
I mean if that's what this is.
What else would it be?
I don't know.
Maybe the demon blood
makes you feel stronger?
More in control?
No.
That's not true.
I'm sorry, Sam.
I know it's a
terrible burden --
Feeling that it all
rests on your shoulders.
???
All rest on my shoulders?
That seems to be where
the story's headed.
Am I strong enough to
stop Lilith tonight?
I don't know.
I haven't seen that far yet.
Omg ???
- Stars
- ???
I'm so sorry. I just didn't
see you. Are you okay?
And sorry about...
You know.
M-My daughter's going
through a doctor phase.
What are you talking about?
You're better now.
, no...
- Dean.
- I take it you knew I'd be here.
You look terrible.
That's 'cause I just got
hit by a minivan, Chuck.
Oh.
That it?
Every damn thida you
write about me comes true.
And all you have to say is "oh"?!
Please don't yell at me.
Why do I get feeling
There's ththing that
you're not telling us?
How you know what you
know, for starters!
???
I don't know how I know. I just do.
That's not good enough.
How the hell are you doing this?!
Dean, let him go.
This man is to be protected.
Why?
He's a prophet of the lord.
You...
You're castiel... aren't you?
It's an honor to meet you, Chuck.
I...???
Whoa, whoa, what? This guy, a prophet?
Come on, he's
-- He's...
He'scticallya penthouse foru
Did you know about this?
I, uh, I might have dreamt about it.
And you didn't tell us?!
It was too preposterous.
Not to mention arrogant.
I mean, writing yourself into the
story is one thing, but as a prophet?
That's like m. Night-Level douchiness.
This is the guy who decides our fate?
He isn't deciding anything.
He's a mouthpiece --
A conduit for the inspired word.
The word?
The word of god?
What, like the new new testament?
One day, these books -- They'll
be known as the winchester gospel.
You got to be kidding me.
I am not... kidding you.
If you'd both please
excuse me one minute.
Him? Really?
You should've seen luke.
Why'd he get tapped?
I don't know how prophets are chosen.
The order comes from high up on
the celestial chain of command.
How high?
Very.
Well, whatever. How
do we get around this?
Around what?
The Sam-Lith love connection.
How do we stop it from happening?
What the prophet has written
Can't be unwritten.
As he has seen it,
So it shall come to pass.
Re d
Come on. We're getting out of here.
What? Where?
Anywhere, okay?
Out of this motel, out of this town.
I don't care if we got to
swim, we are getting out.
Dude, where are all the hex bags?
I burned them.
- You what?
- Look, if Lilith sis coming, which is a big "if" --
No, no, no. It's more than an "if."
Chuck is not a psychic.
He's a prophet.
- What?
- Cass showed up, and apparently Chuck is writing the gospel of us.
- Okay.
- Okay. Let's get the hell out of here.
No.
Lith is gonna slaughter you.
Maybe she will, maybe she won't.
So what? You think you can take her?
Only one way to find out,
Dean, and I say bring her on.
- Sam...
- You think I'll do it, don't you?
- You think I'll go dark side.
- Yes! Okay? Yes.
The way you've been acting lately?
The things you've beendoing?
Oh, I know.
How you ripped alastair apart like it
was nothing, like you were swatting a fly.
Cass told me, okay?
What else did he tell you?
Nothing I don't already know.
That you've been using
your psychic crap,
And you've been getting stronger.
We just don't know why,
and we don't know how.
- It's not what you think.
- Then what is it, Sam?
'Cause I'm at a total loss.
Are you coming or not?
No.
Well,I feel stupid doing this.
But...I am fresh out of options.
I need some help.
I'm praying,okay?
Come on.
Please.
Prayer is a sign of faith.
This is a good thing,Dean.
So does that mean you'll help me?
I'm not sure what I can do.
Drag Sam out
of here -- Now.
Before Lilith shows up.
It's a prophecy.
I can't interfere.
You have tested me and
thrown me every which way.
And I have never asked for anything.
Not a damn thing.
But now I'm asking.
I need your help.
Please.
What you're asking,it's...
Not within my power to do.
Why? 'Cause it's "divine prophecy"?
Yes.
So,what -- We're just
supposed to sit around
A
- And wait for it to happen?
I'm sorry.
Screw you.
You and your mission.
Your god.
If you don't help me now,
Then when the time comes
And you needme...
...don't bother knocking.
Dean.
Dean!
What?!
You must understand
Whyi can't intercede.
Prophets are very special.
They're protected.
I get that.
If anything threatens a prophet,
Anything at all,
An archangel will appear
to destroy that threat.
Archangels are fierce.
They're absolute.
They're heaven's most terrifying weapon.
And these archangels,
they're tied to prophets?
Yes.
So if a prophet was in
the same room as a demon --
Then the most fearsome wrath of
heaven would rain down on that demon.
Just so you understand...
Why I can't help.
Thanks,Cass.
Good luck.
What are you doing here?
I didn't write this.
Come on.
I need you to come with me.
What? Where?
To the motel where Sam is.
That's where Lilith is.
Yeah,exactly.
I need you to stop her.
Are you insane?
Lith?
I know what she's capable of,
Dean -- I
wrote her.
All right, listen to me.
You have an archangel
tethered to you,okay?
All you got to do is
show up and boom! --
Lith gets smoked.
But I-I haven't seen that yet.
T- The
story --
Chuck,you're the only
shot that I've got left.
But...I'm just a writer.
This isn't a story anymore,man.
This is real!
And you're in it!
Now,I need you to get
off your ass and fight.
Come on,Chuck.
No friggin' way.
Okay,well,then,
How about
this --
I've got a gun in my pocket,
And if you don't come with
me, I'll blow your brains out.
I thought you said I was
protected by an archangel.
Well, interesting exercise.
Let's see who the quicker draw is.
Hello,Sam.
I've been waiting for you.
Where's the knife,Sam?
On the nightstand.
By the bed.
You're gonna have to try
a lot harder than that.
How 'bout this?
You're strong.
But you're notthatstrong.
Not yet.
So why don't you throw me around then?
Because I can't
And you know it.
You're immune to my charms.
Seems we're at a stalemate.
Why are you here?
To talk.
Yeah,well,
I'm not interested.
Hmm...
Even if I'm offering
To stand down...
From the seals...
The apocalypse...
All of it?
You expect me to believe that?
Honestly? No.
You were always the smart one.
But it's the truth.
You can end it,Sam.
Right here,right now.
I'll stop breaking seals,
Lucifer keeps rotting in his cage.
All you have to do is agree to my terms.
Why would you back down?
Why now?
Turns out, I don't survive this war.
Killed off,right before
the good part starts.
What do you want?
For it to go back to the way it was.
Before I had angels to deal with 24/7.
The good old days,
When it was all baby blood all the time.
And what do you want in return?
Your head on a stick.
Dean's,too.
Call it a consolation prize.
So what do you say,Sam?
Self-Sacrifice is the
winchester way,isn't it?
You really think I'm stupid
enough to fall for this?
I make a deal, I have to follow through.
Those are the rules,
And you know it.
Are you really so arrogant
That you would put your life before
the lives of 6billioninnocent people?
Maybe it's all that demon blood
pumping through your pipes.
Man after my own heart.
You think I'm likeyou?
I amnothinglike you.
Then prove it.
Going once.
Going twice.
Fine.
Swell.
By the way,a contract with
me will take more than a kiss.
A lot more.
Don't worry.
The dental hygienist in here?
She wants it bad.
I am the prophet Chuck!
You've got to be joking.
This is no joke.
See,Chuck here's got an
archangel on his shoulder.
You've got about 10 seconds
before this room is full of wrath
And you're a piece of charcoal.
You sure you want to tangle with that?
So deals,huh?
That's what she said.
To call the
whole thing off --
Angels,seals,lucifer rising,
The whole nine?
That was the gist of it.
Huh.
What?
You didn't think once about taking it?
You kidding me?
You spent all day trying to
talk me off the Lilith track.
I'm just saying...
She would have found some
way to weasel out of it.
And all it would have
cost us was our lives.
Yeah,
I guess you're right.
Anyway.
That's not the point.
What's the point?
The point is,
She's scared.
I could see it.
Lilith is running.
Running from what?
Don't know.
But she was telling the
truth about one thing.
What's that?
She's not gonna survive the apocalypse.
I'll make sure of that.
Did you see it?
Who are you?
I'm Zachariah.
You may know me
From your work.
What do you want?
Did you see it?
Is it true?
Is all of that...really going to happen?
Have you been wrong so far?
I got to warn Sam and Dean.
I wouldn't advise it.
People shouldn't know too
much about their own destiny.
You try...and I'll stop you.
Where are you going?
To go kill myself.
Don't be melodramatic, Chuck.
We'd only bring you back to life.
What am I supposed to do?
What you always do.
Write.
-=- www.1000fr.com  presents -=-