I remember now, I'm an angel.
I have death sentence on my head.
- Why.
- I disobeyed.
You really shouldn't have come.
You have to stop it.
Stop what?
1973?
Mom?
John Winchester.
My parents are Mary
and John Winchester
and I am your grandson.
Mary gets killed by a
yellow-eyed demon in 1983.
Now, if we don't catch
this thing now and kill it
and it gets away... then Mary dies.
No!
Aaaaahh!
I couldn't stop any of it.
She still made the deal
she still died in the nursery, didn't she?
Destiny can't be changed, Dean.
All roads lead to the same destination.
# she's my cherry pie #
# cool drink of water... #
Oh, I take it all back. I love the devil.
# Grown man cry, sweet cherry pie #
# oh, yeah #
# put a smile on your face 10 miles wide #
# looks so good, bring a tear to your eye #
# sweet cherry pie #
# sweet cherry... #
Now, that's what I call peace on earth.
# Pi-I-I-e #
# huh! #
# swing it #
Anna?
I was just, uh, working on a case.
This is what you dream about.
This is awkward.
Why are you gate-crashing my head?
why don't you just
swing by the motel?
I can't find you.
Oh. Cass did this thing.
Cass. Right.
Now, there's a friend
you can count on.
What?
He didn't tell you?
Tell me what?
Where I've been.
Of course not. Why would he?
Where have you been?
Prison.
Upstairs.
All the torture,
twice the self-righteousness.
- Why wouldn't he have told us where you were?
- 'Cause he's the one who turned me in.
Don't look so shocked
he was always a
good little soldier
did anything under orders.
I didn't know. Are you okay?
No, and I don't have long.
I broke out...
barely.
They're looking for me,
if they find me...
Okay. What do you need?
Meet me. 225 industrial
and please, just hurry.
Hello?
Who's there?
Hello, Anna.
Well...
If I didn't know any better...
I'd say the Winchesters don't trust me.
They do. I don't.
I wouldn't let them come.
And why is that?
If you're out of prison,
it's because they let you out
and they sent you here
to do their dirty work.
And what makes you so sure?
Because I've experienced...
heaven's persuasion.
You mean when you
gave me to them.
That was a mistake.
Anna, whatever they
sent you here to do...
They didn't send me. I escaped.
No one escapes.
All these centuries, and you're
underestimating me now?
If you're not one of them,
then what do you want?
I want to help.
- You want to help?
- Yes.
Then what are you
doing with that knife?
I'm not allowed to defend myself?
Against whom? That blade
doesn't work against angels.
It's not like this one.
Maybe you're not
working for heaven
but there's something
you're not telling me.
Sam Winchester has to die.
Supernatural Season 5 Episode 13
"The Song Remains The Same"
I am sorry. But we
have no choice.
He's Lucifer's vessel.
- He's not the only one.
- What? That guy Nick?
He's burning away as we speak.
No.
Sam is the only
vessel that matters.
You know what that means.
If Lucifer can't take Sam,
his whole plan short-circuits.
No fight with Michael,
no croatoan virus,
the horsemen go back
to their day jobs.
Even if you could... kill Sam,
Satan would just
bring him back to life.
Not after I scatter his
cells across the universe.
They'll never find
him... not all of him.
We'll find another way.
How's that going?
How's the colt working out?
or the search for god?
Is anything working?
If you want to stop
the devil, this is how.
The answer is still no.
Because, Sam is my friend.
You've changed.
Maybe too late
but I have.
Anna, we've been
through much together
but you come near Sam Winchester,
and I'll kill you.
Oh, my god.
Oh, my god. Hey.
- Oh, my god.
- Hey. You okay?
We have to get her
to a hospital. Come on.
Really? Anna?
- I don't believe it.
- It's true.
So she's gone all Glenn Close,
huh? That's awesome.
Who's Glenn Close?
No one.
Just this psycho bitch who
likes to boil rabbits.
So, t-the... the
plan to kill me...
would it actually stop Satan?
No, Sam, come on.
Cass, what do you think?
does Anna have a point?
No.
She's a... "Glenn Close."
I don't get it.
We're looking for the chick
that wants to gank Sam?
Why poke the bear?
Anna will keep trying,
she won't give up until Sam is dead.
So we kill her first.
- I found her.
- Where is she?
Not where.
When.
It's 1978.
What?
Why 1978? I wasn't even born yet.
You won't be...
If she kills your parents.
What?
Anna can't get to
you because of me
- so she's going after them.
- Take us back right now.
And deliver you right to Anna?
I should go alone.
They're our parents, Cass.
We're going.
It's not that easy.
- Why not?
- Time travel was difficult
even with the powers of
heaven at my disposal.
But you're cut off.
So, what? You're like a delorean
without enough plutonium.
I don't understand that reference.
But I'm telling you,
taking this trip,
with passengers, no less...
It'll weaken me.
They're our mom and dad.
If we can save them,
and not just from Anna...
I mean, if we can set things right...
we have to try.
Ready?
Not really.
Bend your knees.
Geez!
Huh...
Did we make it?
Unless they're bringing
pintos back into production,
I, uh, I'd say yes.
Cass?
- Hey.
- Hey. Hey, hey.
Take it easy. Take it
easy. You all right?
I'm fine.
I'm much better than I expected.
Cass!
He's breathing... sort of.
What do we do?
I mean, the moustaches alone...
So I paid for Cass for five nights
up in the, uh, honeymoon suite.
I told the manager.
"Do not disturb, no matter what."
You know what he said to me?
"Yeah. Don't sweat it.
Want to buy some dope?"
Dope.
We ought to stick around here,
buy some stock in Microsoft.
Yeah, we might have to
if Cass doesn't recover.
Is he all right?
What do I look like... Dr.
Angel, medicine woman?
He'll wake up.
He's, you know, tough for a
little nerdy dude with wings.
If he landed like that,
hopefully, so did Anna.
Should buy us some time.
So, did you find 'em?
Yeah. Uh... The
Winchesters. 485 robin tree.
Let's go pop in on the folks.
Sam. Sam. Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Dean, Anna could
be here any second.
What exactly are we gonna
march up there and tell 'em?
- Uh, the truth.
- What, that their sons are back from the future
to save them from an
angel gone "Terminator"?
Come on. Those movies
haven't even come out yet.
Well, then tell her
demons are after 'em.
I mean, she thinks
you're a hunter, right?
Yeah, a hunter who disappeared
right when her dad died.
She's gonna love me.
Just follow my lead.
How was work?
It was, uh, great.
Ah! Not until you wash up.
I love when you get bossy.
Hi, Mary.
You can't be here.
I'm sorry if this is a bad time.
You don't understand. I'm not...
I don't do that anymore.
I have a normal life
now. You have to go.
I'm sorry, but this is important, okay?
Sorry, sweetie, they're just...
Mary's cousins.
Yeah, we couldn't stop through town
without swinging by and saying
"hey," now, could we?
Dean.
You look familiar.
Really?
Yeah, you do, too,
actually, you know?
We must have met sometime.
Small towns, right? Got to love 'em.
I'm John.
This is Sam.
Sam. Uh, Mary's
father was a Sam.
Uh, it's a... it's a family name.
You okay, pal?
You look a little spooked.
Oh. Oh, yeah.
Just a... long trip.
Yeah.
Well, Sam and Dean were
just on their way out.
What? They just got here.
Real happy to meet
folks from Mary's side.
Please come on in for a beer.
Twist my arm.
Are you sure you're okay, Sam?
Wh... oh.
Yeah, yeah. Um, I'm just, um...
You are so beautiful.
He means that in a-a non-weird,
wholesome, family kind of a way.
Yeah, right.
We haven't seen Mary in...
in quite some time, and...
See, she's the spitting
image of our mom.
- I mean, it's... it's...
- Eerie.
So, how are you guys related?
You know, uh, distantly.
Oh. So you knew Mary's parents?
Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
Mary's dad was, uh...
Pretty much like a grandpa to us.
Oh.
That was tragic... that heart attack.
Yes, it was.
So, uh, what are you guys
doing in town, anyway?
Uh, business, you know.
- Oh, yeah? What line of work? - Plumbing.
- Scrap metal.
Oh, gosh. It's almost 7:00.
I hate to be rude,
but I got to get dinner ready.
- Maybe they could stay.
- I'm sure they have to leave.
Uh, look, please stay.
You know, it would
mean a lot to me.
I-I haven't met much of
Mary's side of the family.
Look, Mr. Woodson,
I'm begging you to reconsider.
I'd like to, John.
You're a great mechanic
but times ain't exactly rosy.
E-even just part time.
I really need this job.
All right, look. Come on
in right now, let's talk.
Maybe we can figure something out.
You serious?
I'll see you in 10 minutes.
Don't keep me waiting.
You have to leave. Now.
- Okay, just listen...
- No, you listen.
Last time I saw you,
a demon killed my parents.
Now you waltz in
here like you're family?
Whatever you want... no. Leave me alone.
You and John are in danger.
What are you talking about?
Something's coming for you.
Demon?
- Not exactly.
- Well, what, then?
It's kind of hard to explain,
okay? It's... it's...
an angel.
What?
- There's no such thing.
- I wish.
But they're twice as strong
as demons... and bigger dicks.
Why would an angel want to kill us?
It's a long story, and we'll
tell you the whole thing,
but right now, you've got to
trust us, and we got to go.
Look at my face and tell
me if I'm lying to you.
Okay.
- Where do we go?
- Out of here. We got to move now, though.
Okay. But what do I tell John?
Just tell him...
John?
Mr. Woodson?
You still here?
I wish I could say it's
good to see you, Anna.
You too, Dean.
I'm sorry.
Sorry.
It's not that easy to kill an angel.
No. But you can distract 'em.
Monsters.
Monsters?
Yes.
Monsters are real.
- I'm sorry, I didn't know how...
- And you fight them? All of you?
Yeah.
How long?
All my life.
- John, just try to understand
- She didn't exactly have a choice...
Shut up, all of you!
Look, not another word, or so help me,
I will turn this car around!
Wow. Awkward family road trip.
No kidding.
Place has been in the family for years.
Devil's trap.
Pure iron fixtures, of course.
Um, there should be salt and
holy water in the pantry,
Knives, guns.
All that stuff will do is piss it off.
So, what will kill it?
Or slow it down, at least?
Not much.
Great.
He said not much, not nothing.
We packed.
If we put this up...
and she comes close,
we beam her right off the starship.
Mm.
This is holy oil.
It's kind of like a,
like a devil's trap for angels.
Come on. I'll show
you how it works.
Hey, what's the deal with
the thing on the paper?
It's a sigil. That means...
I don't care what it means.
Where does it go?
On a wall or a door.
How big should I make it?
John...
What?
Y'all might have treated me like a fool,
but I am not useless.
I can draw a damn...
whatever it is... a sigil.
Why don't you go help Sam out?
Okay, 'cause this has
got to be done in...
it's got to be done in human blood.
So, how big?
I'll show you.
What?
All of a sudden, you... you
really remind me of my dad.
That's really good.
You come to check on me?
Uh...
I wanted to say I-I'm
sorry about all this.
I-I know it's a lot.
Look, how long have you known
about this... hunting stuff?
Pretty much forever.
My dad raised me in it.
You're serious?
Who the hell does that to a kid?
Well, I mean, for the record,
Mary's parents did.
I don't care.
You know, what kind
of irresponsible bastard
Lets a child anywhere near...
Y-you know, you
could've been killed!
I, uh... came kind of close.
The number it must've
done on your head...
Your father was
supposed to protect you.
He was trying.
He died trying.
Believe me...
I used to be mad at him.
I-I mean, I used to...
I used to hate the guy,
but now I-I...
I get it.
He was... Just doing
the best he could.
And he was trying
to keep it together
In... in... in this impossible situation.
See...
My mom, um...
She was amazing, beautiful,
and... she was the
love of his life.
And she got killed,
and... I think
he would have gone crazy
if he didn't do something.
Truth is, um...
my dad died
before I got to tell him that...
I understand...
why he did what he did,
and I forgive him
for what it did to us.
I do.
And I just...
I love him.
Uriel.
- You look well.
- - You shouldn't have called.
We're under strict orders
not to come down here,
much less take a vessel.
You're not the Anna of now.
No, but 30 years from now,
I'm still your superior.
I need you to kill some humans.
Always happy to do some smiting.
But what's going on?
In the future, these people
are going to kill you, Uriel.
I'm giving you the chance
to kill them first.
Thank you.
Okay.
You said you'd explain
everything when we had a minute.
We have a minute.
Why does an angel want me dead?
'cause they're dicks.
Not good enough.
I didn't even know they existed,
and now I'm a target?
It's complicated.
Fine.
All ears.
You're just gonna have to trust me, okay?
I've been trusting you all day.
It's kind of hard to believe.
All right, then. I'm
walking out the door.
I'm your son.
What?
Sorry. I don't know how else to say it.
We're from the year 2010.
An angel zapped us back here...
not the one that
attacked you, friendlier.
You can't expect
me to believe that.
Our names are Dean
and Sam Winchester.
We're named after your parents.
When I would get sick,
you would make
me tomato-rice soup,
because that's what
your mom made you,
and instead of a lullaby...
You would sing "Hey Jude"...
...'cause that's your
favorite Beatles song.
I...
I don't believe it.
No.
I'm sorry, but it's true.
I raised my kids to be hunters?
No. No, you didn't.
How could I do that to you?
You didn't do it...
because you're dead.
What? What happened?
Yellow-eyed demon.
He killed you, and...
John became a hunter to get revenge.
He raised us in this life.
Listen to me.
A demon comes
into Sam's nursery
exactly six months
after he's born...
November 2, 1983,
remember that date
and whatever you do...
do not go in there.
You wake up that morning and
you take Sam and you run.
That's not good enough, Dean.
Wherever she goes,
the demon's gonna find her...
Find me.
Well, then what?
She can leave dad. That's what.
You got to leave John.
What?
When this is all over, walk away...
and never look back.
So we're never born. He's right.
I-I can't.
You're saying that
you're my children,
and now you're saying...
You have no other choice.
There's a big difference between
dying and never being born.
and trust me, we're okay with it,
I promise you that.
Okay, well, I'm not.
Listen, you think you can
have that normal life
that you want so bad... but you can't.
I'm sorry.
It's all gonna go rotten.
You are gonna die,
and your children will be cursed.
There... there has to be a way.
No, this is the way
leave John.
I can't.
This is bigger than us.
There are so many
more lives at stake...
You don't understand. I can't.
It's too late.
I'm...
I'm pregnant.
Hey, we got a problem.
Those blood things,
the sigils, they're gone.
Gone as in...
I-I drew one on the back of
the door, I turned around
and when I looked back again,
it was a smudge.
He's right.
There's no more holy oil.
Who the hell are you?
I'm Uriel.
Oh, come on.
Go.
Here goes nothin'.
John!
Sammy!
Sam!
I'm really sorry.
Anna...
Michael.
Michael...
I didn't know.
Goodbye, Uriel.
W-what did you do to John?
John is fine.
Who... what are you?
Shh...
Well, I'd say this
conversation is long overdue,
- wouldn't you?
- Fix him.
First...
we talk.
Then I fix your darling little Sammy.
How'd you get in my dad, anyway?
I told him I could save
his wife, and he said yes.
I guess they oversold me
being your one and only vessel.
You're my true vessel
but not my only one.
What is that supposed to mean?
It's a bloodline.
A bloodline?
Stretching back to Cain and Abel.
It's in your blood,
your father's blood,
your family's blood.
Awesome.
Six degrees of heaven bacon.
What do you want with me?
You really don't know
the answer to that?
Well, you know I ain't gonna
say yes, so why are you here?
What do you want with me?!
I just want you to understand
what you and I have to do.
Oh, I get it.
You got beef with your brother
well, get some therapy, pal.
Don't take it out on my planet!
You're wrong.
Lucifer defied our father,
and he betrayed me.
But still...
I don't want this any more than
you would want to kill Sam.
You know, my brother,
I practically raised him.
I took care of him
In a way most people
could never understand,
and I still love him.
But I am going to kill him
because it is right and I have to.
- Oh, because god says so?
- Yes.
From the beginning,
he knew this was how
it was going to end.
And you're just gonna
do whatever god says.
Yes, because I am a good son.
Okay, well trust me, pal
take it from someone who knows...
that is a dead-end street.
And you think you know
better than my father?
One unimportant little man...
what makes you think
you get to choose?
Because I got to believe
that I can choose what I do
with my... unimportant little life.
You're wrong.
You know how I know?
Think of a million
random acts of chance
that let John and Mary be born,
to meet, to fall in love,
to have the two of you.
Think of the million random
choices that you make...
and yet how each and
every one of them
brings you closer to your destiny.
Do you know why that is?
Because it's not random. It's not chance.
It's a plan that is playing
itself out perfectly.
Free will's an illusion, Dean.
That's why you're going to say yes.
Oh, buck up.
It could be worse.
You know, unlike my brothers,
I won't leave you a drooling
mess when I'm done wearing you.
Well, what about my dad?
Better than new.
In fact, I'm gonna do your
mom and your dad a favor.
What?
Scrub their minds.
They won't remember me or you.
You can't do that.
I'm just giving your
mother what she wants.
She can go back to her
husband, her family...
She's gonna walk right into that nursery!
Obviously.
And you always knew that
was going to play out
one way or another.
You can't fight city hall.
He's home...
Safe and sound.
Your turn.
I'll see you soon, Dean.
Castiel.
Hey. Hey, hey. Whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa.
- Cass!
- We got you.
You son of a bitch. You made it.
I...
I did?
I'm very surprised.
- Whoa! You're okay.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
- Bed?
- Yeah, yeah.
Whoa.
Well, I could use that drink now.
Yeah.
Well...
This is it.
This is what?
Team free will.
One ex-blood junkie,
one drop-out with 6 bucks to his name,
and Mr. Comatose over there.
It's awesome.
It's not funny.
I'm not laughing.
They all say we'll say yes.
I know. It's getting annoying.
What if they're right?
They're not.
I mean, w-why... why
would we, either of us?
But...
I've been weak before.
Sam...
Michael got dad to say yes.
That was different.
Anna was about to kill mom.
And if you could save mom...
what would you say?
Where'd you even get it?
Garage sale. 25 cents.
Well, I'm glad to hear that, anyway.
Hey.
I mean, you really don't think
It's just a-a little cheesy?
Mnh-mnh. I think it's sweet.
Can't even put my finger on why I like it.
I just...
like it.
Well, then, I love it.
Ohh...
Quite a kick there.
Troublemaker already.
It's okay, baby. It's all okay.
Angels are watching over you.
Sync by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
Edited by Scooby