the road so far
let me guess - you're
offering up your own soul?
all you got to do
is bring sam back.
how long do you get?
one year.
let dean out of his deal right
now. i got a boss, like everybody.
who holds the contract?
i can't tell you.
there's a new leader
rising in the west
who doesn't like you
very much.
her name is lilith.
i know about your deal,
dean. who told you that?
the demon that holds it.
she holds mine, too.
she?
her name's lilith.
dean:
so, this is ruby, huh?
she's a demon, sam.
they want us dead.
we want them dead.
sam: what kind of blade
could kill a demon?
bobby: yesterday, i'd have said
there was no such thing.
yellow eyes had some
pretty big plans for you, sam.
you're specialn that
e.s.p.- vision kind of way.
no, that stuff's
not happening anymore.
black dogs? they're seeing
hellhounds - demonic pit bulls.
there's no way of saving me
from the pit, is there? no.
i don't want to die.
i don't want to go to hell.
we'll find a way to save you.
you're gonna die! this is
what you're gonna become!
now..
dig up anything good?
no.
nothing good.
well, bobby has, finally.
yeah?
yeah.
a way to find lilith.
wow. with just, uh,
30 hours to go.
hey, why don't we just make
a t.j. run, you know?
some señoritas, cervezas?
we could - what's spanish
for "donkey show"?
so, if we do save you...
let's never do that.
hey, hey, dean...
uh...
look, we're cutting it close,
i know.
but we're gonna
get this done.
i don't care
what it takes, dean.
you're not gonna
go to hell.
i'm not gonna let you.
i swr.
everything's gonna be okay.
yeah, okay.
-==ææàãğüàöô°çãçé·îï×==-
±¾×öä»½ö¹©ñ§ï°½»á÷£¬ñï½ûóãóúéìòµóãí¾
-==http://www.ragbear.com==-
ğ°¶ñá¦á¿  µúèı¼¾µú16¼¯
-=ææàãğü×öä»×é=-
·­òë£º¸öèëid
ğ£¶ô£º¸öèëid
ê±¼äöá£ºwalden & ¾æäò·¹´ü
no reast for the wicked.
so, you got a name?
that's the whole kit
and caboodle.
with the right name,
the right ritual,
ain't nothing
you can't suss out.
like the town
lilith's in?
kid, when i get done,
we'll know the street.
new harmony, indiana.
and we have a winner.
all right. let's go.
dean: whoa. whoa. whoa.
hold on.
just holster it up,
there, tex.
what's the problem?
"what's the problem"?
come on, where do i begin?
i mean, first of all,
we don't even know if lilith
actually holds my deal.
we're going off
of bela's intel?
now, when that bitch breathes,
the air comes out crooked, okay?
second, even if we could get to
lilith, we have no way to gank her.
and third, isn't this the same lilith
that wants your giant head on a pike?
should i continue?
ain't you just bringing
down the room?
well, it's a gift.
i'm sorry.
so, then, what are we
supposed to do, dean?
well, just 'cause i got to die
doesn't mean you have to, okay?
either we go in smart or we
don't go in at all. okay, fine.
that's the case,
i have the answer.
you do?
yeah.
a surefire wayto confir
and a way to get us
a bona fide demon-killing ginsu.
damn it, sam, no.
we are so past arguing.
dean, i am summoning ruby.
the hell you are!
we got enough problems as it is.
exactly. and we got no time
and no choice, either.
come on, man, she is the miss
universe of lying skanks, okay?
she told you that she could
save me, huh? lie!
she seems to know
everything about lilith
but forgot to mention - oh,
right - lilith owns my soul!
okay, fine, she's a liar.
she's still got that knife.
dean? for all we know,
she works for lilith.
then give me another option, dean. i
mean, tell me what else. sam's right.
no! damn it!
just no.
we are not gonna make the same
mistakes all over again.
you guys want to save me,
find something else.
where you going, bobby?
i guess to...
find something else.
ad constringendum,
ad ligandum eos pariter
et solvendum.
et ad congregantum eos coram me.
you know,
phones work, too.
hey, sam.
how's tricks?
how do you get around
so fast?
i got
the super bowl jetpack.
so...
you called?
did you know?
i'm gonna need
a tiny bit more.
about dean's deal -
that lilith holds the contract.
yes. i did.
and, what, you didn't think
that was important?
you weren't ready.
for what?
if i told you,
you two yahoos
would have just charged
after her half-cocked,
and lilith would have
peeled the meat
from your pretty,
pretty faces.
well, we're ready now.
i want your knife.
you're right
about one thing.
you are ready.
and now's the time, too -
lilith's guard's down.
is that so?
she's on shore leave,
a little r&r.
what the hell
does that mean?
trust me -
you don't want to know.
you didn't lose
those hex bags i gave you?
we got 'em. good. then she
won't sense that you're coming.
so, you'll give us
the knife?
no.
but you just said..
you want to charging with one little pissed sicker?
it's a waste
of a true-blue window,
like hitting h ???
okay, then how?
i know how to save
your brother, sam.
no, you don't!
you told dean you couldn't.
you've been lying to me
all along!
so, just give me
your damn knife!
you're not the one
that i've been lying to.
oh, so you can save him?
no.
but you can.
what?
sam, you've got
some god-given talent.
well, not god given,
but you get the gist.
all that psychic crap?
that's gone ever since
yellow eyes died.
not gone.
dormant.
and not just visions,
either.
why do you think lilith
is so scared of you?
right, she's scared of me.
if you wanted, you could wipe her
off the map without moving a muscle.
i don't believe you.
it's the truth.
and you decided
to tell me this just now?
um... demon.
"manipulative" is kind of
in the job description.
the fact is, is that you never
would have considered it,
not until you were -
desperate enough?
you don't like
being different.
you hate the way dean
looks at you sometimes,
like you're some sort
of sideshow freak.
but suck it up because we got
a lot of ground to cover,
and we got to do it fast.
but we can do it.
look, call me a bitch,
hate me all you want,
but i have never lied
to you, sam.
not ever.
and i'm telling you -
you can save your brother.
and i can show you how.
dean:
so, that's you, huh?
our slutty little yoda.
dean.
charming as ever.
oh, i knew you'd show up...
'cause i knew
sam wouldn't listen!
but you're not gonna
teach him anything.
you understand me?
over my dead body.
oh. well, you're right
about that.
what you are gonna do
is give me that knife.
then you can go crawl back
into whatever slop you came from
and never bother me
or my brother again.
are we clear?
your brother is carrying
a bomb inside of him,
and we'd be stupid
not to use it.
dean, look,
just hold on -
sam, don't. come on, man.
what are you, blind?
can't you see
that this is a trick?
that's not true.
she wants you to give in
to this whole demonic,
psychic whatever, okay?
hell, she probably
wants you to become
her little
"antichrist superstar."
i want lilith dead.
that's all.
why?
i've told you why.
oh, right, yeah.
because you were
human once,
and you liked kittens
and long walks on the beach.
you know, i am so sick
of proving myself to you.
you want to save yourself,
this is how,
you dumb, spineless dick!
whoa! ruby, hey!
what the hell
are you grinning at?
missing something?
i'll kill you,
you son of a bitch.
like i said...
i knew you'd come.
wait!
you're just gonna
leave me here?
let's go, sam.
oh, so, you're just too stupid
to live, is that it?
then fine.
you deserve hell.
i wish i could be there,
dean.
i wish i could smell the flesh
sizzle off your bones!
i wish i could be there
to hear you scream!
and i wish you'd
shut your piehole,
but we don't always
get what we want.
what, you gonna let ruby
rot down there?
that's the idea.
dean, what if, uh...
what if ruby's right?
what if i can
take out lilith?
quit looking at me
likehat.
what, are you gonna give her the
"carrie" stare, and lilith goes poof?
i don't know
what ruby meant.
you know, maybe we should
just go ask her.
sam, you wanted the knife.
i got you the knife.
dean, just listen to me
for a second.
last time,
lilith snapped her fingers
and put 30 demons on our ass,
and all we got's one little knife?
i mean, like you said, we go in smart or we
don't go in at all. well, this ain't smart.
we got one shot at this, dean -
just one.
so, if there's
a surefire way,
they maybe we should
just talk about it.
sam, we are not gonna make
the same mistake all over again.
you said that,
but what does that even mean?
don't you see
a pattern here?
dad's deal,
my deal, now this?
???
that's all ???
ruby's just jerking your chain
down the road.
you know what's it's paved with,
and you know where it's going.
dean.
what are you afraid's
gonna happen?
this is me.
i can handle it.
and if it'll save you -
why even risk it?
because you're my brother.
and because you did
the same thing for me.
oh, i know.
and look how that
turned out.
all i'm saying...
sammy, all i'm saying is
that you're my weak spot.
you are.
and i'm yours.
you don't mean that.
we're - we're family.
i know.
and those evil sons
of bitches know it, too.
i mean, what we'll do for each
other, you know, how far we'll go -
they're using that
against us.
so, what, we just stop
looking out for each other?
no, we stop
being martyrs, man.
we stop spreading it
for these demons.
we take this knife,
and we go after lilith our way,
the way dad taught us to.
and if we go down,
then, uh...
then we go down swinging.
what do you think?
i think you totally
should have been jamming
"eye of the tiger"
right there.
oh, bite me.
i totally rehearsed
that speech, too.
so i need?
yeah. we???
yeah. i guess.
tell me something -
what the hell does
a demon do for fun?
hey, pat.
- tom.
how's that granddaughter
of yours?
homesick, poor thing.
darn bug
that's going around now.
oh, that's too bad.
well, you give her
a big old hug from me and judy.
you bet.
take her easy, tom.
you too, pat.
help us
where is she?
upstairs.
playing with freckles.
we just sit here,
we're dead.
she'll hear you.
it's her or us.
's my baby girl.
not anymore.
there's something
inside her.
shut your mouth.
she's coming.
what were you guys
talking about?
just how much
we love you.
what - w-what happened
to your dress?
oh, freckles
was mean to me.
that's -
that's nice, dear.
daddy, will you push me
on the swing?
sure... honey...
but don't you want
to change first?
you don't want
the neighbors to see...
all that blood.
oh, you're so smart.
i love you, daddy.
uh, i love you, too.
hey, sweetie...
u think
maybe after a while,
do you think
maybe you could...
...let us go?
why?
i, uh...
well, i don't know.
don't you want to be here?
don't you love me?
well, sure i do.
we all do, honey.
we all love you so much.
don't be mean
to me, daddy,
like freckles
or what's her name,
that mean old babysitter.
i- i'm sorry.
that's okay, silly!
now let's go and play.
where do you think
you're going?
we got the knife.
and you intend to use it
without me?
do i look like
a ditchable prom date to you?
no, bobby, of course not.
this is about me
and sam, okay?
this isn't your fight.
the hell it isn't!
family don't end
with blood, boy.
besides, you need me.
bobby -
you're playing wounded.
tell me, how many hallucinations
have you had so far?
how'd you know?
because that's what happens when
you got hellhounds on your butt,
and because i'm smart.
i'll follow.
don't be stopping to pee
every 10 minutes, either.
sam: hey, dean?
yeah?
you know, if this doesn't -
if this doesn't go the way we
want, i want you to know that -
no. no, no,
no, no, no.
"no" what?
you're not gonna bust out
the misty goodbye speech, okay?
i mean, if this is
my last day on earth,
i do not want it to be
socially awkward.
you know what i do want?
bon jovi?
bon jovi rocks...
on occasion.
* and i walk these streets! *
* a loaded six-string on my back! *
* i play for keeps! *
come on.
* 'cause i might not make it back! *
* i've been everywhere! *
* oh, yeah *
* but i'm standing tall! *
* i've seen a million faces *
* and i've rocked 'em all *
* 'cause i'm a cowboy *
* on a steel horse, i ride *
* i'm wanted *
* wanted! *
* dead or alive *
* dead or alive
* dead or ali-i-ve
we getting pulled over?
i got a busted taillight.
it's not like we're
in a hurry or nothin'.
problem, officer?
license and registration,
please.
did you realize you have
a taillight out, mr... hagar?
yes. yes, sir.
uh, you know, i've been
meaning to take care of that.
as a matter of fact...
dean!
what the hell happened?
dean just killed a demon.
how'd you know?
i just knew.
i could see its face,
its real face under that one.
so, what, now you're
seeing demons?
i've been seeing all kinds of
things lately, but nothing like this.
actually, it's not
all that crazy.
how is it not that crazy?
well, you got just
over five hours to go?
you're piercing the veil, dean,
glimpsing the "b" side.
little less new agey,
please.
you're almost hell's bitch,
so you can see
hell's other bitches.
thank you.
it'll actually come in
pretty handy.
oh, well, i'm glad my doomed soul's
good for something. damn right it is.
lilith's probably got
demons stashed all over town.
we can't let 'em
sound the alarm.
if she knows we're here,
we're dead before we started.
wow, this is
a terrific plan.
i'm excited to be
a part of it.
can we go, please?
woman:
happy birthday, sweetie.
both: happy birthday!
yay, it's my birthday
every day!
cake... again.
it's good.
hey, grandpa,
can i ask you something?
sure, jelly bean, anything.
why'd you try to go
to mr. wepram for help?
uh, well, i didn't.
i don't know what you mean.
you're a big, fat liar.
i'm sorry.
it was a mistake.
did you two
know about this?
no.
grandpa,
you don't love me?
i do. i do.
i love you.
no. you don't.
you're lying again.
you're just
a mean, old man.
do something.
help me, please.
i don't think
i like you anymore.
nobody scream, okay?
screaming makes me mad.
mommy, can i have
ice cream with mine?
dean:
it's the little girl.
god, h face
is awful.
all right, then let's go.
we're wasting time.
wait!
for what?
for her to kill
the rest of them?
yeah, and us too
if we're not careful.
look.
see the real go-getter mailman
on the clock at 9:00 p.m.?
and mr. rogers
over there.
bobby: demons?
yes.
okay, fine, we ninja past
those guys, sneak in.
and, what, give a columbian
necktie to a 10-year-old girl?
come on. look, dean, i know it's awful.
you think?
this isn't just about
saving you, dean.
this is about
saving everybody.
she's got to
be stopped, son.
oh, damn it.
girl:
read it again, mommy.
but i've read it 26 times.
again.
"once upon a time
"in the town of celine
"lived a beautiful princess
named cleo.
"but the town was plagued
with an evil dragon
"that demanded
the blood of the children.
"and the princess was doomed
to be sacrificed
to the dark
and terrible dragon."
exorcizo te, creatura aquae,
in nomine del
patris onmipotentis.
i'd like
my knife back, please.
or your neck snaps
like a chicken bone.
he doesn't have it. take it easy.
how the hell
did you get out?
what you don't know about me
could fill a book.
oh.
what?
nothing. i just couldn't see you before,
but you are one ugly broad.
sam, give me the knife
before you hurt yourself.
you'll get it
when this is over.
it's already over.
i gave you a way
to save dean.
you shot me down.
now it's too late.
he's dead.
and i'm not gonna
let you die, too.
try and stop me,
and i'll kill you, bitch.
hit me with
your best shot, baby.
guys, guys!
hey.
have your little
catfight later.
so much for the element
of surprise.
let's go.
go. run. run!
what the hell's
taking bobby?
dean: sam!
i'm trying!
you think lilith
knows we're here?
probably.
shh! shh! shh!
shh! shh!
we're here to help, okay?
i'm gonna move my hand,
and we're gonna talk
nice and quiet, okay?
sam: sir, where
is your daughter?
it's not -
it's not her anymore.
where is she?
upstairs in her bedroom.
dean: okay, okay, okay,
listen to me.
i want you to go downstairs
to the basement,
put a line of salt
at the door behind you.
do you understand me?
not without my wife.
yes, without your wife.
no, not -
do it!
hurry!
wait. wait.
it's not her!
it's not
in the girl anymore!
damn it.
all right,
no matter what you hear,
you, your husband, and your
daughter stay in the basement.
well, i hate to be
a told-you-so.
all right, ruby,
where is she?
i don't know.
could she get past
the sprinklers?
her pay grade, she ain't
sweating the holy water.
okay. you win.
what do i have to do?
what do you mean?
to save dean.
what do you
need me to do?
what the hell do you
think you're doing?
just shut up for a second.
ruby!
you had your chance.
you can't just flip a switch.
we needed time.
well, there's got to be something.
there's got to be some way.
whatever it is -
i'll do it.
don't - dean! i'm not gonna
let you go to hell, dean!
yes, you are!
yes, you are.
i'm sorry.
i mean,
this is all my fault.
i know that.
but what you're doing,
it's not gonna save me.
it's only gonna kill you.
then what am i
supposed to do?
keep fighting.
and take care
of my wheels.
sam, remember what
dad taught you...
okay?
and remember
what i taught you.
ruby:
i'm sorry, dean.
i wouldn't wish this
upon my worst enemy.
hellhound.
where?
there.
give me the knife.
maybe i can fight it off.
what?
come on!
that dust won't
last forever.
wait.
you want to die?
sam, that's not ruby.
it's not ruby!
how long you been in her?
not long...
but i like it.
it's all grown-up
and pretty.
and where's ruby?
she was a very bad girl,
so i sent her far, far away.
you know, i should have
seen it before.
but you all
look alike to me.
hello, sam.
i've wanted to meet you
for a very long time.
your lips are soft.
all right,
so you have me.
let my brother go.
silly goose.
you want to bargain, you have
to have something that i want.
you don't.
so, is this
your big plan, huh?
drag me to hell, kill sam,
and then what -
become queen bitch?
i don't have to answer
to puppy chow.
sic him, boy.
no! stop!
stop it!
no. stop it.
no!
yes.
back.
i said, back.
i don't think so.
no.
dean.
dean: help!
help!
no.
somebody help me!
sam!