Dad wants us to pick up
where he left off...
saving people,
hunting things.
The family business.
THEN
Anybody here?
Don't move.
Sam? Dean?
Mom, you know these guys?
I think these are John Winchester's boys.
Hey, I'm Ellen.
That's my daughter, Jo.
You're not gonna hit me again, are you?
You called our dad,
said you could help.
Help with what?
The demon, of course.
How do you know about all this?
Hey, I just run a saloon.
Hunters have been known
to pass through now and again --
including your dad a long time ago.
John was like family once.
You think dad and Ellen ever had a thing?
No way.
Then why didn't he tell us about her?
How did your mom get into this stuff?
My dad. He was a hunter.
He passed away.
I could help
I'm sure you could,
but I think your mother might kill me.
You're afraid of my mother?
I think so.
NOW
PHILADELPHIA, PENNSYLVANIA
I checked the fuses. They're fine.
It's the wiring!
Look, you promised this placewould
be ready when I moved in.
No! You come up now!
Please.
Thank you.
Gross.
What the hell?
-=www.ydy.com/bbs=-
proudly presents
sync:YTET-cflily
-=www.ydy.com/bbs=-
SUPERNATURAL
Season 02 Episode 06
Los Angeles, California.
What's in L.A.?
A young girl's been kidnapped
by an evil cult.
Yeah?
- The girl got a name?
- Katie holmes.
That's funny.
Of course, on the other hand,
catfight.
I am your mother!
I don't have to be reasonable!
You can't keep me here!
Don't you bet on that,
sweetie!
Are you gonna chain me up
in the basement?
You've had worse ideas
than that recently.
You don't want to stay?
Don't -- go back to school!
I didn't belong there!
I was a freak with a knife collection!
Getting yourself killed on some dusty back road --
that's where you belong?
- Guys,bad time.
- Yes,ma'am.
We rarely drink
before 10:00 anyway.
Wait.
I want to know what
they think about this.
I don't care
what they think!
Are you guys open?
- Yes!
- No!
We'll just check out
the arby's down the road.
Harvelle'S.
Yeah,preacher.
Three weeks ago,a young girl disappears
from a philadelphia apartment.
Take it.
It won't bite.
No,but your mom might.
And this girl wasn't the first.
Over the past 80 years,6 women have vanished --
all from the same building,
all young blondes.
It only happens every decade or two,
so cops never eyeball the pattern.
So we're either dealing with one
very old serial killer --
who put this together?
Ash?
I did it myself.
I got to admit,
we hit the road for a lot less.
Good. If you like the case
so much,you take it.
Joanna beth,this family
has lost enough.
I won't lose you,too.
I just won'T.
Mother told me
yes,she told me
I'd meet girls like you
she also told me,
"stay away
you'll never know
what you'll catch"
Mommy's all right,
daddy's all right
they just seem
a little weird
surrender,surrender
I feel kind of bad,
snaking jo's case.
Well,maybe she put together
a good file,
but could you see her out here
working one of these things?
I don't think so.
You getting anything?
No,not yet.
What's that?
What?
Holy crap.
That's ectoplasm.
Well,sam,I think I know
what we're dealing with here.
It's the stay-puftmarshmallow man.
Dean,I've only seenthis stuff like twice.
I mean,to make this stuff,
you have to be one majorlypissed-off spirit.
Let's find this badass
before he snags any more girls.
Yeah,it's a great building.
I fixed it up real nice.
All the apartmentscome furnished,too.
Yeah,I lovethe furnishings.
It's so spacious,
and the locationis so convenient for me.
What the hellare you doing here?
There you are,honey.
This is my boyfriend,dean,and his buddy sam.
Good to meet you.Quite a gal you got here.
Yeah,she's a pistol!
So,did you already check outthe apartment?
The one for rent.
Yeah. Yes. Loved it.
Great flow.
- How'd you get in?
- It was open.
Now,ed,when did the lasttenant move out?
Uh,about a month ago.
Cut and run,too.
Stiffed me for the rent.
Well,her loss,our gain,
'cause if deano loves it,
it's good enough for me.
Oh,sweetie.
We'll take it.
Okay.
I'll flip youfor the sofa.
Does your mother even knowyou're here?
I told herI was going to vegas.
You thinkshe's gonna buy that?
I'm not an idiot.
I got ash to laya credit-card trail
all the wayto the casinos.
You shouldn't lieto your mom.
You shouldn't be here,either.
Well,I am,so untwist
your boxers and deal with it.
Where'd you get allthat money from,anyways?
Working at the roadhouse.
Hunters don't tip that well.
They aren't that goodat poker,either.
- Yeah?
- Is she with you?
Oh,hi,ellen.
She left a noteshe's in vegas.
I don't believe itfor a second.
-*************
- Dean?
- I haven't seen her.
- You sure about that?
- Yeah,I'm sure.
Well,please,if she shows up,
you'll drag her butt back here,won't you?
- Absolutely.
- Okay. Thanks,hon.
This place was builtin 1924.
It was originallya warehouse,
converted into apartmentsa few months ago.
Yeah?What was here before 1924?
Nothing.An empty field.
So the most likelyscenario --
someone died bloodyin the building,
and now he's backand raising hell.
I already checked.
In the past 82 years,zero violent deaths,
unless you count a janitorwho slipped
on a wet floor.
Would you sit down,please?
So,have you checkedthe police reports,
county death records?
Obituaries,mortuary reports,
and seven other sources.
I know what I'm doing.
I think the jury's still outon that one.
Would you putthe knife down?
Okay.
So,uh,it'ssomething else,then.
Maybe some kindof cursed object
that brought a spiritwith it.
We got to scanthe whole building.
Right.So,you and me --
we'll take the toptwo floors.
We'd move fasterif we split up.
Oh,this isn't negotiable.
So,are you gonnabuy me dinner?
What are youtalking about?
It's just if you're gonnaride me this close,
it's only decentyou buy me dinner.
Oh,that's hilarious.
It's bad enoughI lied to your mom,
but if you think I'm lettingyou out of my sight --
I don't knowif you noticed,
but you're kindof the spirit's type.
Exactly.
You want to be bait?
The quickest way to draw it out,and you know it.
- What?
- I'm so regretting this.
I've had it up to herewith your crap.
Excuse me?
Your chauvinist crap.
You think womencan't do the job.
Sweetheart,this ain't gender studies.
Women can do the job fine.
Amateurs can'T.You got no experience.
What you do have is a bunchof
half-baked romantic notions
that some barfly has putin your head.
And now you sound likemy mother.
Oh,and that's a bad thing
?Because let me tell you --
what?
Forget it.
No,you started this.
Jo,you got options.
No one in their right mindchooses this life.
My dad started me in thiswhen I was so young.
I wish I could dosomething else.
You love the job.
Yeah,butI'm a little twisted.
You don't thinkI'm a little twisted,too?
Jo,you got a motherthat worries about you,
who wants somethingmore for you.
Those are good things.
You don't throw thingslike that away.
They might be hardto find later.
What?
I'm not sure.
Do you smell that?
What is it,a gas leak?
No.It's something else.
I know it.
I just can't put my fingeron it.
Mazel tov.
You just foundyour first spirit.
It's inside the vent.
Here.
There's somethingin there. Here.
Someone's keepingsouvenirs.
This building -- I swear to god.
I'm so out of here.
Morning,princess.
- Where's sam?
- Went to get coffee.
My back.
How'd you sleepon that big,soft bed?
I didn'T.
I've just been going overeverything.
Here.
What's this for?
It'll work a hellof a lot better than that little
pigstick you've been twirling around.
W A H
William anthony harvelle.
I'm sorry.My mistake.
What do you --
what do you rememberabout your dad?
What's the first thingthat pops into your head?
Come on. Tell me.
I was 6 or 7...
and,uh...
he took me shootingfor the first time.
Bottles on a fence --that kind of thing.
I bull's-eyedevery one of them.
And he would smile,like...
*****************
he must have been proud.
What about your dad?
I was still in pigtailswhen my dad died,but...
I remember him coming homefrom a hunt.
He'd burstthrough that door like --
like steve mcqueenor something.
And he'd sweep me upin his arms,
and I'd breathe in that oldleather jacket of his.
And my mom --who was sour and pissed
from the minute he left -
she started smiling again.
And we were...
we were a family.
You want to know whyI want to do the job?
For him.
It's my way of being closeto him.
Now,tell me,what's wrong with that?
Nothing.
- Where's the coffee?
- There are cops outside.
Another girl disappeared.
Theresa ellis --apartment 2-F.
Her boyfriend reported hermissing around dawn.
And her apartment?
Cracks all over the plaster --walls,ceiling.
There's ectoplasm,too.
Between thatand that tuft of hair,
I'd say the sucker'scoming from the walls.
But who is it?
The building's history'stotally clean.
Maybe we're lookingin the wrong place.
- What do you mean?
- Check this out.
An empty field?
It's where this buildingwas built.
Take a look at the onenext door.
The windows.
Bars.
We're next doorto a prison?
Thanks,ash.
Oh,and if you breathe a wordof this to my mom --
that's right. I will.With pliers.
Okay.
Moyamensing prison --
built in 1835,torn down in 1963.
And get this --
they used to execute peopleby hanging them
in the empty field next door.
Well,then,we need a list
of all the peopleexecuted there.
Ash is already on it.
157 names?
- We got to narrow that down.
- Yeah.
Or else we're gonna be diggingup a hell
of a lot of stiffs.
Herman webster mudgett?
Yeah?
Wasn't that H.H. Holmes'real name?
You got to be kidding me.
MULTI-MURDERER MEET HIS  M******
Holmes was executedat moyamensing may 7,1896.
H.H. Holmes himself.
Come on.I mean,what are the odds?
Who is this guy?
The term "multi-murderer" --
they coined itto describe holmes.
He was america's firstserial killer
before anybody knewwhat a serial killer was.
He confessed to 27 murders,
but some put the death tollat over 100.
And his victim flavorof choice --
pretty,petite blondes.
He,uh,used chloroformto kill them,
which is what I smelledin the hallway last night.
At his place,cops found human remains,
bone fragments,and long locksof bloody blond hair.
Boy,he sure knewhow to pick them.
We just find the bones,
salt them,and burn them,right?
It's not that easy.
His body is buried in town,
but it's encased in a coupletons of concrete.
What? Why?
The story goesthat he didn't want
anybody mutilatinghis corpse
'cause,you know,it's what he used to do.
You know something?
We might have an even biggerproblem than that.
How does this get bigger?
Holmes built an apartmentbuilding in chicago.
They called itthe murder castle.
The whole placewas a death factory.
They had trapdoors,acid vats,quicklime pits.
He built thesesecret chambers...
inside the walls.
He'd lock his victims in,keep them alive for days.
Some,he'd suffocate.
Others,he'd letstarve to death.
So theresa couldstill be alive.
She could beinside these walls.
We need sledgehammers,crowbars.
We got to smash these walls
anywhere thick enoughto hide a girl.
Okay.
Call us after you checkthe southeast wall.
Sam's almost donewith the first floor.
He hasn't foundjack squat,either.
What is it?
It's too narrow.We can't go any further.
- Let me see.
- What are you --
- I should have cleanedthe pipes.
- What?
I wish the pipeswere clean.
Shut up!
I can fit in there.
You're not going in thereby yourself.
You got a better idea?
The --
- Where are you?
- By the north wall.
I'm heading downsome kind of air duct.
No,no,no,no.Stay up here.
We got to find this girl,don't we?
I'm okay.
All right.I'm heading to you.
Oh,god.
What is it?
Jo? Jo?!
Jo!
Jo?!
- He's got jo.
- What?How'd that happen?
I wasn't with her.I left her alone.
Damn it!
Look,we'll find her.Where?
Inside the walls.We were inside the walls.
None of the other girlsare there.
She won't be,either.
Look,take a beatand think about this.
Maybe we got holmes'M.O. Wrong.
Well,we better friggin'think fast.
Yeah?
You lied to me.She's there.
- Ellen.
- Ash told me everything.
The man's a genius,but he folds like a cheap suit.
You put my damn daughteron the phone.
She's gonna haveto call you back.
She's,uh,taking careof feminine business.
Yeah,right.Where is she?
Where is she?!
Look,we'll get her back.
Get her back?Back from what?
The spirit we're hunting --it took her.
Oh,my god.
She'll be okay.
I promise.You promise?
*******************That is not the first time
I'veheard that from a winchester.
What?
If anything happens to her --
it won'T.I won't let it.
Ellen,I'm sorry.I really am.
I'm taking the firstflight out.
I'll be there in a few hours.
Damn it!
Don't beat yourself up,dean.
There's nothingyou could have done.
Tell me you got something.
Uh,maybe.
Look.
If you look at the layout
of the holmes murder castle,
there's other torture chambersinside
the walls,right?
But there's one we haven'tconsidered yet --
the one in his basement.
This building doesn't havea basement.
You're right.It doesn'T.
But I just noticed this.
Beneath the foundation,
it looks like partof an old sewer system.
It hasn't been used for --
let's go.
Hello?
Is -- is anybody there?
Your name's theresa?
Yes.
This won't make youfeel better,but...
I'm here to rescue you.
Oh,god.He's out there.
He's gonna kill us!
No,he won't!
We're getting out.
My friendsare looking for us.
Oh,god,it's him!
Shh! Just be quiet!
Here.
Got it?Yeah.
You're so pretty.
So beautiful.
Go to hell!
How do you like that?!
Pure iron,you creepy-assson of a bitch!
Is he gone?
I don't know.
I --
Hey!
No!
Jo!
I'm here!
Hey. I'm gonna get you out
of here,all right?
Sam!
Hang on.
- You all right?
- I've been better.
Let's get the hell out of here
before he comes back.
Actually,I don't think
you're leaving here just yet.
What?
Remember when I saidyou
being bait was a bad plan?
Now it's kind ofthe only one we got.
Now!
Scream all you want!
There's no way you're steppingover that salt!
So...
is this job as glamorous
as you thought it would be?
Well,except for all thepee-
your-pants terror,yeah.
But that theresa girl'sgonna
live a life 'cause of us.
It's worth it,isn't it?
Yeah.
Yeah,it is.
Hey,what if somebodyfinds
that sewer done there
or a stormwashes the salt away?
Both very fine points,
which is why we're waiting here.
For what?
FOR THIAT
You ripped offa cement truck?
I'll give it back.
Well,that ought tokeep him down there
till hell freezes over.
well,you --
you really weren't kidding
about flying out,were you?
How about we listento some music?
You're as cold as ice
This is gonna bea long drive.
Ellen...
it was my fault.Okay?
I lied to you,and I'm sorry.
But jo did good out there.
I think her dad would be proud.
Don't you dare say that --not you.
I need a momentwith my daughter --
alone.
You're angry.I understand.
Angry doesn't beginto touch it!
Let's just think about this.
Everything's okay.
I'm alive.
Not afterI'm through with you!
Is this about me huntingor something else?
You let those boysuse you as bait.
They were backing me upthe whole time.
That is why you do not have
the sense to do this job.
- You're trusting your lifeto them.
- What are you talking about?
Like father,like son.
That is whatI'm talking...
john?
I thought you and johnwere friends.
Yeah,we were. I'm sorry.
I didn't mean --
mom...
what aren't youtelling me?
- That bad,huh?
- Not right now.
What happened?Hey,talk to me.
Get off me!
Sorry.I'll see you around.
Dean...
it turns out my dad hada partner
on his last hunt.
Funny,he usually worked alone.
This guy did,too.
But I guess my father figuredhe
could trust him.
A mistake.
The guy screwed up,got my dad killed.
- What does this have --
- it was your father,dean.
What?
Why do you thinkjohn never came back,
never told you about us?
'Cause he couldn't look
my momin the eye after that --
that's why.
- Jo --
- just --
just get out of here.
Please,just leave.
-=www.ydy.com/bbs=-
proudly presents
sync:YTET-cflily
-=www.ydy.com/bbs=-
SUPERNATURAL
Season 02 Episode 06