Lilith is trying to break the 66 seals
To free lucifer from hell.
- Who are you - castiel.
I'm an angel of the lord.
Anna,you all right
I remember now who i am.
I'm an angel.
You can't run...dean.
Alastair.
This is uriel,a specialist.
Pamela barnes,best damn psychic in the state.
Pamela!
He took me off the rack,and i tortured souls,
And i liked it.
No matter how many people i save,
I can't fill this hole.
It's not the psychic thing i got a problem with.
Yeah,i know what you got a problem with,
But tough.
-  -
It's the only way. no.
I know what you did to that demon,sam.
!
Pamela!
Goodbye,sister.
What the hell
Ruby will meet us outside cheyenne.
She's been tracking some leads.
Look,i know she's not exactly on your christmas list,
But if she can help us get to lilith --
Man,work with ruby,don't. i don't really give a rat's ass.
What's your problem
Pamela didn't want anything to do with this,
And we dragged her back into it,sam.
She knew what was at stake.
Oh,yeah,saving the world.
And we're doing such a damn good job of it.
Dean --
I'm tired of burying friends,sam.
Look,if we catch a fresh trail --
We follow it. i know.
Like i said,i'm just -- i'm just getting tired.
Well,get angry.
""
Home,crappy home.
Winchester and winchester.
Oh,come on!
You are needed.
Needed
We just got back from needed!
Now,you mind your tone with me.
No,you mind your damn tone with us.
We just got back from pamela's funeral.
Pamela -- you know,psychic pamela
You remember her.
Cass,you remember her. you burned her eyes out.
Remember that good times!
Yeah,then she died saving one of your precious seals.
So,maybe you can stop pushing us around like chess pieces
For five freakin' minutes!
We raised you out of hell for our purposes.
Yeah,and what were those again
What exactly do you want from me
Start with gratitude.
Dean,we know this is difficult to understand.
...
And we...
...don't...care.
All of them from our garrison.
The last one was killed tonight.
Demons
How they doing it
We don't know.
I'm sorry,but what do you want us to do about it
I mean,a demon with the juice to ice angels
Has to be out of our league,right
We can handle the demons,thank you very much.
Once we find whoever it is.
...
So,you need our help...
Hunting a demon
Not quite.
We have alastair. great.
He should be able to name your triggerman.
But he won't talk.
Alastair's will is very strong.
We've arrived at an impasse.
Yeah,well,he's like a black belt in torture.
I mean,you guys are out of your league.
That's why we've come to his student.
You happen to be
the most qualified interrogator we've got.
Dean...
You're our best hope.
No.
No way.
You can't ask me to do this,cass -- not this.
...
Who said anything...
about asking
Damn it!
This devil's trap is old enochian.
He's bound completely.
Fascinating.
Where's the door
Where are you going
Hitch back to Cheyenne,thank you very much.
Angels are dying,boy.
Everybody's dying these days.
You can make me do whatever you want,
but you can't make me do this.
This is too much to ask. I know.
But we have to ask it.
I want to talk to Cass alone.
I think I'll go seek...
revelation.
We might have some further orders.
Well,get some doughnuts while you're out.
Ah,this one just won't quit,will he
I think I'm starting to like you,boy.
You guys don't walk enough. You're gonna get flabby.
You know,I'm starting to think
Junkless has a better sense of humor than you do.
Uriel's the funniest angel in the garrison.
Ask anyone.
What's going on,cass
Since when does Uriel put a leash on you
My superiors have begun to question my sympathies.
Your sympathies
I was getting too close to the humans in my charge.
You.
They feel I've begun to express emotions,
the doorways to doubt.
This can impair my judgment.
...
Well,tell Uriel or whoever...
...you do not want me doing this,trust me.
Want it No.
But I've been told we need it.
...
You ask me to open that door and walk through it...
you will not like what walks back out.
...
For what it's worth...
I would give anything
not to have you do this.
Heaven.
I'm in heaven
And my heart beats so that I can hardly speak
I seem to find the happiness I seek
When we're out together dancing
Cheek to cheek.
I'm sorry.
I --
This is a very serious,very emotional situation for you.
I shouldn't laugh.
It's just that,I mean,are they serious
They sent you to torture me
You got one chance.
One.
Tell me who is killing the angels.
I want a name.
You think I'll see all your scary toys
and spill my guts
Oh,you'll spill your guts,one way or another.
I just didn't want to ruin my shoes.
...
Well...
Now answer the question.
Or what you'll work me over
...
But then,maybe...
You don't want to.
...
Maybe...
you're a-scared to
I'm here,aren't I
Not entirely.
You left part of yourself back in the pit.
Let's see if we can...
Get the two of you back together again,shall we
You're gonna be disappointed.
You have not disappointed me so far.
Come on.
You got to want a little payback
For everything I did to you
For all the pokes and prods.
No
Then...
How about for all the things I did to your daddy
I can still smell them.
Seriously,Sam,I'm not exactly dying
to tangle with angels again.
I need you to find out where they took dean.
Not sure I see the problem.
You know they have Alastair
strung up six ways from sunday.
Dean cuts himself a slice,
Al's reduced to a quivering heap,
And the good guys get the goods.
What's wrong with that
He can't do it.
Look,I get it.
You don't want him going all torture master again.
No,I mean,he can't do it.
He can't get the job done.
Something happened to him downstairs,Ruby.
He's not what he used to be. he's not strong enough.
And you are
I will be.
Had your pop on my rack for close to a century.
Can't stall forever.

John Winchester -- made quite a name for himself.
A hundred years.
And after each session,
I'd make him the same offer I made you.
I'd put down my blade if he picked one up.
Just give me the demon's name,Alastair.
But...
He said,"nein"...
...each and every time.
Damned if I couldn't break him.
Pulled out all the stops.
But John,he was... made of something unique.
The stuff of heroes.
And then came Dean.

Mmm,Dean Winchester.
I thought I was up against it again.
But daddy's little girl --
He broked.
He broked in 30.
Just not the man your daddy wanted you to be,huh,Dean
Now...
Now we're getting somewhere.
Holy water
Come on!
Grasshopper,you're gonna have
to get creative to impress me.
You know something,Alastair
I could still dream,even in hell.
And over and over and over,you know what I dreamt
I dreamt of this moment.
And believe me...
...I got a few ideas.
Let's get started.
Let me know if you want some more.
There's plenty left.
Go directly to hell.
Do not pass go. do not collect $200.
Mihi pareas.
Ubicumque in occultatione sis,
Defigo te ut mihi pareas.
Igni...fiat...
Notum.
Relax. The fire is our friend.
Besides,the only part of the map we need
""
is the "where's dean" part.
Out.
There. your brother is there.
And it's a good thing angels aren't concerned
with hiding their dirty business.
Not used to being spied on.
I mean,who'd be stupid enough to try
Ruby,it's been weeks.
I need it.
You don't seem too happy about it.
You think i want to do this
This is the last thing i --
But i need to be strong enough.
It's okay.
It's okay,Sammy.
You can have it.
It's okay,sam.
There's that little pig poker.
I wondered where it went.
Do you really think this is gonna fix you
Give you closure
Oh,that is sad.
That's really sad.
Sad,sad.
I...carved you into a n-new animal,Dean.
There is no...going back.
Maybe you're right.
But now it's my turn to carve.
Who's behind the murders
I want the demon's name.
Anna.
Hello,Castiel.
Your human body.
It was destroyed. i know.
But...
I guess i'm sentimental.
Called in some old favors,and...
You shouldn't be here.
We still have orders to kill you.
Somehow,i don't think you'll try.
Where's Uriel
He went to receive revelation.
Right.
Well,it's your professionalism that i respect.
Why are you letting Dean do this
He's doing god's work.
Torturing
That's god's work
Stop him,Cass,please.
Before you ruin the one real weapon you have.
Who are we to question the will of god
Unless... this isn't his will.
Then where do the orders come from
I don't know. one of our superiors maybe.
But not him.
Who's murdering the angels
The father you love...
You think he wants this
You think he'd ask this of you
You think this is righteous
What you're feeling...
It's called doubt.
These orders are wrong,
And you know it.
But you can do the right thing.
You're afraid,Cass.
I was,too.
But together,we can --
Together
I am nothing like you.
You fell.
Go.
Cass.
Just not getting deep enough.
Well,you lack the resources.
Reality is just...
I don't know.
...too concrete up here.
Honestly,Dean...
You have no idea how bad it really was...
And what you really did for us.
Shut up.
The whole bloody thing,Dean.
The reason Lilith wanted you there in the first place.
Okay,then i'll just make you shut up.
S-sorry.
Something caught in my throat.
I think it's my throat.
Well,strap in.
'cause i'm just starting to have fun.
It was supposed to be your father.
He was supposed to bring it on.
But in the end,it was you.
Bring what on
Every night,the same offer,remember
Same as your father.
And finally you said,"sign me up."
Oh,the first time you picked up my razor,
The first time
You sliced into that weeping bitch...
That was the first seal.
You're lying.
"and it is written that the first seal shall be broken
"when a righteous man sheds blood in hell.
As he breaks,so shall it break."
We had to break the first seal before any others.
Only way to get the dominoes to fall right.
Topple the one at the front of the line.
When we win...
When we bring on the apocalypse
And burn this earth down...
We'll owe it all to you...

Dean winchester.
Believe me,son.
I wouldn't lie about this.
It's kind of a...
...religious sort of thing with me.
No.
I don't think you are lying.
But even if the demons do win...
...you won't be there to see it.
You should talk to your plumber about the pipes.
You've got a lot to learn,boy,
So I'll see you back in class,
Bright and early,monday morning.
Oh,almost.
Looks like god is on my side today.
You know...
Like roaches,you celestials.
I really wish I knew how to kill you.
But all I can do is send you back to heaven.
Omnipotentis dei potestateminvoco.
Stupid pet tricks.
Who's murdering the angels
How are they doing it
You think i'm gonna tell you
Yeah,I do.
How are the demons killing angels!
I...
Don't...know!
Right.
It's...not...us!
We're...not doing it!
I don't believe you.
Lilith... is not behind this.
She wouldn't kill seven angels.
She'd kill 100...
1,000.
Oh,go ahead.
Send me back...
If you can.
I'm stronger than that now.
Now I can kill.
-  -
- Sam. -get in there and heal him.
-    -
- Miracle now. - I can't.
-  -
- You and Uriel put him in there! - no.
Because you can't keep a simple devil's trap together.
I don't know what happened. that trap --
It shouldn't have broken. I am sorry.
This whole thing was pointless.
You understand that
The demons aren't doing the hits.
Something else is killing your soldiers.
Perhaps Alastair was lying.
No.
He wasn't.
Castiel
I received revelation from our superiors.
Our brothers and sisters are dying,and they --
They want us to stop hunting the demon responsible.
Something is wrong up there.
I mean,can you feel it
The murderers -- maybe they aren't demonic.

Sam winchester said
the demons have nothing to do with it.
If not the demons,what could it be
The will of heaven.
We are failing,uriel.
We are losing the war.
Perhaps the garrison is being punished.
You think our father would --
I think maybe our father isn't giving the orders anymore.
Maybe there is something wrong.
Well,i won't wait to be gutted.
Anna.
Anna,please.
Decided to kill me after all
I'm alone.
What do you want from me,castiel
I'm considering disobedience.
Good.
No. it isn't.
For the first time...
I feel.
It gets worse.
Choosing your own course of action --
It's confusing...
It's terrifying.
That's right.
You're too good for my help.
I'm just trash...
A walking blasphemy.
Anna...
I don't know what to do.
Please tell me what to do.
Like the old days
No.
I'm sorry.
It's time to think for yourself.
You called
What do you say,castiel
Will you join me
Will you fight with me
It's strange...
Strange how...
A leaky pipe
Can undo the work of angels
When we ourselves...
Are supppped to be the agents of fate.
Alastair was much more powerful than we had imagined.
No.
No demon can overpower that trap.
I made it myself.
We've been friends for a long time,uriel.
Fought by each others' sides,
Served together away from home...
...for what seems like...
Forever.
We're brothers,uriel.
Pay me that respect. tell me the truth.
The truth is...
The only thing that can kill an angel...
...is another angel.
You.
I'm afraid so.
And you broke the devil's trap,
Set alastair on dean.
Alastair should never have been taken aliv
Really inconvenient,cass.
Yes,i did turn the screw a little.
Alastair should' killed deanand,
For the murders of our kin
Not murders,castiel.
No.
My work...is conversion.
How long have we waited here
How long have we played this game
By rules that make no sense
It is our father's world,uriel.
Our father
He stopped being that,if he ever was,
The moment he created them.
Humanity.
His favorites.
His whining,puking larvae.
Are you trying to convert me
I wanted you to join me,and i still do.
With you,we can be powerful enough to --
to
to raise our brother.
lucifer.
you do remember him.
how strong he was...
how beautiful.
and he didn't bow to humanity.
he was punished for defending us.
now,if you want to believe in something,cass,
believe in him.
Lucifer is not god.
god isn't god anymore.
he doesn't care what we do.
i am proof of that.
but this
what were you gonna do,uriel
were you gonna kill the whole garrison
i only killed the ones who said no.
others have joined me,cass.
now,please,brother. don't fight me.
help me.
help me spread the word.
help me bring on this apocalypse.
all you have to do...
is be unafraid.
for the first time in a long time...
...i am.
you can't win,uriel.
i still serve god.
you haven't even met the man!
there is no will!
no wrath!
no...god.
maybe or maybe not.
but there's still me.
are you all right
no thanks to you.
you need to be more careful.
you need to learn how to manage a damn devil's trap.
that's not what i mean.
uriel is dead.
was it the demons
it was disobedience.
he was working against us.
is it true
did i break the first seal
did i start all this
yes.
when we discovered lilith's plan for you...
...we laid siege to hell,
and we fought our way to get to you before you --
jump-started the apocalypse.
but we were too late.
why didn't you just leave me there,then
it's not...blame that falls on you,dean.
it's fate.
(,)
and the righteous man who begins it
is the only one who can finish it.
you have to stop it.
lucifer
the apocalypse
what does that mean
don't you go disappearing on me,you son of a bitch.
i don't know.
bull!
i don't.
dean,they don't tell me much.
i know...
how our fate rests with you.
well,then,you guys are screwed.
i can't do it,cass.
it's too big.
alastair was right.
i'm not all here.
i'm not -- i'm not strong enough.
well,i guess i'm not the man
either of our dads wanted me to be.
find someone else.
it's not me.