Dad wants us to pick
up where he left off --
Saving people, hunting
things, the family business.
There's a really good
cure for a hangover.
It's a greasy pork sandwich
served up in a dirty ashtray.
Oh, i hate you. I know you do.
We're not gonna start that crap again.
Start what up? That prank stuff.
It's stupid, and it always escalates.
What's the matter, sammy?
Afraid you're gonna get
nair in your shampoo again?
Just remember, you started it.
What
the --
One, me. That's all you got?
It's weak.
You're a friggin' jerk!
You smell like a toilet. Chicken.
Jerk. Bitch.
Shut up. You wuss.
Tch. Jerk.
Bring it on, baldy.
Excuse me.
Are you lost?
No.
I've been waiting for you, professor.
Huh.
Oh, you're in one of my classes?
Don't you recognize me?
Well...
They're big classes.
Anyway, my office hours are
tuesday and thursday mornings.
Really? I was...hoping
i could see you now.
Um...
Well, since you asked
so nicely, come on.
Such a handsome photo.
That old thing.
So, what can i do for you?
How's the anscombe paper coming?
Uh, professor, i
Uh...
I have a confession to make.
Oh? What's that?
I'm not really one of your students.
Really. Then, why are you here?
Maybe i should just go.
Wait.
I get it.
I understand how you're
feeling, and it's only natural.
You are young and wide-Eyed.
And i'm somewhat of a
celebrity around here.
Don't get me wrong, you're
a very beautiful girl.
But it would be wrong of
me to take advantage of you.
I just, uh...
I just respect you too much.
Oh, my god.
What?
Don't you like me anymore?
Don't you want me?
Dude, you mind not
eating those on my bed?
No, i don't mind.
How's the research going?
You know how it's going?
Slow.
You know how it would go
a heck of a lot faster?
If i had my computer.
Can you turn that down, please?
Yeah, absolutely.
You know what?
Maybe you should just go
somewhere for a while, huh?
Hey, i'd love to.
Unfortunately, my car's
all screwed to hell.
I told you, i have
nothing to do --
Hey, bobby. Hey, boys.
Hey, bobby.
It's good to see you again so soon.
Yeah, uh, thanks for coming.
Come on in.
Thank god you're here.
So, um...
What didn't you want to talk
to me on the phone about?
Sam: it's this job we're working.
We weren't sure you'd believe us.
Well, i can believe a lot.
Yeah, yeah, i know.
It's just we've never
seen anything like it.
Not even close.
We thought we could use some fresh eyes.
Why don't you begin at the beginning?
Yeah. Um, all right, please.
So...
It all started when we
caught wind of an obit.
See, a professor took a nose
dive from a fourth-Story window,
Only there's a campus legend
that the building's haunted.
So we pretexted as reporters
from the local paper.
Yeah, we both had the professor
for "ethics and morality."
So, why do you think he did it?
Who knows? He was
tenured, wife and kids.
His book is a really big deal.
Then again, who's to say it was suicide?
Jen, come on.
Well, what else could it be?
Well, you know about crawford hall.
No, i don't, actually.
It's a bunch of crap.
It's a total urban legend.
Well, heather's mom went to school here,
And she knew the girl.
Wait, what girl?
Like, 30 years ago,
This girl was having an
affair with some professor.
He broke it off.
She jumped out the
window and killed herself.
You know her name?
No.
But they say she jumped from room 669.
Get it? You turn the 9 upside down...
So now she haunts the building,
And anyone who sees her...
They don't live to tell the tale.
Well, if no one lives to tell the tale,
Then how does the tale get told?
Curtis, shut up!
You know what? Uh, thanks
a lot, guys. Excuse me.
Dean.
What are you -- What
are you drinking?
I don't know, man.
I think they're called purple nurples.
I think we should check
out the professor's office.
Oh, no, no, no. I can't right now.
I've got a feisty little
wildcat on the hook.
I'm about ready to
-- Zz! -- Reel her in.
I'll introduce
you. De--
Starla. Starla, hey.
This is my shuttle copilot, major tom.
Major tom
-- Starla.
Enchant?
Hi.
Sorry. Just trying to
keep my liquor down.
Yeah. Good job.
Hey, good news.
She's got a sister.
Dean: whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Hold on a minute. What?
Come on, dude. That's
not how it happened.
No?
So you never drank a purple nurple?
Yeah, maybe that, but...
I don't say things like,
"feisty little wildcat."
And her name wasn't starla.
Then what was it?
I don't know, but she
was a classy chick.
She was a grad student,
anthropology and folklore.
We were talking about
local ghost stories.
Here's
to --
Here's to us.
My god, you are attractive.
Thanks. But no time for that now.
You need to tell me
about this urban legend.
Please. Lives are at stake.
Sorry. I just -- I
can't even concentrate.
It's like staring...
Into the sky.
Dean, what do you think you're doing?
Sam, please.
If you wouldn't mind, just
give me five minutes here.
Dean, this is a very
serious investigation.
We don't have time for any
of your blah blah blah blah.
Right.
And that's how it really happened.
I don't sound like that, dean.
That's what you sound like to me. Okay.
What's going on with you two?
Nothing. It's nothing.
Come on.
You're bickering like
an old married couple.
No, see, married
couples can get divorced.
Me and hme? We're
like, uh, siamese twins.
It's "conjoined" twins. See what i mean?
Look,
it --
We've just been on
the road for too long,
Tight quarters, all that.
Don't worry about it.
Okay.
So, anyway, we figured
it might be a haunting,
So we went to check out
the scene of the crime.
So, how long have you been working here?
Janitor: i've been mopping
these floors for six years.
There you go, guys.
What the heck's that for?
Just find the wire in the walls.
Ah. Well.
Not sure why you're
wiring up this office.
Not gonna do the professor much good.
Why's that?
He's dead. Oh.
What happened?
He went out that window right there.
Yeah? Were you working that night?
I'm the one who found him.
You see it happen? Nope.
I just saw him come up here and, uh...
Well... what?
He wasn't alone.
Who was he with?
Come on! I ate one, maybe two.
Just let me tell it, okay?
He was with a young lady.
I told the cops about her,
But i guess they never found her.
You saw this girl go in, huh?
But did you ever see her come out?
Now that you mention it, no.
You ever see her before, around?
Not her.
What do you mean?
I don't mean to cast aspersions
on a dead guy, but, uh...
Mr. Morality here?
He brought a lot of girls up here.
Got more ass than a toilet seat.
One more thing.
This building -- It only
has four stories, right?
Yeah.
So there wouldn't be a room 669?
Of course not. Why do you ask?
Ah, just curious.
Thanks. Sure.
Well, no traces of emf, that's for sure.
And that room 669's a load of crap.
So, what do you think? The
professor's just a jumper?
A legend's just a legend? I don't know.
The girl that the
janitor described --
That's pretty weird. Yeah.
We ought to check out the
history on the building.
See if any coed ganked herself there.
Yeah, you're right.
Dude, were you on my computer?
No. Oh, really?
'Cause it's frozen now
On -- On
bustyasianbeauties.Com.
Dean...
Would you just -- Don't
touch my stuff anymore, okay?
Why don't you control your ocd?
But did you dig up
anything about the building,
Or on the suicidal coed?
No. History's clean.
Then it's not a haunting.
Maybe not.
Tell you the truth,
we're not really sure.
What do you mean you're not sure?
Well...it's weird.
What's weird?
This next part, we, uh...
We didn't see it happen
ourselves, exactly, but...
It's pretty friggin' weird, even for us.
Aaaaaah!
Aliens? Yeah.
Look, even if they are real,
They're sure as hell not coming
to earth and swiping people.
Hey, believe me. We know.
My whole life i've never found evidence
Of an honest-To-God
abduction.
It's all just cranks and pranks.
Yeah, that's what we thought.
But...we figured we'd
at least talk to the guy.
Hey, you ought to give
those purple nurples a shot.
So, what happened, curtis?
You won't believe me. Nobody does.
Give us a chance.
I do not want this in the papers.
Off the record, then.
I, uh...
I blacked out, and...
I lost time,
And when i woke up, i
don't know where i was.
Then what?
They did tests on me.
And, uh...
They, uh...
They probed me.
They probed you?
Yeah, they probed me.
Again and a-- Again
and -- And again.
And again and again and again
And then one more time.
Yikes.
And that's not even the worst of it.
How could it get any worse?
Some alien made you his bitch.
They...
They made me...
Slow dance!
You guys are exaggerating again, huh?
No no.
Then this frat boy's just nuts.
We're not so sure.
I'm telling you, dean,
This was made by some
kind of jet engine.
You mean some saucer-Shaped jet engine?
What else could it be?
What the hell? I don't know.
Seriously, dude -- What
the hell? I don't know.
I mean, first the hating. Now this?
The timing
alone --
There's got to be some
kind of connection.
You mean between the angry
spirit and the sexed-Up e.T.?
What could the connection possibly be?
But what could we do? So
we just kept on digging.
So, you and this
guy, curtis --
You were in the same house? Yeah.
You heard what happened to him, right?
Yeah, he says it was aliens,
but, you know, whatever.
Look,
man, i --
I know this all has to be so hard.
Um, not so much.
But i want you to know...
I'm here for you.
You brave little soldier.
I acknowledge your pain.
Come here.
You're too precious for this world.
I never said that!
You're always saying
pansy stuff like that.
Well, um...
Yeah, uh, thanks.
Thanks for the hug, but, uh, i'm okay.
Really.
To tell you the truth,
Whatever happened to
curtis, he had it coming.
Why is that?
He's our pledge master.
Put us through hell this semester
And got off on it.
So now he knows how we feel.
It's okay.
Still doesn't make a lick of sense.
But, hey, at least
there's one connection.
Between what?
The victims.
The professor and
the frat guy --
They're both dicks.
That's a connection?
You got anything better to
go on, i'd love to hear it.
Where's my laptop?
I don't know.
Think about it.
A philandering professor
gets a dead girl.
A pledge master gets hazed.
I left it in here.
You obviously didn't.
I mean, these punishments
-- They're almost poetic.
Actually, it'd be more like
a limerick, but still --
Okay, hilarious. Ha ha.
Where'd you hide it?
What, your computer?
Yeah, where'd you hide it?
Why would i take your computer?
Because no one else could have.
We keep the door locked.
We never let any maids in.
Looks like you lost it, poindexter.
Dude, you know something? I
put up with a lot from you.
What are you talking about?
I'm a joy to be around.
Yeah? Your dirty socks in the sink,
Your food in the fridge.
What's wrong with my food?
It's not food anymore,
dean! It's darwinism.
All i ask from you, the one thing,
Is that you don't mess with my stuff!
You done?
You know, how would you feel
if i screwed with the impala?
It'd be the last thing you ever did.
Did you take his computer?
Serves him right, but, no.
Well, i didn't lose it.
'Cause i don't lose things.
Oh, that's right,
'cause he's mr. Perfect.
Okay, okay.
Why don't you just tell
me what happened next?
There was one more victim.
Now, we didn't see this
one ourselves, either.
We kind of put it
together from the evidence.
But this guy -- He was
a research scientist.
Animal testing.
Yeah, you know -- A dick,
which fits the pattern.
Hey.
Well, this ought to be quick.
Ok
That is just nasty.
Uh, yeah.
Mutilated?
Looks to me like something was hungry.
They identify him yet?
Yeah. A research
scientist at the college.
Guess where his office was, by the way.
Crawford hall, same as the professor.
That's right where the frat
boy had his close encounter.
Yeah.
Hey, grab me that thing, would you?
Thanks.
What is it?
Looks like a...
A belly scale?
A belly scale? From what?
Uh...
An alligator?
An alligator in the sewer.
Come on.
What? Well, dean, it's
a classic urban legend.
A kid flushes a baby
gator down the toilet,
And it grows huge in the tunnels.
But no one's ever really found one.
They're not real.
Neither's alien abduction,
But something chomped on this guy.
This couldn't get any weirder.
Maybe we should get some
help. I'll call bobby.
Maybe he's run into
something like this before.
Oh, i'm sure he has.
Just your typical haunted campus,
Alien abduction,
alligator-In-The-Sewer gig.
Yeah, it's simple.
We decided to search the sewer anyway,
So we split up, each
taking one end of campus.
Did you find anything?
Yeah, i found something,
just not in the sewer.
Dean: son of a bitch!
Sam!
You think this is funny?
It depends. What?
The car! What about the car?
You can't let the air out of the tires.
You're gonna bend the rims!
Whoa, wait a minute.
I didn't go near your car.
Oh, yeah? Huh.
Then how'd i find this?
Hey, give me back my money.
Oh, no, no.
Consider it reparations
for, uh, emotional trauma.
Yeah, very funny. Now, give it back.
No.
Dean,i have had it up to here with you.
Yeah? Right back at you!
Get off me! Give it back!
Okay, i've heard enough.
You showed up about an hour after that.
I'm surprised at you two.
I really am.
Sam, first off, dean did
not steal your computer.
But i -- Shh,
shh, shh, shh!
And, dean, sam did not touch your car.
Yeah.
And if you two bothered to pull
your heads out of your asses,
It all would have been pretty clear.
What? What you're dealing with.
Uh...
I got nothing. Me neither.
You got a trickster on your hands.
That's what i thought.
What?! No, you didn't.
I got to tell you...
You guys were the biggest clue.
What do you mean?
These things create chaos and mischief
As easy as breathing,
And it's got you so turned around
And at each other's throats,
You can't even think straight.
The laptop. The tires.
It knows you're onto him,
And it's been playing you like fiddles.
So, what is it --
Spirit, demon, what?
Well, more like demigods, really.
There's loki in scandinavia.
There's anansi in west africa.
Dozens of them.
They're immortal,
And they can create
things out of thin air,
Things as real as you and me.
Make them vanish just as quick.
You mean like an angry spirit
or an alien or an alligator.
The victims fit the m.O., too.
Tricksters target the
high and the mighty,
Knock them down a peg, usually
with a sense of humor --
Deadly pranks, things like that.
Bobby, what do these things look like?
Lots of things, but human, mostly.
And what human do we know
Who's been at ground
zero this whole time?
Janitor: oh, that's a good one.
Come here
Could you eat?
I could eat. Come on.
Something's missing.
That's better.
Mmm!
Sorry i'm dragging a
little ass today, boys.
Had quite the night last night.
Lots of sex, if you catch my drift.
Yeah, hard not to.
Listen, we won't be long.
We just need to check a
couple offices up on 3.
No problem.
I, uh, forgot something in the truck.
You know what? I'll
catch up with you guys.
Okay.
Just 'cause he reads
the weekly world news
Doesn't mean he's our guy.
You read it, too.
I'm telling you, it's him.
Look, i just think we
need some hard proof.
That's all.
Another thing bobby mentioned
was that these suckers
Have a metabolism like an
insect, a real sweet tooth.
I didn't find any candy bars or sugar.
Not even equal. Probably
missed something.
I don't miss things.
Oh, right, 'cause you're mr. Perfect.
What?
Are you really still pissed at me
'Cause of what the trickster did?
You been a tight ass long
before that trickster showed up.
Look, just...stay here,
keep an eye on the janitor.
I'll go to his place to see if
i can find any actual evidence
Before you go barging
in and staking the man!
Just wt till i get back, okay?
Okay? Okay!
Eh, screw this.
We've been waiting for you, dean.
Y-Y-You guys
aren't real.
Trust me, sugar, it's gonna feel real.
Come on. Let us give you a massage.
You know, i'm a -- I'm a
sucker for a happy ending.
Really, i am, but...
I-I'm gonna have to pass.
Janitor: they're a peace offering.
I know what you and your brother do.
I've been around a while.
Run into your kind before.
Well, then you know that i...
Can't let you just keep hurting people.
Come on!
Those people got what
was coming to them.
Hoisted on their own petards.
But you and sam
-- I like you.
I do.
So treat yourself...
Long as you want.
Just long enough for me to
move on to the next town.
Yeah, i don't think
i can let you do that.
I don't want to hurt you.
And you know that i can.
Look, man, i --
I got to tell you,
I dig your style, all right?
I mean [chuckles] i do. I mean
And the
slow-Dancing alien --
One of my personal favorites. Yeah.
But, uh, i can't let you go.
Too bad.
Like i said, i like you.
Sam was right.
You shouldn't have come alone.
Well, i'll agree with you there.
That fight you
guys had outside --
That was a trick?
Hmm.
Not bad.
But you want to see a real trick?
Ohh!
Aah!
Ha!
Nice toss, ladies!
Dean...
Dean, dean, dean.
I did not want to have to do this.
Me neither.
You guys okay?
Yeah.
I guess.
All i got to say...
He had style.
Ohh.
Bobby, thanks a lot.
Hey, save it!
Let's just get the hell out of dodge
Before somebody finds that body.
Yeah
Look, dean, um...
I just want to say that i'm, uh...
Um...
Hey.
Me too.
You guys are breaking my heart.
Could we please just leave?