???
Because we have a work for you.
You got a lot
to learn, boy.
Is it true?
Did i break the first seal?
Did i start l this?
Yes.
Why didn't you just
leave me there, then?
The righteous man
who begins it
is the only one
who can finish it.
You have to stop it.
Our fate
rests with you.
Find someone else.
It's not me.
'cause he gets up
in the morning ?
And he goes to work at 9 ?
And he comes back home
at 5:30 ?
Gets the same train
every time ?
'cause his world is built
'round punctuality ?
It never fails ?
And he's oh so good ?
And he's oh ...  ?
According to
the wall street journal,
citigroup inc.
Is negotiating with...
he's a well-respected man
about town ?
Doing the best things
so conservatively ?
And he likes
his own backyard ?
And he likes his fags
the best ?
'cause he's better
than the rest ?
And his own sweat
smells the best ?
And he hopes to grab
his father's loot ?
When pater passes on ?
'cause he's oh so good ?
And he's... ?
All i want to know is,
when are they gonna have another
show like "project runway"?
... and his mind ?
He's a well-respected man
about town ?
Doing the best things so... ?
Net profitability aside,
it's the client-retention rate
that concerns me,
vis-?vis
maximizing return on sales.
Buzz me back once you've seen
the spreadsheets.
Mr. Adler.
Dean.
Good stuff.
Good stuff?
Big things.
Good stuff.
Oh, i hear you. I haven't
been to the gym in ages.
Carrying a little bloat around
myself.
Yeah, it's a sedentary
lifestyle, my man. No two ways.
All right,
tell me one more time.
You said, uh, lemon
and ...  what was it?
Cayenne and maple syrup.
Are you serious?
How much did you lose?
He's a well-respected man
about town ?
Doing the best things
so conservatively ?
Do i know you?
I don't think so.
I'm sorry, man.
You just look really familiar.
Save it for
the health club, pal.
Tech support.
This is sam wesson.
Okay. Uh, well, did you try
turning it off and then on?
Okay, go ahead
and turn it off.
No, no, no, no.
Just ...  just off.
All right, give it a second.
Turn it back on.
Okay, is it ...
is it printing now?
Great.
Anytime.
Hey.
Yo.
What do you think
of, uh, mimi?
She's okay.
Might have to
hit that.
Oh, dude, that's totally
age-inappropriate.
Experience.
Uh, trifocals.
There's a milf there, sam.
I just know it.
Maybe a gmilf.
Come on.
Coffee break?
Yeah, for sure.
Paul,
time for a refuel, buddy.
Sorry. No time.
Since when?
Dude, we get paid
by the hour.
Working!
Okay.
He seems stressed.
Probably just freaked
'cause he got busted
surfing porn on the internet.
No, no, no.
Wait. When?
He got sent up to h.r.
Yesterday.
Guess they put
the fear of god in him.
Ian! Dude!
Just doing a little shopping.
Running low at home.
So, sam...
had any of those
dreams lately?
What?
Don't be like that.
Come on. It's the highlight
of my day.
I never should have told you
in the first place.
They're genius!
Don't hold out on me, dude.
Share with the class.
You're just gonna
be a dick about it.
What?! No way!
I won't say a word ...
total respect.
Go.
I dreamt that i saved
a grim reaper named
tessa from demons.
Classic!
How much d&d did youou play
when you were a kid?
Oh, my.
Okay, so you're
rescuing the grim reaper.
You're a hero.
I mean, thank god
we got harry potter here
to save us all
from the apocalypse.
Dick.
Wird.
Can i ask you
a question?
Look, man, i told you,
i'm not into the ...
oh, dude, come on.
I'm not either.
I just want to ask you
one question.
Sure.
What do you think
about ghosts?
Ghosts?
Do you believe in them?
Uh, tell you the truth, i've
never given it much thought.
Vampires?
What?
Why?
'cause i've been having
some... weird dreams lately.
You know what i mean?
No, not really.
So...
you've never had
any... weird dreams?
All right, look, man,
uh...
i don't know you, okay?
But i'm gonna do
a public service
and, uh, let you know that ...
that you over-share.
Did you turn it off, then on?
All right,
well, let's try that.
No, no, it's fine.
I'll wait.
Is it printing now?
Oh, that's great.
Anytime.
Whatcha doin'?
Nothing.
You get an e-mail
from human resources?
No. Why?
Damn it.
Guess it's just me, then.
I'm supposed to, quote,
"report to h.r.," unquote.
Well, they're probably
finally busting you
for snaking
all those office supplies.
I hope they spank me.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
Come on!
Don't do this to me.
Please!
Hey, man. You okay?
It froze.
They're crap, paul.
They freeze all the time.
You don't understand.
When ...  when i rebooted,
everything was gone.
A whole day's work ...
deleted.
Well, did you back up?
No, i didn't back up.
I wish to god i backed up,
but i didn't.
I'll get it back.
I'll find it.
It's somewhere.
Find it!
Paul, it's okay, man.
These things happen.
Come on!
Please! Please!
All that work...
gone.
Failed.
Something em not right ?
Uh, yeah.
Try the whole thing.
I'm telling you, man...
i'll never eat popcorn
again.
Yeah, right.
Two weeks?
Hey, why would someone
kill themselves
two weeks before
they were supposed to retire?
I mean, paul was two weeks
from freedom.
He should have been...
happy, right?
I don't have time
for this, sam.
That's very funny.
What's with you?
I'm working.
It's important.
H.r. Bust your balls
or something?
You're wearing
the shirt.
Did you shave?
Tech support.
This is ian.
Be right up.
I have to go up to 22,
speak to a manager.
Hi. "Ian," is it?
Yeah, come on in.
Yesterday,
you filled out a 445-t.
And, uh, no problem ...
just a ...  just a few errors.
I mean, we did just switch over
to vista, so i'm sure
you're used to filling out
the dash-r's, am i right?
Oh, no.
No, no, no.
It's fine. It's fine.
I just need you
to redo one today
so i can get the show
on the road with the invoicing.
Oh, my god.
No, it's fine. Just re-file it,
and we're square.
I can't believe i did this.
I can't ...
i can't believe it.
I... can't believe i did this.
Hey, guy, come on ...
no, no.
It affected profits.
It ...  i screwed up.
I-i can't ...
i can't ...
i am so sorry.
How could i do that?
I failed sandover.
I failed the company.
Uh, why don't you
sit down, ian?
No.
Ian. Ian!
Hey!
Ian, hey.
Just chill out, man.
Okay?
H-hey, maybe we should
get out of here, huh?
Come on.
Ian.
Look at me.
Somebody help me!
I, uh, i-i followed him
into the bathroom.
He was, uh...
he was standing there
in front of the mirror,
and then ...
... and, uh, he stabbed himself
in the neck.
I'm sorry.
That's, uh...
tech support.
This is sam.
I need to see you
in my office ...  now.
Come on in.
Shut the door.
Who the hell are you?
I'm not sure i know.
What the hell
does that mean?
Sam wesson.
I started here three weeks ago.
All right.
You cornered me
in the elevator,
talking about ghosts.
And now...
now what?
Now nothing.
I, uh...
so, you started working here
three weeks ago, huh?
Me too.
It's, uh,
master cleanse.
You tried it?
Phenomenal. Detoxes you
like nobody's business.
When you were
in that bathroom with ian...
did you see something?
I don't know.
I don't know what i saw.
Wait.
Are you saying that ...
did you... see a ghost?
I was freaking out.
The guy penciled
his damn neck.
You did, didn't you?
Okay, listen ...
what if these suicides...
aren't suicides?
I mean,
w-what if there's something...
not natural?
So, what ...
ghosts are real?
And they're responsible for all
the dead bodies around here?
Is that
what you're telling me?
Look...
i know
it sounds crazy.
But yes ...
that's what i'm telling you.
Based on what?
Instinct?
I've got
the same instinct.
Seriously?
You know those dreams
i was telling you about?
I was dreaming about ghosts.
Yeah?
And then it turns out
that there's a real ghost.
So you're telling me that
your dreams are special visions
and you're
some kind of psychic?
No. I mean
that would be nuts.
I-i'm just saying,
something weird is definitely
going on around here, right?
So i've been
digging around a little.
I think i found a connection
between the two guys.
You broke into
their e-mail accounts?
I used... some skills
that i happen to have
to...
satisfy my curiosity.
Nice.
Yeah, okay.
So, it turns out ian and paul
both got this same e-mail
telling them
to report to h.r., room 1444.
H.r.'s on 7.
Exactly.
Should we go
check this out?
Like... right now?
No. No, it's getting late.
You're right.
I am dying
to check this out right now.
Right?
Hello?
How'd you know
how to do that?
I have no idea.
Holy crap, dude.
Yeah.
I could use a beer.
Oh, sorry, man.
I'm on the cleanse.
I got rid of all the carbs
in the house.
Hey, how the hell
did you know
that ghosts
are scared of wrenches?
Crazy, right?
And nice job
kicking in that door, too.
That was very jet li.
What are you ...  like,
a black belt or something?
No.
I have no clue
how i did that.
It's like...
we've done this before.
What do you mean,
"before"?
Like "shirley maclaine"
before?
No.
I just can't shake
this feeling like i ...
like i don't belong here,
you know what i mean?
Like i should do something more
than sit in a cubicle.
I think most people who work
in a cubicle feel that same way.
No. Well, look,
it's more than that.
Like ...  like
i don't like my job.
I don't like this town.
I don't like my clothes.
I don't like
my own last name.
I ...  i don't know
how else to explain it,
except that...
it feels like i should be
doing something else.
There's just...
something in my blood.
Like i was destined
for something different.
What about you?
You ever feel that way?
I don't believe
in destiny.
I do believe
in dealing with
what's right in front of us,
though.
All right.
So, what do we do now?
We do what i do best,
sammy.
Research.
Okay.
Did you just call me
"sammy"?
Did i?
I think you did.
Yeah.
Don't.
Sorry.
Oh, jackpot!
What you got?
I just found
the best site ever.
Real,
actual ghost hunters.
These guys are genius.
Check it out.
Instructional videos?
We know
why you're watching.
You've got a problem.
A ghost problem.
A ghost-related problem.
A-a ghost ...
it's like a ghost-adjacent ...
it's like a problem,
and the ghost ...
whatever.
Well, you've come
to the right place.
The only decent place,
really,
because the ghostfacers
know how to solve it.
Period.
Watch and learn.
See, the first step
in any supernatural fight...
figure out
what you're up against.
That's him.
That's the ghost.
P.t. Sandover ...
died 1916.
Devoted his life
to his work.
No wife, no kids.
Used to say
he was the company
and his very blood
pumped through the building.
Wow. Okay.
So, slight workaholic.
Maybe he's still here,
you know, watching over
the company ...
even killing for it.
Plus, turns out
this isn't the first time
people started killing
themselves in the building.
1929 ...  the crash.
Yeah, but lots of guys
jumped off of lots of
high-rises that year.
How many companies
had 17 suicides?
Okay, so, p.t. Sandover ...
protector of the company.
His ghost wakes up
and becomes active
during times
of grave economic distress.
Well, i mean, the worst
time we've seen since
the great depression...
is now.
Yeah, now sucks.
My portfolio's
in the sewer.
I don't even
want to talk about it.
So, sandover's
helping the bottom line...
by zapping
some model employees.
Yeah.
I mean, ian and paul ...
it was like he turned them
into different people.
Perfect worker bees ...
exactly.
So devoted
to the company
that they would commit hara-kiri
if they failed it.
One more
interesting fact ...
the building
wasn't always that high.
Used to be 14 floors.
And the room where
the ghost attacked, 1444 ...
once upon a time,
that was the old man's office.
Once you've got that thing
in your sights...
you kill it!
Using special
ghost-hunting weapons.
First, salt.
It's like acid
to ghosts.
Burny acid.
Not lsd.
No. It's a bad trip
for ghosts.
Next up ...  iron.
That's why
the wrench worked.
Pure power in your hand ...
dissipates ghosts instantly.
Next little trick ...
we learned this from
those useless douche bags...
that we hate...
... the winchesters.
Gun.
Shotgun shell.
Pack it up
with fresh rock salt.
Very effective.
Winchesters
still suck ass, though.
Affirmative.
Suckage ...  major.
Where do we even
get a gun?
Gun store?
Isn't there, like, some kind
of waiting period or something?
I think so.
Then how in the hell?
I don't know, man. It seems
pretty impossible, honestly.
Right.
The aforementioned
super-annoying
winchester
douche-nozzles
also taught us
this one other thing.
You have to burn
the remains.
Okay, this next part
gets a little gross.
Sometimes... you might
have to... dig up the body.
Sorry.
It's illegal
in some states.
All states.
Possibly all states.
Sandover was cremated.
What?
So,
what do we do now?
Now, if the deceased
has been cremated...
don't panic.
Don't panic.
You just got to look
for some other remains.
Hair in a locket, maybe,
fingernails, baby teeth ...
milk teeth.
Genetic material. You know
what we're talking about.
Go find it.
Fight well,
young lions.
Godspeed.
Set your cellphone
to walkie-talkie
in case
we get separated.
How the hell are we gonna find
some ancient speck of dna
in a skyscraper?
Well, that creepy
storeroom used to be
sandover's office, right?
What the hell
are you doing here?
Uh... nothing.
I just ...
come with me.
Man, l-listen ...  it's okay.
I-i work here.
Whatever.
Tell it to the cops.
Well, come on.
What?
Last time
this happened,
it took them two hours
to get here.
Let's just wait.
Seriously ...
i'll wait.
Look, i don't have
the rest of my life here.
Hey. You okay?
Call you back.
????
Yeah.
Listen, i think i got it.
Meet me on 22.
Okay. Yeah.
Just, uh...
take the stairs.
That's a lot of blood.
Yeah, i know.
Right.
So, uh, in there.
P.t. Sandover's gloves.
Yeah.
How much you want to
bet there's a little
smidge of dna in there?
You know, like a
fingernail clipping or a
hair or two. Something.
So, you ready?
I have no idea.
Me neither.
Go for it.
Right.
Nice!
Dean!
Nice catch.
Right?
That was amazing!
Man, i got to tell you,
i've never had so much
fun in my life.
Me neither.
It was a hell of a workout,
too, wasn't it?
We should keep
doing this.
I know.
I mean it.
There got to be
other ghosts out there.
We could help
a lot of people.
Yeah, right.
We'd be like the ghostfacers.
No, really.
I mean... for real.
What?
Quit our jobs
and hit the road?
Exactly.
How would we live?
Come on.
You got to be kidding me.
How would we get by ...
with stolen credit cards? Huh?
Eating diner food
drenched in saturated fats?
Sharing a crap motel room
every night?
That's all just details.
Details are everything!
You don't want to go
fighting ghosts without
any health insurance.
All right.
Uh... confession.
What?
Remember those dreams
i told you about,
with the ghosts?
Yeah.
I was fighting them.
Okay.
With you.
We were...
these, like...
hunters.
And we were friends.
More like brothers,
really.
I mean, what if
that's who we really are?
I mean, you saw us back there,
working together.
The ghost was
scrambling people's brains.
What if
it scrambled ours?
That's insane.
Is it?
Think about it
for just one second.
What if we think
this is our life...
but it's not?
Hey, man, the ghost is dead,
and we're still standing.
I mean, i'm sorry,
but ...
look, all i know is, this isn't
who we're supposed to be.
No.
I'm dean smith, okay?
Director of sales and marketing.
I went to stanford.
My father's name is bob,
my mother's name is ellen,
and my sister's name is jo.
When's the last time
you talked to them?
To any of them?
Okay. You're upset.
You're upset, you're confused ...
yeah,
'cause i only moved here
'cause i just broke up
with my fiancée, madison.
But i called her number and
i got a damn animal hospital.
Okay,
what are you saying?
You trying to say that ...
that my family isn't real?
That we've been injected
with fake memories?
Come on!
All i know is,
i got this feeling in my gut.
And i know ...
i know that, deep down,
you got to be
feeling it, too.
We're supposed to be
something else.
You're not just
some corporate douche bag.
This isn't you.
I know you.
Know me?
You don't know me, pal.
You should go.
I quit.
Got a minute?
Sure. Of course.
How are you feeling,
dean?
Uh... great.
You look
a little tired.
Been working hard,
i gather.
Ah, don't be modest.
I hear everything.
And i'm pleased
with what i'm hearing.
That's why it's important to me
that you're happy.
How's that
for a bonus?
Very generous.
Purely selfish.
I want to make sure
you're not going anywhere.
Are you sure?
Positive.
You are
sandover material, son ...
real go-getter,
carving your own way.
Well, thanks.
I try.
I see big things
in your future.
Maybe even...
senior v.p.,
eastern great lakes division.
Don't get me wrong.
You'll have to work for it ...
seven days a week,
lunch at your desk ...
but in 8 to 10 short years,
that could be you.
Uh, well, thank you.
Thank you, sir.
It's, um...
but...
i am giving
my notice.
This is a joke.
You're kidding me,
right?
No, i...
i recently ...
uh, very recently ...
realized that i have
some other work i have to do.
It's, uh...
very important to me.
Other work?
Another company?
No, i ...
it's hard to explain.
Um...
it's just
that this...
this is,
it's just...
... it's not
who i'm supposed to be.
What?
Dean, dean, dean.
Finally.
What the hell?
Why am i wearing
a tie?
My god, am i hungry.
Welcome back.
Wait. Did i ...
did i just get
touched by ...
you're an angel,
aren't you?
I'm zachariah.
Oh, great. That's all i need,
is another one of you guys.
I'm hardly "another one," dean.
I'm castiel's superior.
Believe me, i had no interest
in popping down here
and into
one of these smelly things.
But after the unfortunate...
situation with uriel,
i felt it necessary
to pay a visit ...
get my ducks in a row.
I am not
one of your ducks.
Starting
with your attitude.
Oh, so, what? This ...  this was
all some sort of a lesson?
Is that
what you're telling me?
Well, very creative.
You should see
my decoupage.
Gross.
No, thank you.
So, what, i'm ...  i'm just
hallucinating all this?
Is that it?
Not at all.
Real place, real haunting.
Just plunked you
in the middle
without the benefit
of your memories.
Just to shake things up?
Hmm?
So you guys can have fun
watching us run around
like ass-clowns
in ...  in monkey suits?
To prove to you that
the path you're on is
truly in your blood.
You're a hunter.
Not because
your dad made you.
god called you back from hell.
But because
it is what you are.
And you love it.
You'll find your way to it
in the dark every single time,
and you're miserable
without it.
Dean, let's be real here ...
you're good at this.
You'll be successful.
You will stop it.
Stop what?
The apocalypse, huh?
Lucifer?
What?
Be specific, man!
You'll do everything
you're destined to do.
All of it.
But i know, i know.
You're not strong enough.
You're scared.
You got daddy issues.
You can't do it, right?
Angel or not,
i will stab you in your face.
All i'm saying is...
it's how
you look at it.
Most folks live and die
without moving anything more
than the dirt it takes
to bury them.
You get to
change things...
save people.
Maybe even the world.
All the while,
you drive a classic car
and fornicate
with women.
This isn't a curse ...
it's a gift.
So, for god's sakes, dean,
quit whining about it.
Look around.
There are plenty of fates
worse than yours.
So, you with me?
You want to go
steam yourself another latte?
Or are you ready
to stand up...
... and be
who you really are?
Présynchro : Flolo
Transcript : yyets.net
www.tvsubtitles.net