He wants us to pick up
where he left off.
Saving people, hunting things...
The family business.
Dad.
Dean.
It's not a dream.
You ever heard of an out-of-body experience?
We're spirits...
of people close to death.
Your son is dying,
and you're worried about the colt?
You shoot me in the heart, son!
You're bringing the demon here,
aren't you?
Having some stupid, macho showdown!
If you killed that damn thing
when you had the chance,
none of this would have happened.
I want to make a deal.
You're much prettier
than the last reaper I met.
I will give you the colt and the bullet.
But you got to help Dean.
So, we have a deal?
You still need to sweeten the pot.
Today is your lucky day, kid.
You watch out for Sammy, okay?
Okay.
Dad?
Time of death, 10:41 a.m.
God, I hate clowns.
Always creep me out.
Shh! She likes them.
Last ride, Nora.
Look, mom, another clown.
What are you trying to do,
scare your father?
Honey.
Look, mom, a clown.
You missed him.
Before he...
Did he say anything to you?
About anything?
No.
Nothing.
How's the car coming along?
Slow.
Yeah?
You need any help?
What?
You under a hood?
I'll pass.
Need anything else, then?
Stop it, Sam.
Stop what?
Stop asking if I need anything.
Stop asking if I'm okay.
I'm okay.
Really. I promise.
All right, Dean, it's just...
We've been at Bobby's for over a week now,
and you haven't brought up dad once.
You know what? You're right.
Come here.
I'm gonna lay my head gently
on your shoulder.
Maybe we could cry, hug,
- maybe even slow dance.
- Don't patronize me, Dean.
Dad is dead, the colt is gone,
and it seems pretty damn likely
that the demon is behind all of this.
And you're acting like nothing happened.
- What do you want me to say?
- Say something, all right?!
Hell, say anything!
Aren't you angry? Don't you want revenge?
But all you do is sit out here all day long
buried underneath this damn car.
- Revenge, huh? Sounds good.
- Yeah!
Got any leads on where the demon is?
Making heads or tails of any
of dad's research? 'Cause I sure ain't.
You know, when we do finally find it...
Oh,
no, wait,
like you said, the colt's gone.
But I'm sure you figured out
another way to kill it.
We've got nothing, Sam.
Nothing, okay?
The only thing I can do is
I can work on the car.
Well, we got something, all right?
It's what I came out here to tell you.
It's one of dad's old phones.
It took me a while, but I cracked
his voice mail code. Listen to this.
John, it's Ellen...
Again.
Look, don't be stubborn.
You know I can help you. Call me.
That message is four months old.
Dad saved that chick's message
for four months?
- Yeah.
- Who's Ellen?
- Any mention of her in dad's journal?
- No,
but I ran a trace on the number,
and I got an address.
Ask Bobby if we can use one of his cars.
This is humiliating.
I feel like a friggin' soccer mom.
It's the only car Bobby had running.
Hello?
- Anybody here?
- Alright.
- Hey, did you bring the...
- of course.
Hey, buddy?
- I'm guessing that isn't Ellen.
- Yeah.
Oh, god, please let that be a rifle.
No, I'm just real happy to see you.
- Don't move.
- Not moving. Copy that.
You should know something, miss.
When you put a rifle on someone,
you don't want to put it
right against their back,
'cause it makes it real easy to do...
that!
Sam!
I need some help in here.
I can't see. I can't even see!
Sorry, Dean.
I can't right now.
I'm a...
little tied up.
Sam? Dean?
Winchester?
Yeah.
Son of a bitch.
Mom, you know these guys?
Yeah, I think these are
John Winchester's boys.
Hey, I'm Ellen.
That's my daughter, Jo.
Hey.
You're not gonna hit me again, are you?
Here you go.
Thanks.
You called our dad, said you could help.
Help with what?
Well,
the demon, of course.
I heard he was closing in on it.
Was there an article in
the demon hunter's quarterly that I missed?
I mean, who are you?
How do you know about all this?
Hey, I just run a saloon.
But hunters have been known
to pass through now and again,
including your dad a long time ago.
- John was like family once.
- Oh Yeah?
I mean he's never mentioned you before.
You'd have to ask him that.
So, why exactly do we need your help?
Hey, don't do me any favors.
Look, if you don't want my help, fine.
Don't let the door smack your ass
on the way out.
But John wouldn't have sent you if...
He didn't send you.
He's all right, isn't he?
No.
No, he isn't.
It was the demon, we think.
It just got him before he got it, I guess.
- I'm so sorry.
- It's okay.
We're all right.
Really, I know how close you and your dad...
Really, lady, I'm fine.
So, look, if you can help...
we could use all the help we can get.
Well, we can't.
But Ash will.
- Who's Ash?
- Ash!
What?
Closing time?
That's Ash?
He's a genius.
You got to be kidding me.
This guy's no genius.
He's a Lynyrd Skynyrd roadie.
- I like You.
- Thanks.
Just give him a chance.
All right.
Well, this stuff's about a year's worth
of our dad's work. So
let's see what you make of it.
Come on. This crap ain't real.
Ain't nobody can track a demon like this.
Our dad could.
These are nonparametric
statistical overviews,
cross-spectrum correlations. I mean...
Damn!
They're signs,
omens. If you can track them,
you can track this demon.
You know, like crop failures,
electrical storms.
You ever been struck by lightning?
It ain't fun.
- Can you track it or not?
- Yeah, With This, I think so.
But it's gonna take time.
Give me...
51 hours.
- Hey, man!
- Yeah?
By the way, I dig the haircut.
All business up front,
party in the back.
Hey, Ellen, what is that?
It's a police scanner.
- We keep tabs on things.
- No, No, No, no. the... folder.
I was gonna give this to
a friend of mine, but
take a look
if you want.
Thanks.
How did your mom get
into this stuff, anyway?
My dad.
He was a hunter.
He passed away.
I'm sorry.
It was a long time ago.
I was just a kid.
Sorry to hear about yo dad.
Yeah.
So,
I guess I got 51 hours to waste.
Maybe tonight we should...
Oh, you know what? Never mind.
- What?
- Nothing, just...
Wrong place, wrong time.
I thought you were gonna toss me
some cheap pickup line.
Most hunters come through that door,
think they can get in my pants with some
pizza, a six-pack
and side one of "Zeppelin 4".
What a bunch of scumbags.
Not you.
I guess not.
Dean, come here. Check this out.
Yeah.
A few murders not far from here
that Ellen caught wind of.
Looks to me like there might be a hunt.
- Yeah, so?
- So,
I told her we'd check it out.
You got to be kidding me.
Killer clown?
Yeah, he left the daughter unharmed
and killed the parents.
Ripped them to pieces, actually.
And this family was at
some carnival that night?
Right, the Cooper carnival.
How do you know we're not dealing
with some psycho carny in a clown suit?
The cops have no leads, and all the
employees were tearing down shop...
Alibis all around. Plus the girl said
she saw a clown vanish into thin air.
- Cops are saying trauma, of course.
- I know what you're thinking, Sam.
Why did it have to be clowns?
Oh, give me a break.
You didn't think I remembered, did you?
Come on, you still bust out crying whenever
you see Ronald Mcdonald on the television.
At least I'm not afraid of flying.
- Planes crash!
- And apparently clowns kill.
So, these types of murders,
they ever happen before?
Uh, according to the file, 1981, the
Bunker Brothers Circus.
Same M.O. It happened three different
times, three different locales.
It's weird though. If it is a spirit, it's usually
bound to a specific locale. A house or a town.
How's this one moving from city
to city? Carnival to carnival?
Cursed object.
Spirit attaches itself
to something, and the
- carnival carries It around.
- Great. Paranormal scavenger hunt.
This case was your idea.
By the way, why is that?
You were awfully quick to jump on this job.
- So?
- So this is not like you, that's all.
I thought you were hell-bent for
leather on the demon hunt.
I don't know. I just think
taking this job, it's what dad
would have wanted us to do.
- What dad would have wanted?
- Yeah.
So?
Nothing.
Check it out.
Evan, look.
- Scary!
- Yeah, dad, scary.
What's over here?
You know, when I was your age,
this would have scared the pants off me.
Evan.
Hey.
What is it?
I...
I saw a clown.
Don't be afraid of clowns.
They're nice. They're your friends.
Okay? Come on.
Dad.
Dad!
Evan.
What is it?
You were right.
He is my friend.
Check it out.
Five-O.
Did you get her number?
- More murders?
- Two More last night.
Apparently, they were ripped to shreds,
and they had a little boy with them.
Who fingered a clown.
What?
Yes, a clown, who apparently
vanished into thin air.
Dean, you know, looking for
a cursed object, it's like
trying to find a needle in a stack
of needles. It could be anything.
Well, it's bound to give off EMF.
So we'll just have to scan everything.
Oh, good. That's nice and inconspicuous.
I guess we'll just have to blend in.
Excuse me.
We're looking for a Mr. Cooper.
Have you seen him around?
What is that? Some kind of joke?
- Oh, god, I'm sorry.
- You think I wouldn't give my eyeteeth
to see Mr. Cooper or a sunset
or anything at all?
Want to give me a little help here?
Not really.
Hey, Barry, is there a problem?
- Yeah, This guy hates blind people.
- No, I don't.
- Hey, buddy, what's your problem?
- Nothing. It's just a little misunderstanding.
Little?
- You son of A bitch.
- No, no, no!
Could somebody tell me where Mr. Cooper is?
Please?
You boys picked a hell of a time to join up.
Take a seat.
We got all kinds of local trouble.
What do you mean?
A couple of folks got themselves murdered.
Cops always seem to start here first.
So, you two ever work the circuit before?
Uh, yes, sir.
Last year through Texas and Arkansas.
Doing what?
Ride jockeys?
Pull shoot?
- A-and-S men?
- Yeah, it's a...
little bit of everything, I guess.
You two have never worked a show
in your lives before, have you?
Nope.
But we really need the work.
And Sam here's got a thing
for the bearded lady.
You see that picture?
That's my daddy.
You look just like him.
He was in the business.
Ran a freak show
'til they outlawed them most places.
Apparently displaying the
deformed isn't dignified.
So, most of the performers went
from honest work to rotting in
hospitals and asylums.
That's progress,
I guess.
You see, this place
is a refuge for outcasts.
Always has been.
For folks that don't fit in nowhere else.
But you two...
you should go to school,
find a couple of girls,
have 2.5 kids,
live regular.
Sir...
We don't want to go to school.
And we don't want regular.
We want this.
Hmm.
What?
That whole, I don't want
to go back to school thing,
you just...
You were just saying that
to Cooper, or were you,
you know,
saying it?
- I don't know.
- You don't know?
I thought that once the demon was dead
and the fat lady sings that you were gonna
take off, head back to wussy state.
I'm having second thoughts.
- Really?
- Yeah, I think...
Dad would have wanted me
to stick to the job.
Since when do you give
a damn what dad wanted?
You spent half your life doing
exactly what he didn't want.
Since he died, okay?
You have a problem with that?
No, I don't have a problem at all.
Who is this?
- Hello?
- Hey, man.
What's the matter?
You sound like you just saw a clown.
Very funny.
Skeleton, actually.
- Like a real human skeleton?
- In the fun house.
Listen, I was thinking.
What if
the spirit isn't attached to a cursed object.
What if it's attached to its own remains.
- Did the bones give off EMF?
- Well, No, but...
We should check it out anyway.
I'm heading to you.
What are you doing here, kid?
- Just sweeping.
- Bull.
And what were you talking about?
Skeletons?
What's EMF?
Dude, your blind-man
hearing is out of control.
We're a tight-knit group.
We don't like outsiders.
We take care of our own problems.
- We got a problem?
- You tell me. You're the one
talking about human bones.
Do you believe in ghosts?
What?
My brother and me...
we're writing a book about them.
What took you so long?
Mommy, look at the clown.
What clown?
Come on, sweetie. Come on.
Dean, I cannot believe
you told Papasian about
the homicidal phantom clown.
I told him an urban legend
about a homicidal phantom clown.
- I never said It was real.
- Keep It down.
Oh, and get this.
I mentioned the Bunker
Brothers Circus in '81
and their evil-clown apocalypse.
Guess what.
What?
Before Mr. Cooper owned Cooper carnival,
he worked for the Bunker Brothers.
He was their lot manager.
So you think whatever's
the spirit attached to
- Cooper just brought it with him?
- Something like that.
I can't believe we keep
talking about clowns.
Want to come in and play?
Want to see mommy and daddy?
They're upstairs.
Hey!
Sam, watch out!
What's going on in here?
- Oh, my god! What do you do to my daughter!
- Get away from my kid!
Mommy, daddy, they shot my clown.
You really think they saw our plates?
I don't want to take the chance.
Besides, I hate this freaking thing anyway.
Well, one thing's for sure.
What's that?
We're not dealing with a spirit.
That rock salt hit something solid.
Yeah, a person, or maybe a creature
that can make itself invisible?
Yeah, and dresses up like a clown for kicks?
Did it say anything in dad's journal?
Nope.
Who you calling?
Maybe Ellen or that guy Ash
will know something.
Hey, you think, uh...
You think dad and Ellen ever had a thing?
No way.
Then why didn't he tell us about her?
I don't know. Maybe
they had some sort of falling-out.
Yeah.
You ever notice dad had a falling-out
with just about everybody?
Don't get all maudlin on me, man.
What do you mean?
I mean this strong, silent thing of yours.
It's crap. I'm over it.
This isn't just anyone we're
talking about. This is dad.
I know how you felt about the man.
Back off, all right? Just because
I'm not caring and sharing like you want...
No, no, no. That's not what this is about, Dean.
I don't care how you deal with this,
but you have to deal with it, man.
Listen, I'm your brother, all right?
I just want to make sure you're okay.
Dude, I'm okay! I'm okay!
I swear, the next person
who asks me if I'm okay,
I'm gonna start throwing punches.
These are your issues.
Quit dumping them on me.
What are you talking about?
I just think it's really interesting
this sudden obedience you have to dad.
It's like, oh, what
would dad want me to do?
You spent your entire life
slugging it out with that man.
I mean, hell, you picked a fight with
him the last time you ever saw him,
and now that he's dead,
now you wanna make it right?
Well, I'm sorry, Sam, but you can't.
It's too little too late.
Why are you saying this to me?
I want you to be honest with yourself
about this! I'm dealing with dad's death.
Are you?
I'm gonna call Ellen.
Thanks a lot.
Rakshasa.
- What's that?
- Ellen's best guess.
It's a race of ancient hindu creatures.
They appear in human form,
they feed on human flesh,
they can make themselves invisible,
and they cannot enter a home
without first being invited to.
They dress up like clowns,
and children invite them in.
Yeah
- Why don't they just munch on the kids?
- No idea.
Not enough meat on the bones, maybe?
- What else you find out?
- Apparently, Rakshasas live in squalor.
They sleep on a bed of dead insects.
- Nice.
- Yeah
And they have to feed a few times.
Every 20 to 30 years.
- Slow metabolism, I guess.
- That makes sense.
I mean, the carnival today,
the Bunker Brothers in '81.
Right.
Probably more before that.
Sam, who do we know that worked both shows?
- Cooper?
- Cooper.
You know, that picture of his father,
that looked just like him.
You think maybe it was him?
Well, who knows how old he is?
Ellen say how to kill him?
Legend goes a dagger made of pure brass.
I think I know where to get one of those.
Well, before we go
stabbing things into Cooper,
we're gonna want to
make damn sure it's him.
Oh, you're such a stickler
for details, Sammy.
All right, I'll round up the blade.
You go check if Cooper's got bedbugs.
Well, I got all kinds of knives.
I don't know if I got a brass one, though.
What do you think you're doing?
Check the trunk.
You?
Me.
All right!
Hey!
So, Cooper thinks I'm a
peeping tom, but it's not him.
Yeah, so I gathered.
It's the blind guy.
He's here somewhere.
- Well, did you get...
- The brass blades? No.
It's just been one of those days.
I got an idea. Come on.
Sam.
Dean.
Dean, find the maze, okay?
Hey!
- Where is it?
- I don't know.
Shouldn't we see his clothes walking around?
Sam!
- Dean, where is it?
- I don't know!
Sam, behind you!
I hate fun houses.
You boys did a hell of a job.
- Your dad would be proud.
- Thanks.
Oh, yeah, I've got to, uh...
I've got to go...
over there...
right now.
- So.
Am I gonna see you again?
Do you want to?
I wouldn't hate it.
Can I be honest with you?
See, normally,
I'd be hitting on you so fast.
It'd make your head spin.
But
these days...
I don't know.
Wrong place,
wrong time?
It's okay. I get it.
Where you guys been?
- I've been waiting for you.
- We were working a job, Ash.
- Clowns?
- Clowns? What the...
You got something for us, Ash?
Did you find the demon?
It's nowhere around,
at least nowhere I can find.
But if this fugly bastard raises its head,
I'll know. I mean,
I'm on it like divine on dog dookie.
What do you mean?
I mean
any of those signs or omens
appear anywhere in the world,
my rig will go off like a fire alarm.
You mind?
What's up, man?
Ash, where did you learn to do all this?
M.I.T., before I got bounced for fighting.
M.I.T.?
It's a school in Boston.
Okay.
Give us a call as soon
as you know something?
Sí, sí, compadre.
Hey, listen.
If you boys need a place to stay,
I got a couple beds out back.
Thanks, but no.
There's something I got to finish.
Okay.
You were right.
About what?
About me and dad.
I'm sorry that the last time I was
with him, I tried to pick a fight.
I'm sorry that I spent most
of my life angry at him.
I mean, for all I know, he died
thinking that I hate him.
So, you're right.
What I'm doing right now...
It is too little.
It's too late.
I miss him, man.
And I feel guilty as hell.
And I'm not all right...
not at all...
But neither are you.
That much I know.
I'll let you get back to work.