Drew: like when you put
on "a little" eye shadow.
And, you know, all this stuff,
It's just very unprofessional.
Don't touch the troll!
Is that what your mom
used to say to your dates?
Put the trolls down,
Or i'll put a staple
right between your eyes.
Now, i know it's hard.
It's hard to look up when you're down.
It's hard to look up and see the light.
But i'm here to tell you folks...
The lord is with you.
You don't have to suffer.
You don't have to be lost.
The lord is talking to you right now.
He's saying, "you are my
child, and you have a purpose."
You think god forgot
about you? I tell you, no!
All you got to do is listen.
Can't you just hear
those angels singing?
Isn't it beautiful?
It's time.
It's time to receive
the message he's sending.
It's time to listen to the word of god!
Can you hear the glory?
I said, can't you just hear it?
I say, can't you just hear the lord?
Good morning. You're not the usual guy.
No, uh... just filling in.
So, how you feeling today, gloria?
I've never felt better.
So, no disturbances lately?
You mean, am i stark-Raving
cuckoo for cocoa puffs?
I didn't say that.
It's all right. I know
what people must think.
What do you think?
I think what i saw was real.
I'd like to know what you saw.
It was all over the news.
I stabbed a man in the heart.
Why would you do that?
Because it was god's will.
Did god talk to you?
I get the sense god's a
little busy for house calls.
No, he -- He
sent someone.
Someone?
An angel.
It came to me in this
beautiful white light.
And it filled me with this...feeling.
It's -- It's
hard to describe.
And this angel...
Spoke god's word.
And the word was to kill someone?
I know it sounds strange.
But what i did was very important.
I helped him smite an evil man.
I was chosen...
For redemption.
This man you stabbed -- Did
the angel give you his name?
No.
He just told me to wait for the sign,
And the very next day,
I saw it right beside the man's doorway,
And i knew.
Why him?
I just know what
the angel told me --
That this man was guilty
to his deepest foundations.
And that was good enough for me.
Hey.
Sam: hey!
Hey, man, you got to try this.
I mean, there really is
magic in the magic fingers.
Dean, you're enjoying that way too much.
It's kind of making me uncomfortable.
You got me on lockdown here.
I'm bored out of my skull.
Hey, you were the bank robber
on the 11:00 news, not me.
We can't risk you just walking
into a government facility.
Mmm.
Aw, damn it.
That was my last quarter.
Hey!
You got any quarters?
No.
So, did you get in to
see that crazy hooker?
Yeah. Gloria sitnik.
And i'm not so sure she's crazy.
But she seriously believes
That she was... touched by an angel?
Yeah.
Blinding light, feelings of
spiritual ecstasy, the works.
I mean, she's living in a locked ward,
And she's totally at peace.
Oh, yeah, you're right
-- Sounds completely sane.
What about the dude she stabbed?
Uh, carl gulley.
Said she killed him 'cause he was evil.
Was he? I don't know.
I couldn't find any dirt on him.
He didn't have a criminal record,
He worked at the campus
library, had lots of friends,
Was a churchgoer.
Hmm. So gloria's just
your standard-Issue wacko?
I mean, she wouldn't be
the first nutjob in history
To kill in the name of
religion, know what i mean?
No, but she's the second in town
To murder because an angel told them to.
Little bit odd, don't you think?
Odd -- Yeah.
Supernatural -- Maybe.
But angels -- I
don't think so.
Why not?
'Cause there's no such thing, sam.
Dean, there's 10 times
as much lore about angels
As there is about anything
else we've ever hunted.
There's a ton of lore on unicorns, too.
I hear that they ride
on silver moonbeams
And they shoot rainbows
out of their ass.
Wait, there's no such thing as unicorns?
That's cute.
I'm just saying, man,
there's some legends
That you just file under "bull crap."
And you got angels on
the "bull crap" list?
Yep.
Why?
Because i've never seen one.
So what?
So i believe in what i can see.
Dean, you and i have seen things
Most people couldn't even dream about.
Exactly.
With our own eyes --
That's hard proof, okay?
But in all this time,
I have never seen anything
that looks like an angel.
Don't you think we would
have crossed paths with them
Or at least know someone
that crossed paths with them?
No. This is a demon or a spirit.
They find people a few
fries short of a happy meal,
And they trick them into
killing these randoms.
Maybe.
Can we just -- I'm
going stir-Crazy, man.
Let's go by gloria's apartment, huh?
I was just there. Nothing.
No sulfur, no e.M.F.
You didn't see any fluffy,
white wing feathers?
But gloria did say the
angel gave her a sign
Right beside carl gulley's doorway.
Could be something at his
house. It's worth checking out.
Hey, sam.
Think i found it.
It's a sign from up above.
I think i learned a valuable lesson.
Always take down your
christmas decorations
After new year's,
Or you might get filleted
by a hooker from god.
I'm laughing on the inside.
You know, gloria said
The guy was guilty to
his deepest foundations.
You think she literally
meant the foundation?
Hmm.
You got something?
What is it?
It's a fingernail.
So much for the innocent
churchgoing librarian.
Whatever spoke to gloria about this
Knew what it was talking
about -- I'll give you that.
Yes?
Hi. My name is zach.
Can i help you?
Ugh!
Did you bring quarters?
Dude, i'm not enabling your sick habit.
You're like one of those lab rats
That pushes the pleasure button
instead of the food button
Until it dies.
What are you talking about?
I eat. And i got news.
Me too. All right, you go first.
Three students have disappeared
off the campus this year.
All of them were last
seen at the library.
Where carl gulley worked. Sick bastard.
So gloria's
angel -- Angel?
Okay, whatever this thing is.
Whatever it is, it struck again. What?
I was listening to the police radio.
There was this guy, zach
smith, some local drunk.
He went up to a stranger's
front door last night,
Stabbed him in the heart.
I'm guessing he went to
the police and confessed?
Yep. Roma downey made him do it.
Now, i, uh...
Got the victim's address.
Find anything?
Frank liked his catalog shopping.
That's about all i got. You?
Not much here.
Except he's got this one locked
file on his computer that...
Hold on.
Not anymore.
God. What?
He's got all these e-Mails,
Dozens, to this lady named jennifer.
This lady who's 13 years old.
Oh, i don't want to hear this.
Looks like they met in a chat room.
These e-Mails are
pretty personal, dean.
Look at that.
Setting up a time and
place to meet. Great.
They were supposed to meet today.
Huh.
Well, i guess if you're
gonna stab someone,
Good timing.
I don't know, man. This is weird.
I mean, sure, some spirits
are out for vengeance,
But this one's almost
like a do-Gooder, like a --
Avenging angel?
Well, how else do you explain it, dean?
Three guys not connected to each other
All stabbed through the heart?
At least two were world-Class pervs,
And i bet if you dug deep
enough on the other guy --
Hey. What?
You said carl gulley
was a churchgoer, right?
Yeah.
What was the name of his church?
Uh... our lady of the angels?
Of course that would be the name.
Looks like frank went
to the same church.
Man: so, you're interested
in joining the parish?
We just don't feel right unless
we hit church every sunday.
Where'd you say you lived before?
Premont, texas.
Really? At's a nice
town. St. Teresa's parish.
You must know the priest there.
Sure, yeah. No, it's fr. O'malley.
I know a fr. Shaughnessy.
Shaughnessy, exactly. What did i say?
You know, we're just happy
to be here now, father.
And we're happy to have you.
We could use some
young blood around here.
I got to ask -- No offense,
but the neighborhood...
It's gone to seed a little.
There's no denying that.
But that's why what the church
does here is so important.
Like i always say, you
can expect a miracle,
But in the meantime,
you work your butt off.
Yeah, we heard about the murders.
The victims were parishioners of mine.
I've known them for years.
And the killers said that
an angel made them do that?
Yes. Misguided souls.
To think that god's messenger
Would appear and incite people
to murder -- It's tragic.
So, you don't believe in
those angel yarns, huh?
Oh, no, i absolutely believe.
It kind of goes with
the job description.
Father, that's michael, right?
That's right.
The archangel michael,
with the flaming sword --
The fighter of demons,
Holy force against evil.
So, they're not really
the hallmark-Card version
That everybody thinks?
They're fierce, right? Vigilant.
I like to think of them as
more loving than wrathful,
But, yes,
A lot of scripture paints
angels as god's warriors.
"An angel of the lord appeared to them,
"The glory of the lord
shone down upon them,
And they were terrified."
Luke 2:9.
Well, thank you for
speaking with us, father.
It's my pleasure. Hope to see you again.
Father, what's all that for?
Oh, that's for fr. Gregory.
He was a priest here.
Was?
Passed away right on these steps.
He's interred in the church crypt.
When did this happen?
Two months ago. He was
shot for his car keys.
I'm sorry.
Yeah, me too. He was a good friend.
I didn't even have time to
administer his last rites.
But like i said, it's
a tough neighborhood.
And ever since he died, i've
been praying my heart out.
For what?
For deliverance...
From the violence and
the bloodshed around here.
We could use a little divine
intervention, i suppose.
Well, padre, thanks.
We'll see you again.
Well, it's all starting to make sense.
Devoted priest dies
a violent death --
That's vengeful-Spirit
material right there.
He knew all the stiffs 'cause
they went to church here.
I'm willing to bet,
because he was their priest,
He knew things about them
that nobody else knew.
Then again, fr. Reynolds
started praying for god's help
About two months ago, right?
Right about the time all this started?
Oh, come on, man. What's
your deal? What do you mean?
Look, i'll admit, i'm
a bit of a skeptic,
But since when are
you all mr. "700 club?"
Seriously, from the get-Go,
You've been willing to
buy this angel crap, man.
What's next? Are you gonna
start praying every day?
I do.
What?
I do pray every day.
I have for a long time.
The things you learn about a guy.
Huh.
Come on. Let's go check
out fr. Gregory's grave.
Sam, come on, get the lead out.
Sammy?
Sammy! Hey.
Okay?
Yeah.
Come on.
You saw it, didn't you? Didn't you?
Yeah. Yeah.
Dean, i saw an angel.
You
--
All right, come on.
I don't want a drink.
So, what makes you think
you saw a, uh, angel?
Just...
It appeared before
me, and i just --
This feeling washed over me, you know?
Like -- Like
peace, like grace.
Okay, ecstasy boy, maybe we'll get you
Some glow sticks and a
nice dr. Seuss hat, huh?
Dean, i'm serious.
It spoke to me. It knew who i was.
It's just a spirit, sam.
And it's not the first one
To be able to read people's minds.
Okay, let
me guess --
You were personally chosen
to smite some sinner?
You just got to wait
for me divine bat signal.
Is that it? Yeah, actually.
Great.
I don't suppose you asked
what this alleged bad guy did.
Actually, i did, dean,
and the angel told me.
He hasn't done anything... yet.
But he will.
Oh, this is -- I
don't believe this.
Dean, the angel hasn't been wrong yet.
Someone's gonna do something
awful, and i can stop it.
You're supposed to be bad, too, sam.
Maybe i should stop you right now.
You know what, dean? I don't understand.
Why can't you even
consider the possibility?
What, that this is an angel? Yes.
Maybe we're hunting an angel
here, and we should stop.
Maybe this is god's will.
Okay. All right.
You know what? I get
it. You've got faith.
That's -- Hey,
good for you.
I'm sure it makes things easier.
I'll tell you who else
had faith like that -- Mom.
She used to tell me
when she tucked me in
That angels were watching over us.
In fact, that was the last
thing she ever said to me.
You never told me that.
What's to tell?
She was wrong.
There was nothing protecting her.
There's no higher power. There's no god.
There's just chaos and violence
And random, unpredictable
evil that comes out of nowhere
And rips you to shreds.
You want me to believe in this stuff?
I'm gonna need to see some hard proof.
You got any?
Well, i do.
Proof that we're dealing with a spirit.
That looks
like --
It's wormwood...
A plant associated with the dead,
Specifically the ones
that are not at rest.
I don't see it growing anywhere else,
Except over the
murdered priest's marker.
It's him, sam.
Maybe.
Maybe?
Dean, i don't know what to think.
Okay.
Want some more proof?
I'll give you more proof.
How?
We'll summon gregory's spirit.
What?
Here? In the church?
Yeah.
Yeah, we just need a few odds and ends
And that séance ritual in dad's journal.
A séance, great. I
hope whoopi's available.
That's funny, actually. Seriously.
If fr. Gregory's spirit is around,
The séance will bring him right to us.
If it's him, then we'll put him to rest.
But if it's an angel, it won't show.
Nothing will happen.
Exactly.
It's one of the perks of the job, sam.
We don't have to operate on faith.
We can know for sure.
Don't you want to know for sure?
Dude...
All right, i'll admit,
We've gone pretty ghetto
with the spell work before,
But this takes the cake.
I mean, a spongebob place
mat instead of an altar cloth?
We'll just put it
spongebob-Side-Down.
Dean, that's it.
What?
That's the sign.
Where?
Right behind that guy.
That's him, dean.
And we have to stop him.
Wait a minute.
What are you doing?
You're not gonna kill somebody
because a ghost told you to.
I'm not gonna kill
him. I'm gonna stop him.
Define "stop," huh? I
mean, what are you gonna do?
Dean, please.
He's gonna hurt someone. You know it.
All right, come on.
Dean.
Unlock my door.
You're not killing anyone, sam.
I got this guy. You go do the séance.
Dean.
What are you doing?
What is this?
Father, please. I can explain.
Uh...
Actually, maybe i can't. Um...
This is a... a séance.
A séance?
Young man, you are in a house of god.
It's based on early christian
rites, if that helps.
Enough. You're coming with me.
Father, please, just wait a second.
Oh, my god.
Is that...
Is that an angel?
No, it's not.
It's just fr. Gregory.
Thomas!
I've come in answer to your prayers.
Sam....i thought i
sent you on your path.
You should hurry.
Father, i'm sorry.
But you're not an angel.
Of course i am.
No.
You're a man.
You're a spirit.
And you need to rest.
I was a man...
But now i'm an angel.
I was on the steps at the church.
I felt that bullet
pierce right through me.
But there was no pain.
And, suddenly, i could see...
Everything.
Fr. Reynolds, i saw you...
Praying and crying here.
I came to help you.
Help me how?
Damn it!
Those
murders --
That was because of you?
I received the word of god.
He spoke to me, told
me to smite the wicked.
I'm carrying out his will.
You're driving innocent people to kill.
Those innocent people are
being offered redemption.
Some people need redemption.
Don't they, sam?
How can you call this redemption?
You can't understand it now.
But the rules of man
and the rules of god
Are two very different things.
Those people --
They're locked up.
No, they're happy.
They've found peace,
beaten their demons.
And i've given them the keys to heaven.
No, no. This is vengeance.
It's wrong.
Thomas, this goes against
everything you believed.
You're lost, misguided.
Father... no, i'm not misguided.
You are not an angel, thomas.
Men cannot be angels.
But...
But i-I don't understand.
You prayed for me to come.
I prayed for god's help, not this.
What you're doing is not god's will.
"Thou shalt not kill."
That's the word of god.
How come we stopped?
Um, weren't we gonna go to the movies?
We should go, or we're gonna be late.
I'm sorry.
It's just, i've never done this before.
Look, i said i was sorry.
Please...
Stop it!
Are you okay? Are you okay?
Thank god! Thank god!
Damn it.
Are you sure you're okay?
You have a cellphone? Call 911.
Let us help you.
No.
It's time to rest,
thomas, to be at peace.
Please. Let me give you last rites.
O holy hosts above,
I call upon thee as a servant of christ
To sanctify our actions this day
In fulfillment of the will of god.
Fr. Reynolds?
Rest.
I call upon the archangel raphael,
Master of the air, to make open the way.
Let the fire of the
holy spirit now descend,
That this being might be
awakened to the world beyond.
Holy...
How was your day?
You were right.
It wasn't an angel. It was gregory.
I don't know, dean, i just...
I wanted to believe...
So badly.
It's so damn
hard to do this --
What
we do --
All alone, you know?
There's so much evil
out in the world, dean,
I feel like i could drown in it.
And when i think about my destiny,
When i think about how i could end up...
Yeah, well, don't worry
about that, all right?
I'm watching out for you.
Yeah, i know you are.
But you're just one person, dean.
And i needed to think
That there was something
else watching, too, you know?
Some...higher power,
Some greater good.
And that maybe...
Maybe what?
Maybe i could be saved.
But, you know, that
just clouded my judgment.
And you're right.
I mean, we got to go with what we know,
With what's right there in
front of our own two eyes.
Well, it's funny you say that.
Why?
Gregory's spirit gave you
some pretty good information.
That guy in the car was bad news.
I barely got there in time.
What happened?
He's dead.
Did you...
No.
But i'll tell you one thing.
The way he died,
If i hadn't have seen
it with my own two eyes,
I never would have believed it.
I mean...
I don't know what to call it.
What?
Dean, what did you see?
Maybe
God's will.