The distant future....
Vampires rule the night, but their numbers are dwindling.
With huge bounties on their heads, a class of hunters has emerged, Bounty Hunters.
One hunter is unlike all the others. He is a Dunpeal; a half human half vampire.
At war with himself, feared by all, tortured and alone, he is...
Here he comes!
Hail Mary, full of grace. The Lord is with thee. Blessed art thou among women. Blessed is the Lord Jesus Christ....
We've been expecting you
I'm Alan Elbourne, and I'm the one that summoned you here today for this reason.
Go on. I'm listening.
It's about my sister, Charlotte
Two nights ago she disappeared
She was in bed, sleeping; it was the middle of the night.
Several people told us they saw a carriage outside our house.
The carriage ...
... belonged to Meier Link, the vampire
I organized a search party of fifty men
but it was no use; we couldn't find them
We were ambushed.
... took my sister and killed my friends.
That's just a down payment.
You'll get the rest when you find her.
Ten million dollars.
But you better move fast
you've got some competition.
I've hired the Markus Brothers
and they've got a head start on you.
I don't think so.
Huh?
It may be too late for her
Your sister may already have been tempted.
What then?
You have to get there before that happens
what do you think we're paying you for?!
That's enough!
My son is emotional; please excuse him
This has been difficult for all of us.
If you knew my daughter, you'd understand
she's kind and beautiful
and her loss is more than this old soul can bear.
Now, I need to ask you something
if you find her changed, can you see that her death is without suffering.
Be kind to her, please.
No -- no!
We can't do that; it isn't right.
No! She won't be changed
you're talking about your daughter!
Alan, listen to me.
It's not easy to ask him for this
but it's something that must be done.
I'm sorry.
Do you understand?
I understand your position, but ...
... ten million dollars is not enough.
What?
How dare you!
Stop it
hold your fire!
I said stop!
I'll double the price.
I'll give you twenty million.
Just bring her back
one way or the other.
Did you see a carriage go by here with four horses in front?
Let me go
let me go
le
You're lying.
Oh, damn; we got company.
Lotsa company.
Look out!
Oh, man. Is everybody OK?
Yeah.
Do you believe that?
The place is overrun with them.
He musta been here already.
Well, c'mon
ready or not, here they come
It's zombie time.
Yeah, come and get it, zombies!
Amen to that.
Leila, are you there?
It won't take long, Grove.
Just...stay in the tank.
Can't load!
Not so fast, buddy.
And
fire!
Gotcha!
Rest in peace, huh?
You hear that?
Sounds like a horse.
It's moving...uphill
Let me try.
Right ...
right about ...
right there!
Beautiful, just beautiful.
I applaud you, stranger.
Tell me what you're doing here.
If we're in the same game, we should be friends.
Tell me your name.
Mine's Borgoff, Borgoff Markus.
D.
Ah, so that's the guy, the dhampir hunter.
I've heard about him.
He's amazing.
Wake up, Borgoff, he's the competition, not some buddy of ours.
C'mon, what are we doing here, we just helped him, think about it.
Yeah, he's right, I agree with him about that.
We help him too much and he'll take all the money.
If it wasn't for us, he'd be dead by now.
We do the work and he gets the reward.
Ah, you boys should relax.
We just did the famous dhampir a little favor is all.
A little favor we can't afford.
Hey
y'ever hear the one about the owl and squirrel?
Squirrel works all summer storin' away stuff for the winter, all kinds of nuts and seeds
works real hard.
Then one day just before the first snow he goes outside for one last look around when
all of a sudden this owl swoops down and
grabs him, carries him off.
"Ah, what a shame," says the squirrel
"'cause what's gonna happen to all that good food?"
Aw, that's a good one.
Yeah, hilarious.
You get it, you guys?
That stupid squirrel is all I can
Leila!
Hey, Leila, what's the rush?
What's with her?
So you're outnumbered, four to one; so what?
They do have a head start, but when the sun comes up, the heat will slow 'em down.
Speaking of, ah, sun and heat, I know I don't need to remind you of your susceptibility.
It's called heat syndrome...
and the last time you ignored it, you almost
Don't worry.
I hate it when you say that.
What...what are those ?
Tracks
let me see
Yes, OK! these are definitely that tracks, six hours old I'd say
OK.
I'm suffocating now.
Hey, how was that?
That's funny
I could have sworn I heard something.
Quiet.
Sand mantas, most likely.
Sweet blasphemy, sand mantas galore!
Talk about your prehistoric pigeons.
They're filthy animals, y'know, they're just filthy!
Well, I--I guess we better just turn back
it's a shame, really, 'cause you know, we could
No -- go back, man
go back, now, c'mon
you're crazy
c'mon, man -- please, let's' just go back
That -- that was good
OK, now, we survived that, could we stop?
Did...did you ever hear the expression "too close for comfort"?
That--that was damn uncomfortable.
What is it ? a resting house?
I didn't think anybody had those any more.
They must be in there.
Wow, it blends in nicely.
OK...oh, here we are.
I -- I see 'em.
How many are there?
Two...I think.
A man ... and a woman.
Look out for the exit door.
No door ...
no door there ...
still no door...
no ...
Are you sure ... about that door ...?
No ... no ...
What was that?
She's out of her mind!
Door! DOOR!
You're dead!
I'm here for the young woman.
I wouldn't recommend it, dhampir.
Taking on a vampire at night is a mission for morons and fools.
which are you?
She's here by her own choice, dhampir.
So unless you're the kind of man who would take a woman against her will for the money in it
and I'm sure it's a lot
I suggest you save your sorry ass now and leave us to travel in peace.
I would if I could believe you, Meier.
Your credibility, however, is less than impeccable under the circumstances.
You kidnapped the girl.
Meier!
Oh, my nose, my nose!
What happened ?
what'd...what'd I miss?
She called out his name.
It may be true, what he said.
No, she's just ignorant
she's a child.
She doesn't know him yet.
She doesn't know what he's capable of.
That poor girl
she's...she's bleeding pretty bad.
I mean, she won't last long.
It's a shame
really -- to waste all that good blood
I mean -- come on, admit it -- you're tempted.
I mean, I know you are!
M...Mother...
Wait, I was just kidding, y'know.
C'mon, let's go.
We got work to do...
...The money, c'mon; think of the money!
Hey, what did you do to me?
I bound your wound and stopped your bleeding. That's all.
Oh, I get it.
You think you can just go ahead and tear off the clothes of whoever you come across.
That's what you think, isn't it, DHAMPIR.
You should go back home and nurse your wounds.
What are you, my mother?
You called out for your mother before
I thought you might be needing her.
Hey
I see her.
When the last vampire is extinct, who will mourn our passing?
Will she? will anyone?
Can anyone understand this pain, this loneliness?
I told you so, didn't I?
I said, leave the girl alone
she's trouble
she's competition, y'know.
YOU aided and abetted the enemy.
I hope this is the right way.
Trust me, I know how they think, these vampires:
when they're threatened, they all head for Barbarois.
They're so predictable.
Barbarois, yeah
And I really hate that place.
It's full of lunatics and monsters, and that old crazy man, y'know.
Does it hurt very much, Leila?
Leila?
Huh?
Your injury...does it hurt you?
Oh, no, it's fine.
I...
Grove, you should lie down, you look tired.
You need to rest...don't worry about me.
Leila...
who dressed the wound? Was it him?
You can tell me.
It was him, wasn't it? The dhampir hunter.
Leila, I'm warning you
he...he's trouble. He's against us.
I don't know why he did that.
Grove, please don't tell anyone, OK?
He stopped there
but what for?
Let's find out.
Nolt and Kyle, you come with me
Leila, you stay in here with Grove.
OK...is everybody ready?
Always.
Ready.
Yeah.
Hey, Nolt,  see what's goin' on in there, willya?
It may be a trap.
Yeah, we'll cover you.
It'll be my pleasure, gentlemen
It's nothin' but a lousy piece of cloth.
What the hell ?
Bastard...unbelievable!
Hey...watch out!
So...
you dare to enter Barbarois
I assume it's arrogance and vast stupidity that brings you here, gentlemen
or perhaps it's ignorance.
You're skillful hunters, I can see
but you're no match for the Barbarois.
Five thousand years of isolation have made us invincible!
Huh?
What?
What the hell's going on?
The shadow...
...watch out for the shadow.
What're you talking about?
The shadow...whaddayou mean?
Hey...Nolt?
Hey, Nolt, what the hell happened to you, huh?
He's...He's dead!
No, he's not!
Come on, Nolt...
...come on, snap out of it, come on...
oh my God, damn it, come on!
I need you!
Oh God...Nolt !
Oh, God...we're getting close.
Those...are the windmills of the Barbarois.
I really wish you'd turn back.
There must be another way.
There isn't.
I am D, the hunter
I have business with the Barbarois.
Oh, no.....
So I see you have dismounted.
You have respect for your elders.
That's very considerate indeed.
I want you to stop your protection of Meier Link.
You what?
You know, you make me laugh, that's a good one.
I see you are a very humorous young man, and beautiful too, I might add.
Or does that make you uncomfortable, to have an old lech like me admire you so?
Do you take me for a fool?
Someone paid me a hundred million dollars to protect Meier Link.
Can you top that?
Well, you drive a hard bargain there, old man
what if I can?
You really are entertaining me, Mr. Stranger!
I suppose you know our reputation
the Barbarois serve the people of the night,
and after five thousand years, I don't think we're about to change our stripes anytime soon,
although if we did for anyone it would be for you.
I have seen many a dhampir,
but somebody like you I've never seen before.
That's why it's such a pity that you have to die.
I really can't let you leave here alive, now, can I?
I'm afraid you have to die, Stranger.
So sorry.
The Barbarois are great warriors.
You are a warrior too, no doubt
and although you may kill some of us,
in the end we will prevail.
I have sworn to protect the carriage
prepare to die!
Fool!
What's he doin' in there?
Borgoff, are we ready yet?
Grove
we have no choice.
We need your help on this, Grove.
Think you can do it there, man?
Give it to me
I'm waiting.
Don't push yourself too hard, now.
I mean it, OK
I want you back.
You know, I really have nothing against the Barbarois personally.
It's a shame I'll have to kill so many of you.
Indeed, I admire your loyalty and your devotion to duty.
Yet I wonder about the fairness when you allow one to fight against so many.
But...
if that will entertain you...
I see.
you make I see. a good argument, young man
how interesting.
Oh, man, I think the fellow is right.
Please allow the three of us to entertain our young guest here,
unless he thinks that's unfair
three against one, how unfair, three against one, unfair...
That's enough!
You mock us with your ridiculous antics, Benge.
I will not have you distracting us from the job at hand, which is the protection of the carriage.
We'll do things my way...huh?
What the devil is that?
Go for it, Grove...go for it!
Kill all those guys
kill every last one of 'em!
Come on, Grove, hold on.
Get the carriage out now!
Follow me, Tinkerbell.
I'm waiting for you!
Grove!
I've got to say this
I admire that young hunter's spirit,
although he doesn't stand a chance against Benge and the others.
Still, it's a pity I'll miss the show.
Oh well, c'est la vie.
Wake up, D!
What's wrong with you?
It's not fair, it's not fair
I'll show you what's not fair!
Stay there till you rot, hunter!
Suckers!
Stop, I beg you.
Say goodnight.
Kyle, did you happen to see where that girl went?
Maybe she got caught in the wheels.
Go look.
Nice, Caroline, very nice.
A little crude, but effective.
They're all yours!
That freakin' monster.
Is everybody all right?
Yeah, but Kyle was outside.
He was up on top.
Kyle?
Kyle, where the hell are you, Kyle?
Down here!
You OK?
Quiet! They're still around!
No!
Damn! That idiot!
Well, how convenient this is for me.
Come on out here so I can finish the job.
Your time is up.
Come on, you coward!
You're gonna pay for the pain you caused my brother.
D! Are you awake?
I need your help to swallow up this spell.
You're a slave driver, you know that?
Hey, remember to watch out for the shadow, huh?
Try and stay still.
Easier said than done.
And keep your mouth shut.
That was close...
Well, the tank is fulla holes.
Fuel's all gone, we can't drive it like this anyway.
What're we gonna do?
What. Should. We. Do?
Borgoff, any idea?
How's Grove?
Honestly, not too great.
Borgoff, wake up!
What are you thinking about over there?
Oh, nothin', really.
I was just thinkin' about the carriage.
Wonder where it is by now.
Well, man, at this point it's pretty much anybody's guess.
If you want my opinion, I'd say they're either setting sail from the port of Abrol or hiding somewhere deep in the Grenerge Mountain Range.
I sure hope so.
Anyway, we still have to get some fuel
and the town of Garucia isn't that far away from here.
Kyle, you go with Leila.
I'll stay here and do the repairs.
If you are seeking the pathway to the stars, come to me.
I pray for your safe arrival with all my heart.
The pathway to the stars....
I dunno about you, but y'know, I sure miss that horse.
What was his name?
Oh...oh, the silent treatment, huh?
Well, I got two words for you: Heat syndrome.
Look -- look, I know I'm a parasite, but haven't I always been a helpful parasite?
You may not care if you die from heat
but becoming a piece of beef jerky is not a lifelong ambition of mine.
Yeah, well, what's the sound of one hand yapping...
How much?
Oh no -- keep your money.
C'mon, just take it --
Let's go.
Leila?
Oh. I see.
It's him, isn't it?
Kyle, why don't you start back without me.
There's something I want to do here first.
Back off.
Have I told you
you're quite irresistible in that sexy skin-tight getup?
No -- tell me about it.
I just did.
Make sure you watch your back with that guy, Leila.
I'd like a beer.
I've just been admirin' your fancy weapon there.
Don't worry.
I have no plans to use it anytime soon.
That's good.
That's good, 'cause I have no plans to let you keep it.
Give it up.
You heard me, little girl.
Mm. Thank you.
Well, here's to ya, Sheriff.
I'd buy you a drink, but...
Thank you, but no thanks.
Oh, OK. I was just gonna say, you must be awfully busy with that new dhampir hunter in the town now.
What dhampir hunter?
I'd like to buy that horse.
Three hundred thousand dollars.
And if you don't like the price, go somewhere else.
Freeze! Put your hands where I can see 'em. Now!
Sheriff, he paid good money for that.
What are you doing?!
Take your money and go.
We don't want you here.
We don't sell to dhampirs in this town, understand?
Understand me, dhampir?
You understand.
Wait a minute. That's my horse you're talking about there,
and I'll sell it to whoever I want if they can afford the price I'm asking.
You can't do that.
We have laws against it, Polk...good laws, and for a damn good reason.
What laws?
Don't play coy, Polk, you know as well as I dhampirs aren't allowed.
Not allowed, right ...
I remember a time not that long ago when we had vampires and dhampirs both around here. But...
And that's why we have the law.
Listen to me, whether you want to hear it or not...you weren't even born when this happened.
Do yourself a favor and listen to the story.
I'm going to tell you about the time when the children were kidnapped.
There were ten children altogether ...
Yeah, I heard about that time.
The kidnappers turned out to be vampires, of course.
And so the townspeople pooled their money to hire a vampire hunter.
They wanted the best.
And when the hunter came...
he was a very strong and quiet man.
and he did his job, too, which was to return the children safely back into their parents' homes.
It wasn't easy, but many vampires died by his hands before this job was over with.
And when it was over and the children were back home,
the people attacked the man.
They said he was a dhampir, half vampire himself...so they punished him.
Can't say I blame them for doing that.
You can't trust 'em, that's all that's about.
They were right about that part, Polk.
He did the job!
I see then, I'll have to take matters into my own hands.
Let him go.
What is that?
What does it look like, idiot?
Put down your guns.
Polk, you can't know what you're doing ... put it down...
I know exactly what I'm doing.
You DON'T know! Put it down now, you old fool!
I would much rather be an old fool than what you are, Sheriff.
Now, don't shoot.
I can tell you I won't think twice about using this weapon.
I might even enjoy it.
Get on your horse, Stranger.
Thank you.
No, it's only fitting I thank you.
It's the least I can do.
I may be just an old fool now, Stranger,  but I could never forget a face like yours.
And I'll never forget what you done for me back then.
That's right...I was one of them kids.
And I always felt bad about that
the way you was treated.
How nobody stopped you, nobody thanked you instead the ignorant bastards ran you right out of our town.
So it's true, isn't it, what they say about you dhampirs.
You don't age.
Now go...I'm getting tired.
Where's Benge? What's taking him so long?
Well, the horses are rested now. We'd better go.
Come on.
Master, what is it? May I help you, sir?
It's still light outside, Master!
What...?
Leave her alone, Mashira.
Yes, sir.
She misses the sunlight. Let her enjoy it.
I am D, the hunter.
Your father sent me.
Don't be afraid...I won't hurt you.
You sit in the sunlight...you must not be changed.
So why do you stay with him?
Last night in the carriage you called out his name.
Why did you call for him?
I suppose my father has not told you that I'm in love with Meier.
You don't know who he is.
You can't be in love with him.
Well, I am.
If you only knew how good he's been to me.
I love him.
Please believe me; no one else will.
You don't understand.
He is what he is, Charlotte.
You can't change him; he'll take you in time.
And when that happens, I will have to kill you.
Fine; kill me, then.
I would rather die than to go anywhere without him.
Don't take me back there...I mean it. I simply could not live without Meier.
How sweet that is.
She loves a vampire.
So very sweet.
Idiot!
You stupid girl, get up! We're going.
Leave me alone!
You'll do what I say.
Do you have any idea how many people have died at the hands of your beloved Meier, this vampire you wanna protect!
None!
You fool! And you...You stay right where you are, my friend.
Sorry, but I really don't want to have to share any of my profits.
You understand, don't you...it's business.
Above you.
What's wrong? Tell me!
Too much sun.
I warned you about the heat, but you don't listen!
Come on. You can't survive unless you dig a hole. You need to bury yourself!
Hurry!
Leila! Leila, are you there? Come in, Leila.
Yeah, I copy.
Thank God. Are you OK? What's your position?
I'm near Lake Chiffon. Our game is heading north from here.
We'll catch up.
Leila, do you know what's happened to the dhampir hunter?
No; I haven't seen him.
All right. Well, take care.
Stay in touch. Borgoff out.
The tables have turned.
Now, that cleared my head.
I really should return the favor, don't you think, honey?
Don't get any ideas.
Hey, I'm just trying to stay dry here.
If there was any other place to go, believe me, I'd be there.
As soon as the rain lets up, I'll be gone from here and from you.
I think I can guess your problem.
Your family was the victim of vampires.
You don't know what you're talking about.
You don't know anything about it.
All right. Perhaps I don't.
This stupid thing...it bothers me.
You really are a weird one, you know that?
In spite of being a dhampir hunter and all that that entails.
How did you know about my mother?
You called her name, remember?
She was kidnapped by vampires.
My father went after her and was trying to rescue her ... so they killed him.
And after a while my mother returned, but she wasn't my mother any more
she'd been changed.
The people in the village stoned her to death while I watched.
After that I left home.
I met the Markus brothers and joined with them.
I wanted to be a hunter to avenge my parents' deaths.
I've seen many terrible things since then, lives destroyed, families devastated, hopes crushed...
every time, it seems ... vampire is to blame.
I can understand why you'd choose to do it, but the life of a hunter is no kind of life.
It's the only life I'm any good for now, and it looks like it's the only life you've ever known.
So I suggest we make a pact.
Since we're both in it for the long haul, whoever dies first, the other one can come and bring flowers to their grave.
How's that?
It's the rain
makes me sentimental.
I don't know why I should care about that...it's just I love flowers.
And I don't think I'll be getting any...
I'm all alone, after all.
We have that much in common, don't we.
That we're both hunters and we're both alone.
Oh well, I'm being silly...doesn't really matter
I'll do it.
I'll bring you flowers if I survive this...but I don't expect to.
Stop, I didn't really mean it when I said that.
And anyway, I don't really understand why you should keep on doing this.
Because I'm a dhampir.
I don't get to have a life; not like you.
Well, with the rainstorm last night, they can't be too far away.
We're even now, dhampir...understand?
I have a very bad feeling about this.
How so?
I think I've finally figured it out, Borgoff.
Well, I'm sure you're right...if you're thinking they're headed for the castle.
Yeah, that's right, the castle...the Castle of Chaythe!
WHAT ARE YOU THINKING, WE CAN'T GO IN THERE, IT WOULD BE SUICIDE!
What are you now, afraid of a little insanity?
Since when have we been sane?
We just have to get to them before they reach the castle.
There's a bridge up ahead...that's where we intercept the carriage.
I remember that trick from the time we got those vampires at Keldo.
Yeah, it worked that time, and it can work again now.
Leila, come in; come in, Leila. Over.
Yeah it's me, I copy.
What's up?
I'm on my way.
Don't move.
I'm warning you...try anything funny and you'll be blown to smithereens.
You wanna try it?
I didn't think so.
We just want the girl.
Hello there!
She's still human!
Come on, get out of there. NOW!
Borgoff, she won't come.
We're doing you a favor!
Come ON, I said get outta there!
Let that be a lesson to ya, you cowardly Barbarois animal.
Borgoff, look.
Borgoff!
What? What the --?
What, is this guy crazy?
Doesn't he know he can't exist outside here in the sunlight?
I won't let you take her!
Oh, yeah?
Thanks a lot...you're making our job a lot easier.
Hot enough for ya?
What you deserve!
Over here, hot stuff!
Oohoo, lookit him burn!
No!
What the hell do you want...
How's that feel...moron...!
lookit him!
Hey, where do you think...!
Why'd you let her go!
I love you.
I can't go on without you.
What?
Borgoff, we should just let her kill herself
and then we can finish him off, what do you think about that idea?
We get the money if she's dead or alive.
Hey, you're right...OK.
Stop it!
Kyle!
I'll blow you to hell!
What!
I don't want you to worry about these wounds of mine.
They will heal.
Then we shall go to the city of night and distant stars.
When we go there we can be alone and free to love each other.
It's true, believe me; we'll be there soon.
We're it now; we're the only ones left, Borgoff; we should just give it up.
If we make it into that castle, none of us will make it out alive.
We CAN'T quit now.
We owe it to Kyle and to Nolt to keep going on.
Listen, Borgoff...
Shaddup! I won't hear it.
Leila...what do you think?
Grove, they fear us.
They fear us because they know our reputation. That we never give up.
And we never can.
If we quit now, we might as well quit the business, and I can't do that.
I won't do it...till every last one of them is gone.
Master...do you hear?
He is coming.
The castle is nearby.
I'll stay here and deal with him.
Getting close. The Castle of Chaythe.
Soon we'll be able to see it
the home of Carmila, the Bloody Countess.
You've heard of her.
For five thousand years her rule of terror lasted, and then, that was that!
Your father, the vampire king, grew angry.
He was impatient with her vanity; offended by her bloodlust, her gluttony.
He grew so tired that he killed her while she slept, impaling her on a sword, and that was it for her.
Except she haunts the place now with phantoms and demons, but you don't care about that, do you?
But I bet I know what really gets to you, dhampir
what REALLY gets to you
the thought of those two lovebirds giving birth to another dhampir, huh?
That's it.
You see, I know you; I know how you think, I know how you feel, I know every move that you make, you can't...
I'm glad we could meet at last, Hunter D.
You are a worthy opponent.
Who hired the Barbarois?
Who were you working for?
It was Carmila who hired us.
And as a Barbarois, my duty has been fulfilled.
Now I can die in peace.
I gather from your letter that you had a rather difficult time.
I think I can understand what it's like.
Love is not unique to humans, you know
we vampires are very susceptible.
I hope I can be of service.
We're very grateful, Carmila.
You both must be exhausted.
Perhaps you should rest first.
I'm sure that the young lady would like to freshen up.
You've probably heard rumors about me, but I can assure you, they all stem from jealousy and envy.
I'm not the "Bloody Carmila" they like to portray me as.
Now, behold...
That's it; that is the ship.
It will take you to the city of the night where you can live peacefully at last.
You can be happy there.
There was a time, many years ago, when every castle had a ship like this one and the night sky was full of their flashing lights.
Those were the days when vampires flourished and a love like yours was not so desperately impossible.
So different from today.
Our numbers dwindling, hunted and alone, we're hopelessly misunderstood
but you two seem to have beaten the odds.
I'm very very happy for you.
The ship hasn't been used in years.
I've no idea if it will fly safely, but I'm sure that's a risk you're prepared to take.
We're very grateful.
I only wish I could go with you.
You look so beautiful.
Why stop? I want you, Meier. I want all of you.
Why not?
You don't know what it's like, Charlotte
to live forever in darkness eternal, forever thirsting for blood despite your best intention.
I can't imagine that life for you; not for you, Charlotte.
You're so selfish, Meier.
I carry a heavy weight on my conscience.
Those villagers and the bounty hunter and my family...they still mourn my loss, Meier.
It wasn't your doing, Charlotte.
It was my fault entirely.
Well, then we're both to blame, because we can't know happiness; not anymore.
I wanted you to be happy, Meier, and so I abandoned my father and my brother for you.
But their pain set the wheels in motion for our pain, and so on and on it goes.
All we have is each other now, and I want to be close to you.
Without that we have nothing.
All the pain I've caused and all the agony I feel is nothing now!
And you are everything to me, my love.
We'll talk more on our trip to the stars, if that's all right with you.
There is some unfinished business I have to attend to.
Do not leave this room, understand?
D.
Listen, Meier. The woman says she wants to go back home.
I don't ... believe it.
Charlotte....
I dunno, something's not right.
'Course, ah, you don't have to take my word for it
you can judge for yourself.
Let's go!
Leila, don't go.
Leila, don't go in there.
If you go in there, you're never coming back!
Oh, I'm coming back.
No!
Leila, check upstairs.
I'm on it.
Nice hat.
I know you hate me, D.
Please try and understand.
I loved your father.
What choice did I have?
Nolt, Kyle
hey, I don't believe it!
You two sure are a sight for sore eyes!
What are you doing? Get up!
Why aren't you listening...I said get up!
Go away.
Get out of here!
Can you forgive me, D?
D?
I know it's been lonely for you.
I was lonely too
until you came along.
Did you hear? D?
It's OK, honey
it's OK to cry.
I know ... I know how you feel.
It wasn't your fault. It wasn't.
Yes it was!
Let go!
It's just an illusion.
Carmila's playing with us.
Excellent...what fun!
I haven't had this much fun in centuries!
You don't mind, do you?
It just makes things so much more interesting.
You're doing very well, by the way very well indeed.
The woman...where are you hiding her?
Borgoff...what are you doing! We don't have time for this!
Leila -- are you in love with this dhampir?
Are you crazy? What is wrong with you
Borgoff!
Dhampir
drop your weapon.
Drop it now!
She took you in, didn't she?
She'll die! I'm warning you, dhampir, don't come any closer.
Enough! Now you die
Grove!
Grove, no!
Lei ... la ...
Look...she's coming...Carmila.
The spirit of Carmila!
Dhampir hunter...your mother was human, but your father was a vampire, and you're betraying his ancient blood.
You side with humans against us.
Your people are facing extinction, and you're contributing to their demise.
You stalk and kill your own ancestors, dhampir
YOU SHOULD BE ASHAMED!
Your human self is your weaker self.
Humans are nothing more than livestock.
We prey on them as they prey on beasts.
This is the rule of nature!
Your time is coming to an end.
Your kind must face extinction.
You cannot survive; you must die.
That is the rule of nature.
Ah...very strong words for a dhampir.
But you seem to forget...our spirits are eternal.
No, Carmila; nothing lasts forever.
I see.
I should have known better than to reason with your kind, dhampir hunter.
I guess my only option is to use force.
No...this can't happen!
Are you the son of the vampire king?
Who are you? Who are you, dhampir?
Such power...!
Charlotte, come back. I need you; please come back.
Darling, is that you?
Oh yes. It's me...Meier.
I'm so happy, Meier, because we are together now. At last.
Together. At last.
You made me happy, Meier.
You let me dream. You let me dream of our beautiful trip to the stars.
Our dream.
Our beautiful, wonderful dream.
It's not a dream. We are going to those stars, Charlotte.
Oh, my dear one.
You and I will get away from here.
We will fly together to the city of the night where we were meant to be free from all of this
where you can rest, my love, finally, and be free.
Yes...freedom! At last....
My precious, precious love.
Let's go...away from here.
Stop right there, Meier.
I'm taking her back...back to her family who loved her.
She knew I loved her best of all.
You can't understand it. You've never loved a human.
I've never killed one, either.
You struggle to resist this nature of ours, but it can't last forever, D.
The urge for their blood is stronger.
If that day comes, then another will hunt me.
It's as simple as that.
What a waste. What a sad waste.
Enough of killing. Enough of misery and death.
I've had enough.
I've ... had enough!
Why ... did you miss ... my heart?
She's dead. The ring is all I need.
I'll take it to her father.
As proof.
Mind giving me a ride just as far as the next town?
I'd appreciate it.
That reward money would rightfully be mine, y'know.
But hey, I'm generous.
I'll let you keep it just this one time.
Where is he taking her?
Away from here.
Away
Fly, COME ON!
You can make it
come on!
Fly away ...
Dearly beloved, we are gathered here in this resting place to bid farewell to our sister.
Into your gentle arms we commend her gracious spirit.
Take her to yourself and give her safe haven.
And though she struggled in life, now she knows your blessed peace.
For all who question will find answers,
and all who love will find contentment, joy, and peace eternal.
For now we see as through a glass darkly,
but then we shall see clearly, face to face.
Mister!
Wait!
Mister, WAIT!
excuse me, sir, but...I was wondering if you knew my grandmother Leila.
Yes ... it's you, isn't it.
My grandmother told me about you,
so...I'd be honored if you'd come to our house, my dad would be so happy
please?
I appreciate your kindness.
Oh, c'mon. We don't live very far.
I just came here to keep a promise to an old ... friend of mine.
She was afraid no one would mourn her death.
I'm glad she was so wrong.
Huh?
OK, I guess I see. .....
Anyway, thank you for coming, sir.
G'bye!
G-bye!!
Well, that was nice.
You're not so bad after all.
You just dress bad.