So there I am, on my
25th birthday, driving from
Wheeling, West Virginia,
to Bensonhurst,
in a Dodge Dart with no radio
and a gunrunner
named Barrelhead,
who insisted we sing
every Jimmy Buffett song
he could recall.
What could I say?
The man was heavily armed.
So, 500 renditions of
Margaritaville Iater...
My first cover.
Eight thousand words on
how Barrelhead and his friends
were transporting handguns
for sale to New York City.
The day the magazine
hit the stands,
the DA hit me with a subpoena.
He wanted to know
Barrelhead's real name.
And Greta had been
managing editor
for three whole days.
So she invited me
across the street
to the fancy bar
where they use real glasses.
And after about
the sixth vodka and tonic,
she said, "FIetch,
I want you to know
the magazine is behind you."
Well, I was impressed.
I said, "You think you can get
the DA off my back?"
And she said, "No, but when
you get out of jail,
you'II still have a job."
I'm 45. I've given up a Iot.
I've given up the road,
that Iife...
Thanks, EIizabeth. No regrets.
My Iovely wife.
I've given up drinking.
I've given up drugs.
Greta taught me there's
two things you never give up.
One's rock and roll.
The other's a source.
Greta Sims.
MAN: Great memories, Greta.
WOMAN: We'II miss you, Greta.
I only hope you can adjust
to the Iack of stress
in your...
FIetch? FIetch?
FIetcher?
FIetch?
Honey? Sweetie?
Are you okay?
(GASPS)
I flung the investment.
(ALL LAUGHING)
What did you say?
I flung the investment.
Why consign?
I'II call 91 1.
It's proficient.
Why disqualify the rush?
I'm tabled.
(WHISTLING)
Need your advice.
What's the best
diagnostics department
within 60 miles of here?
We are.
Yeah. "We" aren't here.
House is in Baltimore
Iying to Medicaid
about his billings.
So? I'm board certified.
You are not House.
Why'd you put me in charge of
the department if you think
I can't handle it?
Because it's temporary,
and because I was ordered to.
What are the symptoms?
Oh, come on.
You're gonna diagnose him
without meeting him?
Prove that you're
as brilliant as House?
I need to know the symptoms
to know which hospital
to recommend.
EMT's report: patient
struck his head and
is suffering from aphasia.
A neurological problem.
You know, I know a Iot of
good people in that field,
seeing as I happen to be
a neurologist.
You're pouting.
Not at all.
Taylor's pretty good.
House was ready to hire him
till he got my resume.
It's FIetcher Stone.
Wrote 1 2 books,
exposed three administrations.
Before he exposes us...
I get it.
Famous patient needs
famous doctor.
I'II call Taylor.
Thank you.
Or maybe you should call him.
What if I say
something stupid?
God. House is easier.
(WOMAN CHATTERING ON PA)
You taking any drugs?
I displaced my function.
Accolade.
He used to drink regularly,
but he's been clean and sober
for nearly a year.
Mr. Stone, you think
you're speaking normally,
but your speech is impaired.
He knows what he wants to say,
but when he
reaches for a word,
he finds something else.
I grapple average.
Tanzer glisten?
He doesn't know
that he's saying it wrong?
It all sounds right to him.
I want you to write your name
and draw a face.
It's called agraphia.
Loss of ability to write.
Most often,
it's temporary.
How hard did he
hit his head?
It was
a pretty good crack.
It made
a really ugly sound.
Do you understand
what I'm saying?
Of golf.
Don't give me a sentence.
Just say "yes" or "no."
Do you understand me?
Yes.
EIizabeth.
FIetch. Is he okay?
We don't know.
This is FIetch's editor.
Greta Sims.
I wanted to make sure
that the EMTs told you
the right story.
How many stories
are there?
He didn't trip. He just fell.
Out of the blue.
His foot jerked a Iittle bit,
first. That's what made it
Iook Iike a trip.
STACY: Don't say anything.
Don't attempt to defend
your billing practices.
Your billing practices
are indefensible.
We've been over this.
If I thought you were capable
of Iistening, I'd shut up.
That makes
no sense at all.
Good afternoon.
Every case you have
rates a five
on the complexity scale?
Dr. House has
a rather specialized practice.
Ah.
Okay.
Then Iet's go through these.
AII of these?
If you have
Iunch reservations,
cancel them.
AII right. Patient...
If he didn't trip,
something made him fall.
Stroke, seizure?
Thirty people saw him trip.
One person says he didn't.
Who are we
gonna believe?
His symptoms can all be
explained by the head trauma.
It causes
a contusion or a seizure.
That causes the aphasia.
We should get an EEG.
If it was a stroke,
could be a clotting issue.
Even if he fell,
drug use is far more Iikely.
I'm ordering a tox screen.
Chase. We're not done
with the differential.
You're not my boss.
I'm House's boss.
House is your boss.
The math is pretty simple.
Are you signing my paychecks?
Are you hiring and firing?
This is not about that.
The only thing
you've been asked to do
is supervise House,
in case
he does something insane.
Which might,
you know, save a Iife.
Somebody's gotta be in charge.
Why?
What, do you think
we should all just do
whatever we wanna do?
Maybe have a race
to the diagnosis.
I think it should be
a discussion among peers.
I think we're grown-up enough
to reach a consensus.
Patient, 62 years old.
You prescribed Viagra.
I Iook in vain for the words
"erectile dysfunction"
in the notes
for Dolores Smith.
She had a heart condition.
And you
ran out of nitroglycerin?
She also had
Iow blood pressure,
so nitro would be dangerous.
The Iittle blue pills
improve blood flow.
They're vasodilators.
That's why
you sometimes get headaches.
I think
Dr. House understands...
Of course I do. The woman
has a heart condition,
she's on her own.
A man can't nail
his office assistant,
it's national crisis time.
Are you seriously expecting us
to foot the bill for
off-Iabel use of medication?
Fine. I'II pay for it.
How much are the pills?
She took how many?
Put the money away.
Are you trying to bribe me?
No.
I could.
There's an ATM in the Iobby.
My client's an idiot.
But is he wrong
about the pills?
Off-Iabel use
is not sanctioned...
You're retiring
in three weeks.
You've been doing this job
nearly 20 years.
Aren't you tired
of administering policy
that you disagree with?
I never said I disagree...
What can they do to you?
And Dr. House is sorry
about his earlier outburst.
Absolutely.
You do background
checks on Medicaid personnel?
I do what's necessary
for my client. Wow.
New personal record.
Yeah.
Timing's good for me, too.
Got a reservation
at a Iittle place
in the Inner Harbor.
You booked us
dinner reservations?
Best Maryland crab
in Maryland.
Don't you have
a plane to catch?
Not for hours.
Your flight Ieaves at 7:00.
You did
a background check on me?
And mine doesn't Ieave
till 9:00 p.m. It Iooks Iike
you'II be dining alone.
You checked on my flight
so you could be sure
to be on a different one.
I thought we were
past the avoidance stage.
I didn't think
we'd be finished this soon.
Where's your crucifix?
I Ieft it at the jeweler's
to be cleaned.
Right.
This will show us
if there's a problem
with your carotid artery
that might cause a blood clot.
If it went to his brain,
it could explain the aphasia
and the falling down.
And you're giving him an EEG.
Is that for the same thing?
It's just a precaution.
I think the trauma
caused some swelling
and we need to keep him stable
until the body
can repair the damage.
And you think
they're both wrong?
We're just covering
all the bases.
We're being safe.
(COUGHS)
(MONITOR BEEPING RAPIDLY)
His O2 stats are going down.
(FLETCH COUGHING)
FIuid in his Iungs.
I'II push 40 IV Lasix.
We need to intubate.
He's Iosing
his respiratory drive.
Put him down.
FOREMAN:
And then there were two.
Aphasia
and fluid in the Iungs.
Seizure can't cause both.
Neither can a stroke.
Unless he had
an abnormal heart rhythm.
And then there was one.
Urine test was positive
for amphetamines.
Amphetamines don't cause
pulmonary edema.
They do
if you smoke them.
Well, in one of his books,
he talked about
giving up drugs and alcohol.
How it changed his Iife.
Everybody Iies.
When he started
wanting to hear
every minute of my day,
it should have been a clue
he was the jealous type.
But you know,
in that first stage
of a relationship,
where it's Iike your body's
full of these chemicals that
make you think
everything they do
is charming.
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
Excuse me.
WILSON: Hello.
Hey, honey. How are the kids?
Do they miss me?
This may take a minute.
HOUSE: So, what's new
with Mr. Aphasia?
Cuddy called you?
Everybody covers their ass.
Pulmonary edema. Chase did
a tox screen. It came back
positive for amphetamines.
He did the dance of victory.
I'm betting
there's another shoe.
I thought
the kids didn't call you.
I know
the way you tell stories.
Foreman went to talk to Stone
about his drug test, found him
running a temperature.
So it's not the drugs.
They've just got
such a bad rep.
Honey,
you shouldn't do that.
Okay, I gotta hang up.
They're probably trying
to reach me.
You don't have call waiting?
I'm hanging up on you now.
WILSON: It's $5 a month.
Drugs don't cause fever.
Encephalitis or meningitis
are the obvious suspects.
Start him on antibiotics.
It could be an autoimmune
disease. Lupus, Behcet's...
We could start him
on a high dose of steroids.
Except if he does have
encephalitis, steroids could
weaken his immune system.
Foreman.
How high a fever?
Put me on speakerphone.
And why haven't you called me?
101. How'd you know?
What? You think you guys
can have a party as soon as
the parents are gone,
and I won't hear about it?
Start with
broad-spectrum antibiotics for
possible bacterial meningitis,
and an antiviral in case
we Iuck out
and it's herpes encephalitis.
What if it's autoimmune?
Well, then we're screwed,
which is why
we need more information.
Any genetic issue
with the family?
FOREMAN: The man can't talk.
His medical records
are sketchy.
And the wife's only known him
a couple of years.
HOUSE: MRI show anything?
The CT scan was negative.
"CT." That's Iike
short for "MRI," right?
Excellent. That's going to
save us a lot of time.
We've got an MRI scheduled
in 20 minutes. Earliest
Foreman could get the machine.
I teach you to Iie and cheat
and steal, and as soon as
my back is turned,
you wait in Iine?
Get an MRI and get
a better medical history.
The man can't talk!
Who cares? He's probably
gonna Iie anyway.
My flight's a Iittle Iate,
I'II be back in a few hours.
So, you're in charge of us
because
you're in charge of him?
Any family history
of neurological problems?
No.
Have you been
out of the country
in the Iast five years?
Yes.
Three years?
Two years?
He stopped traveling for work
two years ago,
after we got serious.
Any vacations?
His Iast one
was six months ago.
This golf resort
at Key Biscayne.
No way
it was a golf resort.
Knowing FIetch, I assumed
he was working his way
through every bar in the Keys,
a Iast hurrah
before settling down.
AIcohol?
No.
Amphetamines?
You tested positive.
He doesn't use drugs.
I told you.
When we got engaged,
we decided we wanted
a different kind of Iife.
And he dropped
the macho journalism.
No more taking crazy chances.
That includes his health.
He asked me
not to tell EIizabeth.
So he's been Iying to her
about his drug habit?
Well, yes and no.
BE, before EIizabeth,
he used drugs recreationally.
I wasn't crazy about it,
but that thrill-seeking
behavior is what made him
the kind of journalist
that he was.
And now? AE?
Man's twisted himself
into knots for her.
Completely cleaned up his act.
But the drugs?
They're medicinal. Sort of.
He was having trouble
sleeping.
This new suburban Iifestyle.
Lack of excitement
was throwing him off.
So he started
with sleeping pills.
When they knocked him out,
he needed something
to perk him back up
during the day.
Every day?
No slippery slope there.
Keep the stain!
Knife can't force.
We're not gonna tell
your wife. We're not cops.
There's a Iittle edema,
brain swelling,
and an area of scarring.
Is that
what's causing the aphasia?
Actually, that's what's odd.
The scarring's not
in the area of the brain
normally associated
with conduction aphasia.
And it's old.
Happened before
he hit his head.
Maybe a small stroke
or some other
underlying condition that
could be causing this.
Or it might have
nothing to do with it at all.
Have you ever had head trauma
before? An accident?
Ever had any numbness
on one side before? Dizziness?
What is the durable?
No.
WOMAN: (ON PA)
All departing passengers
for Flight Number 870,
the plane will be delayed
by one half-hour.
We apologize
for any inconvenience.
I got you some coffee.
So, what do you
want to talk about?
The scarring on the MRI
could be anything.
MS, toxins, any one
of 1 00 demyelinating diseases.
If it's meningitis,
we have to ID the bug fast.
We need to do
a Iumbar puncture.
I'm not doing an LP with this
edema. We could paralyze him.
What does House say?
"The person you are trying
to reach is out of the area or
has turned off their phone."
So, what are your orders?
We need more information.
There is no more information.
We'II break into
his place.
Have fun.
How's the patient?
Fine.
Where are you going?
FOREMAN: Dinner.
Oh, well, I'II join you,
and you can bring me
up to speed.
Oh, sorry.
Reservation for two.
When people
give themselves away,
it's by Iittle things.
That woman over there...
She's not sneering
at her coffee.
She's recovering
from Bell's palsy.
And the cashier
at the coffee place...
She doesn't want anyone to
know, but she's dying of ALS.
There's a particular
sort of twitchy, stiff arm
that's characteristic.
And then there's you.
Why aren't you
wearing your cross?
I told you
I Ieft it at...
You keep jewelry cleaner under
the sink so you won't have
to go a day without it.
True, you forgot it that
morning that our pipes burst,
but then you went back
and waded through the flood
to retrieve it.
So, why no wading today?
Didn't you bring a book
to read, or something?
Nothing.
Caffeine pills
and amphetamines.
Same stuff
he told us he was taking.
And Topamax.
An anticonvulsant?
But he said there was
no history of prior seizure.
It's not even
prescribed to him.
Still doesn't explain
his fever.
He's probably just using it
for weight Ioss.
Just gives us another Iie.
He must really be devoted.
Should we check the home?
If he wanted to hide something
from his wife,
why wouldn't he
hide it in the office?
Or maybe
she's hiding something.
Nothing but aspirin
and flu meds in the bathroom.
Looks Iike this stuff's been
sitting here for weeks.
CHASE: Home improvement.
He probably thought
he could take the project on,
then realized it was a Iittle
more than he could handle.
You got a point to make,
or did you just feel Iike
giving a Iong,
unnecessary explanation
for something
medically irrelevant?
What happened to the Foreman
who always has an answer?
The guy who practically
wears a sign saying,
"I'm as good as House,
but I'm nicer."
I never said that.
I guess it's safe to be
confident when House
is there to overrule you.
Now that it's all on you...
It's different. Yeah.
Either you Ieft it behind
on purpose, or by mistake.
The only reason you'd
Ieave it behind intentionally
is if it no Ionger
meant anything to you.
But since it was
a gift from your mom,
that would mean
you had a fight with her.
But since you don't talk
to ghosts, that's unlikely.
Leave it alone, Greg.
Yeah, I'm good at that.
So that Ieaves
forgetting it unintentionally.
But then we have to explain
why you didn't go back for it
when you realized...
I didn't realize
until I got to the airport.
Nope. You were wearing makeup
when you got to the airport.
You can't put on makeup
without Iooking at yourself.
You can't Iook at yourself
without touching that thing.
Why does this
matter to you?
It's an anomaly.
Anomalies bug me.
Then you're
gonna suffer.
(FLETCH GROANING)
I think
it's his stomach.
I teal indigent.
Was it something
you ate?
He keeps
doing that.
I teal indigent.
Are you hungry?
No.
No, he's in pain.
Is it a sharp pain?
No. Teal indigent!
Taste?
Yes.
A metallic taste?
Yes!
I'II be right back.
HOUSE: I suppose it's also
possible that the clasp broke,
but then you'd be carrying
the thing around
in your purse...
We had a fight.
We had a fight,
and I was angry
and not thinking straight,
and I walked out
without my makeup
and without my cross.
I stopped at the drugstore
to buy makeup,
but I couldn't buy a cross,
because they
don't have an aisle
for personal talismans!
So you had a fight.
I'm sure it'II blow over.
It was about nothing.
Of course it was.
Mark's tired. He's worried.
He's got mobility problems.
It's normal to blow up
over Iittle things.
I don't mind fighting
I didn't mind
fighting over big things.
That I could understand.
We fight over nothing.
You know, a mailbox
with a sign that says,
"Last pickup 5:00 p.m."
Does that mean Iast pickup
to go to the post office,
or Iast pickup to Ieave
the post office
and be sent out of town?
You fought over
mail delivery?
I tried to get him to drop
the subject, but he wouldn't.
I told him he was right.
He thought
I was being condescending.
You were.
He's pushing me
out of his Iife.
Maybe
you're misinterpreting.
Did I misinterpret with you?
At Ieast,
this time I recognize it.
That's the benefit of
convincing the only two men
you've ever Ioved
they're better off
without you.
Yeah, it's all your fault.
You know, "Stacy" in
the original Greek
means "relationship killer."
(SIGHS)
I'm going to go wash my face,
so I Iook Iike a grownup
again.
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
Hello.
It's for you.
House.
Do you know
your phone's dead?
Do you ever
recharge your batteries?
HOUSE: They recharge?
I just keep buying
new phones.
I thought you should know
your aphasia guy
is tasting metal.
Where's his creatinine?
WILSON:
6.8. He's got kidney failure.
Cameron's got him on dialysis,
and he's stable
for the moment.
Unlike Cuddy, who's suicidal.
It's either meningitis
or encephalitis.
Or maybe autoimmune.
That's perfect.
Seems Iike you really
narrowed it down over dinner.
Here's the plan.
We talk to House.
We've been trying.
He's not answering his cell.
It's obvious we have to do
the Iumbar puncture.
(PHONE RINGS)
There's no choice anymore.
HOUSE:
You have to do it just right.
What are you talking about?
Either you've decided to do
a Iumbar puncture,
or you have to fire me
so that I can't fire
all of you as soon as
I get back in charge.
Is Cuddy there, ranting?
If I'd known
you'd be out of contact...
They can handle it.
CUDDY: Right.
So far, only three
organ systems have failed.
HOUSE: Okay, they can't.
Doesn't matter.
The guy's not stable enough
to move.
So go rant in your own office.
Fine.
Call me when you're done.
What do you mean
by doing the LP just right?
We're not gonna screw it up.
The odds are, this guy knows
something we don't.
He could know the answer to
the meaning of Iife,
the man can't communicate!
Have you had any indication
that he's tried to communicate
something important?
No.
Well, that's because you guys
haven't scared him enough.
I'm sure you've been all,
"Oh, we'II take
real good care of you."
Why should he say anything?
When you prep him,
tell him he's gonna die.
Crush all hope.
Don't let Cameron do it.
Cuddy, you got a problem
with any of that?
You're scheduled
for a Iumbar puncture,
but you shouldn't count
on that having the answers.
If your husband
continues to decline...
You'II die.
If there's anything
you haven't told us...
How you holding up?
I know what you just heard
is scary as hell, but...
Couldn't tackle the bear.
They took my stain.
WOMAN: (ON PA)
Attention, please.
Due to weather conditions,
all flights are grounded
till further notice.
Cots are being provided
on the lower level.
We apologize
for the inconvenience.
WOMAN: I don't believe it.
You want me to run down
and reserve you
a cot with a view?
Where's
your knapsack?
Checked it through.
That's right. I forgot.
It's hard for you
to carry and walk.
I booked a room
at the airport hotel when I
saw how bad the weather was.
It's the Iast one
available.
Your Ieg can't handle
a night on a cot.
Thanks.
I'm ready.
Right.
The hotel's upstairs.
Does Mark know
about this?
Mark knows that
when things are bad,
I always Iike to have
an escape route planned.
(DOOR OPENING)
(SIGHS)
I have to know
what's going on here.
Because when you
have a fight with Mark
and you try to avoid me,
then I have to
think that...
That I'm feeling vulnerable,
and I don't want to be
around you,
because it might Iead
to something.
Right.
But then,
a hotel room...
Might also
Iead to something.
So, which is it?
Our relationship's
Iike an addiction.
It's Iike...
Really good drugs?
No, it's Iike Vindaloo curry.
Okay, sure.
Really, really hot
Indian curry they make
with red chili peppers.
I know what it is.
Didn't think
it was addictive.
You're abrasive and annoying,
and you come on
way too strong.
Like Vindaloo curry.
And when you're crazy
about curry, that's fine.
But no matter
how much you Iove curry,
you have too much of it,
it takes
the roof of your mouth off.
And then you never want
to see curry for
a really, really Iong time.
But you wake up one day
and you think,
"God, I really miss curry."
You're a jerk.
I know.
If you hadn't just had
a fight with Mark...
For once in your Iife,
will you shut up?
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
House.
You're on speakerphone.
How did the LP go?
Give me the Reader's Digest
condensed version.
Preliminary results are
some kind of infection which
narrows it down...
From infinity, yeah.
At the rate his organs
are deteriorating,
he's got maybe a day or two.
Okay. Well, call me back
when you have something.
CAMERON: He was trying
to tell us something.
What did he say?
You were wrong.
It wasn't the fear.
He opened up to me when I...
A sympathetic presence
after a traumatic moment.
CIassic interrogation
technique. What did he say?
You knew that I'd...
Act the way you always do?
Yeah, I did. What did he say?
He couldn't tackle the bear.
Now all we need
is the English-Aphasic
dictionary.
A fluent aphasic retrieves
words that are stored
somewhere close
to the one he wants.
They could be filed by sound
or by meanings.
So if he wants to say "table,"
he could say "Iabel"
or he could say "chair."
Or he could just say
"jabberwocky."
There's no way to tell.
He also said,
"They took my stain."
Hold on.
I'm gonna take this phone
downstairs, so I don't
disturb you. Is that okay?
Sure.
Keep him talking.
Write down everything he says.
Stacy.
(SIGHS)
That new makeup you bought,
do you mind if I borrow it?
What did you mean by "stain"?
Dirty, soiled...
No, no.
What about rhymes?
Pain? Brain?
Thane?
He is dying from some kind of
infection, and you all are
playing word games?
Is there anything else
you haven't told us?
Let's start this again.
"Bear." Is it "bare"
as in "naked"?
Crimson Desire
shows up well on Sheetrock.
That's why I chose it.
HOUSE: You must have gotten
one new phrase out of him.
Something.
We've been talking to him
for hours.
Maybe he's just given up.
You sure you've told me
everything you found
at his home and office?
No, we're
hiding something.
Maybe it's not
a rhyme or a synonym.
What else is there?
You think we should just
start guessing randomly?
Maybe House is wrong.
Hope that's not
the end of the thought.
He mentioned "stain"
once before, when Chase
was giving him the MRI.
Before we scared him.
He did?
It's in your notes.
CHASE: So he only talks during
MRIs and lumbar punctures?
Your theory is he can only
talk with a needle
in his back or...
When his wife's
not in the room.
The more devoted,
the more reason to Iie.
That's cynical.
You disagree?
No, I'm just kvelling.
Our Iittle girl is growing up.
Okay, what's the best way
to rip a woman from the side
of her dying husband?
You woke me up
to Iie to a patient's wife?
Tell her there's been
a miscommunication over
their insurance coverage.
Not a big deal.
Tell me.
If it is your aim to sell me
the same crazy ideas that
House does, how are you
an improvement on House?
I brought you a coffee.
Your flight's been
boarding for 20 minutes.
I'II take a Iater one.
Greg, they can't Ieave
without you.
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
You checked your knapsack.
Are we in?
Yeah.
Hi. I'm Gregory House.
I'm your attending physician.
Your wife's not there.
Start talking.
They took my stain.
I couldn't tackle the bear.
Okay, shut up now.
Nice work, Cameron.
Give him the Iist again.
Let us know when
something sounds right.
Dirty, soiled, pain, brain...
Yes.
FOREMAN:
Where does that get us?
We're already paying plenty of
attention to his brain.
We've got an MRI, got a CT...
Are we sure he wasn't
reacting to "pain"?
He's been on painkillers.
HOUSE: Oh, come on, Chase.
Drugs didn't do this to him,
even if he is an addict.
I dissuade the tonal category.
Oh, please,
Mr. SIeeping Pills,
Amphetamines,
Bring Me Up, Bring Me Down...
WOMAN: (ON PA)
Will passenger Gregory House
please report to Gate 7.
Gregory House to Gate 7.
Ever hear this one?
You build a house. Each wall
has a southern exposure.
A big bear comes wandering by.
What color is the bear?
White. It's a polar bear.
You built your house
in the North Pole.
Polar. Whatever your name is.
Patient! Are you bipolar?
What? I can't see.
Is he nodding?
Yes.
Topamax isn't just off-Iabel
for weight Ioss. It's
off-Iabel for mood disorders.
PIenty of bipolars are manic
in the daytime,
depressive at night.
He's been medicating for years
with alcohol, sleeping through
the bad hours.
It explains
the danger journalism.
Explains everything,
including the kitchen sink.
Okay, technically, it's
the kitchen cabinets.
He starts a project,
then he stops.
Except bipolar disorder
does not cause seizures.
And it doesn't shut down
your kidneys.
But what it does do...
GUARD: Excuse me, sir.
May I see your ID?
I'm on the phone.
Now, please.
House? What is it?
I'm a doctor.
This is an emergency call.
You have to
come with me, sir.
I'm not going anywhere.
Do you think
you're gonna take me on?
I kick and I bite.
You're either on that plane,
or you're going into custody.
FOREMAN: House?
Are you still there?
Being bipolar
makes you take risks.
You seek excitement,
you make up stories.
I dime value tale Iever!
Fine, maybe your stories
are Iegit. But people
would start to wonder.
Annoyed politicians,
entire governments
would be on your ass.
So you couldn't tell anybody
you were bipolar.
Which was fine.
Until you fell in Iove.
And you wanted that Iife.
And you hear
that there's a surgical cure.
You can give the woman you
Iove the Iife she wants.
AII you have to do is change.
Bilateral cingulotomy.
An experimental surgery that
some people claim helps
mood disorders.
And if it's done by
Gamma Knife,
there's no trace of cutting.
That's the neural scarring
we saw on the MRI.
Which explained nothing,
because it wasn't even
in the right area.
It's not the surgery,
it's the secrecy.
What causes recurring fever,
neurological problems,
Iethargy that you fight
with caffeine pills
and amphetamines?
It wasn't
your secret psych disorder.
It wasn't your
secret daily drug use.
It was your secret trip
for your secret surgery
in Caracas or Buenos Aires.
Which, by the way,
didn't work, given the state
of your kitchen cabinets.
House. Shut up.
What's going on?
Is he right?
Your doctors know you
better than I do.
That man on the speakerphone,
he never even met you,
and he knows you
better than I do.
You Iove me?
Yes. Yes.
You just don't trust me.
HOUSE:
Get some blood on a slide.
Do not put it through
a computer this time.
Yeah.
FOREMAN: Cerebral malaria.
I'II get him started
on intravenous quinidine.
If a human being had actually
Iooked at his blood
anywhere along the way,
instead of just running tests
through the computer,
the parasites would have
jumped right out at them.
Price of the electronic age.
FIetch.
She'II be back.
Give her time to miss you.
MAN: (ON PA)
Final boarding call
for Flight Number 7...
I'm counting on you
to get me off the no-fly Iist.
Is your patient
gonna be all right?
Physically,
his chances are good.
Physically?
Two people who weren't
meant to be together.
Maybe they'II get
a happy ending just because
they both want it so much.
Yeah, that's usually
the way it works.
He Ioved her enough
to convince himself
he could change.
But he couldn't, could he?
Thank you.
You know what Woody AIIen said
about relationships.
Irrational and crazy,
but we go through it all
because...
We need the curry.