Adam, eyes here.
(SHOUTS)
Follow my finger.
Adam, show me a bicycle.
Eyes here.
No, buddy, that's a ball.
Adam, look at me.
Are you hungry?
Show me what you
want for lunch.
He's still drawing those lines
instead of
looking at the cards.
More juice?
If he wants more juice,
he has to ask for it.
Adam, buddy, eyes here.
He's tired, Dom.
He wouldn't be
if we stuck to the schedule.
Show me the juice, buddy.
I think we've reached
the point of
diminishing returns.
He has to ask for it. Adam.
He's choking.
That's impossible.
It's mac and cheese.
Ten-year-old boy who screams
for his life for no reason.
He's autistic.
Severely autistic.
Can't talk,
can't make eye contact.
Screaming is probably his way
of communicating.
And he went to
three different doctors
who all said just that.
So, clearly that can't be
the answer.
His brain can't
filter information.
It's a constant assault
on his senses.
I'd scream, too.
Or it's something
medical-sounding,
like dysesthesia.
Parents are convinced
that there's something wrong
with their son.
Since when did we start
believing parents? Or anyone?
Where are we going?
Elevator.
Dad was on Wall Street,
Mom was a partner
in an accounting firm.
When their son was diagnosed
with autism, they both quit.
So they're over-protective
and scared. That's all
the more reason to discount...
They study this kid.
Heard him scream a million
times, but in ten years
of caring for him,
this is the first time
they've brought him
to a hospital.
ER checked his throat.
No obstructions, nothing.
Which means the only symptom
was a scream,
which is diagnostic
of nothing.
Kid clutched his chest,
BP was elevated,
maybe there was chest pain.
ER said the heart was fine.
Don't be so quick
to dismiss pain.
Where are we going?
Down.
Stool sample
to check for parasites,
blood culture to
rule out infection,
and ANA for lupus.
Because he screamed?
Could also be
an environmental reaction.
An allergy.
Dust, wheat, pollen,
a toxin or something he ate.
Check the house.
And run a lung
ventilation scan.
Lungs are in the chest,
too, right?
I had a date last night,
she screamed.
Should we spend
a hundred thousand dollars
testing her?
Of course not.
This isn't a
veterinary hospital.
Look, if you don't think
this kid is worth saving...
That's not what I'm saying.
That's too bad.
It was a good point.
Kid's just a lump
with tonsils.
You know what it's
going to be like
trying to put an autistic kid
into a nuclear scanner?
I don't envy you guys.
I want my old carpet back.
We're going to have to
do this later. A kid
in the clinic had an accident.
Generally, when people
are on the phone...
I want my old carpet back.
It was stained with blood.
Yeah, my blood,
which makes the carpet
part of me.
I want it back.
I want to be buried with it.
You think you can get me to do
anything you want,
regardless of
how stupid it is?
It's my office.
It's where I work,
where I think, where
I save lives, allowing you
to brag to rich people,
so they'll give you more money
to spend on MRls
and low-cut tops.
I want it back the way it was.
It's identical
to the old carpet.
Except without
the hazardous
biological waste.
I shall not return to my
office until every patented,
durable micro-fiber
has been restored
to its rightful place.
Inspiring.
If you don't want to
work in your office,
work in the clinic.
If you don't want to work
in the clinic, go home.
And don't get paid.
Attica! Attica!
Attica! Attica! Attica!
Attica?
He just needs to
finish this level.
We only have the scanner
for the next half hour.
After that...
Trust me,
you don't want to move him
until he's finished.
The sooner we do this test,
the sooner we can
get you guys home.
Adam, do you think that...
No.
Ten minutes. Tops.
If he has a vascular disorder,
he might not have...
He might not have ten minutes?
I don't have ten minutes.
No! No! You don't want to
do that. Adam? Adam?
(SCREAMING)
I used Metamucil
like the doctor told me
and finally I was able to
use the bathroom.
But I saw something
in the toilet
I couldn't identify.
I wrapped it in tissue paper,
so you could take a look.
Can't you sedate him
or something?
I could if I didn't want
the test results
to mean anything.
Painkillers, exercising,
we even did that
puncture thing, nothing works.
Then this morning, I get up,
my back feels great.
I figured I'd better
get down here, right away.
Big shocker, Dad's depressed.
Save your time.
SSRls don't cause chest pain.
Wow.
Every minute of every day
is booked.
When he eats, sleeps,
plays his handheld.
Not much of a life for them.
They chose to have a family.
You don't get to decide
what your kid's
going to be like.
Nobody chooses this.
It's funny,
you get a normal kid,
the parent works.
You get a special kid
that costs more,
you quit and turn the backyard
into a therapy circuit.
Yes, if only you
were handicapped.
All the good times
you could have had with Dad.
Hi, Doctor House.
Hello, girl whose name
I don't remember,
but whose dad I treated,
so I don't really know
why she's here.
Ali. I think I caught
what my dad has.
The rhino thing.
Right.
Does that hurt?
Little.
It's in my chest, too.
Of course it is.
Kind of had access
through the shirt,
but this'll work.
That feels good.
Exactly when did New Jersey
run out of horny
17-year-old boys?
About five weeks ago.
It's been very lonely.
The...
The ventilation scan
was normal.
Time to send him home.
Can't leave right now.
Well, congratulations.
You are the proud owner
of your very own
"rhino thing."
A rhinovirus?
You can't leave because
she has a cold?
I can't leave because
Cuddy says I can't leave.
All the tests are normal.
Okay, don't start with me.
We're backed up.
I know this is hard
for all of us,
but thanks to Doctor Cuddy,
I don't have an office,
so I have to work here.
What did she do
to your office?
It's unusable.
So whatever's bothering him,
it wasn't his lungs.
What about the kid's house?
There were some pesticides
and some alcohol, but
the tox screen was negative.
Which means there's nothing
physically wrong
with this kid.
We already had
that discussion.
We get a fecal smear?
Should we do this
someplace else?
No, Cuddy says
I have to work here.
No, I said you can work
in your office,
or you had to work here.
And since I can't work
in my office...
Is this your master plan?
Disrupt hospital business
until I replace your carpet?
Devious. Saw it
in a James Bond movie.
Fecal smear! Talk to me.
Get out of here.
Put back my carpet?
No. Get out of here.
Fecal matter.
Is there a sample
we can look at?
The parents have a smear kit.
The kid is constipated.
Do what you want.
Not replacing your carpet.
Go up his rear
and get a smear.
Which reminds me,
I kind of feel like a bagel.
Carpets.
Need a stool sample.
We should probably wait
until he's finished
playing that level, huh?
I actually think
he's a bit better today.
He seems more like
his old self.
It's possible that
he was never sick.
I guess,
we could've overreacted.
Adam? Adam?
So what makes fluid
fill the lining
of a kid's lungs?
Why are we in here?
Is this some sort of
power play?
Yeah.
So, you stuck your finger
in the kid and gave him
a pleural effusion?
Have you ever considered
getting a manicure?
I took the stool sample
after his lungs failed.
Or do you really
have a problem
with the carpeting?
Change sets you off...
I said it was a power play.
If someone answers yes
to option A, you don't
move on to option B.
If there's a pleural effusion,
we have to rule out
heart failure.
Why now? Why a power play now?
I smelled weakness.
Get the kid an echocardiogram.
That's funny.
It says, "James Wilson."
That's a strange typo.
The fluid comes back
and exudates, get him on
broad spectrum antibiotics.
Thank you for coming.
No problem.
Thought you wouldn't mind
sharing offices for a while.
You share stories, feelings,
toys, you don't share offices.
That is so not Zen.
It was a gift.
Some doctors get those.
So, you want mornings
or afternoons?
You couldn't make
Cuddy miserable, so you're
going to make me miserable,
so I can make Cuddy miserable
on your behalf?
Yeah.
What makes you think
I can make her miserable?
'Cause you're
good at that stuff.
I'm nothing compared to you.
Is there anything
you'll throw out?
That's a gift from
an eleven-year-old
patient of mine.
She and I both knew it was
a piece of junk, and
that's what made her laugh.
So you gotta keep it
until she...
She already did.
(ADAM SCREAMING)
Adam, I need you to
stay still, buddy.
It's okay. It's okay.
I got him.
There we go.
What? What is it?
Is his heart okay?
No.
Echo suggested
a conduction abnormality,
EKG confirmed it.
Still doesn't explain the
effusion. The pleural fluid
was an exudate.
We should be looking for
something that explains both
the heart and lung problems.
An infection, parasite,
cancer.
Microbiology showed
no organisms in the fluids,
so forget infection.
It's not a power play.
Doing a differential
in the clinic makes sense,
piss Cuddy off.
Same thing with
Wilson's office,
works indirectly.
But now we're in office space
because you don't want to be
in your own office.
Which means this has nothing
to do with Cuddy.
You really are obsessed
with your carpets.
Which means...
What are you doing here?
I have this room
booked from two to three.
Two, East Coast Time?
I thought you meant Pacific.
Which is stupid of me,
I guess.
What about parasites?
Stool sample's negative.
It's two o'clock.
Oh, well. We should go then.
That just leaves cancer.
Get a lung biopsy.
It took a half an hour
to get the mask
on the kid for the lung scan.
I'm sorry.
Was there somewhere
you needed to be?
House, can we talk?
Carpet?
Never.
Nothing to talk about.
Your girlfriend called
the clinic 15 times,
looking for you today.
Lot to discuss,
china patterns...
House. She's a stalker.
Right.
Couldn't be that she finds me
interesting, attractive,
has to be that she's insane.
She's called you 15 times.
Your mother's not
that interested in you.
Well maybe I'd be
better adjusted if she was.
I'm notifying security.
Is this about the carpet?
Do you think I'll back off
if you block all my fun?
You better not be having fun.
I'm having fun.
I'm not having sex.
She's dangerous.
She's not dangerous.
She's pretty.
Men are stupid.
I'm with you so far.
I'm notifying security.
Give her a break.
She's not dangerous,
she's insightful.
You can't stop our love!
Hey, you got a minute?
Yeah.
We have a ten-year-old
with pleural effusion
and conduction abnormality,
but no heart failure.
Was there protein
in the pleural fluid?
Yeah. That's why
we're thinking cancer.
Non-Hodgkin's probably.
So we want to do
a lung biopsy.
Lung biopsies usually
come back negative, so biopsy
a lymph node under the arm.
That's probably something
an oncologist should do,
right?
There's nothing real tricky
to it. It's a biopsy.
Still, just to be safe.
You mind?
(SCREAMING)
For the love of God,
can't somebody
shut that kid up?
People are trying to
work around here.
Why don't you show him
a teddy bear or something?
Who are you?
Somebody you'll
never send a gift to.
This is Doctor House,
your son's doctor.
High test, please.
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Out of Vicodin?
What are you doing?
Eating the red berries.
He trusted you.
No, that wasn't trust.
That was self-preservation.
No. That was huge.
It was like a conversation.
A monkey's afraid to eat
the red berries until he sees
another monkey eat 'em.
Monkey see, monkey do.
That's all it was.
Your kid's still just
as messed up
as when we admitted him.
(CRASHING)
That was sensitive.
You have pretty hair.
Hope is all those parents
have going for them.
No, hope is what's
making them miserable.
What they should do is
get a cocker spaniel.
A dog would look them
in the eye,
wag his tail when he's happy,
lick their face,
show them love.
Is it so wrong for them
to want to have
a normal child?
It's normal to
want to be normal.
Spoken like
a true Circle Queen.
See, skinny,
socially-privileged
white people
get to draw this
neat little circle.
Everyone inside
the circle is normal.
Everyone outside the circle
should be beaten,
broken and reset,
so they can be
brought into the circle.
Failing that, they should be
institutionalized,
or worse, pitied.
So, it's wrong to feel sorry
for this little boy?
Why would you feel sorry
for someone
who gets to opt out
of the inane courteous
formalities,
which are utterly meaningless,
insincere, and therefore,
degrading?
This kid doesn't have to
pretend to be interested
in your back pain,
or your excretions,
or your grandma's itchy place.
Can you imagine
how liberating it would be
to live a life free of
all the mind-numbing
social niceties?
I don't pity this kid.
I envy him.
No cancer because
these aren't lymph cells.
Then what are they?
Liver cells.
Wow, liver cells
under his arm.
Wonder what he's got
where his liver's
supposed to be?
Anyone got a clue how
liver cells got
into the kid's armpit?
Make yourself at home.
So, you think maybe
Gray's Anatomy
got it all wrong?
Lymph system circulates fluid,
not organ cells.
Cancer cells break into
the lymphatic system
all the time.
But we're not talking
about cancer cells.
So what's the difference
between cancer cells
and liver cells?
Why can one
pass through walls,
but the other can't?
Cancer cells are damaged,
it lets them grow
into blood vessels,
go wherever they want.
So if the liver cells
are damaged...
The liver isn't damaged.
The tests were normal.
So if the liver cells
are damaged,
it's theoretically possible
they passed into
the lymphatic system.
Liver failure could also
explain pleural effusion,
even the heart issues.
The liver cells are fine.
He was immunized for
Hep A and B, and do you
really think this kid
is having unprotected sex,
or sharing needles?
Daddy does seem
the type to use a rubber.
So it's not viral.
That just leaves
a lot of booze-irrhosis.
Our 10-year-old boy does not
have a drinking problem,
or cirrhosis.
House, when we
echoed his heart,
we got a piece of his liver.
There was no scarring.
Cirrhosis explains
the symptoms,
heart problems, lungs...
Look up cirrhosis
in the dictionary,
it means scarring.
Parents aren't doing
or dosing this kid.
How would you know that?
The kid can't talk.
Why do you think
I took this case?
He's not going to give away
the ending.
They quit their jobs for him.
Yes, they are everything
you'd want in a parent.
Unfortunately,
their kid is nothing
you'd want.
When a baby is born,
it's perfect.
Little fingers, little toes,
plump, perfect, pink,
and brimming
with unbridled potential.
Then it's downhill.
Some hills
steeper than others.
Parents get off
on their kids'
accomplishments.
Bend over and relax.
Cute.
They'll annoy you
with trophy rooms
and report cards.
Hell, they'll even show you
a purple cow
and tell what a keen eye
for color their kid has.
But this kid,
he doesn't smile,
he doesn't hug them,
he doesn't laugh.
His parents get nothing
but the right to brag that
their kid picked orange juice
out of a lineup.
So you figure they slip
the kid a mickey
so they don't have to deal.
Do a biopsy
to confirm cirrhosis.
Don't try to pawn it off
on Wilson, he's going to be
busy with Cuddy.
My parents love me
unconditionally.
Get out of here.
Don't you think
the restraining order's
a little much?
He's not actually going to
have sex with
a 17-year-old patient.
I didn't think he was
going to ask me
to dig a bloodstained carpet
out of a dumpster, either.
It might be easier
in the long run.
Are we stopping here,
so House doesn't find us?
Unless you want to make out.
You want me to surrender
to House's coup?
No, no. You pro-actively
give him what he wants.
I defeat him
by surrendering to him.
He'll never see it coming.
Look, I'll pay for it myself.
What is it, a thousand bucks
to carpet a room?
Actually, it's 400.
Not doing it.
Liver biopsy?
They're doing it now.
How's it going?
Like a biopsy.
Needles, cells, screaming.
What did you find
in the stool sample?
You were too busy
bothering Cuddy.
But as discussed,
it was negative for parasites.
Can we get out of here?
I didn't ask
what you didn't find,
I asked what you did find
in the stool sample.
Stool
and traces of iron, zinc,
calcium carbonate.
Can we leave?
What's the matter?
You afraid of the man?
Yeah.
Too late.
Leave my stuff alone.
You have a meeting with
a Guggenheim in 15 minutes.
You're wearing that?
I'm going to count to three
and then I'm going to
fire you. One.
Calcium carbonate?
That's an anti-diarrheal,
right?
Two.
Think that's significant?
Think hard poops
is significant?
Two and a half.
Never threaten
unless you're ready
to deliver.
Makes you look weak.
Thank God you don't
have children.
(PHONE RINGING)
Doctor Cuddy.
Take a message.
Your patient is being
rushed to cardiac ICU.
Wow. That's like the one thing
that would get me out of here.
I'm sorry,
you can't come in here.
What's going on?
One, two, three.
He's in V fib.
Charged.
CHASE: Clear.
Charging, clear.
He's stable for the moment.
First-degree
atrial ventricular block.
Okay, what else do we know?
His liver's damaged.
Pleural effusion compromised
his lung function.
Biopsy was negative
for cirrhosis.
Parents didn't
poison their son.
It's not his liver,
his heart, or his lungs.
It's the calcium carbonate
in his stool.
Kid was constipated.
Parents probably
just overdid it.
Or they didn't do it at all.
Calcium carbonate
is also what's in chalk.
FOREMAN: So he ate some chalk.
It isn't toxic,
it sure didn't cause
the pleural effusion.
Forget the chalk.
You just said
it was about the chalk.
Yes, and then I said,
"Forget the chalk."
You must be very confused.
The kid's got pica.
You take him to a buffet,
he's going to eat the table.
Or lead paint.
Level of lead in the blood
was normal.
His tox screen was clean.
We're not looking
for typical poisons.
We're looking for anything
that he could
put in his mouth.
Matches, spiders, bricks.
Pressure-treated wood
used to contain arsenic.
Even better.
Hansel, get samples
of the Gingerbread House.
Bag everything.
Hey.
You could get into
a lot of trouble being here.
I wanted to see you.
Yeah, I got that.
So did everyone else.
They think you're a stalker.
One could argue those people
might be jealous
of your attention.
Yes, I actually
made that argument.
You going home?
That's the plan.
In Iceland,
the age of consent is 14.
I'm surprised that tourism
isn't a bigger industry
up there.
Today I'm jailbait,
but in 22 weeks,
anybody can do anything to me.
Will I be so different
in 22 weeks?
Twenty-two weeks is enough
for an embryo to grow
arms and legs.
It's just a line.
An arbitrary line drawn
by a bunch of sad,
old men in robes.
Yeah, who cares
what judges think?
I didn't think of you as a guy
who followed rules
just because they were rules.
You are over ten years
younger than me.
I said, "Over."
(ELEVATOR DINGS)
Gotta go!
House.
Doctor Cuddy.
Do you happen to know the way
to the Icelandic consulate?
This young woman,
a stranger to me,
was just asking directions.
Security was going to
call the police. I don't
want to do that to you.
Go home.
She needed a ride.
She got here on her own,
she can get home on her own.
Now.
If I see you on
hospital grounds again,
I will call the police.
After that look,
I'm feeling a little frisky.
Looks like you're up.
I'm ovulating. Let's go.
The frisky, it went away.
House, this isn't a game.
If I leave her alone,
can I have my carpet back?
No.
If I forget about
my carpet can I have her?
Jimsonweed.
I found a small patch of it
in his backyard.
Jimsonweed contains atropine,
poor man's acid.
Our kid's been tripping on
"Lucy in the Sky
with cubic zirconium."
Explains the pleural effusion,
the heart arrhythmias.
Meeting here will do nothing
to upset Cuddy.
I'm not trying to upset Cuddy.
I'm trying to figure out
what's wrong with the patient.
Continue.
I'm done.
Jimsonweed doesn't explain
the screaming.
You've obviously
never had a bad trip.
I would've thought
you'd try to accomplish
two goals at once.
Why can't you be more like
the other age-inappropriate
girls
who have a thing for me?
Just accept me for me.
Continue.
Treatment for jimsonweed OD
is physostigmine.
Kid's got heart issues.
The two don't mix.
We'd better make sure
that's what he's got.
Serum from the lab
in Patterson is
three days minimum.
He won't survive three days.
What time does he wake up?
7:35 a.m.
Then what? Walk me through it.
7:40 to 7:50 he goes
to the toilet,
washes his face.
What does this matter?
I'm trying to prove
he ate the plant.
His schedule has nothing to do
with jimsonweed.
There are two possibilities.
Either the parents saw him
eat the plant or the kid
has unsupervised time,
and eats plants instead of
playing with blocks.
Even if you find 15 minutes
of free time outside,
it doesn't mean he spent it
eating a bush.
So, what do we do? Nothing?
Wait for the kid to tell us?
What?
Where are you going?
To talk to him.
Ever see your son eat a bush?
I haven't.
I've only ever seen him eat...
Adam, you ate something
at your house.
Something that made you sick.
I need you to show me
what you ate.
He can't answer you.
Neither can you.
This is your backyard.
You may know it
as Mel's Diner.
This is your sandbox.
Your jungle gym.
And under it is this.
I need to know
if you ate this, Adam.
He doesn't know what you want.
Adam, you have to tell me
because if you don't,
game over. You'll be dead.
What the hell are you doing?
Show me what you ate.
Adam, show me what you ate.
Adam?
Honey?
Adam!
Come on in,
brothers and sister,
welcome to
the house of the Lord!
House, come on. The Chapel?
We have been blessed
with the miracle
of a new symptom.
Brother, can you testify
as to why this poor child's
eyeball rolled back
into his head?
It's consistent with
jimsonweed poisoning,
ocular paralysis. I'm sorry.
The wicked shall deceive ye
because they have turned
from the Lord and are idiots.
His ocular muscle
didn't paralyze,
it pirouetted.
MS?
It is easier for a wise man
to gain access to heaven...
Will you stop doing that?
Just say, "Not MS."
A stroke, bleed in the brain.
We'd be seeing other symptoms
besides a single eye
misalignment. Like a coma.
And you've already testified.
It's a tumor.
And all the imaging
just missed it?
It's a micro-tumor.
It started in his lung,
which caused
the pleural effusion.
Then it metastasized
to his liver, which made
it slough cells.
And then it went to his brain
behind the eye, which caused
it to roll back into his head.
So, he had three tumors
and we missed all of them?
What's the opposite
of a miracle?
I have a better chance
of finding it, now that I know
exactly where to look.
So, unless you have
a better idea,
I'm going to go CT his head
and then, if I have to,
remove his eye.
You remove this kid's eye,
he's only going to be
half as good at
not making eye contact.
CUDDY: Hello?
Hello?
I have sad news for you.
She doesn't love you.
You're ugly
when you're jealous.
She showed up at my house
last night. Came on to me.
She's even more perfect
than I thought.
House, she's sick.
You say, "Sick,"
I say, "Freestylin'."
The girl will have sex
with an invertebrate.
Come on, you're not that bad.
She has a problem.
You're not doing her
any favors by indulging her.
How could you lie like this?
Do you not have room
in your heart for love?
You don't believe me.
I didn't believe the kids
when they said that Susie
was sleeping with Johnny.
I didn't believe them then.
I don't believe them now.
I don't care that
Susie married Johnny.
She's mine.
She has a mole
on her right breast,
just below the nipple.
No, she doesn't.
You've seen her breasts?
It was a medical exam.
I was listening to her heart.
It went, "Greg-House.
Greg-House. Greg-House."
Fine. I'm lying.
But she did come back.
She's locked up in my office.
I was hoping
you could talk to her,
put an end to this.
Listen to me.
Do you have any idea
what you'd have
to look forward to
if you stayed with me?
Nine chances out of ten,
we'd both wind up in a jail.
You're only saying that
to make me go.
I'm saying it
'cause it's true.
Inside of us, we both know
that you belong with Victor.
Is there a Victor
in your class?
If you're not with someone
your age, you'll regret it.
Maybe not today,
maybe not tomorrow, but soon,
and for the rest of your life.
What about us?
We'll always have Fresno.
I'm no good at being noble,
but it doesn't take much
to see
that the problems
of two little people
don't amount to
a hill of beans
in this crazy world.
Someday you'll
understand that.
Now, now,
here's looking at you.
Damn.
Was there an earthquake
when you were in Fresno?
What?
I ask all my girlfriends that.
Yeah, a little one.
Damn.
What? What?
What is it?
It's not love.
You have spore in your brain.
Coccidioides immitis.
California's full of them.
They get an earthquake,
they get released
into the air,
you breath it in,
you get a cold.
Turns into sinus congestion,
aches, weakness, milky tears,
and sometimes
loss of inhibition
and judgment.
Damn!
So, loving you,
wanting to have sex with you
was all just
the spores talking?
You'll probably live.
Damn!
Hey! Don't touch his eye!
This is an appendectomy.
Like I said,
don't touch his eye.
Why isn't he in surgery?
Some emergency bumped him.
We've got another room
in ten minutes.
You're not taking him in.
Kill the lights.
He was seeing them
all the time.
What are you looking for?
HOUSE: He was telling us
what he was seeing.
Telling us exactly what was
wrong with him. Drawing them
for us over and over again.
But nobody knew
how to speak autistic.
When I asked him what he ate,
he even told me that.
What are you talking about?
What was he seeing?
Hello, my pretties.
It's not a tumor, Foreman.
It's worms
swimming in his eye.
Animal makes potty
in the sandbox,
boy plays in the sandbox.
Boy eats the sand.
You can probably tell
where this is going by now.
Stool samples were
negative for parasites.
Raccoon roundworms are not
excreted by their human host.
Cameron tested the sand.
All of it?
Worms spread from his gut
to the rest of his body.
They attacked his lungs,
that's what made him scream
and caused the effusion.
They invade his liver,
sending dead liver cells
coursing through his system.
They attacked his eye
and the muscles
surrounding it,
making his eyeball
do a back flip.
Laser photocoagulation
to fix the eye,
and a high dose of
benzimidazole
to kill the worms.
Wait a minute, that's it?
He's going to be okay?
Good news.
He's going to be with you
for a long, long time.
I'm going to read you
something.
"Asperger Syndrome is a mild
and rare form of autism.
"It is typically characterized
by difficulty
establishing friendships,
"and playing with peers,
trouble accepting
conventional social rules,
"and they dislike any change
in setting or routine."
Or broadloom.
It doesn't say that last part,
but you get my point.
House doesn't have Asperger's.
The diagnosis is much simpler,
he's a jerk.
Why do you think
he took this case?
Because he
believes these parents?
Because he wants to
help a young boy?
He sees himself in this kid,
and he's trying to
help himself.
He doesn't want this,
he needs it.
You're not autistic.
You don't even have
Asperger's.
You wish you did.
That would exempt you
from the rules,
give you freedom,
absolve you of responsibility,
let you date 17-year-olds.
But most important,
it would mean that
you're not just a jerk.
At what point does a person
endlessly lecturing someone
make him a jerk?
First tongue kiss is an eight
on the happiness scale.
Child being snatched back
from the brink of death,
that's a ten.
They're clocking in
at a very tepid
six point five,
because they know what
they have to go back to.
Listen,
thanks.
You saved his life.
Yeah, I know. See ya.
That was so good.
(WAITING ON AN ANGEL PLAYING)
That was a ten.
All change is bad?
It's not true, you know.