(BABY CRYING)
(BRENT RETCHING)
Honey?
(COUGHING)
Are you all right?
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm just fighting off
a stomach bug. I'II be fine.
Did he sleep okay?
Great, as Iong as
I was holding him.
I can't wait
for colic to be over.
(BABY WHIMPERS)
(SHUSHING)
Hold on, Mikey.
Bath time's coming.
He Iifted his head
yesterday.
Take the day off.
I mean, you're sick anyway,
and you hardly ever see him
or me.
I can't.
I've got a meeting with
Crandall's Kitchens. I think
that deal's gonna close.
They called about
the car payment again.
It's two months Iate.
We're gonna be fine, honey.
Enjoy your bath,
Iittle man.
(GURGLING)
(VOMITING)
You know, honey?
Honey, I'm not gonna go in.
I'm coming down
with something.
Honey?
Kara?
Kara!
Mikey!
Four-week-old infant
submerged in a bathtub.
Don't know how Iong.
Non-responsive
at the scene.
WOMAN: Get a trauma team
for six.
Obviously breathing now.
Continue the Bodybox.
Stat portable chest.
EMT: Caucasian female, 32.
Where am I?
EMT: Tonic-clonic seizure
in the bathroom.
Brent, where am I?
CHASE: On one, two, three.
KARA: Where am I?
CHASE: One, two, three.
You're in the hospital, honey.
You're in the hospital.
Honey, Mikey's here,
and the doctors say
he's gonna be okay.
Hopefully. He needs
to be checked out
by the NICU.
KARA: What happened?
You passed out.
KARA: What?
Mikey fell.
Has your wife
had a seizure before?
No.
I can't move my head!
I want to see him!
BRENT: He's right here, honey.
He's okay. He's right here.
Tonight. L Word marathon.
You watch The L Word?
On mute.
I'II pass.
Dinner with Cuddy.
Still sucking up so
she'II fund your play space
for the chemo kids?
They really ought to
save their energy
for other things, Iike crying.
She's the suck-up.
She asked you?
She's smart.
She knows if she
buys me enough alcohol
my defenses just
might be weakened.
It doesn't make sense.
Unless she ran out
of batteries.
Hey. I'm recently single,
she's single.
You're too nice for her
to Iike you. She's not needy
enough for you to Iike her.
She's got an agenda,
just not one that includes
an appearance by Iittle Jimmy.
I'II poll my peeps.
How many of you think
that Cuddy asked...
Or, rather, peep.
Chase caught a case in the ER.
He wants us to take a Iook.
Unless Chase broke his neck
falling off his polo pony,
he had no reason
to be in the ER.
Cuddy put him on a two-week
NICU rotation. Patient had
an unexplained seizure.
Seizures are cool to watch,
boring to diagnose.
What about Foreman?
He needs to get his
malingering butt back here.
He almost died.
"AImost" being
the operative word.
Hey.
How are you doing?
You Iook great.
Thanks. I feel great.
GIad you're back.
Cameron makes Iousy coffee.
I take mine black,
the way I take my
brain-damaged neurologists.
Happy to help.
How are you coming along?
Tell her everything's great.
Neither of us wants
to deal with her guilt.
I don't feel guilty.
Of course not.
Hell, if people felt guilt
every time they accidentally
Iobotomized a guy...
I was trying to save his Iife.
Yeah. Your heart
was in the right place.
It's just his brain
that's not quite where
it's supposed to be.
Tell her
everything's great.
It's true.
No more Ieft side/right side
reversals. Still some
short-term memory Ioss
and spatial processing
problems, but I'm trying
not to be too hard on myself.
Yeah, might pull a muscle.
We have a case?
Seizure that can't be
explained by epilepsy
and accompanied
by elevated calcium Ievels.
Still bored.
Tell her why.
Because seizure with
mildly elevated calcium
is diagnostically simple.
It's either hyperparathyroid,
cancer, or calcium-mediated
neurotoxicity.
Well done.
But until you can remember
how to make coffee,
hands off the patients.
House.
AII those reasons this case
bores you, the ER has
already ruled them out.
Lungs are clear. Get an EEG.
Confirm the brain function
is okay.
Can we focus
on the task at hand?
Why did Mommy twitch so hard
that she tossed the baby
in with the bath water?
You don't need me for this.
Of course I need you.
We're a team.
Polyarteritis nodosa.
Inflamed arteries in the
brain cause seizures.
Inflamed arteries
in the kidneys
cause calcium buildup.
You're a moron.
Did you even Iook at the file?
Kidney function is fine.
Whipple's?
What?
Whipple's.
Test her.
Cameron thinks
it starts with a "W".
I'm thinking "V".
The dad vomited
this morning. Maybe
they've both got strep.
You think you can
do a strep-throat culture
without the swab ending up
in the guy's poop chute?
"V" for "vasoconstriction."
That'd be my guess.
Excess calcium
makes blood vessels
in the brain clamp down.
Best case scenario, seizure.
Worst case, stroke.
Do a digital subtraction
angiogram.
Foreman can't tell up
from down, Cameron's a girl.
AII that mechanical stuff.
Sorry. Cuddy says
I'm stuck here.
HOUSE: You're Iate.
And you are
in my Iocked office.
Again.
What you got there?
Special panties
for your date with Wilson?
It's not a date. And it's
none of your business.
If it's not a date,
it is business.
And if it was business,
you wouldn't say it was
none of my business.
What do you want?
I want to talk about
your date with Wilson.
It's not a date.
This is fun.
Spring Chase from NICU
and I'II shut up
about your date.
NICU is short-staffed.
Have you suddenly
Iost the ability to Iie?
Nobody's quit NICU
in two years.
And if you're making up reasons,
that means there is no reason,
which means he asked
for the assignment,
didn't he?
If Chase needs
a break from you,
he should take it.
Absolutely.
Both Mom and Dad
are negative for strep.
You'II be back playing
with the big toys soon.
Or not. Either way,
I'm fine.
You don't have to say that.
It's okay. I could always work
in a research Iab or teach.
And you'd be okay with that?
Why wouldn't I be?
You were planning on
pursuing grants of your own,
running a department.
I'm alive.
Changing jobs,
not making coffee,
if that stuff bothers me
now, I don't deserve
this second chance.
(MIKEY CRYING)
They say that
physical contact helps
the healing process.
(CRYING)
(MACHINE BEEPING)
What's happening?
Your son's not getting
enough oxygen.
Take Mr. Mason outside.
(GROANING)
(GASPING)
Lung's collapsed.
He's not getting any air.
I need an IV catheter.
(SCREAMING)
Another seizure?
Her chest muscles
aren't contracting.
It's something else.
Her whole back is spasming.
I need two milligrams
of Iorazepam, stat!
He's okay.
His Iung wouldn't collapse
if he was okay.
What the hell's happening?
I have no idea.
HOUSE:
So what causes seizures,
hypercalcemia, and the thing
where Mommy bends Iike Gumby.
Little busy here.
Uh-oh.
Baby's Iungs are gonna
conk out any minute. Probably
want to deal with that.
I'II get right on it as soon
as I finish indulging my boss.
Multi-task.
Chemical pneumonitis.
Bubble bath got
into the baby's Iungs
when he was underwater.
Start him on prednisone.
Keep him on high FI02.
Let the indulging
commence.
Lithium could cause all three
of the mother's symptoms.
No record she's on Iithium.
And the tox screen
was negative.
Lithium doesn't show
on a basic tox screen,
Scarecrow.
Myelomatous meningitis
could also cover everything.
Rare complications
of a rare blood cancer.
You're not totally hopeless.
Get an S-PEP
and an MRI for
myelomatous meningitis.
Search the patient's place
for Iithium.
The baby's Iung problem
is bacterial and not chemical.
Start ECMO.
While you're searching
for the Iithium, take a water
sample and check the pipes.
You want me to write
this down for you?
I ask you, is almost dying
any excuse for not being fun?
I'm not putting
that baby on ECMO.
The chance of there
being bacteria in bathwater...
Why don't you want
to work for me?
I'm nice,
I'm fun at parties.
I'm not working NICU
because of you.
The baby's x-ray suggested
chemical pneumonitis.
Not to me. The x-ray
was too consolidated.
So, why are you down here?
Hoping to expand
your make-out pool
to include the preemie
to nine-year-old demographic?
I needed a break.
From the patients.
They Iie to us
all the time.
Foreman almost died
trying to save
a drug-dealing cop.
I just wanted to get away
from that for a while.
What a complete Ioad of crap.
What am I?
A nurse you're trying to prep
with this vulnerability thing?
ECMO could kill him.
You don't start him on ECMO
and that infection could
rampage through his body
Iike Pistons fans
after a championship.
But you do it your way.
Nothing more honest
than a dead baby.
ECMO stands
for extracorporeal
membrane oxygenation.
Basically, we remove
your son' s blood...
Okay, all of his blood?
We run it through a machine
which takes out carbon dioxide
and adds oxygen.
Then we re-warm the blood
and run it back into his body.
There is a significant risk
of internal hemorrhaging,
and he may also suffer...
You put him on antibiotics.
Won't that take care
of the infection?
Not fast enough.
Are you sure this is
Mikey's best shot?
Absolutely.
Cuddy's trash?
Not anymore.
I paid good money for it.
Look at what she bought.
Red clover.
What is red clover
used for, Dr. Wilson?
AIso used to treat asthma,
psoriasis, joint pain...
She doesn't wheeze,
flake, or ache.
And she didn't ask
a pulmonologist or a
dermatologist for dinner.
She invited an oncologist.
It's not a date.
It's a consult.
Mom's MRI was negative
for masses, abscesses.
There's no sign
she has myelomatous...
Fascinating.
Call me when we have...
She has a subarachnoid bleed.
So, why is our patient
bleeding into her brain?
Her blood workup shows
her pro-time's elevated.
She's bleeding because
she's not clotting.
So, why is she not clotting?
What did you
bring us, Daddy?
The only mood-altering
drug was vodka at
the back of a drawer.
Hiding booze is a classic
alcoholic behavior.
That'd explain the bleeding.
What bleeding?
You don't remember?
She bled all over you
this morning. Kidding.
Idiots are fun. No wonder
every village wants one.
If she's an alcoholic,
she would also be more
prone to hypercalcemia.
But the tox screen
was negative for alcohol.
Hey, it was your idea.
Now, it's even better.
Mommy quits.
She gets the DTs.
Even explains the seizure.
It also fits
conversion disorder.
They're deep in debt,
he' s working around the
clock, they got a new baby.
I think the seizure
was a physical response
to psychological stress.
Boozy Mommy
covers more symptoms.
Put her in a nice
phenobarbital coma
before the DTs kill her.
Where are you going?
To put her in a pheno coma.
What if I'm wrong?
What if Daddy's the drunk?
Do you want us to give her
the pheno or not?
I want him
to argue his point.
I assume you considered
the father and ruled him out.
What's that saying?
When you assume, you become
a pain in the ass to me.
Why should I argue?
You'd just overrule me.
Enough! Get a pony
or a watermelon farm.
House?
I need him to react.
I need him to act
Iike a human being.
I need him to
get over this boring
near-death rebirth.
I have changed. That's not
something you get over.
Nearly dying changes
everything forever.
For about two months.
Two months is too Iong.
I need the guy
I hired back. Now.
No matter how much your
misery Ioves company,
it's not getting mine.
I'II talk to the dad.
Cameron can take the mom.
We'II figure out
if Mom was the drinker.
Waste of time.
Put her in a coma
before the DTs kill her.
So,
is this a separation, or...
Well, Iawyers
have been hired,
friends divvied up.
Oddly, she didn't
fight me for House.
(CHUCKLES)
At Ieast there aren't kids
involved. You just have
each other to deal with.
If there had been kids,
maybe we would have
done more of that.
Do you want kids?
Listen, is there anything
in particular you wanted to...
Hospital business or...
Catching up.
(CHUCKLES)
I mean, you know,
it's not Iike
either one of us has
anybody to run home to.
No.
How are you feeling?
Okay. A Iittle groggy.
There's somebody here
to see you.
BRENT: Hey, Mikey.
Mommy's awake.
Oh, Mikey.
Gosh, I was so scared.
(WHIMPERING)
Oh, I Iove you.
I Iove you so much. Oh.
(SHUSHING)
I'm sorry.
You don't have anything
to be sorry about.
You were sick.
Turns out she and
her husband met in AA.
Obviously, she slipped.
Good call.
It wasn't hard,
considering my other choice
was your stupid psych theory.
Which was not stupid.
I'm telling you, I'm gonna
drop the N-bomb if I have to.
You're addicted to conflict.
Did they change the name?
You could have
handled this patient
without dragging Chase in.
But the fact that
he didn't want in killed you.
Just Iike the fact
you can't get
a rise out of me.
Where's the baby?
(GRUNTING)
Get off me! No!
I have to do this!
No breath sounds.
Crash cart and epi! Stat!
I told you your psych theory
wasn't stupid.
Your son is stable.
But the Iack of oxygen
damaged his kidneys.
She must have rolled
over on him by mistake.
Mr. Mason,
I was there.
Your wife tried
to smother your son.
That's impossible.
Kara would never hurt Mikey.
He knows.
They said Mikey knows.
You hear voices?
They wouldn't quit saying
that Mikey would be
better off if...
They were right.
We've been trying
to diagnose a seizure
that didn't exist.
She faked it when
her husband caught her.
I don't think she faked it.
She just happened to seize
right in the middle of
drowning her child?
Lucky break for the kid.
Hey, take it easy on Foreman.
He's playing with one Iobe
tied behind his back.
Postpartum psychosis makes her
want to drown her kid.
The internal conflict
triggers a seizure.
You know what else might be
a trigger? A physical illness.
It's a wild idea, I know.
Especially since she
doesn't have any obviously
physical symptoms,
Iike internal bleeding
or excess calcium.
I'II draw some blood,
test for...
Oh! Jeez!
You've done it again!
Will you argue with me?
Drinkers don't eat right.
That explains the bleeding
and the calcium.
This might just be
some crazy drunk,
and I'm telling you that
she's about to die of
myelomatous meningitis.
We already tested for...
Exactly. It's an insane idea.
Okay. What do you
want me to do?
Have an original thought.
In the meantime,
stress her into having
another seizure.
We can't.
She's on haloperidol.
You also can't
because it's dangerous
and highly unethical.
Therefore, if you
get caught, pretend
you can't make coffee.
Mental defectives
get tons of slack.
Take her off the haloperidol,
hook her up to an EEG,
flash some Iights,
make her pant,
shoot her up with a placebo.
When she starts twitching,
if the machine twitches along,
it's real. If not,
well, call the cops,
'cause she's a psycho killer.
Stop pushing him.
Stop protecting him.
He needs it.
Not if he wants
to get better.
He might not be able
Well, then, I need
a new neurologist.
He got sick doing his job.
If he got killed
doing his job, I wouldn't
keep him on the payroll.
I don't care how guilty
you feel or how touched
you are by his reborn spirit.
I am not touched.
Then you're guilt-ridden.
I'm not guilt-ridden.
Then you're pathetic.
Right now, I'm annoyed.
Keeping him up all night
in the seizure Iab
is not the way
to advance his recovery.
It's too much.
You're right.
You should stick around.
Make sure he doesn't screw up.
FOREMAN: Kara, look directly
into the light.
Keep Iooking.
Thought you'd be
gone for the day.
Thought I'd wait for the
bone marrow biopsy results.
House sent you
to baby-sit me, didn't he?
He asked me
to wait for the results.
Cameron, it's fine.
Of course it is.
Look, a few weeks ago,
you were upset that I didn't
consider you a friend.
Now you're upset
that I'm happy?
What can I say?
Apparently, I'm a bitch.
I didn't say that.
It's annoying.
Insisting every day
of your Iife is a blessing
is basically calling
everyone else shallow.
It gets old.
Sorry.
Oh, give it a rest.
How was dinner?
Cuddy did not
mention cancer.
She Iost her nerve.
It was a date.
What are you doing?
PCR test.
You're doing it yourself
in the middle of the night.
On a spoon.
Cuddy's spoon.
I'm checking her saliva
for cancer markers.
Yeah. I do that
after all my dates, too.
People think
you're the nice one.
Why are you so worried
about Cuddy?
You go first. You desperately
want this to be a date.
Because the alternative
is cancer.
Just admit that you Iike her.
She's smart, funny,
got a zesty bod.
I think it's great you can
Iook beyond the fact
she's the devil.
I stole a spoon.
You stole her garbage.
She's my boss.
If she gets sick, the
hospital might replace her,
especially if she dies.
I'd have to Iearn
how to manipulate someone new.
Whoa.
I think I'm gonna cry.
Find me when
the results come in.
Mr. Mason,
because of the damage
done to your son's kidneys,
his potassium is climbing.
That's causing
irregular heartbeats.
I'm doubling the meds
and starting him on dialysis.
But unless we get
his potassium down,
he's gonna have
a heart attack.
Kara, just another
few minutes.
Biopsy's back. She's negative
for myelomatous meningitis.
And she's not seizing.
So, we're wrong
and House is wrong.
And you're okay with that?
(BEEPING)
She's seizing.
She's not doing anything.
Her brain activity
isn't accelerating,
it's slowing down.
(SUCKING)
Muscle rigidity,
involuntary grasping
and sucking motions.
She's in an
encephalopathic delirium.
Hmm.
A genuine
physiological illness.
That rules out a few things.
Like what, I wonder?
Postpartum psychosis
and conversion disorder.
The thing about being
a good Ioser,
you're still a Ioser.
Ouch.
The delirium means
her brain is shutting down,
reverting to its most
instinctual functions.
And since it's progressing,
I think we can assume
it's progressive,
which means it won't be
Iong before the brain
closes shop altogether. Ideas?
(ALARM BEEPING)
He's in V-fib.
His potassium's
still too high.
No pulse. Get him
off the machine.
Charge to 10. CIear.
(BEEPING)
Still in V-fib.
Another amp of epi.
Chase shouldn't be
wasting his time in NICU.
Could be Wernicke's.
No. Treatment for Wernicke's
is thiamine. We gave her
that together with the pheno.
Delirium points to Iithium.
I know we didn't' t find any,
but...
She'd have to be smuggling
it in to be getting sicker.
Whipple's causes
encephalopathic delirium.
The test was negative.
The test could have
been wrong.
Ideas are not soda cans.
Recycling sucks.
Give me something
new and shiny.
Or go retro. Take an old idea,
shine it up, and add
a new symptom.
Encephalopathic delirium.
Pellagra.
She drinks.
AIcoholics get pellagra.
They eat Iousy diets,
so no niacin.
He agrees with me.
What a shock.
Well, you're right.
Lack of niacin starves
the brain. Neurons shut down.
Causes seizures,
encephalopathic delirium
and psychosis.
We give Kara niacin, she'II
come out of her delirium
and she'II be totally sane.
Don't think she's ever
gonna be sane again.
Her son just died.
How do you feel?
Uh...
(GASPING)
My stomach kinda hurts.
I need to ask you
some questions,
see how you're doing.
Mmm-hmm.
Tell me your name.
Kara Mason. Is my son here?
When were you born?
PIease. Where's Michael?
Is he okay?
Do you hear any other voices
besides mine?
No. Answer me.
You've been suffering
from delusions.
They were caused
by a vitamin deficiency,
pellagra.
It made you believe things
that were not real.
Like the voices.
I
remember doing things
to Mikey.
Were those real?
I'm afraid so.
So, I...
You tried to suffocate
your son.
But...
You... You stopped me.
And
that other doctor,
he got Mikey breathing.
Your son's organs
were damaged too severely.
He passed away this morning.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no!
No!
Oh, my God! No! Oh, my God!
FOREMAN: Pellagra doesn't
cause bloody vomit.
She's still sick
and getting worse.
So what causes pellagra
and crimson spew?
Dead baby, while sad,
not our problem.
I should have given him
more polystyrene.
You killed him.
If you don't get over it,
you're gonna kill Mama, too.
Her alcoholism caused
the pellagra. Maybe it also
explains the vomiting.
Gastritis.
Gastritis meds
aren't helping,
which may confirm her story.
She only slipped once.
You remove drinking
from the equation,
internal bleeding,
hypercalcemia, seizure,
and pellagra are all back in.
Chase, will you get your head
out of the dead baby's butt
and focus on the barely alive?
How much polystyrene
did you give the kid?
One gram.
His potassium
just kept rising.
I need your son.
Who are you?
Your wife's doctor.
Your son may have had the
same condition she does.
My son didn't have
a condition. She killed him.
If I biopsy her intestine,
she'II bleed out.
He obviously won't.
You're not using my
son's body to help her.
Okay. How about trading him
for a beer?
Or maybe you're more
of a whiskey guy.
You didn't have strep
or a stomach bug
the morning you came in.
You puked because
you were hung over.
Accuse a recovered drunk
of slipping and most of
the time, you'II be right.
So I drink.
You're acting Iike
this is my fault.
People are gonna
feel sorry for you,
and they'II tell you that
you can't anticipate
the unthinkable.
The fact is, you can.
It's just not
all that pleasant.
Look, you don't know
anything about...
I know that people
don't get crazy enough
to kill someone
without first being
crazy enough
for someone to notice.
How many times
did you go out for a drink
because she was crying?
How many times
did you stay at work
because you couldn't Iisten
to her telling you
what a bad mother she is?
You were relieved
when she shut down
and just sat staring
for hours at a time.
She held the pillow
over his head. You slept
while she went nuts.
Not exactly a draw, but...
What is wrong with you?
What kind of a person
says those things now?
Let me do the test.
It'II be one Iess thing
for you to feel crappy about.
I got a dead baby
for you to biopsy.
Let Cameron do it.
Love working NICU?
I could get you transferred.
I told you. I just wanted
to trust patients.
You don't give a crap
about patients.
Your paycheck.
You've been double-dipping.
Taking your vacation time
here, while drawing
a salary in NICU.
Strange.
Rich boy doing all that
for some extra cash.
I'm not rich.
But your dad was.
Now he's dead.
If you're not rich,
that means that
Daddy cut you out.
I'm not rich.
Don't Iet it change you.
And do the test.
God of compassion,
take Michael into your arms
and welcome him into paradise.
Let there be no sorrow,
no weeping, and no pain.
Peace and joy forevermore.
I'm sorry.
It was a date.
Cuddy's negative
for all cancer markers.
It was a date.
The baby's intestine
shows slight
villous atrophy.
Why would a baby
have flattened villi?
He was being treated
with polystyrene.
Polystyrene shouldn't...
It didn't.
The question is,
what do they use in the NICU
to bind it together?
Wheat gluten.
It's great stuff.
Unless your body
can't tolerate it.
The baby didn't have colic?
He had celiac disease?
Just Iike Mom.
Celiac can be triggered
by all kinds of stress.
Bills, childbirth,
drunk husband...
Every time she had a bowl
of pasta or a slice of bread
or a slosh of soy sauce,
her small intestine became
more damaged,
Iess able to absorb
the vitamins and minerals
into her bloodstream.
Her body couldn't
absorb enough niacin,
caused the pellagra.
Couldn't absorb vitamin K,
caused the bleeding.
And celiac is why
the baby's meds didn't work.
His body just couldn't
absorb them.
Switch Mom to IV nutrition.
It's gluten-free. That'II
spruce her villi right up.
No. Celiac causes nutritional
deprivation. Our patient
has excess calcium.
Tell them what causes
excess calcium with
a chaser of bloody vomit.
Celiac patients
are susceptible to cancer
of the stomach Iining.
She has MALT Iymphoma.
Well, she's your patient, now.
And it wasn't a date.
You don't have cancer.
You don't have dwarfism.
You have no proof of that.
I, on the other hand,
have this.
You ran a PCR on me
without my consent?
Hey, it's good news.
Really?
It's just hard to access
because of this overwhelming
sense of personal violation.
Deal with it
on your own time.
Bad news.
Estrogen is too high.
No matter how many people
you tell otherwise,
I am and always have
been a woman.
Estrogen is normal.
Not this much.
Not for, at Ieast,
another week.
That's when you ovulate.
You monitor my periods
based on when
I get bitchy or...
Once a month, when you Ieave
the kids' cancer ward,
your eyes glisten.
And about three days Iater,
you break your ban on sugar
and chow down a bucket
of frozen yogurt in the
cafeteria. Sprinkles included.
Based on the Iast yogurt
sighting, you've got another
week before you ovulate.
You're on fertility meds.
With red clover
as an herbal booster.
And the dinner with Wilson
was an audition.
It's too bad he
didn't Iand the gig.
He would have had fun.
I was considering a donation.
Not a party.
So when's our dinner?
(WILSON TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
Oh, he's gonna be
so disappointed.
Right.
You two are gonna have
a Iot of fun with this.
Your patient won't Iet me
touch her.
I killed my son.
Is it my turn to say
something obvious now?
Oh, I know. You were insane.
I did it.
I chose to do it.
Yeah. Like diabetics choose
to not produce insulin.
Listen. Someone got sick.
Someone died.
It happens every day.
The only difference
in this case is,
it wasn't the same someone.
I could have stopped.
I didn't have to Iisten
to those voices.
Spoken Iike a true
sane person.
This is not your fault.
You're healthy now.
Except for the cancer.
Those voices felt
as real to me
as Michael's hand
right here, when he nursed,
and the smell of his hair.
You do not deserve to die.
Maybe.
I don't want to Iive.
(DOOR OPENING)
She said no.
So we get her
declared unstable,
appoint a medical proxy...
She was unstable.
Now, she's sane. She's
entitled to refuse the treatment.
You have to change her mind.
You can't just walk away.
Fine! Go on in there
and tell her that
every day is a blessing.
"So you killed your baby?
Shake it off. Think positive.
At Ieast you're alive."
Hmm.
Kinda hard to sell when
you don't believe it, huh?
And you never believed it.
You just wanted all that
crap you went through
to mean something.
Well, it didn't mean
anything. It never does.
Welcome back.
Why are you
doing this to me?
I was happy.
You were aspiring
to be content.
Don't give me a semantic
argument. I was content
with the way things were.
That's what happiness is.
Yeah.
If we were all just satisfied
with what we had, what a
beautiful world it would be.
We'd all slowly starve
to death in our own filth,
but at Ieast we'd be happy.
Listen. I need your self-worth
to hang on this job.
Kicking ass here to be all
that Iets you rise
above miserable.
If waking up in the morning
is enough, I don't need you.
I can Iive with that.
No, you can't. Not anymore.
If you got treatment,
then maybe we could...
When you see Mikey,
tell him his dad says
he's sorry.
Hi.
Night.
Did you tell Cuddy
we tested her for cancer?
Yeah.
And?
It wasn't a date.
Turned out she had
some skin Iesions. Guess there
was no genetic predisposition.
You TiVo The L Word?