BOY: Welcome to
the world of illusion!
What is real
and what is magic?
This is what you will wonder
as I perform feats
that will astound you!
As you see,
there is nothing up my sleeve.
And this hat,
it's just an ordinary old hat.
Watch, as I wave
three times above the hat,
and whisper the magic words.
And now...
(AUDlENCE APPLAUDlNG)
Mom, it's not working!
It's ripped!
It's okay, baby,
it's just a little tear.
Hurry up, Mom!
What are you
so worried about?
Sally's gonna make fun of us.
Sally Ayerson?
She said her mom bought her
dress at Bloomingdale's
and you had to make ours.
We're gonna look stupid.
Do you girls remember
that music we were
listening to yesterday?
That lady who
sang about respect?
Reetha?
Aretha, that's right.
Do you think she
had lots of money
growing up in Detroit?
What's Detroit?
It's a city.
The point is, is that she's
one of the best singers ever.
If Sally's mean to you again,
I'm just gonna have
to key her daddy's
new convertible.
(AUDlENCE APPLAUDlNG)
BOY: Great. And thank you!
Do you know
what that means?
Good.
(MUSlC PLAYlNG)
(BOTH HUMMlNG)
(SlNGlNG)
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa
Oh, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa
Little-bitty, pretty one
Come on and talk to me
Lovey-dovey, dovey one
Come on sit down on my knee
Oh, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa
(KAYLA GROANlNG LOUDLY)
(KAYLA SCREAMlNG LOUDLY)
(WOMAN ANNOUNClNG
ON P.A. SYSTEM)
Hey.
You speak to
Chase and House yet?
The disciplinary hearing.
The McGinley case,
that's not for two weeks.
Tomorrow.
Scheduling disaster,
you don't wanna hear it.
You gotta get the boys' okay
to move the hearing up,
and you gotta do that
whole legal advice thing.
Can you ask someone else?
I'm asking you.
Let me work with Chase.
House should have
separate counsel.
Stop looking for
whatever you're looking for.
For the last month,
House has been crowing
that you can't work
with him because you're
just swooning in love.
There is nothing approaching
love in what I feel
about him right now.
Well,
if you can't work with him,
it amounts to the same thing.
We had a fight. It's awkward.
Why not use another lawyer?
Because 40% of our
lawsuits last year
were about House.
If you can't work with him,
you can't work here.
HOUSE: She's overreacting.
WlLSON: You snuck into
her shrink's office
and read her private file.
When Nixon did that,
he got impeached.
So you're saying I'm not
allowed to have oral sex
with an intern, either?
Yes! And yes.
That file got me on the floor
of her attic with her pouring
out her soul.
The only thing I did
wrong was get caught.
STACY: Where's Chase?
He's too busy to service you
until after work.
I got a couple minutes,
though.
Feel free to say
something like,
"What'll we do
with the time left over?"
Or you could just stew,
that works as well.
She stews before
she gets violent.
This one says you're okay
with moving the disciplinary
hearing to tomorrow.
This one says I've advised
you of your legal rights.
Any legal rights
I should know about?
Nope.
Great.
And you thought
this was gonna be awkward.
You shouldn't sign it.
Postponing is almost always
the smart thing to do.
Tempers cool, memories fade.
They rule on me,
it's done, right?
Yeah, but...
Then let's get it over with.
Have you ever done
a peer review before?
No.
Good.
Peer's a misnomer.
These are your bosses.
This could cost you
some money, some privileges
or it could cost
you your career.
All I can tell them is
what happened.
There is an objective reality
to what happened,
and that committee is
never gonna know it.
All they're gonna know is
what they picture happened,
which depends a little
on what you tell them
and a whole lot
on how you tell them.
May 1 1.
The patient presented
to the clinic.
What's her name?
It's in the file.
Do you know it?
Then use it.
Kayla presented
to the clinic with multiple
joint and stomach pain.
CHASE:
Dr. Foreman was called in
for a neurological consult.
What's the point
of this, man?
Checking your sister's
cerebral coordination.
The thing is in her leg
and her stomach.
Wait in the clinic for
six hours so she can play
patty cake?
You could have gone
to the ER last night.
You gonna come over
and baby-sit her kids?
Okay. Patient comes from
a family of jerks, I get it.
Can you stick
to the medicine?
Something wrong?
CHASE:
There was some uveitis.
STACY: Meaning?
Her iris,
the colored part of her eye,
was inflamed.
Meaning?
Worst case, blindness.
But there was an upside.
It was weird enough
to get House interested.
Young woman, joint pain,
gonorrhea's a possibility.
It's polyarticular.
Maybe rheumatoid.
That's typically small joints,
this hit her knee.
Takayasu's arteritis.
Get a sed rate
and serologies.
"Childproof."
How many kids are
hopped up on Vicodin?
Give me.
Right. Like I'd ever
get it back.
HOUSE: Chase?
STACY :
Don't care about the Vicodin.
Might not just be
her arteries, could be
all her blood vessels.
Vasculitis,
with stomach pains,
so Behcet's.
No, she'd have oral sores.
Or genital.
Go find them.
I thought she was
Foreman's patient.
Why did you do the exam?
FOREMAN:
She'd have oral sores.
HOUSE: Or genital.
Go find them.
Whoa, whoa, Foreman.
Chase can handle the pelvic.
Any pain?
Is it bad?
This would go a lot easier
if you talked to me.
I'm sorry.
I, um...
I just really hate hospitals.
When I was 1 2,
I had my tonsils out.
Got to skip school,
lots of ice cream,
made me wanna be a doctor.
My mom died when I was eight,
so I spent months
at Princeton General.
She died of DTs, your mom?
Bottles stashed
around the house?
Mood swings? That whole deal?
You've been there?
My mom.
Dad left, Mom crawled
inside a bottle.
Made for a great
year 1 2 of high school.
You okay with your dad now?
No.
Does your dad have anything
to do with this story?
No, it's just...
Okay, I get it, the two of you
bonded, which is probably
why you haven't been sued.
Patients never sue
doctors they like.
But keep it brief, okay?
The panel doesn't
like to think
they're being manipulated
when they're
being manipulated.
She had some ulceration.
Confirming Behcet's.
I gave her some prednisone,
an antacid, and I ran
a pathergy test on her arm.
Takes 24 hours to confirm.
Told her any doctor
could check it out.
You didn't make
an appointment.
Nope.
She just showed up.
Dr. Chase?
Hi.
All right,
let's take a look.
Okay, those little pustules
mean it's positive.
Talk to Nurse Preven,
get an appointment with
Dr. Brustin in Rheumatology.
Behcet's is very treatable,
you're gonna be fine.
Okay. Thanks.
And you were just chatting
on the phone with someone
and she happened
to run into you.
That's what happened.
No appointment,
no real examination?
Just gave her
the test results.
So, lower standard of care,
you really couldn't
be expected to notice
there was anything else wrong.
We didn't even go
into an exam room.
As your lawyer,
I can't stop you from lying,
I can't even be in the room.
But I would be remiss
if I didn't prep you
to lie better.
You wrote her a prescription,
which means
there was an examination.
What really happened?
I was on the phone.
Dr. Chase? Hi.
Hi.
Kayla. I'm here
for the test. My arm.
Oh, yeah.
Okay.
It's positive.
Talk to Nurse Preven,
get an appointment with
Dr. Brustin in Rheumatology.
I took that medicine
you gave me,
but my stomach still hurts.
Behcet's could be
stronger than we thought,
or it could be reflux
from the prednisone.
Here's a stronger antacid.
Doctor?
Yes?
Nothing.
STACY:
You didn't ask her anything
about the stomach pain?
I made one little mistake.
As little mistakes go,
that was a biggie.
She's only advising Chase?
Not you?
Well, what's
the committee gonna do to me?
I never even met this patient.
Your disdain for
human interaction
doesn't exculpate you,
it inculpates you.
You signed the charts,
you're responsible
for everything Chase does.
Which is why
this doesn't matter.
She protects Chase,
she protects me.
Unless her advice
to Chase is to make a deal
and give you up.
"I'm so sorry,
if only Dr. House
had paid attention.
"He never even met her,
he never does."
Chase loves me.
And isn't Turkish.
Cameron loves you,
Chase loves his job.
You really think
Stacy hates me that much?
I think right now
she hates you
more than enough.
You think emotion
only affects
doctors' judgments?
Everything stemmed
from that one interaction.
They're gonna
slam you on it.
Were you distracted?
Your problem. Overworked?
That's their problem.
Forgetful, yours, lazy...
I just figured
the stomach pain
was the Behcet's.
Any doctor would have
thought the same.
Then why did you
call her an hour
after she left the clinic?
Nurse Preven said
you asked her to have
Kayla come back in.
The way she hesitated,
I thought she might have had
a doorknob question.
Patient comes in,
says he's got a sniffly nose,
you examine him for
10 minutes, right?
Then you're leaving,
hand on the doorknob,
and he says, "Oh, yeah,
and my penis
has turned green."
Embarrassing question,
the only important one,
patient saves it for last.
So you knew she was
about to ask
the most important question
and you left.
No, I didn't.
I figured it out later.
What changed?
Nothing.
Bad answer.
I wasn't thinking
clearly at first.
Worse answer.
So what was her
doorknob question?
I figured it might be
blood in her stool,
which could indicate
a bleeding ulcer.
CHASE: Talk to me.
Thirty-five year old female,
vomiting massive
amounts of blood,
LOC at work, BP 80
over 20, heart rate 140.
You push fluids?
Three liters in the field,
and we're bolusing
another one right now.
It's gotta be
a bleeding ulcer, Doc.
Her coworkers said
she's been eating
ibuprofens like candy.
I thought
she had Behcet's!
One, two, three.
CHASE: I'm in the stomach.
There's too much blood,
I can't see.
Did she burst an artery?
No.
There. Bubbling.
Just a bad ulcer.
Cauterizing.
I can't see,
use some more saline.
Hold on.
Okay.
(EXHALES)
Looks good.
Bleeding ulcer. We got it.
(MONlTOR BEEPlNG)
She was fine two hours ago.
FOREMAN: Systolic BP 70.
Where's the ulcer?
It's brown, I cauterized it.
There must be
something else.
There.
FOREMAN: A second ulcer?
Not anymore. It perforated.
Get her to an OR!
The surgeons were able to
suture the perforation.
But the contents
of the patient's,
Kayla's, stomach had
spilled into her body.
She got septic.
Then the infection
lowers her blood pressure...
Fifty over palp
at one point.
It damaged her liver
and kidneys.
Listen, I know
this looks bad.
I obviously got
the diagnosis wrong,
but I did everything
by the book.
I couldn't have known
what was gonna happen.
If I skip my coffee,
I get cranky.
Do you want anything?
STACY: Why did Chase screw up?
He forgot to ask a question,
does there need
to be a reason?
It might help him.
As far as I'm concerned,
he made a little mistake.
It happens.
How far are you concerned?
You think I'm biased?
You're colleagues.
You worked together
for over a year.
And everyone says
you slept together.
Who says?
The correct answer is,
"We're not involved
and I'm not biased."
We're not involved,
and I don't know
why he messed up.
House has worked with him
longer than I have.
You should talk to House.
Yeah.
STACY: Why did Chase screw up?
Because he doesn't give
a crap about patients.
Well, he always gets
positive patient reviews.
Yeah. He smiles
all 84 of his teeth,
tells them
his tonsil story...
It's a nice story.
He still has his tonsils!
As soon as he's out
of the room, which is as soon
as he can be out of the room,
he starts in on
the trash talking.
He thinks not giving a crap
makes him like House.
Like it's something
to aspire to.
Am I gonna have to testify?
I won't be
encouraging them
to call you.
What did House say?
(CHUCK COUGHlNG)
Two months like this.
Let me guess, no insurance.
You've just heard
about the free clinic.
It's a good move.
You don't wanna skimp
on the essentials like
wristwatches, MP3 players.
I need to talk to you.
From the doorway?
It's confidential.
Cool. I love gossip.
HOUSE: You hear that
crackling sound?
Like crumpling up paper?
Keep listening,
let me know if it changes.
Two questions.
Why did Chase screw up,
and how bad was it?
Wow. Talk about efficient,
I only need one answer.
Chase didn't screw up.
He said he did.
Well, I'm not a lawyer,
but that seems like
a sucky legal strategy.
They're gonna wanna know
what you think a reasonable
doctor would have done
in Chase's position.
If I thought he was
a reasonable doctor,
I wouldn't have hired him.
God, you two are
a couple of geniuses.
Deny everything,
completely fool the lawyer
who's trying to help you.
Too bad the review
committee members
are actually doctors.
Stacy.
(SlGHS)
I'm in the stomach.
There's too much blood,
I can't see.
Did she burst an artery?
No.
There. Bubbling.
Just a bad ulcer.
Okay. Cauterizing.
Looks good.
Bleeding ulcer. We got it.
She was fine two hours ago.
If by "fine," you mean
she had fountains of blood
(MONlTOR BEEPlNG)
spurting out of every orifice,
then yeah, I believe you.
(MONlTOR BEEPlNG)
I'm guessing those are
celebratory bells.
Systolic BP 70.
Show me the ulcer.
It's brown,
I cauterized it.
Sweep back.
Show me the whole stomach.
Stop.
FOREMAN: A second ulcer?
Not anymore. It perforated.
Get her to an OR!
Let's go.
She was not "fine"
two hours ago.
Did she mention stomach pain?
Yeah, so I gave her
a stronger...
You didn't do an exam.
She just came in
for a follow-up.
The results of
the pathergy test...
Did you listen
to her stomach?
Check her vitals?
Maybe if she'd said
something about
taking ibuprofen,
mentioned
the rectal bleeding...
Yeah!
Why didn't she go to
med school like you did?
Diarrhea, blood in the stool,
these are routine questions!
That doctors
skip all the time!
It was a minor mistake,
I couldn't have known
this was gonna happen...
Mistakes are as serious
as the results they cause!
This woman could die
because you were too lazy
to ask one simple question!
No, she might die
because I had
the bad luck to spill
your damn Vicodin pills!
I responded
with a number of
trenchant remarks
which made Chase cry,
none of which
I'm gonna testify about.
Unless you convince
Chase to roll on me.
Excuse me.
Testify about what?
Chuck.
I'm gonna break
from the parable
of the wicked doctor
and tell a little
story about a patient,
let's call him Buck.
Who has low O2 sats
and crackling lung sounds.
Like I have.
Buck has idiopathic
pulmonary fibrosis.
His lung tissue's
turning to rock.
There's no known cause,
no treatment.
He is slowly suffocating.
You're talking about me?
Lung transplant's
about $500,000,
but this poor sucker's
got no insurance.
If he tried to sign up now,
he'd be excluded,
preexisting condition.
But let me confirm
with my lawyer.
She confirms.
If only Buck hadn't been
diagnosed with fibrosis
before he got insurance.
So, back to the exam.
That's how you tell
this guy he's dying?
Oh, relax. He's got a cold.
And soon, health insurance.
Such a hero,
always righting wrongs.
Who cares who
you have to manipulate?
I'm sorry.
I didn't realize
you and Buck were so close.
It's a point of principle.
Right.
It's got nothing to do
with what I did to you.
There's nothing
for us to talk about.
That's why
you're following me.
I read some notes.
If Chase screwed up...
I was wrong!
I'm terribly, terribly sorry.
If Chase screwed up so badly,
why didn't you fire him?
He has great hair.
What are you hiding?
I'm gay.
Oh, that's not what you meant.
It does explain a lot, though.
No girlfriend,
always with Wilson.
Obsession with sneakers.
Diarrhea, blood in the stool.
Two simple questions
you could have asked
her six months ago
and averted this whole thing.
You didn't ask either, why?
Judging from your question
and your demeanor,
I assume you were
visiting with House.
We've been over this.
I don't know.
Good doctors don't
make mistakes like that.
Good doctors never forget
to ask questions?
Then you've got your answer,
apparently,
I'm not a good doctor.
FYl, self-pity generally
is not a good strategy
in these hearings.
What happened
after the operation?
The kidney damage
isn't so bad.
The liver damage
is more worrisome.
There's no dialysis
for livers.
I know.
But if she loses a liver,
she can get a transplant,
right?
We can put her on a list.
I could do it.
I could give her
part of my liver.
Surgeons won't operate
unless the donor's
had a long time to
weigh the decision.
There's black markets.
For organs?
(KAYLA GROANlNG)
That's just...
Oh, my stomach!
The pain constant?
Yeah!
Sharp or dull?
I don't know!
It's ferric.
It's a little cold.
She's got ascites.
No. It's a clot.
Nurse! Call the OR.
We gotta prep her
for an embolectomy.
(GROANlNG)
Run CBC, PT,
and a liver panel.
Sepsis had lowered
her BP so much, she got
clots in her liver.
They blocked
the hepatic artery,
cut off the blood flow.
Her liver was shocked.
And Cuddy listed her?
With all the other problems?
Forget it!
We can't give a liver
to a woman this sick.
Do you listen to
what you're saying?
There is no point in giving
a new liver to somebody
who also has vasculitis.
Treatable.
And kidney damage.
It's healing.
You know what's
really killing her?
Chase forgot to ask
a standard question
about stomach pain.
So he missed the diagnosis,
so she perforated,
so she got sepsis,
so her BP tanked,
so she got blood clots,
so she lost her liver.
Livers are important, Cuddy.
You can't live without them,
hence the name.
Here's the big issue.
Chase is a hospital employee,
and Kayla is
a sympathetic mother
of those two
jury-friendly moppets,
Caleb and Cody.
Dory and Nikki.
Your point, beyond
just trying to make
Chase wet himself,
seems to be that
the hospital faces
liability here.
Well, thanks for
clearing that up.
I still need
a medical reason
to list her.
That is the medical reason.
If the family wins
this hospital in a lawsuit,
they'll turn it into condos.
And people will die
waiting outside a condo
for medical care.
Start praying
for a 1 2-car pileup
on the turnpike,
'cause we're not exactly
swimming in livers over here.
When you're testifying,
skip the details on
how House convinced Cuddy.
I don't think the people
who got bumped down
the transplant list
need to know why.
It didn't matter anyway.
SAM: She next on the list?
Yes.
But she's AB negative,
very rare.
SAM: How long can she
go on like this?
Probably another day or two.
I'm donating my liver.
Sam, we talked about this.
I'm a perfect match,
six out of six HLA proteins.
How'd you get
checked out so fast?
I know a guy in
medical testing,
and I paid him to rush it.
Sam bribed someone
to rush his tests?
Wouldn't you?
Someone's going to get
the blame for what happened,
so the more we
spread it around,
we might as well...
You said no surgeon would do
a live donor transplant
on such short notice.
House took care of that, too.
Your patient's
hardly clotting.
Sub-Q vitamin K and fresh
frozen plasma pre-op.
Pretty risky.
Well, that's why I came
to the best transplant
surgeon in the hospital.
She's dead without you.
Get her in this afternoon.
Thank you very much.
My pleasure.
And this was right
before you ran the marathon,
I suppose?
Was it the part
where he warmly clasped
my hands in thanks,
was that too much?
What did you do to him?
The hospital lawyer asks me
if I did something unethical?
If I did,
the last person I'd tell
is the hospital lawyer,
especially since she's gone
all Old Testament on me.
You'll tell me.
Oh. Okay then.
One caveat,
I've moved past threesomes,
I'm now into foursomes.
If someone backs out, then,
you've still got a threesome.
And if two people back out,
you're still having sex.
You'd be amazed,
even if three people...
Anything you say
is attorney-client.
So you can get advice
about the bad,
bad thing you did,
knowing I'll be tortured
because I can't tell a soul.
Actually,
it is kind of cool.
Are you completely
out of your mind?
She's dying on her own,
why would I volunteer
to be her executioner?
And I'd just be inviting
a lawsuit from the brother
no matter what.
5 grand.
And that's just ante money.
After the surgery,
you get another 15.
Though I warn you,
that includes the tip.
(LAUGHlNG)
I make 600 grand a year.
You think I'm gonna risk
tanking my percentages
for $20,000?
It's tax-free.
For the record,
I hope the Department
takes you and Chase
and drop-kicks
both your asses
out the back door.
Great!
That means
I don't have to bother
welshing on the 15 grand
I would have owed you.
If you don't do the surgery,
I'm gonna tell your wife
that you've been sleeping
with a series of nurses.
Currently Nurse Cutler
in Radiology.
Now, what's 600 grand
divided by two?
Last Christmas party,
Nurse Cutler handed you
one of those little hot dogs.
And you didn't thank her.
Well, that only happens
when you're very,
very intimate.
That, and the fact
that you've been
practically dancing around
with your zipper open,
and a used condom
stuck on your shoe.
Your wife is apparently
the only one who doesn't know.
There's no way
you'll tell her.
Of course I won't.
I'm much too cowardly.
No, I'll just send
an anonymous letter.
Now, I've got an OR booked
for 4:00 this afternoon.
Are you free?
Oh, and "for the record,"
you are the worst
transplant surgeon
in this hospital.
But unfortunately, you're
the only one who's currently
cheating on his wife.
You bribed him
and then you blackmailed him?
She'd have been dead
in two days if I hadn't made
Ayersman do the surgery.
Leave the blackmail
out of the story
you tell the committee.
I tried to leave it out
of the story I told you.
And then there was
that incident
in the parking lot.
Don't do that!
Hey, what, are you nuts?
No, please,
I didn't do it!
I didn't do anything! Please!
No!
Apparently,
someone sent an anonymous
letter to his wife.
You blackmailed Ayersman,
he performed the surgery,
and you ratted him out anyway?
Doesn't seem fair, does it?
You just can't
control yourself, can you?
No matter how stupid,
how self-destructive...
To make this
conversation easier,
can we discard the fiction
that we're talking about
anything other than
what I did to you?
You're not mad because
I broke into your
psychiatrist's office.
Yeah, I was
thrilled about that.
Okay, it was
a lousy thing to do.
But if what I had found
was that everything was
all kittens and moonbeams
in Markville,
you'd be over it.
No, I wouldn't!
You're mad at me
for letting you
know what I did.
Because you liked
where things were going.
And for that,
I actually am sorry.
It was stupid.
(SlGHS)
Let me tell you
a story about a patient.
A patient we'll call Fusan.
CHASE: Because Sam had
rushed his tests,
we were able to
get them into surgery
that afternoon.
Dr. Ayersman performed
the live-donor transplant.
He resected the right lobe,
hepatic vein,
and hepatic artery
of Sam 's liver,
and transplanted it
into Kayla.
The operation was a success.
Kayla and Sam continued
to receive routine care.
Two months later,
she came by for an exam.
July 24, be precise.
You did the exam?
Honestly, I just wanted...
"Honestly"?
So you've been
lying up until now?
Let's make a deal.
I won't use
the word "honestly,"
and you'll quit
stopping by to see House
so you don't take it
out on me afterwards.
How about that?
I wanted to be as far away
from Kayla as possible.
And House was
rubbing my nose in it.
How are the girls?
They're great.
Dory had her first crush,
which was cute.
Oh, yeah?
And then her
first sort of breakup,
(BEEPlNG)
which was not so cute.
You're hot. 99.3.
Have you been coughing?
No.
Pain in urinating?
99's not that high, is it?
Immunosuppressants
block fevers,
you shouldn't
have one at all.
I'm sending a nurse in here
to draw cultures.
And I'm ordering
a chest x-ray.
I wasn't making
any more mistakes.
Another phrase to avoid
in front of the committee.
She spiked a fever
an hour later.
Her AST and ALT are up.
She's rejecting the liver.
No, it's just an infection.
One of her cultures
is growing out strep.
Just one?
Probably a contaminant.
She's dehydrated,
her hematocrit's way up.
It's strep.
Her transaminases
are up, too.
That's just
stress from the strep.
Jeez, Chase.
You and this strep.
Get a room already.
She's not rejecting
the liver.
It's just an infection,
she'll be fine.
CAMERON: Worst case,
we could re-list her.
You House?
Well, that depends.
Are you gonna hit Dr. House?
You haven't even seen
my sister, and you're being
cute with me?
Sam, we're talking
about her right now.
Her fever might...
Could be hep B,
hep C, right?
This is treatable.
You give her interferon,
she's okay, right?
You know a lot
about hepatitis.
He just donated his liver.
You're flushed. You sick?
I'm tired.
You're hiding the fact
that you're sick.
Now, why would you do that?
Hey, what are you...
Now, either you
specifically asked
for a tattoo of a heart
that's been left out
in the sun too long,
or that is
a really bad home job.
It's a very common
way of getting hep C.
Which you have.
And you've had it
a long time.
It was gonna keep me
from giving my liver.
You paid off that lab tech
to say you were clean?
It hasn't been active
in years, she was
gonna die if I didn't.
You paid someone off?
That is
totally unethical!
Get an MRl for him
and his sister, right now.
She got hep from me,
didn't she?
No! No, no, no, no.
God, no.
I think she got
cancer from you.
House was right?
The brother had
an undiagnosed hepatoma
that was transplanted
with his liver.
It grew a lot faster
in Kayla because she was
immunosuppressed.
How could House
have known?
Hepatitis can cause
liver cancer.
Plus, her hematocrit,
red blood cell count,
was high.
Usually means dehydration.
Rare cases, cancer.
It probably saved
Sam's life.
CHASE: We were able to
operate on him early enough,
before it metastasized.
SURGEON: O2 sats 94.
Kayla had already
started rejecting the liver.
And you couldn't re-list her
because of the cancer.
Nothing we could do.
This is good.
The brother lying
about his hep,
it's an intervening act.
The proximate
cause of her cancer,
not your mistake.
She would have died
six months ago if he hadn't
given up his liver.
Maybe. Can't prove it.
(PAGER BEEPlNG)
You need to come with me.
Just been served with papers.
Actually, paper.
One page.
"Defendants
Princeton-Plainsboro Hospital
"and Dr. Robert Chase.
Blah, blah, blah.
"Medical malpractice,
negligence. Blah, blah."
HOUSE: You're surprised
they're suing?
You think people
love Chase so much
they're gonna just forgo...
Punitive damages
in the amount of
$10 million.
Punitives? That means
they're alleging
gross negligence.
Their lawyer's obviously
out of his mind.
Larry Ruseckas,
he's not crazy.
Oh, no.
I've been sued by him.
You have been hiding things
and lying to me all day.
I haven't lied
about anything.
Except for the parts that
I admitted I was lying about.
And I'm not the one
being sued. I feel funny.
Well,
what haven't you told us?
(SlGHS)
Before she checked out,
Sam found her a second liver.
She had cancer,
how could she...
Black market.
There's a doctor
in Mexico City who was gonna
do the surgery.
She's leaving
from JFK at 5:00.
To meet some Mexican guy
in the back of a van
with a pig's liver
and a hacksaw?
This is nuts!
You wanna
rat me out to House?
He'll say if there's a chance
in a billion then go for it.
This is not what she wants.
She's being manipulated
by a morally guilty brother
and a legally guiltier doctor.
You think
she wants to die?
She's dying either way.
Chase!
How many people you know
walking around with
a black market organ
from a Third World
surgeon, huh?
This isn't gonna be
your salvation.
It's just one more thing
they'll pin on you.
Go in there,
be the good guy.
We need to talk.
No, there's no time.
Two minutes.
Kayla.
I made a mistake.
I wasn't as blunt
as I should have been
about your odds.
I probably didn't
want to face them myself.
Dr. Chase,
please don't do this.
The stress of the travel,
the operation
and even then the cancer...
Kayla, we're going!
My dad died.
Lung cancer.
I saw him a couple of months
before it happened.
We never talked about it.
I'm sorry your father died,
but it has nothing...
He never even told me
he was sick.
I wish he had.
It would...
You're gonna die. Alone.
Thousands of miles
from your children.
You don't wanna
do that to them.
Kayla...
I'm sorry, Sam.
Kayla, you can't give up.
If you do this,
if you go home,
I killed you.
No.
You gave me
three months.
You gave Dory and Nikki
three more months with me.
And when they
found my cancer,
they found yours.
And I got to save
my baby brother.
(SOBBlNG)
CHASE: A week later,
Kayla died at home.
Sam was furious.
Gotta be why the big lawsuit.
Are you buying this?
STACY: Of course not!
There was no
illegal transplant,
there's no causation.
He was ready to kill me.
Maybe he's lying
to his lawyers.
Or you're lying to us.
Last Thursday he saw you
for post-op care.
If you hate your doctor,
you find another doctor
before you find a lawyer.
This guy didn't sue
Cameron or Foreman,
he didn't even sue House!
There's something
personal here,
something you don't
want us to know
before your hearing.
The guy didn't hate you
before that meeting,
he hated you after.
So, how's
everything else?
The girls?
Oh, you know.
A lot of crying,
some nightmares.
We'll be okay, though.
Good.
Girls are not gonna be happy
about leaving town, though.
They love that house,
the yard, their friends.
You're moving?
Yeah.
Ever since the operation,
I've been on disability,
and the mortgage...
So, we're moving out of state,
somewhere cheaper.
Anyways, thanks.
I killed your sister.
I misdiagnosed her ulcer.
It killed her.
Shut up, man.
She liked you, just...
I was hung over
when she came back
to see me.
I'd been up half
the night drinking,
had a headache,
and I just wanted to
get the hell out of there.
I couldn't care less
what your sister was saying
about her stomach pain.
(CRASHlNG)
May I speak to my future
former employee?
HOUSE: Great story.
CHASE: You think I'm lying?
That's exactly
what I told him.
I'm sure it is.
But you lied to him.
You want him to sue you.
I killed his sister.
I ordered black coffee
this morning and got cream.
Everybody screws up.
They didn't put poison
in your coffee.
I've seen you hung over.
You weren't the day you blew
his sister's diagnosis.
What does it matter why?
Is she less dead
if I have a good excuse?
If I thought you'd screwed up
because you were drunk,
I would have fired you.
You knew?
You were depressed
and distracted.
I assumed you'd
gotten a phone call
from your stepmom.
This is Robert.
What did he die of?
That's impossible.
I saw him two months ago.
If he had lung cancer,
he would have...
Dr. Chase?
Good news is,
both your parents
are dead now.
So no reason to
screw up this bad again.
How'd you know?
There's this interconnected
network of computers,
or "lnterweb,"
where you can...
How did you know to look?
When he visited,
he told me he only had
two months left.
When you screwed up,
I did the math.
Why didn't you tell me
he was dying?
He asked me not to.
So you just
hung me out there
to be blindsided?
Yeah, Chase,
it was all my fault.
Look, you've got a choice.
You can either tell the truth,
the hospital settles,
the family gets some money.
They get to keep their house.
Or you can keep up this lie.
The family gets
punitive damages,
they buy a jet,
and they move to Park Avenue,
and you have to
find another career.
You're not gonna
say anything?
I'm gonna keep my mouth shut.
Legally, it's better for me
if you go down in flames.
Is Chase telling
the committee about his dad?
I don't know.
(SlGHS)
I thought you were gonna
get him to sell me out.
I wouldn't do that.
Why not?
You're my client, too.
Yeah.
And that's not gonna change
unless you leave this job,
or I do.
So how do you deal
with a coworker that
you have feelings for?
Positive or negative.
I don't wanna
end up like Chase.
I don't wanna get
emotionally caught up
and kill you.
It's not all negative.
Maybe you were right,
maybe...
Maybe that is the problem.
So what do we do?
I don't know.
DR. SCHlSGAL: Dr. House?
After considering
the testimonial and
documentary evidence,
this ad-hoc committee in
the matter of Kayla McGinley
has reached a decision.
Dr. Chase,
your error resulted
in a patient's death.
You also lied,
both to your superiors
and the patient's brother.
But, taking into account
the mitigating factor
of your father's death,
we've decided not to
revoke your privileges.
You'll receive one week's
suspension, and a letter
in your permanent file.
Now, as for Dr. House.
There is no evidence
of a failure to supervise
that would lead to
disciplinary action.
And yet, there is enough
in the record to be
very troubled by your conduct,
including certain allegations
of blackmail from members
of the transplant team,
and by your general refusal
to meet with your patients.
It should be noted
that your patient's cancer
was diagnosed
as a result of a direct
physical examination...
Not of the patient.
I met the brother,
never met her.
Do you want me to
go to a family reunion
every time
I take on a patient?
The committee has
determined that
for no less than one month,
Dr. House will have
his practice supervised
by another doctor,
to be designated
by Dr. Cuddy.
This proceeding is adjourned.
Did you know this was coming?
They contacted me
about an hour ago.
CAMERON:
What's happening to Chase?
Now you're fired!
No. He's not.
Dr. House,
meet your new boss.
Guess I'm his best friend now.