Two spades.
Three hearts.
It's all yours.
I fold.
And that's five.
- And that's six.
- Yay!
Not bad.
On a slam contract, you normally
want to play your winners early.
Sorry, Dad.
Nah. You're learning.
You're doing fine.
Woman:
Connie Gilman's a good player.
And a widow.
I should, uh, take her out
because she can play bridge.
You're a true romantic.
Woman 2:
You should ask somebody out.
You think Cecile's not dating yet?
- Cecile was dating before she left.
- Oh, shut up, Marv.
No. I have a partner.
And she's doing great.
Amy should be out having fun.
I'm having fun.
Yeah.
Look like you're having
the time of your life.
- One no trump.
- (Woman, laughing) Ooh!
I'm just...a little nauseous.
I, uh, I think I ate too much.
- Can we take a break?
- Of course.
Excuse us.
What did you eat?
Nothing weird.
- Have you been drinking?
- No, Dad. You know I don't--
Because I don't mind if you--
Dad?
[Echoing] Dad?
Dad, what are you doing?
You're scaring me.
It hurts. Let go!
What are you doing?
Man:
Henry?
Henry.
Let go of her.
The occasional drink
doesn't bother me. But...
What?
Are you okay?
What's the matter?
2X14 - Sex Kills
Original Airdate (FOX):  7 March-2006
You had what's called
an "absence seizure."
Anything like that
happen to you before?
No, Nothing.
He's been really healthy.
He jogs, he eats right. He--
I--well, I did have
a headache last Sunday.
And for the past two years,
I've been getting acid reflux a lot.
And I thought that, uh,
antacids were all I needed.
Should I have come in sooner?
For acid reflux and a headache?
Well, I--you know,
I hear the coffee downstairs
is really good.
Could you get me a cup, Honey?
Would you mind
closing the blinds?
Foreman:
His right testicle is almost
twice as big as his left.
Cool.
It's probably testicular cancer.
Mmm, no.
That's impossible.
- The symptoms all indicate--
- The shoes aren't right.
Here's how testicular cancer
would manifest itself.
First, the patient would get
the exact symptoms that he's got.
Then Foreman would examine him.
Then he'd suspect
testicular cancer on account of
the symptoms being so perfect.
Then he'd stick a needle in it.
Then he'd call a surgeon.
And while that guy operates,
the rest of us would be out bowling.
And since we're not
wearing bowling shoes,
the disease obviously
did not progress in that fashion.
LP showed some white cells.
But his MRI is clean.
Sure. If you call a microabscess
in his brain "clean."
What, you don't trust me?
Are you talking about
the left temporal lobe?
Neat. You can see
through my hand.
- It's just a shadow.
- Or it's an infection.
When guys have brain/crotch problems,
it's usually the result of using
one too much and the other too little.
Blood and urine were negative for
syphilis, gonorrhea, and chlamydia.
So treat him for all three.
Stat.
Um...negative means
he doesn't have it.
No. Negative means
he probably doesn't have it.
Which means he probably has cancer.
I thought we were wearing
the wrong shoes for cancer.
We're wearing the wrong shoes
for testicular cancer.
They're perfect for lymphoma.
Except Chase's.
They're just goofy.
Lymphoma could cause infiltrants
in his reproductive organs and his brain.
If it's this advanced,
he's dead no matter what we do.
So give him the STD meds
and hope the tests were wrong.
Svinnuk.
Who's the lucky woman?
My wife.
No, I don't want to know
who gets the chocolates.
I want to know who
you're having the affair with.
Fell  on his head as a child.
Tragic.
Norwegian chocolate.
Frankly,
you buy that stuff,
the terrorists win.
Some people bottle up their feelings,
have them come out as physical pain.
Healthy human beings express feelings,
such as affection, by giving gifts.
Gifts express guilt.
The more expensive the expression,
the deeper the guilt. That's a $12 box.
So either you haven't
slept with her yet,
or she wasn't that good.
It's not all about sex, House.
Really?
When did that change?
I want to get Depo-Provera.
Actually, at your age,
as long as you're careful,
the risk of you getting
pregnant is pretty limited.
Yeah, but it would
calm me down.
Right? If I get
a high enough dose.
You mean
"calm" as in a peaceful lake,
on cool summer evening?
Or in the lesser used meaning of,
nothing can ever bother you again
because life has absolutely no meaning?
High dose of Depo-Provera
will chemically castrate you.
Yeah.
Okay. I'm gonna
get up to leave now.
And I'm gonna walk to that door,
turn the handle.
And then you're
suddenly gonna decide that
you have to tell me the truth.
I'm gonna have to turn around
and come all the way back.
See, the thing is,
my leg hurts.
Can we cut the walking
out of the equation?
I love cows.
Any particular...variety?
Guernseys? Holsteins?
Which are the black and white ones?
Oh, God.
I  pass a farm
on my way to school.
And they're so beautiful.
They're so majestic.
I dream about them.
Leather shoes, hamburgers.
How can anybody do that to a cow?
Make love, not belts.
It's beautiful.
- I haven't actually--
- Well, relax.
Something we doctors
deal with all the time.
I'm gonna write you
the name of a drug.
You don't need a prescription.
And it looks just like Depo-Provera.
- But does it do the same thing?
- Oh, God, no.
That stuff has
all sorts of nasty side effects.
It's real medicine.
No,  this is all you need.
Your frat buddies will
be completely fooled.
Tell them how appalled
the doctor was.
Lots of laughs.
We think you may have
a sexually transmitted disease.
No. It's not possible.
Sir, maybe we should
speak in private?
Have you tested him for this?
The tests were negative.
Well, then it's not that.
So what else could it be?
Nothing good.
If you've been having sex,
you have to tell me.
I have not had sex
since my divorce.
I didn't ask him
to take the medicine.
I asked you
to give him the medicine.
He hasn't had sex
in over a year.
- He's lying.
- He knows what's at stake.
We should start treating him
for lymphoma right away.
- Maybe if we hit him hard and fast--
- Wilson!
How long can you
go without sex?
go without annoying people?
No, seriously.
Week? Month?
I'm not having an affair.
I didn't say you were.
Not in this conversation.
We're talking about a patient.
People have impulse control.
We don't need sex.
Well, not like air.
But as a biological imperative,
sure we do.
There's two things
we get stupid for.
Money and sex.
And since money rarely
enters the bloodstream...
Was his daughter in the room
when you asked if he'd had sex?
I told him we could talk privately.
He didn't care if she was there.
It's almost noon.
Little girl would go to lunch.
Soon as she's out the door,
you're gonna get paged.
Then you page me.
[Foreman's pager beeps]
Lunch is early, huh?
Hi.
I'm Dr. House.
I hear you'd rather die
than admit you had sex.
I'm sorry. I...
couldn't tell my daughter.
Right. 'Cause she's...what, 22?
I slept with her mom.
She probably knows
that's happened already.
Roll over.
My wife had an affair.
I forgave her.
She had another affair.
And I forgave her again. And...
Amy thinks I was an idiot.
So smart.
You must be very proud.
Roll over.
I assume you've been in love.
Is that the one that
makes your pants feel funny?
I'm starting you
on a cocktail of STD meds.
Amy is just getting over it.
She barely spoke to her mom
for months actually.
If she thought that
it was happening again,
that that's why I got sick--
We just happened to be at
the same Italian cheese-tasting thing.
Cheese is the devil's play thing.
It was just the one night.
Oh, you're obviously
completely over her.
Amy thinks love leads you
to make stupid choices.
You're certainly setting
a good example for her.
Yeah. She just doesn't get it.
If you're not prepared to look stupid,
then nothing great is
ever gonna happen, right?
On the other hand,
I guess your testicles
aren't going to explode either.
Dad.
Is everything okay?
I have a sexually transmitted disease.
How's that possible?
He met a woman in church.
Does she play bridge?
[Laughing]
Does she-- Ha-ha.
[Monitors start beeping]
- Crash cart!
- Oh, God...
- Is this another seizure?
- Shut up.
Comin' in!
Amy:
Oh, God.
- Here you go.
- 40 milligrams furosemide.
Knock him out.
How would an STD do this?
It wouldn't.
Chase:
It was flash pulmonary edema.
We took a liter of fluid off, but
the problem wasn't with his lungs.
It's his heart.
There are vegetations
obstructing his mitral valve.
It's not an STD.
Lymphoma wouldn't
erupt that suddenly.
So what is it, then?
A disease that attacks
his brain, heart, and testicles.
I think Byron wrote about that.
Could be psittacosis.
Chlamydia cultures
would've come back positive.
Strep viridans
can hit the heart.
Wouldn't mess with
the reproductive system.
Maybe things aren't...
so nicely connected.
He's 65.
We could be looking at
multiple systems just starting
to break down independently.
Way to a man's heart
is through his stomach.
He's had acid reflux for years.
It--it can't be relevant.
It seems there are
other ways to kill people
besides having sex with them.
You don't need this so much.
Problem  is not your lungs.
It's your heart.
That Italian cheese thing
at the church.
What sort of cheese?
Why do you need to know?
I'm having a fondue party.
- Was it sheep cheese?
- Might have been. Why?
- Was it soft?
- Yeah.
- Taste like crap?
- Yeah. Bitter.
Taste like this?
- Yeah. But how did you--
- That was regularlow-fat American.
I added some bacteria.
For flavor.
You fed him bacteria?
It's pretty much on everything.
Especially the unpasteurized
sheep cheese they make in the Alps.
That stuff will give you brucellosis.
Key to a long life.
Exotic women, boring cheese.
Gonna start you on
rifampin and doxycycline.
Doesn't make any sense.
I mean, nobody else
at the church got sick.
99.9 % of Christians have
so much acid in their stomach,
they become churning cauldrons of death
for all those nasty little brucellosis bugs.
But you were taking antacids
for your acid reflux.
So that turns your digestive tract
into a pleasant scenic river
for all those bacterial tourists.
You sure you're right?
Absolutely.
Your socks don't match.
Which means you got up
and got dressed in the dark,
which means you don't
want to wake your wife.
Which means you don't
want to talk to her.
- Which means--
- I was referring to your patient.
Oh, that. No.
Come on,
I'm basing it on cheese.
How long before
you get the tests back?
We'll know before that.
If I'm wrong,
he'll just keep
getting worse and slowly die.
But if I'm right,
either we caught it in time
and he gets better.
Or we didn't and he goes into
cardiac arrest at any moment.
[Monitors beeping and flatlining]
Paddles.
Charging.
250. Clear.
Charging. 300.
Clear.
Charging.  360. Clear.
Epinephrine.
[Repeats defibrillation shocks]
Are you gonna tell her?
That you suspect an affair?
Sure. Well, she already
hates you, why not?
Because you think that
getting it off your chest will
let you sleep better. It won't.
You'll end up sleeping
on my lumpy couch.
There's nothing to tell.
Then why are you playing
foosball here at 8:00 at night?
You always want
to simplify everything.
[House's beeper goes off]
Boil it down to
nice, easy equations.
Nice, easy answers.
Go home and have sex
with your wife.
His heart is back in sinus rhythm.
There's a lot of damage, though.
It was brucellosis,
but we got to it too late.
The vegetation broke off
in his main coronary artery
and caused an infarction.
His heart muscle's half-dead.
He'll be lucky to last a week.
Other than that,
how's he doing?
Seriously.
His brain, testicle, lungs, tonsils.
How's all that other stuff doing?
Uh...his brain is clear now.
And so is the genito-urinary tract.
And his kidney function is good.
So, all he needs is a heart,
and he's outta here.
He's a prime candidate
for transplant.
He doesn't smoke,
drinks moderately.
His tox screen was
negative for illegal drugs.
And legal ones.
Surveillance blood cultures
show absolutely no sign of
any lingering brucella bacteria.
He's 66 years old.
He told me he was 65.
Liar. I'm outta here.
There is an inverse correlation
between patient age and success rates.
He's in excellent health.
This was his first hospitalization
since breaking his leg at 23.
Or 22. I'm not sure anymore.
If this patient were
to survivethe operation,
he'd get another what?
5, 10, maybe 20 years
if he's very lucky.
So you're saying that
old people aren't as worth
saving as young people.
He's saying that
hearts are a scarce resource.
We obviously have to
choose criteria--
No, I get it. Women live longer,
so they should get preference, right?
And African-Americans,
they die a lot younger.
So to hell with them.
What, you think
you're gonna win me over
by calling me a racist?
If the test is who gets to use it the longest,
you can either be a racistor a hypocrite.
Your patient had a life.
A family.
We've got 18-year-old kids
who will neve--
How old are you, Doctor?
When do we get to
toss you on an ice flow?
Cuddy:
And thank you, Dr. House.
Unless anybody else has
any further questions,
we will now go into private session.
Oh, I'm on pins and needles.
I wonder how you'll decide.
The Nets just won
their third game in a row.
Beat the Lakers.
I'm sorry.
They voted no.
So...
when...
will I die?
Might have a week.
[Amy sobs quietly]
God.
I wrote a letter to the board of directors,
appealing the transplant committee's decision.
I'm alleging bias against you
clouded their medical judgment.
I need you to sign.
They made the right call.
You don't believe that.
You told the committee--
I was advocating
for my patient.
- Then why are you--
- Advocating for my patient.
I've got clinic duty.
I need you to get me the files
on everybody who dies here today.
You really think this thing'll
change their decision?
Nope.
Mooooo!
I think I broke my ankle.
I was kicked. By a hoof.
I'm so in love.
She was so beautiful.
- Which one?
- One of the black and white ones.
- I'm not sure what type.
- Which "type"? Which one?
I want a name.
- Why would it have a name?
- Well, not "it." She. Or he.
I want to know
her dreams, her hopes.
It's a cow.
Hey, I'm not the one
who said he was in love.
People who actually have this condition
rationalize it. They dismiss it.
They don't elevate it to the level of poetry.
Plus there's
a wooden splinter in there.
So either you hit yourself
with a two-by-four
or Elsie has a peg leg.
I'm off duty at 6:00.
Give yourself another whack,
come back and scam somebody else.
I'm sick. And you're a doctor.
You have a duty to help me.
Technically I don't
have to treat anybody.
Before running a series of
painful and often humiliating tests.
Whatever you need.
90-year-old woman
died of pneumonia.
Unless she has a bionic heart,
what's next?
- Um...baby died in the ICU.
- Babies are useless.
They've got hearts the size
of ping-pong balls. Next?
Um...40-year-old male...
Yes?
Heart attack.
If you really cared about me,
you'd find me a better corpse.
There's no other deaths.
There's one woman who
was in a car accident.
Bad one, I hope.
The organ procurement people
have been notified.
Give me her file.
It's  in the ER.
They're still working on her.
- Age?
- About 40.
- Young. Damn.
- Young is good.
- Smoker?
- Don't know.
Find out.
She's still alive.
Even if we get on the list,
we can't go near her until--
Overweight?
She's on the hefty side.
Excellent.
Our odds just went up.
What odds?
What is this?
60 % of potential donor hearts
get tossed in the trash because
there's something wrong with them.
With fat people,
it's closer to 80.
But if her heart's
no good, then--
Big, fat, sloppy heart.
Beats no heart at all.
- Are you Mr. Neuberger?
- Yes.
I'm Dr. House.
Need to ask you a few questions
about your wife.
Is she gonna be okay?
I'm afraid I don't know that.
Could you tell me
about her accident?
They, uh, think she fell asleep,
went off the road.
That's all they told me.
Any problems with her health
up until now?
Why?
Please, it's important.
Um...
she had a fever today,
but otherwise she was--
How high?
About 101.
She hasn't missed a day
of teaching in years.
And I should've
made her stay home.
Any other symptoms?
A stomachache. Who cares?
She was in a car crash.
- Mr. Neuberger.
- Yeah.
My name's Ellen Stambler.
I'm the organ procurement coordinator
for Southern New Jersey.
I just want to assure you
that we'll treat her organs
with care and dignity.
Her organs?
Laura died?
I--I'm sorry.
I thought, um--
She was just pronounced dead.
I thought he was telling you.
I didn't know.
You should never make assumptions.
What did you want from me?
I'm sorry for your loss.
But I need your wife's heart.
The organ procurement coordinator
just left the hospital.
Means we got lucky.
Either that or she's getting lunch.
Dead woman's last name
have a "U" or "W"?
You're hacking into
a confidential patient file?
Is that a problem for you?
It's a "U". N-E-U.
Berger.
Three minutes ago,
her organs were officially
declared not viable.
Time to go dumpster diving.
Hey.
She's got hepatitis C.
Her ALTs are three times normal.
With Henry's immune system down,
an infected heart will kill him.
Fortunately,
she didn't have hep C.
- She tested positive.
- Her history says otherwise.
Her husband told me
she was running a fever
with stomach pains.
Not symptomatic of hep C.
Hey, what are you doing?
What are you doing?
Hey. What are you doing?
Again, sorry.
But we need to talk.
Mr. Neuberger has every right
to take his wife off the ventilator.
His wife signed
an organ donor card.
Which became invalid when
her organs were turned down.
I can use them!
I just need some time.
Committee says
they won't take her heart.
Another committee says
the guy can't have a heart.
It's a marriage made in heaven.
I can find a surgical team
that can do this.
Classified as experimental,
it's not gonna screw
with their numbers.
- This is what she wanted.
- No.
She wanted her organs to help--
She never wanted to
be kept alive on a ventilator.
She's not. She's dead!
She's not in pain.
She's not suffering.
It's just her...
meat we're dealing with here.
- This is my wife.
- Not anymore.
She deserves some respect.
Some dignity.
- I respect the living.
- Right.
That is why you made me think
that you were her doctor.
Made me believe that
maybe there was some hope.
I never said that
I was her doctor.
Fine, you didn't lie.
But you sure as hell
didn't give me any respect.
I am taking her
off the machines. Now.
Nicely played.
It's not over.
Excuse me.
Are you Mr. Neuberger?
Yeah. Why?
I'm Amy Arrington.
I wanted to thank you.
This girl's father will die
by next weekend unless
he gets your wife's heart.
House. Don't you think
that's a little manipulative?
No. It's hugely manipulative.
You're an ass.
Hey. Listen!
You take your wife
off life support,
and I'll have forgotten
about this in two weeks.
- Gail here, on the other hand--
- Amy.
Whatever.
You're mad at me.
Fine, I get that.
Take it out on me. Not on her.
Oof!
Fine. Your dad can, uh...
have her heart.
Fever. Stomach pain.
Raised liver enzymes.
She's sick.
Worse than that.
She's dead.
My point is,
even if it's not hep C,
it's something.
They turned her down as a donor
because if we put that heart
into someone, they won't survive.
Whatever made her sick
will kill him.
Yeah. So what is it?
Enzymes indicate--
You want us to do
a differential diagnosis
on a dead person?
We're going to cure her.
We're going to cure death?
[Laughs theatrically like a demon]
Doubt it.
Just want to get the infection
out of her heart before
we get the heart out of her.
The fever indicates an infection.
She probably has hep C
and a bad case of the flu.
Let's assume, just for fun,
that the answer is something
that might be helpful.
Fever and belly pain
could be a gall bladder infection.
Like that.
Do an MRI. Stat.
You really don't need to be here.
I assume, uh,
House is a great doctor.
Why would you assume that?
Because, uh,
when you're that big a jerk,
you're either great or unemployed.
No sign of gall bladder infection.
But there was a cyst.
Perfectly round.
Now, hep C wouldn't cause--
The question was never,
is it hep C?
The question was given
that it's not hep C, what is it?
- Adenoma?
- Not solid enough.
Cavernous hemangioma?
Not vascular enough.
What if she was sloppy about
washing her hands after pooping?
Uh...amoeba infection?
If the amebiasis started in her liver,
then spread to her blood,
that would explain all her symptoms.
Except for the crushed skull, but
I'm assuming that's from the car crash.
I'll start her on
paromomycin and chloroquine.
Ten grams each.
That's...20 times
the normal dose.
Right. So we'll destroy
her retinas and damage her hearing.
Whoever wants those parts
is having a very bad day.
Couple hours on the meds,
she'll be feeling great.
Got your labs.
- Do you eat guinea pigs?
- No.
How about hamsters or mice?
Humans?
What are you talking about?
Is something wrong with me?
Absolutely nothing.
Your blood work is perfect.
You've got lots of vitamins,
minerals. All kinds of proteins.
Including a little something
I like to call bovine serum albumin.
Which you get from eating
the animals mentioned.
Or cow.
You don't really worship cows.
So I have to wonder,
what could be more humiliating than
someone calling your girlfriend a cow
and not being metaphorical?
- Nice.
- It's my mom.
Well, either that's
a very old photograph,
or it's your stepmom.
She goes around the house
in a bikini. Or less.
I-I can't stop
thinking about her.
My dad's in Europe.
I'll be watching TV,
she'll give me a massage.
I can't walk for an hour.
- Still. Cows?
- She's my mother!
Step.
Please.
I just need the medicine
for three months until I graduate
and I move out of the house.
Please.
You're not gonna have
any fun at graduation.
Keep up the good work.
Your shirt is ironed.
That means you haven't
told your wife anything.
Let's say you're right.
You're saying I'm right?
No. Let is saying.
Does it occur to you that maybe
there's some deeper guidance
than "keep your mouth shut"?
That maybe a friend might value
concern over glibness? That maybe...
Maybe I'm going through
something that I need to have
an actual conversation about?
[Hosue's beeper goes off]
Does it occur to you that
if you need that kind of a friend,
you may have made some deeper errors.
Chase:
Her heartbeat's irregular.
Looks like global hypokinesis.
Stop the meds.
You're giving up?
Either we're wrong
and her heart is unusable...
or right, but the treatment
we had to give her will
make her heart unusable.
I'm sorry.
You can pull the plug now.
Find me another body.
That fat guy on Ortho service
didn't look so hot.
No!
She's not ready.
You were ready this morning.
She's not done.
She's gotta save that guy.
House:
Alternate theories?
Amebiasis was our best hope.
The fact that her heart rate
went back to normal when
we stopped the meds pretty much--
What's our second best hope?
House, put down the wand.
There's no obstruction.
Maybe we should just biopsy it.
She's a fridge
with the power out.
We start poking around inside,
the vegetable goes bad.
No offense.
I don't see that
we have a lot of choice.
The only way we're
gonna find that infection--
Cameron:
What if it's not an infection?
Toxins can cause similar symptoms.
Especially if whatever it is did liver damage.
Her, uh, toxin screen was clean.
Those things never cover
for any of the really cool toxins.
Run the screen again
for whatever you can think of.
You, keep the other patient alive.
You, check out the school.
And I seem to need
o hire another doctor
to go search her home.
Come on.
If she was taking
any medications,
I'd know about it.
Did your wife dye her hair?
No.
Her mom never went gray.
She didn't either.
Guess this must be yours, then.
Can you think of anything else
she might've lied to you about?
Any drugs she "gave up"
when she married you?
How are you feeling, sir?
Mr. Arrington?
[Monitor starts beeping]
What's going on?
His heart's not pumping
enough blood to his brain.
We're gonna have to
give it some help.
Get the balloon ready.
You use this drawer?
Neuberger:
No, that's for her vitamins.
And sleeping pills.
She never took sleeping pills.
Okay.
You on a diet?
No.
I guess you never really
know someone, do you?
Quite the insight.
She lied to you
about her hair color.
And didn't want you to know
she thought she was fat.
Unless you never lied to her
about anything that huge.
And then you can
probably let those slide.
Diet pills could've
messed her up.
Raised the live enzymes
and caused the bellyache.
But not the fever.
Maybe something else
set off the fever.
Like what?
Before I show you these,
they were in a locked drawer
in her desk.
The vice principal said that
Laura must've confiscated them.
They've had some problems with--
Neither interesting nor helpful.
This at least is interesting.
[Scoffs]
No, it's not.
Sex with teenagers
isn't interesting?
Where did you grow up?
It isn't helpful.
Teenage boys aren't toxins.
What if the cyst isn't a cyst?
Then we have nothing to go on.
I said it's not a cyst.
I didn't say it was nothing.
What if it's a scar?
Foreman:
Fitzhugh-Curtis syndrome?
You're pushing gonorrhea again?
You got anything better?
Test her.
And start her on ceftriaxone.
What are you testing for now?
Just some more infections.
She's positive for gonorrhea.
I think that's the first time
those words have been uttered in joy.
Meds are started.
Her heart should be clear enough
to use in about four or five hours.
I'll go tell the families.
He's in a coma.
Start him on dobutamine.
Already did.
We either do the surgery now
or we find him a new brain too.
House, she's still got
a significant amount of
gonorrhea in her system.
Hopefully tomorrow,
it'll be in his system.
I need two O.R.s
and the transplant team.
What is it?
Amy:
What's going on?
- Is he getting a heart?
- Yeah. Excuse me.
I assume this means
you, uh, you found out
what was wrong with Laura?
She had a amebiasis.
We just found a different way
to get rid of it.
Thank you.
That was kind of you.
I didn't want him
going postal on us.
Soon as his wife's heart's in our hands,
you can tell him about the gonorrhea.
He's gotta be tested.
Preferably before he gets
any sympathy sex.
Paddles.
50 joules.
Charging.
[Heart begins to beat]
Let's take him off bypass.
Mr. Neuberger.
There's something
I need to tell you.
The last, uh...
year or so, uh...
Laura was kind of
distant with me.
I don't know why.
I thought maybe
she was having an affair.
But...not Laura.
And I'm not excusing myself,
but when I was traveling
during Christmas, I had a...
I had a one-night stand.
I got gonorrhea.
- Are you sure--
- Yeah.
I should've said
something to you.
But I didn't want to believe
that I gave it to her.
That's what made her sick,and...
that was why she got
into the accident.
Cecile?
Am I dead?
Hopefully not for a long time.
Why are you here?
Amy called me.
If you do Mom again,
you gotta wear a condom.
You're gonna have gonorrhea
in your system for a while.
"Honky Tonk Women"  by Taj Mahal
# I met a gin-soaked
barroom queen in Memphis #
[Knock on the door]
# She tried to take me
upstairs for a ride #
# She had to heave me
right across her shoulder #
# 'Cause I just can't... #
Could I stay with you
for a few days?
You idiot.
You told her.
She told me.
Things have been
crappy at home lately.
I figured I wasn't
spending enough time there.
I figured...
It turns out, you're right.
It's always about sex.
She's been having an affair.
# It's the honky-tonk women #
Want a beer?
# That gimme, gimme, gimme
the honky-tonk blues  #