What are you doing out here?
I'm lost.
This is a restricted area.
Oh, I didn't know
that. There's no signs.
They're everywhere.
Let's see some ID.
Why?
There's a broken gate back
there, and you're trespassing.
Excuse me, sir, that gate was open
and I was under the opinion
that this was a detour.
Let me see the ID. Take it out.
What kind of uniform is that?
I'll ask the fucking questions.
It's a private outfit, huh?
I tried to get one of those
jobs. I like guarding things.
Really?
Here you go, sir.
I think what must have happened
is I just must have
gotten turned around.
Is it in the high-end
or the low-end range?
Oh, there's no question it's up!
Yes, but 20%?
Foreclosure, foreclosure, foreclosure!
We're talking about over
two-thirds of the market,
and, of course, it's
linked to unemployment.
So, the opportunity for the average
investor with the right know-how...
Is all in the book. In the seminars.
Very little doubt?
Yes, their distress sales makes
them want them off the books.
Oh...
They need to sell them.
They have to, right?
...you name it, we teach them all.
I guesstimate
that I have about 50
pounds of copper wire,
100 pounds of chain-link fence
and two manhole covers.
The nice thick ones.
I'll give 50 cents a pound for the wire,
15 for the fence, and 10 for the covers.
That's below market value.
Market value?
You know the cops came by
asking about manhole covers?
I'd like to counter at a
dollar a pound for the copper,
30 cents a pound for the fence,
and 20 cents per for the covers.
Ah, sell them somewhere else.
I'd feel good at 75, 25, and 15.
I'm not negotiating with you.
I think we're close. I'm done.
I'm willing to take less to
establish a business relationship.
If that's your last best
offer, then I guess I accept.
All right. Drive around
back and unload them.
Excuse me, sir?
I'm looking for a job.
In fact, I've made up my mind
to find a career that I
can learn and grow into.
Who am I? I'm a
hard-worker, I set high goals
and I've been told that I am persistent.
Now, I'm not fooling myself, sir.
Having been raised with
the self-esteem movement
so popular in schools,
I used to expect my
needs to be considered.
But I know that today's work culture
no longer caters to the job loyalty that
could be promised to
earlier generations.
What I believe, sir, is that good things
come to those who work their asses off.
And that people such as yourself,
who reach the top of the
mountain, didn't just fall there.
My motto is if you
wanna win the lottery,
you have to make the
money to buy a ticket.
Did I say that I worked in a garage?
So, what do you say? I could
start tomorrow, or why not tonight?
No.
How about an internship then?
A lot of young people are taking
unpaid positions to
get a foot in the door.
That's something I'd be willing to do.
I'm not hiring a fucking thief.
This thing's gonna blow!
Crap! Gotta move!
Help!
This thing is not budging. Hold on.
I can't move!
Let's go. Let's go!
Let's go!
We're first!
No shit! Get a shot on the other side!
All right, all right.
Get a shot inside the car.
Go around. Get inside the car.
The fuck am I paying you for?
Yeah, it's free.
Get back, Loder. Get back!
I'm back, I'm back, I'm back!
All units. EMS, just past exit 31.
Excuse me.
Will this be on television?
Morning news. If it bleeds, it leads.
What channel?
Whoever pays the most.
What do you get for something like this?
Not nearly enough.
Enough to buy all that gear.
Let me tell you something.
It's a flaming asshole of a job.
Can I ask you, are you currently hiring?
Fuck, no.
Well, thank you for taking the time
to discuss what you do.
You've been very helpful.
Any Compton unit, Code
Three response needed.
211 in progress. 239 Rose Crest.
Hey, we got a 211 on Rose Crest.
Hurry your ass!
Coming through.
There was another drive-by
shooting today downtown...
You're entitled to fear
and adequate compensation.
We'll fight for you.
Potatoes!
Okay, I give up. Potatoes!
Any family would agree.
Bird's Eye turns
vegetables you want to serve
into vegetables they want to eat.
Bird's Eye.
Now, dinner is complete.
Live from the CBS broadcast
center in Los Angeles.
This is CBS2 News at 6:00 a. m.
Coverage you can count on.
Good morning, everyone. Thanks
for joining us. I'm Pat Harvey.
Hope your day's getting
off to a good start.
I'm Kent Shocknek.
An unclaimed Mega Millions ticket
sold at a 7-Eleven in South San Diego
is worth a whopping $266 million.
The question is, is it yours?
We'll have the numbers, coming up.
Evidence has police hunting
for one of their own.
A fast-moving bank robber in
Sylmar didn't move fast enough.
And we'll explain how the FBI...
A landmark court decision,
Lisa, has cyber-music fans
singing the blues.
Ouch!
I may have to budget more for my music.
Closet space!
Twisted metal, a shattered life.
All of it caught on tape last night
at the scene of a fiery one-car
collision out on the 110.
Melinda Flores of Yorba Linda.
She was severely injured, but somehow
managed to escape with her life,
thanks to the bravery of
a couple of CHP officers.
The crash started a fire that then
quickly consumed the entire vehicle.
And as we see in this dramatic video,
CHP officers Mike Tilly and John Wall
risked their lives to
save the single mom.
Flores was then transferred
to St. Joseph's Hospital
in serious but stable condition
after suffering smoke inhalation.
I don't know. I'll give you $500.
This is a custom racing bicycle, sir.
Designed for competitive road cycling.
This bike has a light-weight,
space-age carbon frame
and handlebars positioned
to put the rider
in a more aerodynamic posture.
It also has micro-shifters
and 37 gears,
and weighs under six pounds.
I won the Tour de Mexico on this bike.
$700 is as high as I'll go.
It cost me over $8,000 new.
$700.
$2,500, and that's giving it away.
No bike has got 37 gears.
$2,000.
No.
Could I please speak to your boss?
I'm the owner.
How about $800 in store credit?
What are you after?
A camcorder and a police scanner.
7-X-76 Roger.
David 1099965.
Checking in C.I.C.
8859. One, Lincoln, Adam,
David, Young, John, one.
R.O. not on file.
Any northeast unit. 415 fight,
13932 Tularosa Drive.
Suspect number one, male, black.
Suspect number two,
male, black, juvenile.
No further description.
Code Two, incident 3679. ID 1125.
Hey! Who the hell are you?
Freelance!
What are you doing?
Filming for TV.
No. Back away.
What's happening?
I said turn around and leave.
I'm fairly certain I'm
allowed to film this.
Film what?
I don't know. What's happening?
Walk away, or get
arrested for obstruction.
Yes, Officer.
Hurry up. Get out of here.
Blow, blow, blow. Almost. Almost.
Will you move that cam?
Man, you better back up.
Leave!
Do you think I'm playing with you?
More street units, ambulance to 11.
Just occurred. Western and Third.
Suspect last seen
northbound Western on foot.
Code Three, incident 4259. ID 703.
All right, let's get some blood
pressure. He's pretty shocked.
Breathing is very shallow.
He's got a second chest wound
here. MEDIC 1: Put pressure on it.
We got it. Strap it on the other side.
You got a dressing on it? MEDIC 1: Yeah.
GCS is
1-1-1, guys.
Give me pressure.
90 over 60.
No radial pulse.
We're losing him.
He's bleeding out. Can you bag him?
Let's start bagging him.
Keep on high flow, too.
Yep.
I got no pulse here.
Unresponsive.
Get back. You. Get back.
Get the fuck back now.
Okay.
Shit. All right.
Get back, 100 feet back, now.
You get back, too. 100 feet.
Fucking asshole, you shut it down.
I had a great fucking angle
back there until you crowded in.
Get the fuck home. There's people
trying to do their fucking job.
Fucking asshole.
Yeah. It's Ace Video. Your lead's
gonna be at First and Western.
Yeah, you wanna get
there. It's a shooting.
Yeah, I got some great footage
of a victim being treated.
No, the LAPD hasn't released it
but a manager at a Walgreens says
it's a carjacking and
the victim is the owner.
He's Asian and critical.
Right.
Look, I got a 60-second cut
with the manager and a neighbor.
$500.
Then, make me a deal. $400.
$300. All right, deal.
Are you fucking kidding me?
Get out of here.
Okay, dip into graphics.
I don't think that's going to cover it.
Frank, it's not my call.
Oh, excuse me.
Excuse me. I have video footage.
Uh, down the hall, to the right.
Right here. Okay.
Put the neighbor here, and the
kids with their mother by the door.
You can get it back from
2:16. MALE EDITOR: Yeah.
Then I want to lay in some nat-sound.
Let's loop the neighbor's dog barking.
And then try taking the
crying kid from B-roll
and dropping that in the background.
Got it.
You my fill-in operator?
I don't think so. I'm Lou Bloom.
I have some footage for sale.
A stringer?
What? Who do you work for?
At the moment, I work for myself.
See Frank out there, the way you came.
Uh, what's it timed to?
1:06.
What do you have?
Something I'm fairly certain
you'll be very excited about.
What is it?
It's a shooting. A man was
shot. Several times, in fact.
He's lying on the ground, and
he's bleeding on the ground.
I'd be surprised if
he survived, honestly.
He was shot during a carjacking.
Western and First?
Yes, that's right.
We're getting that from Ace.
I was there. I was much
closer to what happened.
Okay. Okay.
Let's see it.
You can fast forward through this.
Keep going, keep going.
Walk away, or I'll arrest you for...
A minute-and-a-half
in.
There.
Oh, fuck.
I need you to see something.
Yeah? Lou Bloom.
Frank Kruse, our assignment editor.
Play it back.
I got no pulse, here.
That's the lead.
I want to break it up and do
a wrap-around from the scene.
I want a walking stand-up,
teaser at five, repeat on the half
and I want the copy to
start with a warning.
You're going to show this?
With a warning. It's excessive.
We should have packages
like this every day.
People are eating breakfast.
And they'll talk about it at work.
Tie it in with the carjacking
last month in Glendale.
And the other one, the van in
Palms. When was that? In March?
March, yeah.
It's a carjacking crime wave.
That's the banner.
Call the victim's family,
get a quote, mic it.
You know what to do.
Yeah.
How much?
I'm selling this
particular piece for $1,000.
Not even close.
This late, you have nowhere else to go.
And the quality's for shit.
I'll give you $250,
that's the most I'll do.
Now, let's get you paid.
Here you go.
Buy yourself some better
equipment, a directional mic,
and get interviews when you can.
You have a good eye.
Thank you.
I'm just beginning, so praise
from someone such as yourself,
well, you can imagine
that it means quite a lot.
I'll help in any way I can.
And, of course, you can
help me by calling us first.
I want you to contact me
when you have something.
Something like this. That's right.
Bloody.
Well, that's only part
of it. We like crime.
Not all crime.
Carjacking in Compton, for example.
That isn't news, now is it?
We find our viewers are more interested
in urban crime creeping
into the suburbs.
What that means is a victim, or victims,
preferably well-off and white,
injured at the hands of
the poor or a minority.
Just crime.
No. Accidents play.
Cars, busses, trains, planes. Fires.
But bloody.
Well, graphic.
The best and clearest way
that I can phrase it to you, Lou,
to capture the spirit of what we air,
is think of our newscast
as a screaming woman
running down the street
with her throat cut.
I understand.
I'm a very, very quick learner.
You will be seeing me again.
I believe you.
Live from the KWLA broadcast
center in Los Angeles.
This is KWLA 6 News at 6:00 a. m.
Coverage you can count on.
A tragic drug store visit
to help his ailing wife
claimed the life of a loving husband
last night near Hancock Park.
Reporting from the
scene is Ron De La Cruz.
An act of kindness turned
into a savage deadly attack
just outside this market on
Western and First around 2:00 a. m.
when 68-year-old
Richard Cho of Mar Vista
was walking towards his car
with a prescription for his sick wife
when he was confronted right here
by a man with a 9mm handgun
police believe wanted
to take his vehicle.
The vicious tragedy and
senselessness of the brutal shooting
as well as the victim's final moments
were all caught in graphic video
which we are about to show.
Viewer discretion is advised.
Paramedics worked feverishly
to save the life of Richard Cho.
But despite heroic efforts,
the husband and father of three,
was pronounced dead at
Good Samaritan Hospital.
Alarmingly, this is the
third violent carjacking
in the area in recent months.
And residents here are growing concerned
as police are still without any leads.
This is Ron De La Cruz, reporting live.
Hollywood clear.
Rescue. 2249.
Engine 99 for Coldwater. Acknowledge.
4220 South Beverly Glen Boulevard.
Burglar alarm, all
companies return course.
Any Hollywood unit, Code 37.
Last seen northbound La Brea at Oakwood.
Blue Prius. No suspect description.
Code Two, incident 2475. RD 693.
Hey. I'm sorry I'm late.
Are you Richard?
Uh, Rick.
I'm Louis Bloom. Hey, Lou.
Louis. Sit down.
The situation is that
I lost an employee,
and I'm interviewing for a replacement.
Okay. The ad didn't
say what the job was.
It's a fine opportunity
for some lucky someone.
Okay.
I'd like to know about
your prior employment
and hear, in your own words,
what you learned from each position.
My old jobs?
I did landscaping for a couple months.
Like, mow, blow, and go.
Uh...
I learned that I had
hay fever, so I quit.
Other jobs?
I don't know.
Like, a week here, a week there.
Why hire you?
Sell yourself.
Okay. Go.
Okay.
I'm Rick. Of course.
Uh...
I took three buses to get here.
I finished high school. I need a job.
I'll do pretty much anything.
That's me. Hire Rick.
So... Hmm.
What's your address, Richard?
I don't have one.
Not a permanent one right now.
You're homeless.
I was for a while.
You trick.
Work the street? No.
Wasn't a question.
I'm straight.
Plenty of straight guys trick.
Do you have a driver's license?
Yeah.
Do you know Los Angeles?
Yeah. I grew up all around here.
Can you start tonight?
Doing what?
I run a successful TV news business.
We film breaking stories.
Maybe you saw my item this morning
of a fatal carjacking.
No. I don't have a TV,
but that sounds cool.
Do you have a cellphone?
Yeah.
Does it have GPS?
Yes, it does.
Congratulations. You're hired.
Okay.
Your job will be to listen
to the emergency radio,
learn police codes, help
navigate, and watch the car.
Okay.
And what does it pay?
It's an internship.
Man, I, uh...
I can't do that. I need money.
I'm giving you a chance
to explore career options
and get insight into my organization.
It's not at all unusual for me
to make full-time job
offers to my interns.
No, I know.
I got to get paid,
like, something at least, you know.
I'll give you $30 cash per night.
Okay. Okay.
Thank you. Thanks.
4-A-27 at Main
and Washington,
requesting Code Ten for one.
Calling back stand-by.
4-A-27, go ahead.
4-A-27 is
requesting a Code Ten
to clear the frequency
for warrant information.
4-A-1, prowler complaint,
Sixth and Rampart.
Female Hispanic wearing a blue shirt.
Code 2, incident 2156, RD 235.
Code Two is "Respond immediately,
no lights and sirens. "
And Code Three is?
With the lights and sirens on.
Very good.
2-A-1 responding. Sixth
and Rampart, Code Two.
So, should we go?
No. We want victims
and not the kind that
live on Sixth and Rampart.
Any Van Nuys unit, 415 man.
7227 Van Nuys Boulevard
at the Big King Market.
Inside the location, the
suspect is a male Hispanic
wearing an orange construction
vest and blue jeans.
In custody with security guards.
I'm going to get some
water. You want anything?
No, thank you.
Rampart units,
domestic violence,
restraining order violation.
Suspect last seen on foot on
Fifth Street towards Virgil.
Structure fire. Station 58. Engine 58.
Task force 58, task force 43.
Engine 43. Battalion 10.
1642 Rincon Avenue...
Structure fire!
Engine 58 on scene. 1642 Rincon Avenue.
Seat belt. Seat belt. Seat belt.
Where are we going?
We're taking the next right coming up.
Slow down, man.
That's too fast!
Talk to me, Richard.
What next?
Next left, coming up.
Fuck!
I need more warning next time.
Where are we going?
Talk to me! What's next?
Okay. Keeping on this five...
No, six blocks. Then a right.
On what?
I made a mistake!
It's a right five blocks back.
It's just five blocks.
Did they bring him out?
Ambulance left two minutes ago.
You're a lifetime too late.
Nice camera!
On to the next.
I bet I wasted five dollars
of gas just getting here
or don't you think
that's a lot of money?
I'm sorry.
I couldn't see the screen,
you were driving so fast.
Okay, first of all, Richard,
don't answer me by telling me a problem.
I have enough of those already.
Bring me a solution, and then
we can make a decision together.
Okay. Maybe if you didn't rush me.
Don't rush you. Okay.
I can use that.
See, Rick, they've done studies
and they found that in any
system that relies on cooperation
from a school of fish,
say, or even a professional
hockey team, for example,
these experts have
identified communication
as the number one single key to success.
You know what "fear" stands for?
What?
"False Evidence Appearing Real. "
You're going really fucking fast, dude.
Get out of your head, Rick.
It's a bad neighborhood.
Now, when you get a chance,
I'd like to know where we're going.
Uh, left on Third. Six blocks.
Find a more appropriate
place to park the car,
and don't get blocked in.
Are you the one that made the call?
No, no. I think...
I was trying to go to
sleep, and I heard a sound.
It scared me. That's why I called.
Sir, what's going on?
Who the fuck are you?
TV news. What happened?
It was a shooting.
I told the cops that he
was waving a gun last week,
but they didn't fucking care.
Can you try one more
time without swearing?
I'm not doing it again.
But this is for TV.
Yeah? I don't have a TV.
It's over.
Shot the place to shit.
All right, guys, pack
it up. Let's move it out.
...running out of there as fast as
we could. Through that window there.
Great shot.
Oh, that's fantastic.
Oh, that's a great piece of tape.
You didn't get an
interview with the couple?
I have footage of them.
I have an interview with a neighbor.
She curses, but you can cut that out.
How did you get inside the house?
The door was open.
They allowed you?
I heard somebody yell to come in,
and when nobody was inside, I left.
And the only shot of the
couple is through a window?
The police were shutting it down.
I don't like it. Like what?
The footage looks like he broke in.
There's no close-up of the homeowners
and he's giving us their name
off a piece of private correspondence.
Excuse me, that's junk mail.
Well, I have a problem with that.
We'll knock out a killer package.
This is my job. No!
Your job is writing
the tweet of the day.
And getting Deb to turn sideways
during the weather forecast.
We're running it.
I like how you handled Frank.
You didn't soften the
truth or dilute it.
I think being clear with your
objectives is more important
than trying to present your ideas
in a non-confrontational manner.
Do you have experience in an office?
Myself? Not presently, no.
Where did you get all that?
I study a lot online.
Yeah? Like what?
All sorts of things, actually.
I'm on my computer all day.
I haven't had what you'd call
much of a formal education,
but you can find most anything
if you look hard enough.
Last year, I took an online
business course, for example.
And I learned that you
have to have a business plan
before starting a business.
And that why you pursue something
is equally as important
as what you pursue.
The site advised you
to answer the following question
before you decide where
to focus your abilities.
The question was
"What do I love to do?"
The site suggested making a list
of your strengths and weaknesses.
What am I good at?
What am I not good at?
Maybe I want to strengthen
and develop knowledge
about the things I'm already good at.
Maybe I want to
strengthen my weaknesses.
I recently remade my list.
And I'm thinking
that television news
might just be something I love
as well as something
I happen to be good at.
On TV, it looks so real.
Yes. It does.
Well, I have a show to do.
Your check is at the desk.
Outstanding work, Lou.
Really, just great.
Thanks, Nina. That means an awful lot.
Okay.
It's every parent's nightmare.
Imagine singing a lullaby to your
infant and tucking them into bed
and then having to shield them
as a barrage of high-caliber bullets
literally blast into your home.
For the Cahills of Echo Park,
that fear became a terrifying reality
when an adjacent house
became the setting for a scene
right out of the Wild West.
Dude!
Paying too much at the pump?
Well, sign up for our super saver card
and you'll be saving buckets
of duckets on every purchase.
Takes minutes to sign up
and you'll start saving right away.
You'll also be eligible
for some sweet giveaways.
So sign up now and start saving!
Rick, I'm very pleased
with how you progressed.
You're doing a great job.
However, you just
spilled gasoline on my car
which will eat the paint.
I need you tighten up a bit on this.
Because if you fill it like that again,
I will terminate you immediately,
I promise you.
"Bed, Bath & Beyond. "
Oh, that's a good store.
Making peace with what you don't have,
that's what it's all about.
Living with what you ain't got, right?
Don't you think?
Traffic units,
ambulance traffic, Benedict Canyon.
Overturned vehicle with injuries.
Crash with injuries. Good neighborhood.
TV news. What happened?
I think it was a head-on collision,
and there's a guy who's dead over there.
There's a woman... Did
you see what happened?
Am I supposed to help? I
didn't see, I came after.
Can you tell me exactly what happened?
Will you get the camera out of my face?
Get it out!
I'm trying to talk to 911!
No, it's at... The guy is down.
Make some room! We'll block it off.
Not getting through here.
Son of a bitch.
Let's go.
Fuck this.
Here you go.
Ben Waterman wears the
same gold tie on Fridays.
We're leading with it.
That's your third start this week.
I'm focusing on framing.
A proper frame not only
draws the eye into a picture
but keeps it there longer,
dissolving the barrier
between the subject and
the outside of the frame.
Is that blood on your shirt?
I don't think so.
I recently heard of a Mexican restaurant
called Cabanita. Have you heard of it?
It's also on your sleeve.
I didn't see that.
What I'm asking is,
do you like Mexican food, Nina?
Yes.
Stand by, people. Here we go.
Cabanita has been called
"an authentic taste of Mexico City. "
Do you wanna go with me?
I think we could have fun together.
Thanks, but I'm busy.
Saturday is your night off, isn't it?
I have a rule, Lou.
I don't date people I work with.
And I'm twice your age.
I like older women.
Besides, I don't work with you.
You're someone I sell to.
And I don't wanna fuck that up.
What if by saying no, you fuck it up?
All right, 10 seconds to go and back on.
Is that what you're saying?
I didn't say that.
Eight, seven, six, five...
Well, I don't know what to say.
...three, two, one.
Good morning. Thank you for
joining us. I'm Lisa Mays.
And I'm Ben Waterman.
First up on This Morning on KWLA News,
a horrible car crash
over in Benedict Canyon.
It's claimed the life now of one man.
Severely injured a young woman.
Hey, Lou!
Hey, man. Joe Loder, Mayhem.
Great get tonight.
They were closing it down
by the time we showed up.
Were you waiting for me out here?
No, I was driving by and I saw your car.
You're not dropping your shit
off, are you? Nobody does that.
You need an air card if
you want to be in the game.
Import the video to your laptop.
Cut the video.
Upload to your FTP site
and notify stations you
got something for sale.
Boom, boom, boom!
Otherwise, it's a nice ride.
Listen, man, you got a good run going
but there's valleys out there.
Take it from me. I've been
nightcrawling for 14 years.
You heard I'm adding a second van?
No. I didn't hear that.
Gonna be a game changer.
Cut my on-scene time in half.
I'm setting up a
dedicated dispatch, too.
No more listening and
driving. That's for suckers.
You like the Canon 305s?
Never used one.
Six thou a piece.
2.4 megapixels. Night vision. 18:1 zoom.
I got one of those puppies
with your name on it.
I have a camera.
I want you running my second van.
Two crews. Half the area to cover.
Now, I know what you're thinking.
Half the money, right?
You should be thinking, twice the sales.
Because we're going to be the first
at every scene.
Why compete when we can work together?
You can share my press cards.
Puppy dog off my police connections.
This is the big move, the next level.
We can corner this whole thing.
I'm talking about putting some
heavy digits in our pocket, brah.
Thank you for offering me the position
but working for myself is more in line
with my skills and career goals.
Take a few days to think about it.
No.
You'll need to hire someone else,
and I don't want to hold up the process.
You want to be on the
inside of this, man
because I'm going to be
tag-teaming every call.
You keep talking like it's something
that I may be interested
in, but I'm not.
You don't even understand the offer.
If you did, you'd be
fucking sucking my dick!
You'd be asking me questions.
What does this mean?
What does that mean?
I feel like grabbing you
by your ears right now
and screaming in your face,
"I'm not fucking interested. "
Instead, I'm going to drive
home and do some accounting.
Fuck you!
Twerp.
I didn't wake up until 5:00.
My body is so off, I feel
like it's time for breakfast.
I bet you're beautiful
any time of the day.
In fact, I'd say
you're much prettier than Lisa Mays.
I like the dark makeup on your eyes.
I also like the way you smell.
So, where you from, Lou?
The north end of the Valley.
Some of the calls sometimes
take me over there,
but nobody I know still lives out there.
You're from Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.
How did you know that?
It's online.
Everything about you is online.
Not everything, but definitely a lot.
I've watched all the videos
from when you were a reporter.
I'm sure you look at those, of course.
No. God, no.
Not without a drink in my hand.
I watch my work all the time.
Yeah? Do you want to become a reporter?
No.
Most of you guys want air time.
Not me.
I want to be the guy that owns
the station that owns the camera.
The business is going well,
but in order to grow to the next level,
I need to stay one step
ahead of my competition
and take risks.
I also need financial support
to implement expansion.
Would you like another margarita?
One is enough.
Thanks for coming out to talk.
The place I'm in now
is that I want a relationship
with someone I can team up with
and share, like we share, the
same job and hours and whatnot.
I could go down a laundry
list, but you get the idea.
Yes.
Well, I hope you find someone.
Here's the thing about that, Nina.
I'm quite certain I already have.
Okay.
Let me put this politely.
I only came out to dinner with you, Lou,
purely as a professional courtesy.
Thank you.
I don't think it's any secret
that I've single-handedly raised
the unit price of your ratings book.
Our ratings book price? Whoa!
I'm a very fast learner.
We had a conversation where
I specifically mentioned that.
Do you remember that?
Well, do you?
Yes.
I recently learned, for instance,
that most Americans watch
local news to stay informed.
I also learned that
the average half-hour of
Los Angeles television news
packs all of its local
government coverage
including law enforcement,
budget, transportation,
education and immigration
into 22 seconds.
Local crime stories, however,
not only usually led the news
but filled 14 times the broadcast,
averaging five minutes
and seven seconds.
KWLA relies heavily on such stories.
With Los Angeles crime rates going down,
I think that makes items like
mine particularly valuable.
Like rare animals.
I can only imagine that
your needs will increase
during next month's
rating sweeps period.
Ooh!
Yeah.
Well, we certainly
appreciate what you do.
There's certain good
things about being alone.
You have time to do
the things you wanna do,
like study and plan,
but you can't have dinners like this
or be physical with a person.
I mean, outside of flirtation-ship.
Where are you going with this?
I want that.
With you.
Like you want to keep your
job and your health insurance.
Look, just for starters,
I don't need you to keep my fucking job.
You're the news director
on the vampire shift
of the lowest-rated
station in Los Angeles.
We have what could be considered
an almost-exclusive relationship.
There are many other places I could go.
I have to think that you're
invested in this transaction.
Here you are.
Wow.
Enjoy. Thank you.
Where did you get the balls to
even suggest something like this?
We're still talking.
No. There's nothing more to say.
You can leave.
Okay, look.
You've done well. Okay?
And we pay you well,
very well. We always have.
If you like, I could get
you an exclusive retainer.
That would be on top
of your segment fees.
I could maybe even get
you a job at the station
starting as a production assistant.
So that you could learn the
business from the inside.
That's where you said
your interests lie.
Mmm-hmm.
You're not listening, Nina.
I happen to know that you
haven't stayed at one station
for longer than two years at a time,
and you're coming up on two years soon.
I can imagine
that your contract is
for that length of time.
And that next month's ratings
directly affect that.
So, you're threatening
that if I don't...
I'm negotiating.
You're threatening
to stop selling to me.
That's your choice.
The true price of any item
is what somebody's
willing to pay for it.
You want something.
And I want you.
To fuck you.
And as a friend.
Jesus Christ, friends
don't pressure friends
to fucking sleep with them.
Actually, that's not true, Nina.
Because as I'm sure you know,
a friend is a gift you give yourself.
Okay, a left on Roth,
and then six blocks to the ramp.
You're putting me on the 5?
Yeah, the 2 to the 5
to the 110 to the 10.
Did you read my traffic memo yesterday?
Did I read it?
Yeah, I read it.
What did it say?
About the 5?
Okay. I looked at it. What?
Well, for one thing, it included that
the 5 has floating construction
in the fast lane for
the next three weeks.
So, given that, I expect you to put me
on the 2 to the 101
to the 110 to the 10.
That's half of one, six of the other.
It's half dozen of
one, six of the other.
What I'd like you to do is admit that
you didn't read what you said you did.
You know I'm a reasonable person,
but nobody likes to be lied to!
Okay! When am I going to get my raise?
That's reasonable, right?
You keep talking about
this performance review.
When is it gonna happen?
I've been out here two months already,
busting my ass every night.
I'm tired of your
promises for more pay, man.
I'm sleeping in a garage.
Rick, trying to leverage your salary
in this economic environment
is near impossible.
Most firms have set starting wages.
Ideally, you could
leverage with other offers,
but that's just not the case
in your situation right now.
Test 498.
Engine 91. North division. Battalion 12.
Heavy rescue. 56.
Air ops respond. Reported plane down.
Whiteman Field, south of Foothill.
Reroute us to that.
We're 22 minutes from Foothill,
and only five from a hit and run.
They're rolling heavy
rescue and an air ambulance.
Get me there, please.
It's good right there.
Stay on that spot.
Not getting through here.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. It's
all over here, buddy.
Turn it around, let's go.
You're late.
Hey, brah!
Five fatals. Come screaming
out of the fucking sky.
All lit up with the brush on fire.
Mine. Exclusive. I'm banging!
And my other van is in
Carson, getting the jumper.
You know...
I was trying to hook you up, man.
I was trying to teach you something.
Welcome to the future, brah.
A car crash.
Well, none of this is
gonna knock anybody out.
I can't use any of this in my rundown.
Is this it?
No, I have a stabbing in Corona.
Where's the plane crash at Foothill?
I don't mind saying that I'm
trying to bring you stories
that happen here on the ground.
Two has it. It'll be their lead.
Well, I hope that works well for them.
Now, let me show you
the stabbing in Corona.
I don't give a goddamn
about fucking Corona!
You know how important this week is.
This shit is fucking death to me!
I understand your frustration.
I was just trying not
to be too hard on myself.
I sold you upstairs as some
kind of fucking sweeps savior.
And I'm leading with a goddamn stabbing.
In Corona!
So, you want that, then?
I want you to get in the goddamn game!
I want something people
can't turn away from.
I want what you fucking promised me!
Good morning, everyone.
Thanks for joining us. I'm Pat Harvey.
Hope your day's getting off to
a good start. I'm Kent Shocknek.
We begin with a tragedy last night
in the foothills of Santa Susana Pass
where a private plane
crashed with no survivors.
CBS2 has obtained this exclusive video.
We want to remind you now
that what you're about
to see is graphic,
and viewer discretion is advised.
Since when did Coldwater
become faster than Laurel?
Huh? What was the thinking there?
I didn't ask that to hear myself speak.
Because, you know, Coldwater
only has six lights.
Laurel has places to pass.
I can't get around this
person until Ventura.
It's the same argument,
man. I said this route.
If you wanted to take Laurel,
you should have said something.
I thought that you
worked in other factors.
If I didn't think that
you could do better,
I wouldn't ride you so
hard about the routes.
I think you know that, Rick.
I think it may just be possible
that I have a higher opinion of
you than you have of yourself.
What the fuck?
God damn it!
Seriously?
To get to a van crash on Moorpark?
Who cares? What's the rush?
Why aren't we at the rape at
Griffith Park like everybody else?
Oh, fuck! Oh, fuck me.
Oh, God! That's the fucking Mayhem van.
Joe Loder and the other dude.
What's his name? Fucking Marcus.
Park the car and get your camera.
Now, let's get one guy
inside. Hold the seats back.
You can't get that in right there?
No, there's no room.
Here we go.
What the hell happened?
According to witnesses, they were
driving at a high rate of speed,
probably toward Griffith Park,
when, apparently, they ran
head-on into this light pole.
No other car. Single vehicle.
How did they just run into a pole?
Get that backboard right up against him.
Easy.
Hey, don't film that,
man. He's one of us.
Not anymore, Rick.
We're professionals.
He's a sale.
Got facial trauma. Got
lacerations all the way down...
Yeah, I'm calling it in.
Minimize that movement.
Get him back in the ambulance
and put some oxygen on him.
Drop him down. Keep pressure on him.
Back that unit off.
Yeah, let's get some
four-by-fours on there.
Bring the gurney all the way up.
Come on, let's go.
Stay with me.
I got him, I got him.
Make sure you size him
right. MAN 3: All right.
Man, we are way the hell out here.
Any Mission unit.
Residential 211 in progress.
37 Bonhill Road.
Receiving 211 siren activation.
Armed response on a home invasion.
We're five blocks away. Pull a U-turn.
At the end of the street. Coming up.
4808. Here!
We beat the police.
What do you want me to do?
You know what to do, Rick!
3-X-21.
Go ahead.
3-X-21,
confirm address
on the 211 at Bonhill Road.
What is going on?
We're leaving. What?
What's in there? What's going on?
What happened in there?
You should have walked
in and looked, Rick,
if you're that curious.
That's what I'm paying you to do.
You need to show initiative.
There is no better way
to achieve job security
than by making yourself
an indispensable employee.
I heard gunshots!
All the more reason you
might have helped me.
You might have learned a new
skill that made you more useful
and put us on a track toward growth!
Stay in the car.
Why? Because I said so.
We have a hit-and-run
in Beverly Hills,
a car versus pedestrian
incident and a robbery.
Do we have footage of the crash?
Surveillance footage.
I've been trying to reach
you for the last hour.
In the future, when
you don't have anything,
man up and don't dodge my fucking calls.
I do have something.
What?
Home invasion, triple
murder in Granada Hills.
That's just breaking now.
We got there before the police.
You have it?
I'm not going to list the
many benefits of this piece.
I think it's probably best if
you just watch it for yourself.
I could have had
someone out there by now.
Why didn't you call it in?
To increase your need, and
improve my bargaining position.
Frank, Jenny! Bay 2, now!
Get Linda in here.
Home invasion in Granada.
He got there before the cops.
We have 10 minutes to airtime.
How much of this can we show?
You mean, legally?
No, morally. Of course, legally.
Have they been identified?
It just happened, so
you have to assume no,
and that's just one of the issues.
We can't broadcast their identities
without notifying the next of kin.
We're not identifying them.
You are by proxy, by
showing their faces.
We pixelate the faces.
Where did you get this?
Stringer.
Hi, Linda. I'm Lou.
Um, Jesus. Is there a
dead baby inside of there?
No. The crib was empty.
Oh, for Christ's sake.
Are we breaking the law by showing this?
Block the faces, don't
give out the exact address.
Do that, I guess. I don't know.
I wouldn't think so, no.
Journalistically and ethically?
This isn't Hartford.
We are beyond all broadcast standards.
Have you seen the overnights?
I'll risk the fine.
What did you pay for this?
The price hasn't been negotiated yet.
Give us a minute.
Thanks.
How much? $100,000.
How much? $50,000.
I need a number. Nine
minutes. I need a number.
I just gave you two.
$3,000.
I got $3,000 for the
food truck stabbings.
There were more dead.
Those were poor Mexican
people in a roach coach.
Two of them were illegals.
These are three wealthy white people,
shot and killed in their mansion.
Including a suburban housewife
shotgunned in her bed.
I know you, Nina.
I know your interest and
excitement in this product
is greater than the
amount you're offering.
$5,000. $30,000.
$7,000. $25,000.
$8,000. $15,000.
$9,000. $15,000.
$10,000. $15,000.
Give me a serious number.
$15,000.
Can't do it. Never happen.
There's a matter of precedent.
Ten is my last best offer.
Okay.
Really?
Where are you going?
Seven has approached me
at least several times.
The ND there gave me his number.
They'll make me a better
offer. It's a five-minute drive.
Hold on!
Twelve.
Fifteen.
I can't spend a month's
budget on a single story.
What if the story's not over?
The people who did this escaped.
They're still out there, walking
around with the rest of us.
If I had a family and I lived in
a home, that might make me nervous.
I'd want updates on what was going on.
With this footage, people would
turn to your channel for the story.
I like you, Nina.
And I look forward to our time together.
But you have to understand.
$15,000 isn't all that I want.
From here on, starting now,
I want my work to be credited
by the anchors and on a burn.
The name of my company is
Video Production News, a
professional news-gathering service.
That's how it should be read
and that's how it should be said.
I also want to go to the
next rung, and meet your team.
And the station manager and
the director and the anchors.
And start developing my
own personal relationships.
I'd like to start
meeting them this morning.
You'll take me around, you'll
introduce me as the owner and President
of Video Production News
and remind them of some
of my many other stories.
I'm not done.
I also want to stop our
discussion over prices.
This will save time.
When I say that a particular number
is my lowest price,
that's my lowest price.
And you can be assured that I arrived
at whatever that number
is very carefully.
Now, when I say that
I want these things,
I mean that I want them.
And I don't want to have to ask again.
And the last thing that I want, Nina,
is for you to do the
things that I ask you to do
when we're alone together
in your apartment.
Not like the last time!
So...
I'll tell you what.
I have the van crash
on Moorpark tonight.
It was a couple of stringers, actually.
That could lead by itself
on an average night.
I'd be willing to
throw that in for free.
So what do you say, do we have a deal?
Lisa Mays, Ben Waterman, Lou Bloom.
Hi. Hello. How are you, Lisa?
You remember Lou from
the Benedict Canyon crash.
Oh, yeah. Amazing stuff.
That was my company,
Video Production News.
I would just like to say
that I think that what the two
of you do is incredibly valuable.
Thank you. That's nice of you to say.
We appreciate it.
I don't know how long
this tape runs, we might dump out.
Twenty seconds to back. Ben
and Lisa, 20 seconds to back.
Set up a sting dig,
Camera Two on a two-shot.
Where's the banner?
Did we decide on one?
Horror House.
What did we talk about?
Can you build that? Put it on CG-one.
Back in 10 seconds.
Nine, eight, seven, six,
five, four, three,
two, one. Sting it.
Mics. Dissolve. Cue.
Hello, everybody. This is
KWLA with breaking news.
Over the last half-hour or so,
we've now received word of an
apparent home invasion triple homicide
in the Granada Hills area
of the San Fernando Valley.
Now, at present, the
number of those dead...
Preset Camera Two.
...have not been
confirmed yet by the police
but KWLA has obtained exclusive footage
from inside the crime scene
in which at least three
bodies can be observed.
Now, we're going to show
you segments of that footage
throughout the rest of this broadcast,
but also throughout the day.
Ben, Lisa, I have a tape.
When you're ready, throw to it.
I'll follow you.
Again, we're about to show
you exclusive KWLA video
from inside the actual crime scene.
It's graphic. Repeat it.
And before broadcasting this video,
we want to warn our viewers that
these are extremely graphic images.
And I'm hearing from our control
room that we have that video,
and we're going to show it now.
This is footage that we have
obtained exclusively by KWLA
from Video Production News.
This is a professional
news-gathering service.
This is what appears to be a shotgun,
something you might
use for home defense.
You can see the pistol grips
on the front and the back there.
Quite possibly the murder weapon.
And now, Lisa, as we move
inside, this is a beautiful home.
A beautiful home in a
very safe neighborhood.
Or, what most people think
is a safe neighborhood.
It appears that that is the first body.
A young woman, I'm
guessing, from this angle.
A young woman on a sofa, there.
All of the faces, though,
have been blurred out.
They've escaped. They're on the loose.
That is the first of what we understand
are three bodies in the
home in Granada Hills.
And this was committed
by a suspect, or suspects
who are still out there.
They're believed to have escaped.
And if you think about that, that
is a very frightening thought.
Repeat that.
Yes, scary, and very concerning,
particularly given what
we're looking at here.
The savagery of what
these pictures show.
And now, look, there on the floor.
Lisa, what is that? A
bloodied article of clothing?
It looks like a silk shirt.
Maybe a woman's silk blouse.
It's just so sad.
Stand by to dissolve, Two.
And, obviously, there
is the second body.
They've escaped. Repeat it.
- The person or people
who committed all of this
brutal home invasion robbery,
they're presently unidentified
and at large, still on the streets.
Hit it again. Harder.
This has got to be a huge worry
not only to the residents
in this neighborhood,
the Granada Hills area as well.
All of Los Angeles,
if you think about it.
Yeah, the entire Southland,
really. Tonight, absolutely.
An apparent family
attacked, savagely killed.
We believe this is their own home.
In what is one of the quieter,
I think a frankly more upscale
and affluent neighborhoods
in the whole Valley.
In all of Los Angeles.
And now, as we're
moving, this is a nursery.
And you hope to God... Build it.
...that there's not a baby in that crib.
Yeah, you're just praying
that that crib is empty.
Because this is
definitely a child's room.
And, now, as we look, thank
goodness. Absolutely great.
In fact, our understanding right now
is that there was no
baby found in the house.
Or any baby that was seen at all
by the people who filmed this for us.
Thank goodness.
That's Video News,
this is a professional
news-gathering service that we use.
Apparently, what we're
hearing from their photographer
is that they arrived even
before the police did.
And then entered this home to help,
or at least offer
some sort of assistance
and then came upon what
you're looking at here.
They came upon three bodies.
And that, right there is
the third body on the floor.
This is a man, gray hair. What would
you think, Lisa? Maybe 40s, 50s?
Yeah, 50s. Maybe even 60s.
"Vicious attack. "
We've been looking at
all this graphic footage
and just the viciousness,
the severity of violence.
Master control, we're
going to come to a break.
We're going to commercial, then
cutting to Joel and a police statement.
I'm getting word right now that police
are getting ready to issue a statement
from the scene and Joel
Beatty is there for that.
Right now, we're going
to take a quick break.
Ready to break in five, four...
Sneak in your music.
Three, two, one.
Fade to black. Roll your break.
That's a 10-share.
I want theme music on the return,
the cut we used for the Simi rail crash.
Audio, cut 32, please.
Cut 32 when we come back.
Hello?
Rolling with your banner.
Thank you.
Actually, he'd like to meet you.
Come back, One, and key on Ben.
Hey, heads up, you guys.
The police spokesman
is making an announcement
in 60 seconds. I gotta go.
Nina, we are getting a ton of heat
from the police out
here about that video.
Tell them to call the station.
Fifteen seconds.
They want to talk to the
person who shot it. I shot it.
Joel, it's Video Production News.
Tell them to call me.
Lou, they can't hear you.
Coming back in five,
four, three, two, one.
Fade up.
We have more information coming
in from the Granada Hills area
and the scene of an
apparent home invasion
that has left a husband and wife
and their housekeeper...
What we know at the moment is that
at some time around 5:00 this morning,
gunmen broke into this upscale...
Residents are disturbed and concerned
by the brutal triple murder...
The way we got it, though,
is a video production crew
that we work with from time to time.
They, apparently, arrived on the scene
in Granada Hills before
the police got there.
Before anybody.
The photographer who took those pictures
told us earlier that he
walked up to the door,
he saw what we all saw in his videotape.
And then he started to look
inside, so that he could help
or render assistance to someone.
That's when he walked into the house
and started shooting the video.
He found the three
deceased in the house.
The two females and the one...
Hello. Hi.
I'm Detective Frontieri. This is
my partner, Detective Lieberman.
Are you Louis Bloom?
Yes, I'm Lou.
You live here? Yes, that's right.
May we come inside?
Why? Why not?
You want to? Yes.
I don't care.
Wonderful.
You were in Granada Hills last night.
Yes, that's right.
You shot the video in the house?
Yes, ma'am, I did. That's right.
You went inside the house? You
filmed all through the house?
You even filmed the bodies.
All before the police came.
That door was open, ma'am.
Detective.
The door was open and what I did was
I went in to see if I could help,
because the alarm was ringing.
An active crime scene.
I didn't know it was a crime scene.
You knew what it was.
I know that an alarm means
someone is in trouble.
And you sold it to be shown on TV.
We're a professional
news-gathering service.
What did you see when you arrived?
Uh, two men leaving in a vehicle.
You saw two men?
They were just shapes,
really. I was afraid, so I hid.
And then I saw the shapes of two men
moving inside the
vehicle, if that helps.
Describe the men.
It was dark.
And then they drove away.
Black? White? Tall? I couldn't see.
What were they driving?
An SUV.
Dark-colored.
Rims? Tinted windows?
Maybe. Not that I saw.
Do you have any film
on the men or the car?
No, I don't. I only started
filming when I was inside.
Mmm-hmm.
I'd like a copy of that footage.
Do I have to give it to you?
Is there any reason why you wouldn't?
No, no, I made you a copy.
I expected someone to come.
What's up, man?
I'm tired. Aren't you tired?
Why are we starting so early?
One of the people in the
house last night was alive.
I cut that part out.
I also cut out the men
leaving in their car.
I have a name and an address.
We're gonna drive there.
We're gonna find the
person that drove that car.
So you know who killed those people?
One of them, quite possibly, yes.
You gotta call the cops.
And we will, at the right time.
I'm offering you a real
opportunity here, Rick.
To do what?
I don't usually share my
business plan with you.
But a moment has arrived
that could allow the company
to make enough money to
expand to the next level.
We could call this
the critical moment.
I'm inviting you, Rick,
to be a part of the team
that pounces on this opportunity.
You've been asking a lot
about your performance review.
Yeah.
Well.
For starters,
I've been seeing a great improvement
in your overall focus
and order-following.
Given complex problems, you're
developing a real ability
to find clear and simple solutions.
I'm also aware of your
increased enthusiasm.
It's great to see your eyes light up
when you're working on a new idea.
I hope you'll be inspiring us
with your innovative
thinking for years to come.
Thank you, man. I'm trying. You know?
Which is why I'm promoting you
to Executive Vice
President of Video News.
What am I now?
You're an assistant.
That's... Big.
Does it come with a raise?
Absolutely.
How much?
Pick a number. You pick a number.
A...
$75 a night?
Agreed.
What about more? You know?
Not now.
We closed the deal.
I could have gotten more, couldn't I?
Absolutely.
All right. It's coming up on the left.
Halfway down the
block. 1701 North Burns.
Is that the car? That's the car.
Oh, shit.
Do you think there's a reward?
There is a reward.
How much? $50,000.
Do I get any of that?
I just gave you a raise.
That's salary. I mean, a bonus.
Bonuses come at the end of the year.
So, we're gonna call it in?
We're gonna wait. For what?
First, we want to see
if he's actually inside.
And then, we want to find a more
interesting place to film the arrest.
Like where?
Anywhere we want.
What we're going to
do, is we're gonna wait
and then we're gonna follow him.
Then, when he reaches
what would be considered
a better or more populated neighborhood,
then we'll report his
location to the police.
He's a violent, wanted criminal.
I can't believe
that he's just going
to peacefully surrender.
Okay. I want more money.
A lot more.
What makes a job desirable, Rick,
isn't just the dollar
amount attached to it.
You're at the ground floor
of a growing business.
Your reward is a career.
Fuck that.
You're talking about some
seriously messed-up shit.
You're expecting me
to just go along with it. I want more.
I can't make people do things, Rick.
You have a choice if you wanna do this.
And I have a choice if you don't.
Are you threatening to fire me?
Hey, I... I got something, too.
How about not calling in criminals,
waiting for them to start
some shit so you can film it?
That's against the fucking law.
Yeah, cops would be majorly
interested in that, no doubt.
Okay? So, I... I want more money.
We can re-open negotiations, Rick.
But, remember,
when it comes to your work reputation,
you can't un-ring the bell.
I want half of whatever we make tonight.
How did you arrive at that number?
There's two of us out here.
So, 50-50.
I'll counter at $10,000.
You don't set the numbers on this.
I want half. I want half.
If you're saying I can't negotiate,
then I guess I'm...
I'm just gonna have to give it to you.
Well, all right, then.
Oh...
Now I can feel good about it, at least.
Now, I'll go the extra mile.
That's what you never understood, man.
It's been the problem the whole time.
You gotta bring people
in, Lou. Seriously.
You gotta talk to them like
they're fucking human beings.
I'm saying this for you, dude.
For the future, to help you.
Because you got a seriously
weird-ass way of looking at shit.
You know you do!
You know what your trouble is, man?
You don't fucking understand people.
Okay?
Mmm-hmm.
I'll take the first watch.
Okay.
Rise and shine.
He's leaving.
Is that him?
That's one of them.
You're too fucking close, man.
Oh, shit.
You're too fucking close.
This guy might have already seen us,
and he's bringing us here as a trap.
You ever think of that?
Oh, shit.
They're gonna see us.
We're in a red fucking car.
Lower your window, please.
Keep your window down.
I'm fucking cold.
Shit, they're parking.
Keep going.
911, what's your emergency?
Uh, yes, good evening.
I'd like to report
the location of two men
responsible for the triple murder
in Granada Hills last night.
What's your address?
Uh, I followed them,
and they just pulled into the
Chinatown Express at Western and Third.
Um, I can see them inside.
Okay, it's a restaurant
called Chinatown Express
at Western and Third.
That's right. I can see them at
the counter and they're ordering.
These men are wanted for the triple
murder in Granada Hills last night.
What's your name, sir? Louis Bloom.
Do you have a description of the men?
Uh, yes, I do. They're
both Latin American men.
Uh, probably what you
would call Hispanic.
Uh, one is big, very
much on the heavy side.
And the other's face is scratched.
He has scratches on his face.
How old are the men?
Uh, thirty. Perhaps, maybe, 35.
What are they wearing?
The big man is wearing light
pants and a striped sweater,
and the man with scratches is
wearing brown pants and a vest.
He looks like he has a gun.
You said the suspect is armed?
I believe so, yes. I'm
sorry, I have to go.
Otherwise, they might see me.
All west units, possible 187.
Suspects there now. Western and Third.
Western and Third at Chinatown Express.
Suspects are two male Hispanics.
Number one, large build.
Number two with scratches on
his face, inside the location.
Possibly armed. Code Three,
incident 357 and 9753.
There's fucking people in there.
I count six.
So, they could start shooting.
They could.
So you said we were waiting for
a better neighborhood with more people,
not a fucking restaurant.
We work with what we're given.
Unit 14, responding to that Code Three.
You're going to go down the street,
get an angle inside from over there.
Steady hands. Use the zoom.
No fast pans.
I'll be filming from here.
Fuck that. I'm not
getting out of the car!
I need a second angle
from down the street.
We'll cut it together.
Two angles.
Believe me, it's more
dangerous here in the car.
I don't believe anything you say.
Man, this is fucked!
Do you know I've never once
sworn in front of an employer?
I am not doing it! I'm
not getting out of the car.
You're making a mistake.
I don't care about
the fucking job title.
What if my problem wasn't
that I don't understand people,
but that I don't like them?
What if I was obliged to hurt
you for something like this?
I mean, physically.
I think you'd have to believe
afterwards, if you could,
that agreeing to participate
and then backing out at the
critical moment was a mistake.
Because that's what I'm telling you.
As clearly as I can.
7-A-14. We're Code Six to location.
7-A-21. Show us backing 7-A-14.
Oh, God.
7-A-21. We're Code Six with 7-A-14.
Gun!
Oh, God! Oh, fuck!
We have a gun! Two of them!
Call it in!
Shots fired. Shots fired.
Officer down. Officer needs help.
One's down! In pursuit!
Go, go, go!
Oh, my God!
Suspect leaving in a black Escalade
and out of the location, heading north.
Fuck!
Did you get it?
There's people dead in there!
7-A-27. I'm behind
vehicle, we are in pursuit.
7-A-27,
roger.
All units at all frequencies, stand by.
Aim the camera at the
car and start filming.
7-A-27 in
pursuit,
northbound through the alley of 187.
Suspect vehicle is a black Escalade.
Rick. Start filming!
Oh!
7-A-27. We just turned
northbound on Western.
Stay on the police car.
You're right up his ass.
Wide angle. We want all of this.
Requesting backup and an air unit.
Any air unit, come in
on Wilshire frequency.
Lou, Lou, Lou! I got it.
Northbound. 70 miles an
hour. Approaching a fresh red.
Steady hands, Rick.
It's a red light! It's
a red light! Red light!
...approaching a red light.
Oh, shit!
Six, North, Charles, Queen,
5-3-2. Black
Escalade. Fuck!
Give me an ETA on an air ship.
Air A team responding
with a light for mission. Stand by.
Heading northbound
Western, south of suspect.
Approaching another fresh red.
Suspect is turning...
Oh, shit!
7-A-27,
come in.
Oh, my...
Did you see that? Did you see that?
No acknowledgment
from 7-A-27.
Lou, look out, look out!
7-L-0-7. I'm
now primary.
Suspect is behind me.
7-L-7 is
now primary.
Lou, Lou, please.
We're way too close.
This guy's crazy. Fucking shit!
He's ramming my vehicle!
All units. Officer needs help.
Northbound Western.
Suspect now ramming a police vehicle.
No matter what, keep shooting.
Continuing northbound.
Fuck!
Oh, shit! Shit!
Oh, my God!
7-L-7,
come in.
Turn off the car.
He's dead.
Get this shot.
Steady hands.
Use your zoom.
Hold it right there! Put the gun down!
He had a weapon. That was a just fire.
He's not moving.
Let's seal this off.
You saw him.
You saw him!
I can't jeopardize my company's success
to retain an untrustworthy employee.
You're crazy.
You're crazy!
You took my bargaining power, Rick.
You used it against me.
You would have done it again.
Just admit it.
I don't know.
I know.
Don't touch that unless it's
for prints. Make a clean sweep.
Go around the vehicle.
Let them through, here they come.
Hello, Juliana.
Hello, Willy.
Hello, Ben. Hello, Lisa.
- Hi!
Hey. It's Lou, right?
Yes, that's right!
Video News? That's right.
You got something good for us tonight?
I think so. I'm about
to show Nina right now.
I can tell by your tie, it's Friday.
You can leave.
Wasn't that your partner?
As a matter of fact, that's him.
Oh, I'm floored.
I mean, it's amazing.
Thank you.
I mean, just amazing.
No, thank you.
Thank you for bringing it to me.
You're welcome.
I want it, obviously.
How much do you want it?
You tell me.
Get this to graphics.
Who's in charge here?
Who are you?
LAPD. Major case.
Pull the footage from these screens.
Round it up. Let's go. All copies.
Excuse me.
I'm the news director. Can I help you?
You can help yourself
by collecting up every
copy of the shootout
the chase, the crash, all of it. Now.
It's KWLA property.
It's evidence. Of what?
I got a cop near death in the hospital,
three dead, four wounded,
and a dozen major crimes
stretching a mile of Third.
This tape is evidence.
It's news footage bought and paid for
from an independent contractor.
And how do you think he got it?
If there's an issue, speak to him.
Don't get in the way of this.
Unless you have a judge's order,
we're going with it in four minutes.
Hey.
Isn't that him?
Camera One, stay centered up.
Camera Two, we'll do a
zoom out when we come out.
Joel has got a source on the
taskforce who says they found drugs
at the Granada Hills house.
Cocaine in wrapped packages hidden
in crawlspaces. Over 50 pounds.
He confirmed it with an
investigator at the scene.
It wasn't a home invasion.
It was a drug robbery.
Give it to the noon crew.
This is news.
It detracts from the story.
It is the story.
The story is urban crime
creeping into the suburbs.
That's the story.
Jesus, you sound like Lou.
Ten seconds to back.
I think Lou is inspiring all
of us to reach a little higher.
Five, four, three, two, one. Sting it.
Mics. Dissolve.
You understand that you've
been read your rights,
and you're here voluntarily?
That's right. Yes.
And this is being recorded and filmed?
Yes, from the camera up there.
Wide angle.
Mmm-hmm.
Would you tell me how it is you were
at the Chinatown Express tonight
and called the 911?
Of course.
It began earlier in the day.
I was watering my plant.
I looked out my window at my apartment.
The one you visited.
I saw a dark-colored vehicle with two
men inside parked across the street.
I didn't think anything of it,
otherwise I would have reported it then.
We began our night,
my employee and myself.
And around approximately 12:38,
I looked in my rearview mirror
and I saw what looked like the same men
in the same vehicle following us.
I made an evasive maneuver.
I circled back and tailed
them to the restaurant.
At which point, I saw them go inside
and recognized them as the
same men from the home invasion.
You told me you didn't see the men.
That you didn't get a good look at them.
Well, it all came back to
me when I saw them going in.
Their shapes and their movements.
And then I saw that one of the
men had a gun under his shirt,
so I immediately got
my phone and dialed 911.
That's your story?
That's what happened. That's
why I'm sitting here with you.
I think that the men saw my footage
and they tracked me down.
You want to know what I think?
Yes, please.
I think you withheld information.
I think you saw the two men in
the murder house in Granada Hills
and you saw the car and you sat on it
to get something you could film.
What do you think about that?
I think that would be
a very unprofessional thing
for me to do in my business.
It would be murder.
I can understand why
you're looking into it,
but I didn't do anything like that.
Nothing that could be considered wrong.
You don't fool me for a minute.
I'm glad.
I think everything you said is a lie.
I wish my partner was here
to back up what happened.
You left your dead partner.
No, the ambulances arrived.
They're trained professionals.
Yeah, and you seem real
broken up about that.
No, um...
He died doing what he loved.
You filmed him dying.
Yeah. That's what I do. It's my job.
I like to say that if you're seeing me,
you're having the
worst day of your life.
Any Rampart unit,
ambulance to 11 Rampart
on Second Avenue.
Victim, female, white.
Unknown property taken.
Congratulations.
Your selection by Video Production News
is evidence of the hiring
committee's recognition
of your employment history
and unique personal qualities.
It is my hope that through
hard work and commitment,
you will move through the intern program
and continue to pursue your career goals
as full-time employees
of Video Production News.
I can tell you from experience
that the surest way up the
ladder is to listen carefully
and follow my orders.
You may be confused at times,
and other times, unsure.
But remember, I will never
ask you to do anything
that I wouldn't do myself.