Evening barkeep. I would like
to purchase some alcohol, please.
Uh-huh. What can I get you?
Well, I'm 26, as you can see
from my license.
Congratulations.
What can I get you?
A banana daiquiri, my good man.
I'm Crystal.
What's your name?
- Hi, Crystal.
- I'm Gary.
Gary, I don't want
to embarrass you,
but you are just...
you are just a
stunning-looking man.
[ exhales sharply ] I know, right?
Ooh! Thanks!
So, Gary, you having
a good time tonight?
Mm! Thank you
for asking, Crystal.
This is, like, the best night ever.
Do you think we could
make it any better?
[ slurps ]
Probably. I don't know.
I mean, do you want
to get out of here?
Well, I-I kind of like this bar,
and I just ordered this daiquiri.
[ slurps ]
I mean...
Do you want to get out
of here with me?
Are we talking about sex?
Well, I, uh...
[ laughs ]
Yeah. I suppose we are.
[ inhales sharply ]
Crystal, I would love to
have the sex with you.
[ chuckles ]
Great.
Then let's go.
Love that jacket on you, by the way.
Thanks.
Actually...
the whole outfit is new.
Season 5 Episode 12
"Swap Meat"
Dean and Sammy Winchester.
So, how long has it been?
The summer before 6th grade.
Mm-hmm. I remember.
You assigned yourself
your own reading list.
[ chuckling ] That's right.
I forgot about that.
Your mom happens to be the
best babysitter we ever had.
Well, when I was a
maid at the Mayflower,
out on the interstate,
long before you were even an idea...
their daddy used to
pass through town
and leave the boys with me
While... he went off to...work.
One time, he was
gone for two weeks.
- Two weeks?
- Mm-hmm.
Oh, he'd always come limping back.
He loved you boys.
Do you know what
he did all that time?
Little Sammy kept trying to tell me.
of course, I didn't believe him.
Not at first, anyway.
[ inhales sharply ]
Katie, our dad, um...
happened to be an expert
at getting rid of ghosts,
and now, so are we.
That's why I called them, sweetie,
they can help us.
Sounds like you guys got
yourself a poltergeist.
Started a month or
two after we moved in.
Yeah, first I-it was, uh,
just bumps and knocks
and, uh, scratches on the walls
and then it started breaking things
and then it attacked Katie?
That was two nights ago.
Can you show them, honey?
"murdered Chylde."
Dean: Katie...
Everything's gonna be fine.
I promise.
Why don't you guys take
yourselves a little vacation,
and, uh, we'll take care of it.
[ sighs ] Thank you.
Uh, bacon burger turbo,
large chilli-cheese fry,
uh, and a health-quake salad shake?
I know. I know.
It's, uh [clears throat] it's not mine.
[ sighs ]
[ rattling ]
[ rattling stops ]
Oh, you shake it up, baby.
[ clears throat ]
You know, poltergeist aside,
Donna looked pretty
good, don't you think?
Dude, don't tell me
you've still got the
hots for our babysitter.
What? No.
That's weird. [ chuckles ]
I'm just saying that she, you know, she...
She's... she's doing good.
You know, with her husband, her kid.
This whole amityville thing being thrown
at them, and they're hanging tough.
Yeah.
You ever think that you'd
want something like that?
Wife, rugrats, the whole nine
[ sighs ]
No. I mean, not really my thing anymore.
Yeah.
What do you got?
Uh, well, that house of theirs,
It's old... really old.
Um, hundreds of years
and I found a legend.
It's unconfirmed, but still...
Saying?
Supposedly, in the 1720s,
house was owned by a guy
named Isaiah Pickett.
Legend has it
he hung a woman in his
backyard for witchcraft...
a woman named Maggie Briggs.
Okay, so an angry ghost witch?
If it's true.
That still doesn't explain
what "murdered Chylde" means.
No. Or where the bitch is buried.
You know, I mean,
it's a long way back,
but I can see if I can find
something in the town records.
Dean: It's worth a shot.
Manager: Gary! Curly fries are up!
Dean: So, any luck?
Bupkis.
Can't even find proof a woman
named Maggie Briggs existed,
much less where she was planted.
Alright. Well, we've got a
minute to breathe here
so, let's pick it up first thing.
Yeah, you bet. See you in a few.
[ cellphone beeps ]
[ wood creaks ]
Aah!
What...
[ inhales sharply ]
[ deep voice ] Who...
[ groans ]
[ wind blowing ]
[ siren chirps ]
Yeah, this is Collins
out on route 30.
I think we got him.
Mr. Frankel?
Mr. Gary Frankel?
Who?
Your family's worried
sick about you, son
My... my family?
My... brother called you?
Come on. Get in before you freeze solid.
Thanks, uh...
but, uh, w-where are we?
You're home, son.
N-no, officer, I-I'm not staying here.
Gary! Oh, my god!
Gary! Oh, god! Gary!
Oh, hey!
Are you all right? [ chuckles nervously ]
Oh! Okay. Okay. Okay.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Uh... w-what's going on here
- What do you mean?
- Lady, who are you?
Mr. Frankel: Young man, are you drunk?
And who are you?
Gary, are you drunk?
Answer your father.
My father?
Look, I...
Who is that?!
Who the hell is that?!
He's out of his gourd.
Young man, I'm very surprised at you.
Yeah,
tell me about it.
[ Gary's voice ] Oh, yeah.
Bring it!
Holy crap.
Dean: Sam.
Where the hell you been, man?
I've been trying to call you for hours.
I picked up some food.
Bacon burger turbo,
large chilli-cheese fry, right?
Sorry, man. Really.
I-I just... I lost track of time.
I didn't mean to freak you out.
Thanks.
Don't know why it took you
two hours, but thanks.
Oh, you're gonna want
to eat that on the road.
Why?
The maid came in, saw that,
and now they're all kind of freaking out.
Why'd you let the maid in?
It just happened.
Whatever.
I got to hit the head,
and then we'll take off.
All right. I-I'll be outside.
[ door closes ]
[ cellphone closes ]
[ car door closes ]
Hey. You ready?
Absolutely.
Hey, can I drive?
[ car doors close ]
[ engine turns over ]
Oh, this is so sweet!
[ engine revving ]
You want to get the lead out,
Andretti? Come on.
Reverse.
Reverse!
[ tires squeal ]
It's in reverse.
I am really, really sorry.
Shut up.
Dean: This is Dean's
other, other cell, so
you must know what to do.
Dean, I've called every
phone we've got.
Where are you, man?
So...
This is gonna sound crazy...
really crazy... but, um...
I think I'm in the wrong body.
[ chuckles nervously ] Could
use a little help here.
I-I think I got asthma.
Call me back.
[ cellphone beeps ]
Man: Lucky star motel.
Hello, uh, could you please
connect me to room 102?
102?
Nah, man, those guys checked
out middle of the night.
Wait... "guys"? Plural?
Yeah... one leather jacket, one sasquatch.
they left.
[ cellphone beeps ]
Who are you?
[ sighs ]
Smart kid.
[ scoffs ]
[ sighs ]
Virgin.
Frustrated virgin.
Witchcraft, huh, Gary?
You little satanic bastard.
[Mrs. Frankel] Gary! Breakfast.
Leave me alone.
Gary!
All right, I'm coming!
[ sighs ]
So, Gary, I'd like to know
what happened last night.
[ scoffs ] So would I. Believe me.
I mean, what happened
with the plan, buddy?
The plan?
S.A.T.S, M.I.T... The plan.
You want to be an engineer,
you need a full ride.
So, tell me, how does getting
drunk fit with the plan?
Right, yeah.
Listen, buddy, no offence,
but at the moment,
I couldn't give a rat's
ass about your plan.
Excuse me?
Uh... [ chuckles ]
Listen, h-have I seemed,
uh, moody lately?
Withdrawn?
Wow.
Any... any occult fixations?
What?
Let me guess... I'm amazing at Latin.
You have an ear for languages.
Hmm.
Um, any of the neighborhood
pets go missing recently?
Are you smoking drugs?
Leonard. He is not smoking drugs.
Have any of you seen
me w-w-with a book?
It'd be big and old, uh, leather-bound,
maybe some strange writing on it.
Or [sighs] frankly, I'm probably hiding it.
Gary, no!
W-what?
You're allergic to wheat gluten.
[ laughs ]
[ toilet flushes ]
[ burps, sighs ]
[ groans ]
Gluten.
- You've seriously sprung a leak.
- What?
If mom and dad ever found
that creepy old book of yours,
you'd be grounded for a decade
and you're bringing it up at breakfast?
So there is a book.
Sydney, where do I keep it?
So, uh, where we going, anyway?
To work.
The case?
Oh, right. Yeah... the case. Of course.
Where, uh, do you want to start?
Well, since you couldn't find
where Maggie Briggs was buried,
now we have to do
an all-day tombstone roll
to see if we can dig her up.
Wait. M-Maggie Briggs?
You mean, like... like,
the witch Maggie Briggs?
Yeah, Sherlock.
Yeah, she's in the basement.
Come again? W-what basement?
Isaiah Pickett's house.
Okay, there's this legend that
he hung her, but he didn't.
The real truth is...
is that she was carrying
his illegitimate child,
and he killed her and then
buried her in the basement.
Her "murdered Chylde."
That would explain the scratches.
How do you know all this?
Oh, I've done all kinds
of research on it.
I mean, you know... Last night.
Yeah.
Nice work... I guess.
[ Bob Seger's "rock 'n'
roll never forgets" plays ]
Aw, man, turn it up!
Seriously?
Hell yeah!
#you can come back, baby#
[ louder ] #rock 'n' roll never forgets#
#ooooh, the band's still
playin' it loud and lean#
#listen to the guitar
player makin' it scream#
#all you got to do is
just make that scene#
Sam: Dean! Someone has stolen my body!
The guy right next to you is not me!
Check your friggin' voice mail. Damn it.
[ cellphone beeps ] [ sighs ]
Gary?
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm Gary. Uh...
Gary is okay.
So we're referring to ourselves
in the third person now?
We heard about last
night. What happened?
Got drunk. No big thing.
Look, uh, what's my locker number?
[ chuckles ]
What? Are you...
are you still drunk?
Yeah. Yeah. I see, like
three of you right now.
Um, so... so, what's
my locker number?
Oh, no, Gary.
[ sighs ]
This is a very, very bad book.
[ door creaks ]
Boo-yah!
Master chief is in the house, bizatches!
Are you all right?
Yeah. Fine.
Well, I'll be damned.
Willow Moss.
Yeah, right. It's, uh,
supposed to grow
over witches' graves, right?
Yeah.
[ grunting ]
Hey, man, I'm really sorry about this.
Sorry about what?
Sam?!
[ grunts ] You okay?
Let's get the hell out of here!
Whoa, whoa, whoa. We still got
to burn the body, you idiot.
Come on.
[ fire crackling ]
Dude...
that was sweet!
Hey, Gary, wait up!
Where are you going?
I got something to do.
You're skipping class? You?
I'm just...
Not feeling like myself, okay?
Well, whatever it is,
we can talk it out, bro.
Come with us.
I don't have time. I got to go. I'm sorry.
[ sighs ]
Hey!
Trevor!
Well, what else was I supposed to do?
[ southern-rock music playing ]
- Here you go, guys.
- Do me a favor, sweetheart.
Would you bring me a
cheeseburger with extra bacon?
and fry an egg on top of it, would you?
Absolutely.
Ooh, that... that sounds good. Ditto.
Be right back with your order.
Okay, who are you and what
have you done with Sam?
W-what do you mean
Bacon cheeseburgers now?
I don't know. I eat them, don't I?
Anyways, we are celebrating.
Yeah, I guess.
Another one bites the dust.
Nice work today.
You too.
I had a, uh, really awesome day, man.
Seriously.
[ sighs ]
Whoo!
Sweet.
A really awesome day?
Yeah. Why not?
It was a random, d-list ghost hunt.
That's... that's awesome to you?
I can't be in a good mood?
Yeah, I guess. It's...
No, actually.
It's not really your style, Sam.
Well, then, it's a new me.
I mean, come on.
Why shouldn't I be happy?
I've got a gun, I'm getting drunk,
and I look like this.
[ sighs ] I don't know.
You ever feel like your whole
future is being decided for you?
Uh, yeah, Sam, I feel like that a lot.
No matter how much you fight it,
you can't stop the plan.
The stupid, stupid plan.
So, I don't know.
I guess it's, uh, it's just nice
to do a little ass-kicking
for a change, that's all.
Uh, you know what? I... I'm drunk.
[ chuckles ] Sorry. Just... just forget it.
No, no. It's all right.
It's, uh...
I'll drink to that.
Wow, you know, is it just me,
or are we actually drinking together?
We don't do it that often, huh?
[ scoffs ] Yeah, you could say that.
Well, we should.
You're a good guy, Dean.
Man, you are drunk.
Here we go.
Mmm!
Thank you.
Enjoy.
No, but I mean it.
You really are a good guy.
Mmm!
The bread alone!
Love that jacket on you, by the way.
Thanks
Actually...
The whole outfit is new.
We're gonna do it!
[ Sam grunts ]
Hey!
What the hell's going on?!
You can scream all you want.
No one can hear you,
my parents are out of town!
Gary.
T. What up?
Where are you?
Uh, I can't really tell you right now,
But, man, you wouldn't believe it.
Well... Well, where's Dean?
Uh, the Cloverleaf
on route 6. Why?
You mean you haven't killed him yet?
Sam: What?
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
W-what do you mean?
Kill Dean?
I'm... building up to it.
Look, Gary, we got problems here.
For one...
I'm looking at your body right now...
with this other dude in it.
What?
Yeah, he's been in your house
he's hanging out
with your parents.
Okay, just... calm down.
Whatever he says, no one's
gonna believe him, right?
I mean, w-we're still good.
Would you just hurry up and kill the son
of a bitch already, would you?
Don't rush me. I'll do it.
Yeah, you better.
[ door opens ]
Uh... Got to go.
Oh, man. I am in way over my head.
I don't think he's gonna do it.
Just relax. This is Gary
we're talking about.
What the hell's going on here?
How do you know who Dean is?
Everybody knows Dean.
He's "hell's most wanted."
Oh, no.
No.
Have you idiots been talking to demons?
Oh, right. We're the idiots.
[ sighs ]
You're just kids.
You have no idea what
you're messing with.
Well, we know that there's
a price on Dean's head,
and we're the ones
that are gonna collect.
What's that supposed to mean?
About a month ago,
we were down here...
Nora.
What? We're not allowed
to talk about him?
We were down here,
goofing around with that book.
Um, I wouldn't exactly call
praying to our dark overlord
"goofing around."
Don't be a loser, Trev.
Yeah, Trev.
Anyway, all of a sudden,
the lights flickered
and Gary went into
this weird trance.
He closed his eyes, picked
up a pencil, and drew this.
Trevor: And you know what's really weird?
Gary can't draw.
He said he heard a voice in his head,
the demons were putting
out a bounty on this guy.
A bounty?
Yeah, to, like, every witch or Satanist
across the whole country.
But Gary... Gary's the
one who spotted you.
And the "freaky Friday" crap?
another spell from the book.
Gary's idea... go in trojan horse-style.
He's really smart.
That is, if he has the
beanbags to go through with it.
Listen to me.
You are making a terrible mistake.
We're talking about a demon deal...
Killing somebody.
This isn't a game.
You're crossing a line
you won't come back from.
Believe me.
What?
Nothing. I-I...
Nora, don't tell me you're
actually listening to this jerk.
I don't know.
M-maybe.
I-I mean, what if he has a point?
I don't believe this,
first Gary, now you.
I can't...
You know what?
Fine.
You want something done right...
What, you're gonna...
You're gonna go kill
Dean yourself, tough guy?
Don't have to.
I can do this.
N-no. Y-you can't be serious.
I'm calling up one
of these bad boys,
turning these punks
over, and getting paid.
Dollar, dollar bills, y'all!
I-I really don't think
that that's a good idea.
It's not. It's a very, very bad idea.
No one asked you.
You're not Sam.
Who the hell are you?
Ow!
Sam: Don't do this.
I'm begging you.
Trevor, I think he's right.
Hey, you want to get
into Vassar, don't you?
Please! Stop!
Attrahendum eos...
You're gonna get us all killed!
...Ad ligandum eos pariter
Eos coram me!
Maybe I said it wrong.
Nora?
No! No, no! Don't touch her!
Nora, you okay?
Oh, yeah
I'm peachy.
So, what'd you call me here for, Skippy?
Unless...
[ gasps ] It's dinnertime?
What? I-I... n-no.
Uh, we have Dean Winchester.
You do?
Where?
Trevor, keep your mouth shut.
The Cloverleaf Motel over on route 6.
Sam?
Is that you in there?
[ laughs ]
Well, aren't you just
98 pounds of nothing.
The kid is a moron.
He doesn't have any
idea where Dean is.
[ laughs ]
So, if Sam's in this body,
Who's in Sam's?
A dangerous warlock.
Named Gary.
You mean to tell me
you've got Dean Winchester
and Sam Winchester's meat suit?
An empty vessel just
waiting to be filled.
And you're handing
them both over to me?
Uh, y-yeah. I guess.
[ chuckles ]
Well...
I got to hand it to you.
I'm impressed.
Thanks.
Um...
So, if you don't mind my asking...
there's a reward?
Sure.
My... Undying gratitude
[ chuckles ]
What, are you serious?
Be quiet, you idiot!
Consider yourself lucky, kid.
[ sighs ] Uh, w-wait a minute!
We worked our asses off here,
and, uh, I want my reward!
Please. [ chuckles ]
Okay.
[ gasps softly ]
I'm sorry.
You're right.
What can I get you?
Well, h-how about a million bucks?
Oh, for god's sake, Trevor,
just shut up and run!
A million doesn't buy
you much these days.
Why not make it 10?
Okay, $10 mill.
And I want...
I want Mindy Schwartz
to fall in love with me.
Love... Money,
[ chuckles ] sticking to the basics.
I can respect that.
But here's my counter.
[ squish ]
[ grunts ]
[ thud ]
Yep.
Tastes like moron.
[ beep ]
Woman's voice: You have 38 messages.
Sam: This is gonna sound crazy...
Really crazy... but, um, I think
I'm in the wrong body.
[ chuckles nervously ]
[ beep ]
Dean, the guy right next
to you is not me!
[ beep ]
Dean, check your friggin'
voice mail. Damn it.
All right, pal
either you start talking
or I start water-boarding.
Oh, my god. Please, don't hurt me.
Please! I'm sorry! I'm so, so sorry!
Okay. Hey, pull it together, champ.
I don't want to die. I don't want to die.
Where's Sam?
In my... my friend's basement.
His parents are out of town.
Parents?
How old are you?
I'm 17.
17?
Nora
Not at the moment.
[ grunting ]
[ ropes creaking ]
[ breathing heavily ]
Whoo!
Damn it!
Boy, you earned your
dessert tonight, kiddo.
Tell me... what is it you want?
Anything.
Anything?
Lay it on me.
I want to be a witch
for real.
And really powerful.
Mm. Good choice.
I get it.
No daddy, no M.I.T.
No plan.
You get to be big and strong,
and no one can tell you
what to do anymore.
There's just one small formality first,
you got to meet the boss.
The boss?
You know... your satanic majesty,
or whatever the kids are
calling it these days.
The devil?
Mm-hmm.
Uh... No.
O-okay.
Um...
It's okay.
I...Don't really want to bother him.
Oh, but he's gonna
want to meet you.
Relax.
It'll be easy,
he's just gonna ask you
one little question, and
all you got to do is, say "yes."
And then... you get your reward.
[ grunting ]
Exorcizamus te, omnimundus.
What was that?
Uh, n-nothing.
Were you trying to exorcise me?!
You little piece of crap?!
[ groaning ]
[ straining ] spiritus, omnis satanica potestas.
Omnis incursio infernalis adversii.
Omnis congregatio.
Et secta diabolica.
Ergo, draco maledicte.
Ecclesiam tuam securi tibi
facias libertate servire.
Te rogamus.
Adiós, bitch!
Uh, it's "audi nos."
Aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaah!
Gary: Animae domum redeant.
Fas atque nefas instauretur.
Potestate et auctoritate, sic fiat.
[ sighs ]
So, we good?
Yeah. We're good.
Oh, man, it's nice to be back.
Yeah. Awesome.
So...
[ clears throat ] Gary...
Yeah. I know... my bad.
"My bad"?
Kid, "my bad" ain't gonna cut it.
See, if you were of voting age...
You'd be dead,
because we would kill you.
So either you straighten
up and fly right
or we will kill you.
Are we clear?
Crystal.
Good.
[ thunder rumbles ]
Crap.
Gary, look.
Take it from someone who knows...
Chin up, man.
Your life ain't that bad.
Uh, you met my parents.
Yeah. So what? It's your life.
You don't like their plan
for you, tell them to cram it.
Rebel a little bit.
In a healthy, non-satanic way, of course.
By the way, you know why
Nora's into witchcraft?
What do you mean?
She doesn't like Satan,
you moron. She likes you.
Really?
You... you think?
Yeah. I know.
I'm telling you, kid...
I wish I had your life.
You do?
Thanks.
Get out of here.
[ sighs ]
That was a nice thing to say.
I totally lied.
Kid's life sucked ass.
[ sighs ]
[ car door closes ]
All that apple-pie,
family crap? It's stressful.
Trust me... we didn't
miss a damn thing.
Or we don't know
what we're missing.
[ engine turns over ]
[ "rock 'n' roll never
forgets" plays loudly ]
Hey, come on, man.
Turn it down.
[ volume decreases ]
Welcome back, kotter.
#come back, baby#
#rock 'n' roll never forgets#
#said you can come back, baby#
#oh, come back, baby#
-- Sync by honeybunny --
www.addic7ed.com
Edited by Scooby