what do you say we kill some evil sons
of bitches and we raise a little hell?
sam,look out!
sam!
you're offering up your own soul?
all you got to do is bring sam back.
i'll give you one year and one year only.
i couldn't let him die,bobby. he's my brother.
i could throttle you!
i don't care what it takes.
i'm gonna get you out of this.
if we trap the crossroads demon
try to welsh our way out of the
deal in any way,you die.
what kind of blade can kill a demon?
yesterday,i would have said
there was no such thing.
who was that masked chick?
who the hell are you?
i'm the girl that just saved your ass.
thanks for driving her back here.
it's not like i had a choice.
she pitched a fit.
hey,sweetie.
what's wrong?
nothing. i missed you.
okay,but tonight's your dad's night.
no.i don't like dad's night.
i don't want dad to have a night anymore.
since when?
you used to love going to your dad's house.
you know,he loves you, and he misses you a lot.
but i hate it there!
you don't hate it.
yes,i do!
he's mean, and there are monsters there.
i don't w-want to go back.
please don't let the monsters get me.
okay,sweetie.
okay.
supernatural season 3 episode 2
what do you mean you don't
think it will work,bobby?
it's a demon-dispelling ritual.
well,maybe we got the translation wrong.
look,we can't just let dean fry in hell while we
there's got to be something
yeah. no. i got to go.
okay. never mind.
hey. who was that?
i was just ordering pizza.
dude,you do realize that
you're in a restaurant?
yeah. yeah. oh,yeah.
i just felt like pizza, you know?
okay,weirdy mcweirderton.
so,i think i got something.
yeah?
cicero,indiana.
falls on his own power saw.
and?
hat,that's it? one power saw?
well...yeah.
and you think that this is a case?
well,i don't know.could be.
i don't know,dean.
there's something better in
cicero than just a case.
and that is?
lisa braeden.
should i even ask?
remember that road trip i took,uh...
gosh,about eight years ago now?
you were in orlando with dad
wrapping up that banshee thing.
yeah. the five states,five-day --
well,kind of.
although i spent most of my time in
lisa braeden's loft.
so let me get this straight.
you want to drive all the way to cicero
just to hook up with some random chick?
she was a yoga teacher.
it was the bendiest weekend of my life.
come on. have a heart,huh?
it's my dying wish.
how many dying wishes are you gonna get?
as many as i can squeeze out.
come on. smile,sam.
god knows i'm gonna be smiling
after 24 hours with gumby girl.
gumby girl.
does that make me pokey?
don't wait up for me,sammy.
wait,dean. dean,you
dean.
lisa.
how's it going?
wow.so,how long has it been?
eight,going on nine years now.
crazy,right?
yeah.
so,what are you doing here?
oh,i was just passing through,
and i couldn't resist.
i remember that you love surprises.
yeah.
dean winchester.
wow. just...wow.
i'm -- i'm sorry.
you kind of came at a bad time.
we're having a party.
a party?
well,i love parties.
so,uh,who's the party for?
ben,my son.
oh. you have a --
yep.
that's him.
yes! ac/dc rules!
how old
8.
oh,dean,could you excuse me a minute?
yeah,sure.
don't mind me.
did you hear lisa call him "dean"?
yeah. why?
you don't know about dean?
the dean. best-night-of-my-life dean.
no. tell me.
oh,my god.
so,they had this crazy,
semi-illegal --
hi.
hello.
what's up?
what's up with you?
so,it's your birthday.
guilty.
it's a cool party.
dude,it's so freakin' sweet.
and this moon bounce --it's epic.
yeah. it's pretty awesome.
you know who else thinks they're awesome?
chicks.
it's like hot-chick city out there.
so...
how you holding up?
fine.
really?
oh,you know.
i just
never mind.
what?
it's just...
i'm worried about katie.
i think there might be something...wrong with her.
of course there is.
the poor girl just lost her dad.
she's devastated.
no. that's not what i'm talking about.
there is something really...
wrong with her.
i'm not sure that katie is...katie.
what?
i'm not sure that's my daughter.
i know you're grieving,but you can't talk like that.
katie needs you.but you don't understand --
seriously. we're gonna get you help.
it'll be okay.
katie?
come on,we're leaving.
so,i,uh,met ben.
cool kid.
yeah.
i couldn't help but notice that,uh,he's turning 8.
you and me...you know.
you're not trying to ask me if he's yours?
no.no,of course not.
he's not,is he?
what?
no.
right.
something wrong with your friend?
she's been through a lot.
her ex just died in this horrible accident.
oh,yeah.didn't i just read about that?
the power saw.
yeah.
guess there's been a lot of bad luck
in the neighborhood lately.
what kind of bad luck?
hello,sam.
you've been following me since lincoln.
not much gets by you,huh?
hese are amazing.
it's like deep-fried crack. try some.
that knife you had
you can kill demons with that thing?
sure comes in handy when i have to swoop in
and save the damsel in distress.
where did you get it?skymall.
Why are you following me?
I'm interested in you.
why?
because you're tall...
and i love a tall man.
and then there's the whole antichrist thing.
excuse me?
generation of psychic kids,yellow-eyed
demon rounds you up,
celebrity death match ensues.
you're the sole survivor.
how do you know about that?
i'm a good hunter.
so,yellow eyes had some pretty
big plans for you,sam.
"had" being the key word.
oh,yeah,yeah,yeah.that's right.
ding-dong, the demon's dead.
good job with that.
it doesn't change the fact that you're special...
and that anthony michael hall
e.s.p. visions come into play.
no. that's stuff's not happening anymore...
not since yellow eyes died.
well,i'm thinking you're still a pretty big deal.
i mean,after all that business with your mom.
what about my mom?
you know, what happened to her friends.
you...don't know.
you've got a little bit of catching up to do,my friend.
so,why don't you look into your mom's pals
and then give me a call and we'll talk again?
and,by the way,
you do know there's a job in this town,right?
hello.
dude,there is a job here.
really?
yeah. you know that one freak accident
we read about in the paper?
there's four more that never
even made the paper,
all in this morning hill gated community.
people falling off of ladders and
drowning in their jacuzzis
all over the neighborhood.
-that is weird.  -yeah,something's up...
something these nice,
big gates can't protect them from.
katie.
what are you doing?
play with me,mommy.
okay.
sure. yeah let's,um,let's play.
oh,good.
i love you,mommy.
i love you too,sweetie.
i'm hungry,mommy.
yeah.
so,once again, i'm very sorry to disturb you.
we just really want to expedite
that life-insurance policy.
-of course.  -okay.
this is,um,where he fell.
i see.
now,how exactly did he --
he was just inside changing a light bulb.
must have lost his balance.
-were you here when this happened?
-no. i was out.
uh,the only one here was our daughter,dakota.
okay.
okay. well,uh,i think that's all i need.
i'll get out of your way now.
thank you.
thank you,mommy.
you eat.
mommy will be right back.
mommy?
just --  just give mommy a second.
let me in.
mommy.
mommy!
let me in!
what are you doing?!  let me in!
let me in! let me in! let me in!
let me in!
give mommy a minute.
aren't you just the cutest thing?
oh,thank you.
uh,katie,could you put
these in the kitchen,please?
katie seems okay, considering
she's fine. yeah.um,look,i'm
and you -- how are you doing really?
i'm fine. look,we're fine.
um,this isn't a good time
i wasn't sure if you were
keeping the house or selling.
we at cicero realty would like
look,i told you it's not a good time!
i want ice cream.
mommy,ice cream,please.
hey,ben.
hey.  you were at my party.
yeah. yeah,i'm dean.
everything okay? something wrong?
is that your game they're playing with?
ryan humphrey borrowed it,
and now he won't give it back.
-well,you want me to go...
-no! don't go over there!
only bitches send a grown-up.
you're not wrong.
and i'm not a bitch.
is that humphrey?
the one that needs to lay off the burgers?
ryan.
i'd like my game back, please.
fine. take it back.
see? told you guys he was a
thanks
dude,that was awesome!
benjamin isaac braeden... what's gotten into you?
he stole my game.
so you kick him? since when is...
did you tell my son to beat up that kid?
what? somebody had to teach him
how to kick the bully in the nads
-who asked you to teach him anything?
-just relax.
what are you even still doing here?
we had one weekend
together a million years ago.
you don't know me. you have
no business with my son.
lisa.
just leave us alone.
ben!
thanks.
i love you most in the
whole wide world,mommy.
um,me,too,sweetie.
come on,hold still.
what's wrong,mommy?
nothing,sweetie.
are we going for ice cream now?
yeah, we're going for ice cream.
can i have the ice cream now?
kids in this town.
yeah. tell me about it.
so,what do you know about changelings?
evil monster babies?
no,not necessarily babies.
they're kids...
creepy,"stare at you like you're lunch" kids.
yeah.
there's one at every victim's house.
so,changelings can perfectly mimic children.
according to lore,they climb in
the window,snatch the kid.
there were marks on the windowsill
at one of the kid's houses.
looked to me like blood.
the changeling grabs a kid,
assumes its form,
joins the happy fam just for kicks?
not quite.
changelings feed on the mom...
synovial fluid.
the moms have these odd bruises on the back of their necks.
changelings can drain them for a few weeks
before mom finally croaks.
and then there's dad and the babysitter
yeah. seems like anyone who gets
between the changeling's food source ends up dead.
and fire's the only way to waste them?
great. we'll just bust in, drag the kids out,
torch them on the front lawn.
that will play great with the neighbors.
what about the real ones?
what happens to them?
they stash them underground somewhere.
i don't know why, but if it's true,
the real kids might be out there.
we better start looking.
so,any kid in the neighborhood is vulnerable?
-yep. -we got to make a stop.
i want to check on someone.
if the real kids are still alive,
we don't have time
we have to.
dean
i was thinking... ben's birthday.
i didn't bring him a present.
that's okay.
no. no. no. i feel terrible,so,uh...
here.
take a long weekend --
just the two of you -- on me.
what?
I hear six flags is great this time of year.
Go now. avoid the traffic.
"Siegfried Houdini."
Whose card is this?
Mine.
Never mind. it'll work.
I promise.
You should leave.
Lisa...
Mommy,what's wrong?
Nothing,Ben. It's cool.
Make him go away,mommy.
You heard him.
Get out.
Lisa...
I don't think this is a good idea.
Get out!
They took ben he's changed.
What?! Are you sure?
Yeah,i'm sure. I checked his windowsill.
Blood?
I don't think it is blood,
And i think i know where the kids are.
Red dirt.
That's what was on the window.
You take the front.
I'll go around.
ben..ben...it's okay.
I'm gonna get you out of here.
What do you think you're doing?
This is private property.
I'm calling the police.
You heard me! Get out!
Let me get my bag. I'm going.
I don't mean to cause any trouble.
Mommy?
ben.. Play with me.
This isn't funny anymore.
I put you to bed three times.
I don't want to go to bed.
I want to be with you,mommy.
That's sweet,hon.
Come on.
Let's go.
All right,come on.
I'm hungry.
Mini pizzas okay?
Deluxe is all we've got.
Okay.
That's funny --
I thought we were anti-olives this month.
it's ok. get out here ok?
Come on,girls! Come on!
Everybody back! Everybody back!
Cover your eyes!
Here. Use this.
All right.
All right,ben. Come on.
Him first.
Hey! Dean! There's a mother.
A mother changeling?
We got to get these kids out quick.
Right there. There's one more.
You got to break the lock!
I guess that's why the changelings
are keeping the kids alive
--so the mom can snack on them.
What's wrong,mommy?
You're not my son.
Yes,i am. Where's ben?
I'm ben.
I love you,mommy.
They don't want you to leave me,mommy.
Mommy? Mommy?
Let me in!
What are you doing?!
Let me in! Let me in! let me in!
ben,get them out of here!
ben?!
ben!
baby,are you okay?
i'm okay,mom.
oh,my god.
what the hell just happened?
i'll explain everything if you want me to,
but,trust me, you probably don't.
the important thing is that ben's safe.
thank you.
i'm gonna give you guys some time.
come on.
changelings?
you know how i never mentioned my job?
this is my job.
i so didn't want to know that.
do you think he'll be okay?
yeah. i think he'll be fine.
okay. seriously...
i mean,you're 100%
sure that he is not mine,right?
you're off the hook.
i did a blood test when he was a baby.
there was this guy some
bar back in a biker joint.
what? i had a type.
leather jacket,couple of scars,
no mailing address
i was there.
guess i was a little wild back then...
...before i became a mom.
so,yeah. you can relax.
good.
i...
i swear you look disappointed.
yeah,i don't know.
it's weird,you know your life.
i mean,this house and kid.
it's not my life...
never will be.
some stuff happened to me recently,and,uh...
anyway,a guy in my situation --
you start to think, you know.
i'm gonna be gone one day,
and what am i leaving behind besides a car?
i don't know.
ben may not be your kid,
but he wouldn't be alive if it wasn't for you.
that's a lot if you ask me.
you know, just for the record...
you got a great kid.
i would have been proud to be his dad.
look,if,um...
if you want to stick around for a while...
you're welcome to stay.
i can't.
i got a lot of work to do, and it's not my life.
hi. i needed to check
some facts with your,uh...
with your secretary
about a fire that occurred
on november 24,2006,
in lawrence,kansas.
hardecker was his name.
okay. great.
i was just trying to find out the date he died.
this is police chief phil jones. july 13th.
can you check the
records for a robert campbell?
july 19,2001.
dead on arrival.
what i'm after is cause of death.
heart condition?
wasn't he a cardiac surgeon?
wouldn't he have known about that?
i'm looking for information on
on mrs. wallace's death.
two deaths.
who was the other?
ed campbell.
any survivors?
no,that's all i needed.
thank you very much.
oh,my god.
they're dead all of them.
all of my mom's friends.
her doctor,her uncle --
everyone who ever knew her
systematically wiped off
the map one at a time.
someone went through
a hell of a lot of trouble
trying to cover their tracks.
the yellow-eyed demon.
so,what's your deal?
you show up wherever i am.
you know all about me.
you know all about my mom.
i already told you. i'm
oh,right,right. yeah. just a hunter.
just some hunter
who happens to know more about
my own family than i do.
just tell me who you are.
sam,it
just...tell me who you are.
it doesn't matter.
just tell me who you are!
fine.
think twice before going for that holy water.
give me one reason i should.
i'm here to help you,sam.
is this some kind of joke?
god's honest truth...
or whatever.
you're a demon.
don't be such a racist.
i'm here because i want to help you.
and i can if you trust me.
trust you?
sam,calm down.
start talking. all those murders...
- what was the demon trying to cover up?
- i don't know.
what happened to my mother?
i honestly don't know.
that's what i'm trying to find out.
all i know is that it's about you.
what?
don't you get it,sam?
it's all about you.
what happened to your mom,
what happened to her friends
they're trying to cover
up what he did to you.
and i want to help you figure it out.
why would you want to help me?
i have my reasons.
not all demons are the same,sam.
not all of us want the same thing.
me?
i want to help you from time to time.
that's all.
and if you let me,
there's something in it for you.
what could you possibly
i could help you save your brother.