- Who are you?
- Castiel, an angel of the Lord.
I've got demon blood in me, Dean!
I'm a whole new level of freak!
Lilith is trying to break
the 66 seals to free Lucifer from hell.
And why would an angel
rescue me from Hell?
We have work for you.
She's no nurse.
She's Lilith's personal chef.
- Sucking blood? You know that's wrong.
- I wish to God I could stop.
You give yourself over wholly
to the service of God and his angels?
Yes, I swear.
You're an angel?
- I'm Zachariah.
This man is a prophet of the Lord.
I'm not drinking
the demon blood for kicks.
She's poison, Sam.
Look what she did to you.
You walk out that door,
don't you ever come back.
No, no, no!
Our father who art in heaven...
...hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come,
blah, blah, blah...
Lead us not into temptation...
...but deliver us from evil.
Truer words never spoken,
huh, Sisters?
But sometimes it seems
as if it's difficult to know the creator.
Sometimes I feel,
in a very literal sense...
...that I have been wandering
the desert for years...
...looking for our father.
Well, not our father.
My father. See, he's in jail.
Your dad put him there.
I almost gave up hope.
But ye of little faith.
Because I finally found him.
Or at least, you know,
the spot where his cage door opens.
It's right here.
In a damn convent, for God's sake.
- Life is funny.
- Uh, Father?
Shut your frigging pie hole,
you little slut!
Then again, I suppose it makes sense.
Folks forget,
my daddy is an angel, after all.
Or was.
I mean, I suppose
some dumb bastard stood here...
...felt a jolt of his holy juice
and thought...
..."I'm gonna build me a nun factory. "
Well...
...it's the right idea...
...wrong angel.
So, um...
...if any of you gals
are the praying type...
...now would be a good time to start.
Help!
Sam?
Your head in the game here?
I'm good. Let's go.
Are you okay?
I just said I was.
Look, I know handholding
really isn't my thing...
...but Dean was wrong,
saying what he said to you.
No, he was right to say it.
- I don't blame him, after what I did.
- After, you guys will patch things up.
- You always do.
- You're talking like I got an after.
Don't say that.
I can feel it inside me, Ruby.
I've changed.
For good.
There's no going back now.
- Sam.
- Look...
...I know what I gotta do.
It's okay. I'm just saying...
...Dean's better off
as far away from me as possible.
Anyways, doesn't matter.
Let's just get this done with.
Dean?
Dean.
You listen to a word I said?
Yeah, I heard you.
I'm not calling him.
Don't make me get my gun, boy.
We are damn near kickoff
for Armageddon.
We got bigger fish at the moment.
I know you're pissed and I'm not
making apologies. But he's your-
Blood? He's my blood?
Is that what you're gonna say?
He's your brother and he's drowning.
Bobby, I tried to help him. I did.
- Look what happened.
- So try again.
No, it's too late.
- There's no such thing.
- No, damn it.
No. We gotta face the facts.
Sam never wanted part of this family.
He hated this life growing up.
Ran away to Stanford
first chance he got.
Now it's like déjà vu all over again.
Well, I am sick...
...and tired of chasing him.
Screw him. He can do what he wants.
- You don't mean that.
- Yes, I do, Bobby.
Sam's gone.
He's gone.
I'm not even sure
if he's still my brother anymore.
If he ever was.
You stupid, stupid son of a bitch!
Well, boohoo, I am so sorry
your feelings are hurt, princess.
You under the impression that family's
supposed to make you feel good?
Bake you an apple pie, maybe?
They're supposed to make you miserable!
That's why they're family!
I told him, "You walk out that door,
don't come back. "
And he walked out anyway.
That was his choice.
You sound like a whiny brat.
No.
You sound like your dad.
Well, let me tell you something.
Your dad was a coward.
My dad was a lot of things,
but a coward?
He'd rather push Sam away
than reach out to him.
Well, that don't strike me as brave.
You are a better man
than your daddy ever was.
So you do both of us a favor.
Don't be him.
Hello, Dean.
It's almost time.
We're gonna take you
to the nursery, sugar.
Let mommy and daddy
get some sleep.
He's a beautiful child.
Absolutely scrumptious.
Pattycake, pattycake, baker's man
Bake me a cake as fast as you can
Pat it, and roll it
And mark it with a B
And put it in the oven-
So we need to talk.
Hello, Dean.
You're looking fit.
Well, how about this.
The Suite Life of Zach and Cass.
It's a-
Never mind.
- So, what is this? Where the hell am I?
- Call it a green room.
We're closing in
on the grand finale here.
Wanna keep you safe
before showtime.
Try a burger. They're your favorite.
From that sea-side shack in Delaware.
You were 11, I think.
- I'm not hungry.
- No?
How about Ginger
from season two of Gilligan's Island?
You do have a thing for her,
don't you?
Tempting. Weird.
- We'll throw in Mary Ann for free.
- No, no, it's...
Bail on the Holodeck, okay?
I wanna know what the game plan is.
Let us worry about that.
We want you focused, relaxed.
Well, I'm about to be pissed and leaving,
so start talking, chuckles.
All the seals have fallen...
...except one.
That's an impressive score. That's right
up there with the Washington Generals.
You think sarcasm's appropriate, do you?
Considering...
...you started all this?
But the final seal...
...it'll be different.
Why?
Lilith has to break it.
She's the only one who can.
Tomorrow. Midnight.
- Where?
- We're working on that.
- Well, work harder.
- We'll do our job. You do yours.
Yeah, and what is that, exactly?
I'm the one that stops her. How?
With the knife?
- All in good time.
- Isn't now a good time?
- Have faith.
- What, in you?
Give me one good reason
why I should.
Because you swore your obedience.
So obey.
What, no devil's trap?
- I don't need one.
- Look at you, all roided up.
It's like ARod and Madonna
over here.
Where's Lilith?
- I'm not scared of you.
- Yeah, you are, actually.
And with good reason.
Look, what's my upside?
Okay, I tell you, you kill me.
I don't tell you, you still kill me.
I get away somehow, Lilith will
definitely kill me. So where's my carrot?
I think what you should be worrying
about is what happens before you die.
Ah, screw it.
It's Sam, leave me a message.
Hey. It's me, uh...
Ahem. Look, I'll just get right to it.
I'm still pissed...
...and I owe you a serious beat down.
But...
...I shouldn't have said what I said.
You know, I'm not dad.
We're brothers, you know.
We're family.
And, uh...
...no matter how bad it gets,
that doesn't change.
Sammy, I'm sorry-
- Stop. Stop. Please.
- You'll tell me where she is?
- Fine, fine. Just let me die.
- Deal.
Tomorrow night. Midnight.
She's gonna be at a convent.
St. Mary's. Ilchester, Maryland.
- A convent?
- Lilith.
She's gonna break the final seal.
- And what is the final seal?
- I don't know.
Aah, I don't know! I don't know!
I don't know, I swear.
Oh, please.
I'm begging you. Kill me, please.
Fine.
- Wait. You can't.
- Why not?
We gotta take her. It's the final run
on the Death Star. You need more juice.
You promised.
Sorry, sister. You're a walking,
talking can of whup-ass.
- You bitch.
I know.
Just can't trust anyone these days.
Well, least you won't be able
to crack me open that easy.
- That so?
- Don't forget...
...it's not just me you're bleeding.
In fact, I think I'm gonna take
a little siesta in the subconscious...
...hand over the wheel for a little bit.
- What are you talking about?
- Cindy McCellen, R.N.
Come on down.
What?
Where am I?
Huh?
Oh, my God. I can't move.
What's going on?
Help.
Help me, please.
Great.
Father, look.
I'm not exactly the praying type,
but still...
...I made the sacrifice.
I got you a bag full of nuns.
So, uh...
...can you hear me?
Can you whisper through the door?
I'm here, my son.
It's so good to hear your voice, Padre.
I have been searching for you
for so long, you have no idea.
The others have lost faith.
Dickless heathens.
- But not me.
- You've done well.
So, uh...
...how do I bust you out?
Lilith.
Lilith?
Father, she's trapped
neck deep in the pit.
Won't be easy.
Lilith.
Lilith can break the seals.
Yeah, okay.
But what do I do?
You must find me a child.
A very special child.
What do you mean?
What child?
You gotta be kidding me.
What?
Get this.
"St. Mary's abandoned in '72
after a priest disemboweled eight nuns. "
What's black and white
and red all over?
That's not funny.
The priest said it wasn't his fault.
He said a demon made him do it.
He remembered the demon's name.
- Yeah?
- Azazel.
Wow, so Lilith, Yellow Eyes,
all the A-listers are paying visits.
- Gives the joint credibility.
- It's where the final seal goes down.
Well, it's good enough for me. Let's
pack up Nurse Betty and hit the road.
Hey, maybe, uh- Uh-
- What?
- Maybe we can find another demon.
Sam. No.
That blubbery, don't-hurt-me crap,
it's just an act.
- She's playing you.
- I'm not so sure.
There's still a hell bitch snoozing
in there.
I mean, come on.
It's not like you haven't
done this before, right?
No. Please, don't.
Just listen to me, okay?
My name is Cindy McCellen.
I'm a nurse in the NICU
over Enfield Memorial.
I have a husband, Matthew.
We've been married six years.
He's gonna be worried.
I don't know you,
I'm not gonna tell anybody anything.
Just, please let me go.
No! No! No!
Please. No. Ple-
No! No!
You asked to see me?
Ahem, yeah.
Listen, I, uh, need something.
Anything you wish.
- I need you to take me to see Sam.
- Why?
- Something I gotta talk to him about.
- What's that?
The BM I took this morning,
what's it to you? Just make it snappy.
I don't think that's wise.
Well, I didn't ask you for your opinion.
Have you forgotten what happened
the last time you met?
No.
That's the whole point.
I'm gonna do whatever
you mooks want, okay?
I just need to tie up this one thing.
Five minutes. That's all I need.
No.
What do you mean "no"?
- You saying that I'm trapped here?
- You can go wherever you want.
- Super. I wanna go see Sam.
- Except there.
- I wanna take a walk.
- I'll go with you.
- Alone.
- No.
You know what? Screw this noise.
I'm out of here.
Through what door?
Damn it.
What are you, a 12-year-old girl?
Play it.
Mind your own business.
Let me out!
God, I wish she would just shut up.
Well, that can be arranged.
Let me out!
I don't get it. All the demons you cut,
what do you think happens to the host?
- How is this different?
- That supposed to make me feel better?
I know you're having a tough time here.
But we're on the final lap.
Now is not the time
to grow a persqueeter.
Would you drop the frigging attitude?
I'm about to bleed and drink
an innocent woman while she watches.
And save the world as a result.
I know, I just-
I'm starting to think...
- ... maybe Dean was right.
- About what?
About everything.
We're gonna see this through,
right, Sam?
Sam?
Let me out! Let me out!
Son of a bitch.
Quit hurling feces like a howler monkey,
would you?
- It's unbecoming.
- Let me out of here.
I told you, too dangerous out there.
Demons on the prowl.
I been getting my ass kicked all year,
now you're sweating my safety?
You're lying.
I wanna see my brother.
That's ill advised.
You know, I am so sick of your crap
riddles and your smug fat face.
What the hell is going on, huh?
Why can't I see Sam?
And how am I gonna ice Lilith?
You're not...
...going to ice Lilith.
- What?
- Lilith's going to break the final seal.
Fait accompli, at this point.
Train's left the station.
But, me and Sam, we can stop-
- You don't wanna stop it, do you?
- Nope. Never did.
The end is nigh,
the Apocalypse is coming, kiddo...
...to a theater near you.
What was all that crap
about saving seals?
Grunts on the ground,
we couldn't tell them the whole truth...
...we'd have a full-scale rebellion
on our hands.
I mean, think about it. Would we really
let 65 seals get broken...
...unless senior management
wanted it that way?
- But why?
- Why not?
The Apocalypse.
Poor name, bad marketing,
it puts people off.
When all it is, is Ali-Foreman.
On a slightly larger scale.
And we like our chances.
When our side wins, and we will...
...it's paradise on Earth.
What's not to like about that?
And what happens to all the people
during your little pissing contest?
Well, can't make an omelet
without cracking a few eggs.
In this case, truckloads of eggs,
but you get the picture.
Look...
...it happens.
This isn't the first planetary enema
we've delivered.
Oh, no, probably shouldn't try to bash
my skull in with that thing.
Wouldn't end up too pleasant for you.
What about Sam?
He won't go quietly. He'll stop Lilith.
Sam...
...has a part to play.
A very important part.
He may need a little nudging
in the right direction...
...but I'll make sure he plays it.
What does that mean?
- What are you gonna do to him?
- Sam, Sam, Sam.
Marcia, Marcia, Marcia.
Forget about him, would you?
You have larger concerns.
Why do you think I'm confiding in you?
You're still vital, Dean.
We weren't lying about your destiny.
Just omitted a few pertinent details.
But nothing's changed.
You are chosen.
You will stop it.
Just not Lilith
or the Apocalypse, that's all.
Which means?
Lucifer.
You're going to stop Lucifer.
You're our own little Russell Crowe,
complete with surly attitude.
And when it's over...
...and when you've won...
...your rewards will be unimaginable.
Peace. Happiness.
Two virgins and 70 sluts.
Trust me, one day
we'll look back on this and laugh.
Tell me something.
Where's God in all this?
God?
God has left the building.
Howdy.
Lady, uh, this is private property.
You're not supposed to be here.
But I'm here for Mass.
And so are you.
You can't reach him, Dean.
You're outside your coverage zone.
What are you gonna do to Sam?
Nothing.
He's gonna do it to himself.
What's that supposed to mean?
Oh, right, right.
Gotta toe the company line.
Why are you here, Cass?
We've been through much together,
you and I.
And I just wanted to say I'm sorry
it ended like this.
Sorry?
It's Armageddon, Cass.
You need a bigger word than sorry.
Try to understand.
This is long foretold.
- This is your-
- Destiny?
Don't give me that holy crap.
Destiny, God's plan...
...it's a bunch of lies,
you poor, stupid son of a bitch.
It's just a way for your bosses
to keep me, and keep you, in line.
You know what's real?
People.
Families. That's real.
- And you're gonna watch them all burn?
- What is so worth saving?
I see nothing but pain here.
I see inside you.
I see your guilt, your anger, confusion.
In paradise, all is forgiven.
You'll be at peace.
Even with Sam.
You can take your peace...
...and shove it up your lily-white ass.
Because I'll take the pain and the guilt,
I'll even take Sam as is.
It's a lot better than being some
Stepford bitch in paradise.
This is simple, Cass.
No more crap
about being a good soldier.
There is a right and there is a wrong here
and you know it!
Look at me. You know it!
Now, you were gonna help me once,
weren't you?
You were gonna warn me,
before they dragged you to Bible camp.
Help me now, please.
- What would you have me do?
- Get me to Sam. We can stop this...
- ... before it's too late.
- I do that, we will all be hunted.
We'll all be killed.
If there is anything worth dying for...
...this is it.
You spineless...
...soulless son of a bitch.
What do you care about dying?
You're already dead. We're done.
- Dean.
- We're done.
Sam. It's time.
Are we doing this or not?
- Give me a minute to think.
- Sam.
Give me a damn minute, Ruby!
Better think fast.
First unread message.
Listen to me, you bloodsucking freak.
Dad always said I'd either
have to save you or kill you.
Well, I'm giving you fair warning.
I'm done trying to save you.
You're a monster, Sam. A vampire.
You're not you anymore,
and there's no going back.
Do it.
Thank God.
Help!
Castiel!
Would you mind explaining
just what the hell you're doing?
He won't be gone long.
We have to find Sam now.
- Where is he?
- I don't know, but I know who does.
We have to stop him, Dean.
From killing Lilith.
- But Lilith's gonna break the final seal.
- Lilith is the final seal.
She dies, the end begins.
Oh, yeah? Really?
At the same time? Really? Wow.
- That sounds moist.
Well, it can be.
- Uh, what are your rates?
- We can get you one girl...
...one hour, 1000.
Okay. Then I'll take 20 girls...
...for the whole night.
I'm not sure you can afford that.
Lady, sometimes you gotta live
like there's no tomorrow.
- Wait. This isn't supposed to happen.
- Sir?
No, lady,
this is definitely supposed to happen.
But I just gotta call you back.
All right.
Don't be afraid.
We're going to save the world.
- St. Mary's? What is that, a convent?
Yeah.
You guys aren't supposed to be there.
You're not in this story.
Yeah, well,
we're making it up as we go.
What? Oh, man. Not again.
It's the Archangel.
I'll hold him off, I'll hold them all off.
Just stop Sam!
I've been waiting for this...
...for a very long time.
Then give me your best shot.
Sam!
Sam.
Sammy.
Dean?
What are you waiting for?
Now! Do it now, damn it!
Sam!
Sam, now!
You turned yourself into a freak.
Ha, ha. A monster.
And now you're not gonna bite?
Ha, ha. I'm sorry,
but that is honestly adorable.
What the hell?
I can't believe it.
Ruby, what's going on?
You did it.
I mean, it was a little touch-and-go
there for a while, but you did it.
What? What? What did I do?
You opened the door.
And now he's free at last.
- He's free at last.
- No, no, no.
He- Lilith, I stopped her. I killed her.
And it is written, that the first demon
shall be the last seal.
And you bust her open.
Now guess who's coming to dinner?
Oh, my God.
Guess again.
You don't even know
how hard this was.
All the demons out for my head.
No one knew.
I was the best
of those sons of bitches.
The most loyal.
Not even Alastair knew.
Only Lilith.
Yeah, I'm sure you're a little angry
right now, but I mean, come on, Sam.
Even you have to admit I'm-
I'm awesome.
You bitch. You lying bitch.
Don't hurt yourself, Sammy.
It's useless.
You shot your payload on the boss.
The blood...
...you poisoned me.
No.
It wasn't the blood.
It was you and your choices.
I just gave you the options,
and you chose the right path every time.
You didn't need the feather to fly.
You had it in you the whole time,
Dumbo.
I know it's hard to see it now...
...but this is a miracle.
So long coming.
Everything Azazel did, and Lilith did,
just to get you here.
And you were the only one
who could do it.
Why?
- Why me?
- Because.
Because it had to be you, Sammy.
It always had to be you.
You saved us.
You set him free
and he's gonna be grateful.
He's gonna repay you in ways
that you can't even imagine.
- You're too late.
- I don't care.
I'm sorry.
- Sammy, let's go.
- Dean...
...he's coming.