i dragged you out of hell.
i can throw you back in.
you should show me
some respect.
in the coming months,you will
have more decisions to make.
sam:
dean,what was it like?
what,hell?
i don't know.
i-i must have blacked it out.
i don't remember
a damn thing.
this is uriel,
a specialist.
specializing in what?
both of you,you need to leave
this town immediately.
why?
because we're about
to destroy it.
the only reason you're still
alive,sam winchester,
is because
you've been useful.
the moment that ceases
to be true,
then i will
turn you to dust.
ask dean what he remembers
from hell.
hello?
is anybody there?
um,hello?
it just doesn't make
any sense,dean.
i mean,
why would uriel tell me
you remembered hell
if you didn't?
maybe because he's a
prick -- might have
something to do with it.
maybe,but he's
still an angel.
yeah,an angel who was ready
to level an entire town.
look,i don't know what --
man: radical.
what else can i get
you guys?
uh,i think we're good.
yeah?
you want to try a couple
of fryer bombs
or a chipotle
chili changa?
no,no,
we're still good.
okay,awesome.
sam,honestly,
i have no idea why uriel
told you what he did,okay?
right.
what?
okay.
fine. then look me
in the eye
and tell me
you don't remember a thing
from your time
down under.
i don't remember a thing
from my time down under.
i don't remember,sam!
look,dean,
i just want to help.
you know everything i do. okay?
that's all there is.
outstanding.
dessert time?
huh? am i right?
dude.
listen,bros.
you have got to try
our ice cream extreme.
it's extreme.
uh,no extremities,
please.
just the --
check?
all right,awesome.
thanks.
all right,
so,where do we go from here?
i'm not sure.
uh,looks like
it's been pretty quiet lately.
no signs of demon activity,
no omens or portents i can see.
that's good news
for once.
yeah,just
the typical smattering
of crank ufo sightings
and one possible
vengeful spirit.
here,check this out.
uh...
up in concrete,
washington,
eyewitness reports
of a ghost
that's been haunting the showers
of a women's health facility.
the victim claims
that the ghost
threw her down
a flight of stairs.
i can see
you're very interested.
women,showers.
we got to save
these people.
i'm not surprised
the spirit world
chose to make contact
with me.
i'm something of a...
natural sensitive.
i can sense that about you,
candace,that whole...
sensitive thing.
so,what did you say
you're calling your book?
oh,well,um...
well,the working
title is...
"supernatural."
yeah,i've been crossing
the country,
gathering stories
like yours.
but,anyways,you were telling
me about your encounter.
yes. well [sighs]
once i saw the apparition,
that's when i started
to run.
and you said
the ghost chased you?
not just that.
it knew my name.
it kept yelling,
"mrs. armstrong!
mrs. armstrong!"
and that's when i hit
the stairs and fell.
you fell?
the ghost didn't push you.
oh,i don't --
i don't know.
i mean,i think it did.
maybe.
did you feel like it meant
to hurt you,
like it was violent,or...
it was a ghost.
i'm lucky to be alive.
anyway,i was at the bottom
of the stairs,
and that's when
it got weird.
[ chuckles ]
it helped me up.
say again?
yeah.
it helped me up.
and it kept saying
over and over,
"please,
don't tell my mom."
yeah,that's weird.
well,you pick up
anything?
no emf in the shower
or anywhere else.
this house is clean.
yeah.
i'm not surprised.
i kind of got the feeling
back there
that crazy pushed mrs. armstrong
down the stairs.
i got to tell you,
i'm pretty disappointed.
[ exhales sharply ]
you wanted to save naked women.
damn right i wanted to save
some naked women.
[ chuckles lightly ]
come on,guys,get him!
boy: i got him!
i got him!
run,forrest,run!
sorry,dean,but i
don't think anything's
going on around here.
gus: how the hell was i supposed
to get a look at it?
it grabbed me from behind
and threw me into a tree!
something's going on.
man: yeah,okay,gus.
i understand you got shook up.
anyone would be.
but don't you think it --
don't you think
it had to be a bear?
i know a damn bear track
when i see one!
this thing didn't leave
bear tracks!
its feet were huge!
now,gus --
it was bigfoot,hal --
the bigfoot!
gus,you're not talking
sense here.
there's a bigfoot out there,
damn it,
and he's a son
of a bitch!
excuse us.
fbi.
what?
yes,sir.
we're here about the...
that.
about bigfoot?
that's right.
sir,can you tell me exactly
where this happened?
yes,i can.
what the hell's going on
in this town?
first there's a ghost
that's not real
and now a bigfoot
sighting?
well,every hunter worth
his salt knows bigfoot's a hoax.
well,maybe somebody's
pumping lsd
into the town
water supply.
okay.
what do you suppose
made that?
that,uh...
is a big foot.
okay.
so,what -- bigfoot breaks
into a liquor store,
jonesing for some hooch?
amaretto and irish cream.
he's a girl-drink drunk.
hey. check this out.
he took the whole
porno rack?
well,i'll say it again.
what the hell is going on
in this town?
i got nothing.
it's got to be
a joke,right?
some big-ass mother
in a gorilla suit?
or it's a bigfoot.
you know,and he's some kind of
a alcoholo-porno addict.
kind of like
a deep-woods duchovny.
a little young
for busty asian beauties.
what's this,like a
"harry and the hendersons" deal?
hello?
sam: hello!
um,could we...
you know what?
are your parents home?
nope.
no.
um...
have you seen
a really,really furry...
is he in trouble?!
no.
[ chuckling ]
no,no,no.
not at all.
we just -- we wanted
to make sure he was okay.
exactly.
audrey:
he's my teddy bear.
i think he's sick.
wow. uh...
amazing.
'cause you know what?
we...
are,uh...
teddy bear doctors.
really?
can you please take
a look at him?
sure.
sure. yeah.
he's in my bedroom.
he's pretty grumpy.
teddy?
there's some nice doctors
here to see you.
close the friggin' door!
see what i mean?
all i ever wanted
was a teddy
which was big,real,
and talked.
but now he's sad
all the time --
not "ouch" sad,
but ouch-in-the-head sad --
says weird stuff,
and smells like the bus.
um,little girl...
audrey!
audrey.
how exactly did
your teddy become real?
i wished for it.
you wished for it?
at the wishing well.
look at this.
[ chuckling ]
you believe this crap?
not really.
it is a terrible world.
why am i here?!
for tea parties!
tea parties?
is that all there is?
[ guns firing on tv ]
audrey,give us
a second,okay?
okay.
are we...
should we...
are we gonna kill
this teddy bear?
how? do we shoot it,
burn it?
i don't know.
both?
how do we even know
that's gonna work?
i don't want some giant,
flaming,pissed-off teddy
on our hands.
yeah.
besides,i get the feeling
that the bear
isn't really the,you know,
core problem here.
audrey.
where are your parents?
my mom wished they were in bali,
so i think they're in bali.
okay,well...
i'm really sorry to have
to break this to you,but...
your bear is sick.
yeah,he's --
he's got...
lollipop disease.
it's not uncommon
for a bear his size.
but,see,
it's really contagious.
yeah,so,
is there someone,
maybe a grown-up,
that you can stay with
while we treat him?
mrs. hurley lives
down the street.
perfect.
good,yeah,good.
uh,we'd like you to stay there
for a few days,okay?
okay.
oh,and,audrey?
where is this wishing well?
think it works?
got a better explanation
for teddy back there?
well,there's one way
to find out.
what are you
gonna wish for?
shh!
not supposed to tell.
[ sniffing ]
somebody order a footlong
italian with jalapeÑo?
that'd be me.
i think it works,dude.
that was pretty specific.
the teddy bear,
the sandwich...
mm.
i'm guessing this.
i'm guessing that.
well,that definitely
goes on the list.
what are we
supposed to do,huh?
stop people's wishes
from coming true?
sounds like kind of
a douche-ey thing to do.
yeah,maybe.
but come on,man.
when has something like this
ever come without a price tag?
and usually a deadly one.
i don't know.
it's a damn good sandwich.
all right. fine.
we'll put a hold
on the wishing
till we figure out
what's going on.
uh,gentlemen,gentlemen.
i'm sorry.
we don't allow people
to eat outside food here.
well,i am certainly not gonna
eat the inside food here.
health department.
you,my friend,
have a rat infestation.
we're gonna have to shut
this place down
under emergency hazard
code 56c.
rats?!
typical fountain,
plaster buddha.
nothing i can see.
yes,nothing.
we keep a clean place here.
sir,i'm gonna have
to ask you to leave
during the preliminary
investigation,okay?
thank you.
oh,come on.
aren't you
a little bit tempted?
[ chuckles ] no.
wouldn't be real.
i wouldn't trust it.
i don't know.
that bear seemed pretty real.
yeah.
come on,if you could
wish yourself back,
you know,
before it all started...
think about it --
you'd be some big yuppie lawyer
with a nice car
and a white picket fence.
not what i'd wish for.
seriously?
it's too late to go back
to our old lives,dean.
i'm not that guy anymore.
all right,well,what,then?
hmm? what would sammy wish for?
lilith's head on a plate.
bloody.
okay. [ sniffs ]
what is that?
some kind of old coin.
i don't recognize the markings.
damn.
lift with your legs.
is that little mother
welded on there?
huh.
man: hey,hey,hey,
what is this?!
you are gonna break
my fountain!
sir,i don't want to slap you
with a 44/16,but i will.
all right,thanks.
let me see that.
i got an idea.
ho!
damn!
coin's magical.
boy,i'd say.
i think it's hoodoo
that's protecting the well.
i don't think
we can destroy this.
all right,here.
you got to look into this.
where you going?
something just
occurred to me.
aah!
what?
don't worry,ma'am.
i'm with the health
department.
so,you can turn it
on and off,huh?
how -- how did you know
that i was...
you actually walked up
to a wishing well,
dropped a dime,
and wished to be invisible
so you could spy on women
in the shower?
n-no. no.
n-no,no,no.
that's crazy.
[ exhales sharply ]
put on some pants.
and stay visible.
o-- okay.
you better run!
you got a problem,
mister?
what? no.
dean?
you all right?
[ strained voice ]
the wishes turn bad,sam.
the wishes turn very bad.
the sandwich,huh?
the coin was babylonian.
it's cursed.
i found some fragments
of a legend.
i'm good.
the,uh...
the serpent is tiamat,
which is the,uh,babylonian god
of primordial chaos.
i guess their,uh,priests
were working
some serious black magic.
they made the coin?
yeah,to sow
the seeds of chaos.
whoever tosses a coin
in the wishing well,
makes a wish,
it turns on the well.
then it starts granting wishes
to all comers.
but the wishes get twisted.
you ask for a talking teddy...
you get a bipolar nut job.
and you get e. coli.
mm.
this thing has turned
more than one town
upside down
over the centuries.
it's even wiped a few
off the map.
i mean,one person gets
their wish,it's trouble,
but everybody
gets their wish...
it's chaos.
mm-hmm.
any way to stop it?
yeah. one way.
we got to find
the first wisher.
whoever dropped the coin in
and made the first wish,
they're the only ones
who can pull it back out
and reverse the wishes.
so for now,we've got a couple
of nutso dreams come true,
but once the word gets out
about the well,
things are just gonna get
crazier and crazier.
sam: dean,wake up!
what?
i'm up.
sleep well?
yeah.
tan,rested,and ready.
dean,come on,man.
you think i can't see it?
see what?
the nightmares,
the drinking.
i'm with you 24/7.
i know something's
going on.
sam,please.
uriel wasn't lying,
but you are.
you remember hell,
don't you?
what do you want
from me,huh? what?
the truth,dean.
i mean,i'm your brother.
i just wish you'd talk to me.
careful what
you wish for.
cute.
come on,can we stow
the couples therapy,huh?
we're on a job.
i want to work.
what do you got?
please?
we got teddy bear,
uh,lottery guy,
invisible pervert guy.
they all must have wished
sometime in the last two weeks.
but who wished first,
and how are we
supposed to know
who else wished
for what when?
well,it helps when they
announce it in the paper.
goes back a month.
wesley mondale
and ms. hope lynn casey
have announced
their surprise engagement.
ah,true love.
[ chuckles ]
best lead we got.
[ mid-tempo theme song
playing on tv ]
wes,are you sleeping?
hmm?
oh,uh,no.
no,no.
i was just,um --
i was just
resting my eyes.
[ chuckles ] i thought
you might want a snack.
oh.
oh,wow,hope,
you didn't have to do that.
i wanted to.
well,no,i...
i had to.
because i love you more
than anything,lover.
yes.
um,hope,sit down,okay?
yes,wes.
um...
hope,uh,are you happy?
i love you more
than anything.
i know.
and i love you.
very much.
that's why i want you to start
doing things that make --
that made you
happy before.
yes,wes,
i'll try to be happier.
i'll start right away.
no,no,no,
that's not what i mean.
i-i'm talk--
oh,wes,please.
[ voice breaking ]
please don't be angry with me.
you know,i'd just die,
i'd just die,i'd die!
no,no,no.
don't -- i'm -- i'm not angry.
i'm not angry!
no.
then let me make it up
to you,wes.
let me make it right.
no,no,i'm -- i'm...
i'll get it.
wes!
you didn't tell me that
you called the florists
for the wedding.
huh?
you're the best!
mmm! ah!
i'm gonna go get
my folders.
uh,o-- okay.
wesley,how's it going?
it's "we...
s-s."
aren't you the guys
from the health department?
yeah.
and florists
on the side.
plus fbi.
and on thursdays,
we're teddy bear doctors.
huh?
doesn't matter who we are.
what matters is what we know.
so,coin collector,
huh,wes?
oh. yeah. my...
grandfather
gave them to me.
did you happen to lose one
of those coins lately?
and by "lose," i mean drop
into a wishing well
at lucky chen's
and make a wish on it?
no,i -- i don't know
what you're,uh,talking about.
hope: okay,now.
i have a lot of ideas,
but,you know,we don't have
all the money in the world.
wes is between jobs
right now.
means more time for me.
you know,i'm thinking
a japanese-ey ikebana
kind of thing.
yes. i can see it.
yeah.
so,hope,uh,tell us
how you two lovebirds met.
oh,best day
of my life.
i bet.
yeah! it's
the funniest thing.
we both grew up here,
but i never really knew
who he was.
not by name anyway.
until one day last month,
it was like
i just [sighs]
i just saw him
for the first time.
he was just...glowing.
oh,just glowing.
uh,babe,can you get us
some coffee?
yeah,anything,yeah.
oh. okay.
okay.
mm-hmm.
oh,okay.
oh. mm-mm,okay.
okay. okay.
yeah.
sam: wes,we know.
so tell us the truth.
my -- my grandfather found
the coin in north africa,
you know,world war ii.
and,uh,
he brought it back.
he,um,he said it was
a real wish-granting coin,
but that nobody
should ever use it.
eh...
it was all i had,
and when he died,i thought,
"well,you know what?
why not give the coin a shot?"
yeah,well,now you're
gonna wish it back.
ha ha,no,i'm not.
if you don't stop it,
something bad's gonna happen.
something bad --
like us.
we really wish
you'd come with us.
i don't get it.
so,my wish came true.
why does that have to be
a bad thing?
because the wishes
go south,wes.
your town
is going insane.
come on. you're gonna sit there
and tell me
that your relationship with hope
is functional,
that it's what you
wished for?
i wished she would love me
more than anything.
yeah,and,uh,
how is that going?
that seem healthy
to you?
well,it's a hell
of a lot better
than when she didn't know
i was alive.
you're not supposed to get
what you want,man,
not like this.
nobody is.
that's what
the coin does.
it takes your heart's desires
and it twists it back on you.
you hear of the whole
"be careful what you wish for"?
did we just
hit something?
i didn't see anything.
ow!
ow.
[ mockingly ]
"careful what you wish for."
[ normal voice ]
you know who says that?
good-looking jerks
like you guys,
the ones who've got it
so easy
because you happen
to be handsome.
easy?easy?
yeah. women --
women look at you,right?
they notice you.
believe us,
we do not have it easy.
we are miserable.
we never get what we want.
in fact,we have to fight
tooth and nail
just to keep
whatever it is we got.
but you know what? maybe
that's the whole point,wes.
yeah,people are people 'cause
they're miserable bastards,
'cause they never get
what they really want.
right,yeah,you get what
you want,you get crazy.
take a look at michael jackson,
hmm? or hasselhoff.
you know what?
hope loves me now -- completely.
and it's awesome.
besides,look around.
where's all this,uh,insanity
you guys were talking about?
just hit the button!
well,that should
cover it.
kneel before todd!
stop it!
fine!
i'll handle todd.
you get wes to lucky chen's.
go!
right.
hey,kid!
can i talk to you
for a second?
get out of my way!
okay. hey,
i can dig it,todd.
it -- it's todd,right?
look,i-i know the score.
okay? they're --
they're bullying you.
every day.
every day!
you do not know what it's like!
no,no,i don't. but,you know,
you're you and i'm me,
so [chuckles]
couldn't stop them.
i couldn't do anything.
then audrey elmer told me
the wishing well worked.
okay,okay. look --
look,i get it.
they're -- they're
mean little jerks,huh?
but they're not superhuman
like you.
you see,with great power
comes great,great -- ohh!
that -- that -- that kid
turned over that car
like -- like
it was nothing.
you should have seen
the teddy bear.
now,come on. fun's over.
time to pull the coin.
wes!
well,why can't we
just get what we want?!
because that's life,wes.
ugh!
hope?
i had to do it,didn't i?
he was gonna make you
wish away our love.
hey,kid!
i didn't want
to have to do this.
ohh!
you wished a man dead?
i love you more
than anything.
stop saying that.
stop it!
[ voice breaking ]
but i do.
more than anything.
more than me.
more than life.
oh,wes.
don't hate me.
it'll be okay.
i'll make it okay.
it's gonna be okay.
okay.
follow my lead
and you won't have a problem.
come on.
okay,man,no more!
no more,okay?
i wouldn't mess with this kid
any more if i were you.
stay back!
hope.
do i know you?
it shouldn't cause
any more problems.
audrey's parents
are back from bali.
looks like all the wishes
are gone.
and so are we.
hang on a second.
what?
you were right.
about what?
i shouldn't have lied
to you.
i do remember everything
that happened to me in the pit.
everything.
so tell me about it.
no.
uh...
i won't lie anymore.
but i'm not gonna talk
about it.
dean,look,you can't just
shoulder this thing alone.
you got to let me help.
how?
do you really think
that a little heart-to-heart,
some sharing and caring,
is gonna change anything?
hmm?
somehow...heal me?
i'm not talking
about a bad day here.
i know that.
the things that i saw...
...there aren't words.
there is no forgetting.
there's no
making it better.
because it is
right here...
forever.
you wouldn't understand.
and i could never
make you understand.
so i am sorry.