Dad wants us to pick
up where he left off.
Saving people, hunting things.
The family business.
Before dad died, he told me something.
Something about you.
What's did he tell you?
He said that I might
have to kill you, Sam.
What the hell is that supposed to mean?
I don't know.
Did he know the demon's plans for me?
Am I supposed to go
dark side or something?
Who are you? Please.
You're in danger.
What's your name? Ava Wilson.
You must be one of us. One of who?
One of the psychics like me.
There are others like us out there,
And we're all part of something.
I'm not part of anything, okay?
Do you see this?
I am getting married in eight weeks.
You can't run from this,
And you can't protect me.
I can try.
Maybe I can help.
You've done all you can.
Just go back to your
fiancé. You'll be safe there.
Promise me you'll call, then.
I promise.
Ava...
Most of the stuff is up here.
Still can't believe
you're closing this house.
My parents got engaged here.
My grandparents too.
Yeah, a lot of people did.
Boxes are at the end of
the hall. Need any help?
No, ma'am. I got it.
He's gonna take our toys?
Only the ones you
don't play with anymore.
It's not like you don't
have enough already.
Son of a bitch. Son of a bitch.
Watch your mouth.
Maggie said it first.
Watch your mouth too, Maggie.
Good night, Tabitha.
Oh my god! Yes, yes are you there?
Please you have to send someone now.
There's been an accident.
A man fell down my stairs,
and I don't know if he's...
His head is like
completely turned around.
Tyler, don't look! Don't look!
Oh yes, yes!
As soon as possible.
Just hurry, please hurry!
I don't know, I didn't
see how it happened.
Yeah.
Okay. Thanks, Ellen.
What did she have to
say? She got nothing.
Me, I've been checking every
database I can think of,
Federal, state, and local.
No one's heard anything
about Ava. She's just...
Into thin air, you know?
What about you?
No, same as before. Sorry, man.
Ellen did have one thing.
A hotel in Cornwall, Connecticut,
Two freak accidents in
the past three weeks.
Yeah, what's that have to do with Ava?
It's a job.
I mean, a lady drowned in the bathtub,
Then a few days ago, a
guy falls down the stairs,
Head turns a complete 180,
Which isn't exactly normal, you know?
Look, I don't know,
Dean, it might be nothing,
But I told Ellen we'd
think about checking it out.
You did? Yeah.
You seem surprised. Yeah,
it's just, you know...
Not the patented Sam
Winchester way, is it?
What way is that?
Just figured after Ava,
there'd be, you know, more
Angst and droopy music and
staring out the rainy windows.
I'll shut up now.
Look,
I'm the one who told
her to go back home.
Now her fiancé's dead,
And some demon has taken
her off to god knows where,
You know?
We've been looking for a month now,
And we got nothing.
So I'm not giving up on her, but
I'm not gonna let
other people die either.
We got to save as many people as we can.
Wow, that attitude is just
way too healthy for me.
I'm officially
uncomfortable now. Thank you.
All right, call Ellen.
Tell her we'll take it.
Dude, this is sweet.
I never get to work jobs like this.
Like what?
Old-School haunted houses. You know,
Fog, secret passage ways,
Sissy  british accents.
Might even run into Fred and
Daphne while we're inside.
Daphne... Love her.
Hey, wait a sec.
I'm not so sure haunted's the problem.
What do you mean?
You see this pattern here?
That's a quincunx. It's a five-Spot.
Five-Spot. Yeah.
That's for hoodoo spellwork, isn't it?
Right. Hey, you fill
this thing with bloodweed,
You got a powerful charm
to ward off enemies.
Except I don't see any bloodweed.
Don't you think this
place is a little too
White-Meat for hoodoo?
Maybe.
May I help you?
Hi. Yeah, I'd like a room
for a couple of nights.
Hey!
Sorry about that. No problem.
Well, congratulations. You could
be some of our final guests.
Well, sounds vaguely ominous.
No, I'm sorry. I mean, we're
closing at the end of the month.
Let me guess. You guys
are here antiquing?
How'd you know? You just look the type.
So, a king-Size bed?
What? No. No, no.
Two singles. We're just brothers.
Oh. Oh, I'm so sorry.
What did you mean that
we looked the type?
You know,
Speaking of antiques, you have a really
Interesting urn on the front porch.
Where did you get that?
You know, I have no idea.
It's been there forever.
Here you go, Mr. Mahogoff.
You'll be staying in room 237.
Sherwin, could you show these
gentlemen to their rooms?
Let me guess...
Antiquers?
I can give you a hand with that bag.
I got it. Okay.
So the hotel's closing up, huh?
Yep. Miss Susan tried
to make a go of it,
But the guests just don't
come like they used to.
Still, it's a damn shame. Oh yeah?
It may not look it anymore,
but this place was a palace.
Two different vice-Presidents
laid their heads on our pillows.
My parents worked here. I
practically grew up here.
I'm gonna miss it.
Here's your room.
Thanks.
You're not gonna cheap
out on me, are you, boy?
What the...
What?
That's normal.
Why the hell would anyone stay here?
I'm amazed they kept
in business this long.
All right, victim number one,
Joan Edison, 43 years old,
A realtor handling
the sale of the hotel.
And victim number two
was Larry Williams,
Moving some stuff out to goodwill.
Well, there's a connexion. They're
both tied up in shutting the place down.
Yeah, maybe someone here
doesn't want to leave,
And they're using hoodoo to fight back.
Who do you think our witch
doctor is. This Susan lady?
Doesn't seem likely.
I mean, she's the one selling.
So, what then, Sherwin?
I don't know.
Of course, the most
troubling question is,
Why do these people assume we're gay?
You are kind of butch.
Probably think you're over compensating.
Right.
Hey.
Look at that. More hoodoo.
Hi, there. Hi.
Everything  okay with your room?
Yeah, yeah. Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, everything's great. Good.
Well, I was just in the
middle of packing. So...
Hey, are those antique dolls?
'Cause this one, this one here,
He's got a major doll
collection back home.
Don't you? Huh?
Big time. Big time.
You think he could come in, well,
we could come in and take a look?
I don't know. Please?
I mean, he loves them.
He's not gonna tell you this,
But he's always dressing them
up in little tiny outfits.
You'd make his day. She would. Huh? Huh?
It's true.
Okay. Come on in. All right.
All right!
Wow.
This is a lot of dolls.
They're nice, you know.
They're not supercreepy at all.
I suppose they are a little creepy.
But they've been in the family forever.
A lot of sentimental
value. What is this?
The hotel? Yeah, that's right.
Exact replica, custom-Built.
His head got twisted around.
What happened to it?
Tyler, probably.
Mommy.
Maggie's being mean.
Tyler, tell her I said to be nice, okay?
Hey, Tyler. I see you broke
your doll. You want me to fix it?
I didn't break it. I found it like that.
Well, maybe Maggie did it.
No, neither of us did it.
Grandma would get mad if we broke him.
Tyler, she wouldn't get mad. Grandma?
Grandma Rose. These were all her toys.
Oh, really?
Where's grandma Rose now?
Up in her room.
You know, I'd really
love to talk to Rose
About her incredible doll... No.
I  mean,
I'm  afraid that's impossible.
My mother's been very sick, and
she's not taking any visitors.
What do you think?
Dolls, hoodoo,
Mysterious shut-In grandma?
Well, dolls are used in all
kind of voodoo and hoodoo,
Like curses and binding spells.
Yeah, maybe we found our witch doctor.
I'll go see what I can dig upon granny.
You get online, check old obits,
freak accidents. That sort of things.
See if she's whacked
anybody before. Right.
Don't go surfing porn. It's
not the kind of whacking I mean.
I've been meaning to ask...
What sort of renovations
are you planning?
They never told you?
Told me what?
Miss Thompson, we plan
on demolishing the hotel.
Oh. I see.
Excuse me.
What happened?
The maid went into turn down
the sheets, and he was just
Hanging there. That's awful.
He was a guest?
He worked for the company
that bought the place.
I don't understand. What?
Had a lot of bad luck around here.
Look, if you'd like to check
out, I'll give you a full refund.
No, thanks. I don't scare that easy.
There's been another one.
Some guy just hung himself in his room.
Yeah. I saw.
We got figure this out and fast.
What did you find out about granny?
You're bossy.
What?
You're short.
Are you drunk? Yeah.
So?
Stupid.
Dude, what are you thinking?
We're working a case.
That guy who hung himself...
I couldn't save him. What
are you talking about?
You didn't know. You
couldn't have done anything.
That's an excuse, Dean.
I should have found a way to save him.
I should have saved Ava too.
Well, you can't save
everyone. Even you said that.
No, Dean, you don't
understand, all right?
The more people I save,
the more I can change.
Change what? My destiny, Dean.
All right, time for
bed. Come on, sasquatch.
Come on.
I need you to watch out
for me. Yeah, I always do.
No. No, no, no. You have
to watch out for me...
All right?
And if I ever turn into
something that I'm not...
You have to kill me. Sam...
Dean, dad told you
to do it. You have to.
Yeah, well, dad's an ass.
He never should have said
anything. I mean, you don't do that.
You don't lay that
kinda crap on your kids.
No, he was right to say it.
Who knows what I might become?
Even now, everyone around me dies.
Well, I'm not dying, okay?
And neither are you. Come on, sit down.
No, please, Dean, you're
the only one who can do it.
Promise me. Don't ask that of me.
Dean, please.
You have to promise me.
I promise.
Thanks.
Thank you...
Find any good antiques?
No, no. Got distracted.
Have a drink.
Yeah, thanks.
So, poor guy, huh, killing himself?
That kind of thing seems
to be going around lately.
Yeah. Yeah, I heard
about the other ones.
It's almost like this hotel
is cursed or something.
Every hotel has its spilled blood.
If people only knew what's going on
In some of those rooms
they've checked into.
You know a lot about
the place, don't you?
Down to the last nail.
I'd love to hear some stories.
Boy,
You should never say that to an old man.
This is little miss Susan
and her mother, Rose.
Happier days.
They're not happy now?
Well, would you be, leaving
the only home you ever knew?
I don't know. I never really knew one.
Well, this is Rose's home.
Been in the family over a century.
Used to be the family estate,
And now she gets to live in
some senior-Living graveyard,
And they tear this place down.
That's too bad.
I hear Rose isn't feeling well either.
No, she isn't.
What's wrong with her?
It's not my business to say.
Who's this?
That's Rose
When she was a little girl.
Who's that with her?
That's her nanny, Marie.
She looked after Rose
more than her own mother.
How you feeling, Sammy?
I guess mixing whiskey and jager
wasn't such a gangbuster idea, was it?
I'll bet you don't remember a
thing from last night, do you?
No, I can still taste the tequila.
You know, there's a really
good hangover remedy. It's uh...
It's a greasy pork sandwich
served up in a dirty ashtray.
Oh, I hate you. I know you do.
Hey, turns out when
grandma Rose was a tyke,
She had a creole nanny
who wore a hoodoo necklace.
So you think she taught
Rose hoodoo? Yes, I do.
All right.
I think it's time we talk to Rose, then.
Oh, you need to brush your teeth first.
Hello?
Susan?
Clear?
Mrs. Thompson?
Rose?
Hi, Mrs. Thompson. We're not
here to hurt you. It's okay. We...
Rose?
Dean.
This woman's had a stroke.
Yeah, but hoodoo's hands-On. Yeah.
You got to mix herbs and
chant, build an altar.
So it can't be Rose.
Hey, maybe it's not even hoodoo.
You know, she could be faking.
What do you want to do,
poke her with a stick?
Dude, you're not gonna
poke her with a stick.
What the hell?
What are you doing in here?
We just wanted to talk to Rose.
Look at her. She's
scared out of her wits.
I want you out of my
hotel in two minutes
Or I'm calling the cops.
Your turn. Eightsies.
Have you started packing yet?
No. Why not?
I don't want to move.
Yes, I know, but we have to.
But Maggie says we're
not allowed to move.
Yeah?
Tyler, enough. Maggie is imaginary.
You're too old to have an imaginary
friend, and I am done pretending.
I don't like her.
I  could lug those boxes for you.
I got it, Sherwin. Thanks.
Okay, then.
See you later.
You okay? I think so.
Come on. Come on. Let's
get inside. Let's go.
Whiskey. Sure.
I know the feeling.
What the hell happened out there?
You want the truth? Of course.
At first, we thought it was
some sort of a hoodoo curse,
But that out there...
That was definitely a spirit.
Here.
You're insane.
It's been said.
Look, I'm sorry, Susan.
We don't exactly have
time to ease you into this,
But we need to know when
your mother had the stroke.
What does that have to do...
Just answer the question.
About a month ago.
Right before the killings began.
You see?
So what if Rose was working hoodoo,
but not to hurt anyone, to protect them?
She was using the urn patterns
to ward off the spirit.
Right. Until she had a
stroke and couldn't anymore.
I don't believe this. Listen,
That car didn't try to run
you down by itself, okay?
I mean, I guess it did technically,
but with a spirit. Forget it.
Just believe what you want, alright?
But the fact is you and
your family are in danger.
So you need to clear
everybody out of here.
Your employees,
Your mother,
Your daughters, everyone.
I only have one daughter. One?
I thought Tyler had
a sister named Maggie.
Maggie's imaginary.
Where's Tyler?
She's going to stay here with me,
And you can't stop me.
There's nothing you can do about it.
Maggie, don't. You're not
supposed to bother grandma.
I know.
Come on.
Let's play.
Can we have a tea party?
Tyler!
Oh, my god! Tyler!
She's not here!
Susan,
Tell us what you know
about Maggie. Not much.
Tyler's been talking about
her since mom got sick.
Okay, did you ever know
anyone by that name?
Uh no. Think, think.
Somebody that could have lived
here, might have passed away.
My god... My mom had
a sister named Margaret.
She barely spoke about her.
Did Margaret die here
when she was a kid?
Yeah, she drowned in the pool.
Come on.
I don't like it up here.
I'm scared.
It's okay.
All you have to do is jump.
I can't swim.
I know.
But it won't hurt.
I promise.
And then we can be together forever,
And no one will bother us.
Why don't you just
come with me and mommy?
Because I can't leave here,
and you can't leave me.
Please.
I don't want to be alone.
Tyler!
Mommy!
Is there another entrance?
Around back. All right, let's go!
Keep working.
It'll all be over soon.
Stand back.
Son of a bitch.
Margaret...
Oh, thank god. Thank god!
Mommy?
Yeah, baby, I'm here.
Tyler, do you see Maggie anywhere?
No, she's gone.
You'd really do that for me?
Yes...
If you did,
I'd let them go.
But I don't understand.
You kept me away for so long.
I thought you didn't love me anymore.
Okay...
Little sister.
Don't worry, honey. We're
leaving in two minutes.
We just got to get grandma.
I don't get it. Did Maggie just stop?
Seems like it. Where
the hell did she go?
Paramedics said it was another stroke.
Do you think...
Margaret could have had
something to do with it?
We don't know.
But it's possible,
Yeah.
Susan, I'm sorry.
You have nothing to apologize for.
You've given me everything.
Ready to go, kiddo?
Yeah.
Tyler, you're sure
Maggie's not around anymore?
I'm sure. I'd see her.
I guess whatever's
going on must be over.
You two take care of
yourselves, all right?
Thank you.
Yeah.
Both of you.
Think you could have hooked
up some milf action there, bud.
Serious, I think she liked you. Yeah,
That's all she needs.
Well, you saved the
mommy, you saved the girl.
Not a bad day.
'Course,you know, I could
have saved them myself,
But I didn't want you to feel useless.
All right, I appreciate it.
Feels good getting back
in the saddle, doesn't it?
Yeah.
Yeah, it does.
But it doesn't change what we
talked about last night, Dean.
We talked about a lot
of things last night.
You know what I mean. You were wasted.
But you weren't...
And you promised.