Are you saying that this
is the... Apocalypse?
And these specific omens,
they're prelude to what?
The Four Horsemen.
And which one
rides the red horse?
War.
This town is suffering from famine.
A-as in the Horseman?
Great.
The angel of death must
be brought into this world
through a place of awful carnage.
Oh, hello death
Bobby, who is that?
She's my wife.
It's the end of the world.
And if I don't stop
it and save everyone,
then no one will, and we all die.
I'm just tired, man.
I'm done.
I am just done.
I need some help.
Here on the Savanna,
the wildebeest lounges.
Lazy and self-content...
and is oblivious to
the fierce predator
that stalks him from the shadows.
The great wildebeest
herds migrate south
search of water,
drinking their fill in
preparation for the
long dry season to come.
The wildebeest are on edge.
Every move they make, every
sound of potential attack
A mere rustle of the winds
through the bushes can spring
the entire herd into a
bone crushing stampede...
First the animal
reacts with confusion...
The wildebeest returns
wearily to its watering hole.
It's...
who are closing in for the kill.
When it attacks,
it attacks quickly.
No.
Please! God! No!
Season 5 Episode 15
"Dead Men Don't Wear Plaid"
Bobby, listen, when you
get this message, call!
Okay?
Is he still not home?
How far could he get in that chair?
So, what do we do?
Well... guess we just
do it ourselves.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Mr. Wells, why don't you
tell us what you saw...
in your own words.
- Call me Digger.
- Digger?
Who... who gave you that name?
I did.
You gave yourself
your own nickname?
You can't do that.
Who died and made you queen?
Okay. Uh, why don't you
just tell us what you saw?
I saw Clay Thompson climb
into Benny Sutton's trailer
through the window.
Couple minutes later,
Clay walked out,
and Benny's dead.
And, uh...
is this the guy you saw?
Well, he was all covered
with mud but, yeah.
That's Clay.
And you are aware that Clay
Thompson died five years ago?
Yep.
And you're positive
that it was this guy.
You calling me a liar?
No, no, no.
Of course not.
Look.
Can you think of any
reason why Clay Thompson...
alive or dead...
would want to kill Benny Sutton?
Hell, yeah.
Well, five years ago,
Benny's the one that killed
Clay in the first place.
Is that a fact?
Well, yeah, so-called
"hunting accident."
But, if you ask me...
Clay came back from the grave
to get a little payback.
Go on.
Owen, put down the cupcake
and pick up an apple.
Okay?
Okay. I love you.
Heads up.
"Fargo."
Digger.
Sheriff.
Gentlemen.
I'm Sheriff Jody Mills.
I don't believe we've
had the pleasure.
Agents Dorfman and Neidermeyer.
FBI.
Welcome to Sioux Falls, gentlemen.
Can I ask you what you're
doing with Digger here?
Oh, they're doin' their job.
They believe me... Sheriff.
The FBI believes a dead
man committed a murder?
Look, we're just asking a
few questions, Sheriff.
That's all.
Of course, if a dead man
didn't commit the murder,
then, uh, who did?
What'd you say your
jurisdiction here was again?
Our jurisdiction is
wherever the United States
government sends us.
Oh, yeah. How 'bout
me and your supervisor
have a little chat about that?
Absolutely.
Agent Willis speaking.
Agent Willis, this is
Sheriff Jody Mills.
Bobby?
Oh...
Excuse me?
Is this Bobby Singer?
Listen, I don't know
who this is, but...
This is Agent Tom
Willis of the FBI.
Bull crap.
FBI, huh?
So, uh...
So you know Bobby Singer?
That is... a fun coincidence.
Here's what I know
about Bobby Singer.
He's a menace around here...
ass-full of drunk-and-dis-orderlies
and mail fraud.
You understanding me?
I think we all can agree that
you've made yourself
perfectly clear, yes.
So, whatever the three
of you are planning,
it ends here... now.
Ten-four on that, agents?
Yeah.
You know how
many times we called?
Where have you been?
Playing murder ball.
What's that smell?
Is that soap?
Did you clean?
What are you, my mother?
Bite me!
Bobby, seriously.
I been working.
You know, trying to find
a way to stop the devil.
- Find anything?
- What do you think?
Bobby, it's just...
there's a case
less than five miles
from your house.
What, the... the
Benny Sutton thing?
That's what this is about?
You knew about this?
Hell, yes. I checked
into it already.
There's nothing here.
Except a witness who saw
a dead guy commit murder.
What witness? Digger Wells?
Yeah. So?
So, he's a drunk.
Well, what about the
lightning storms?
They look like omens.
Except in February
in South Dakota in storm season.
Guys, I thought it
was something, too.
Sometimes a cigar is just a cigar.
So who killed the guy?
Take your pick.
This Benny Sutton guy was
a grade -A- son of a bitch.
There's a list of the
living a year long
wouldn't mind putting
a cap in his ass.
So, you're telling
us... nothing?
Sorry.
Looks like you wasted a
tank of gas on this one.
Great.
What's up?
Isn't that the
graveyard back there?
Yeah. So what? Bobby
already checked it out.
And? What, Bobby's never wrong?
Come on. We'll take a peek,
and then we'll hit the road.
Can't hurt.
Hey.
That look fresh to you?
Yeah, actually.
What's going on here?
I don't know, but something stinks.
Don't shoot me! Please!
There's money in the safe.
We don't want your money.
What do you want?
Anything. Please...
You're Clay Thompson, right?
Who are you?
FBI.
FBI?
Oh, my God. This is about Benny.
Wha... what about Benny?
He killed me! He
shot me in the back!
I'm supposed to let him
get away with that?
Hold up. Are... are you confessing?
Please. I'll go with you.
Just... just don't wake my kids.
Y-you'll go with us where?
Jail.
Let me get this straight.
You're Clay Thompson,
and you died five years ago?
Yes.
And three days ago you
climbed out of your grave,
- and you killed Benny Sutton?
- Yes.
- So you are, in fact, a dead guy.
- I guess.
I-I-I don't know what I am.
Clay?
I called 911.
It's okay, honey.
These men are the FBI.
They're here about Benny.
Why don't you come
with us, Mr. Thompson?
I think that'd be best.
Dean.
He's a monster.
He's a soccer dad.
What do you want to do with him?
Freeze!
Drop your guns!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
All right. Hey.
Remember the guy you
said that was dead
and couldn't possibly
commit murder?
There he is.
And?
"And"?
And you're welcome...
for catching the
un-dead killer zombie.
Whatever he is or isn't...
that don't give you
the right to shoot him
- in the middle of the street.
- Shoot me?
- You're free to go, Mr. Thompson.
- Free to go?!
I can't believe you
were gonna kill me.
- You're a zombie!
- I'm a taxpayer!
So, what Sheriff's on the take?
Yeah. No.
The zombies are paying her off?
Hey.
So, what now they're friends?
Bobby, I thought the
Sheriff hated you?
She did till five days ago.
What happened five days ago?
The dead started
rising all over town.
So you knew about this?
Yep.
I think what Sam meant
to say is, you lied to us?
Look... I told you
there was nothing here.
And there isn't. Not for you.
There are zombies here.
There are zombies...
and then there's zombies.
Come with me.
You want to tell
us what the hell...
Oh, hey.
I didn't realize you
were bringing company.
It's 4 A.M. babe.
You didn't need to cook.
Oh, please. I'll get
some more plates.
Who was that?
Karen. My wife.
Your new wife?
My dead wife.
Mmm. Mmm.
This is incredible, Mrs. Singer.
Thank you, Dean.
A-hem...
What? It is.
It's great, Karen. Thanks.
Could you, um,
just give us a minute?
Are you crazy, what the hell?
Dean, I can explain.
Explain what, lying to us?
Or the American girl zombie
making cup-cakes in your kitchen?!
First of all, that's
my wife, so watch it.
Bobby, whatever that thing
is in there, it is not your wife.
And how do you know that?
Are you serious?
You think I'm an idiot, boy?
My dead wife shows
up on my doorstep,
I'm not gonna test her
every way I ever learned?
So what is it, zombies, revenant?
Hell if I can tell.
She's got no scars, no wounds,
no reaction to salt,
silver, holy water...
Bobby, she crawled
out of her coffin.
No, she didn't. I cremated her.
Somehow, some way, she's back.
That's impossible.
Tell me about it.
You bury her ashes?
- Yeah.
- Where?
In the cemetery.
That's where they all rose from.
- How many?
- 15, 20.
I made a list.
Uh, there's Karen...
Clay...
Sheriff Mills...
her little boy came back.
And there were
no signs, no omens?
Well, there were the
lightning storms.
That's what we said. What else?
"And through the fire stood
before me a pale horse.
"And he that sat atop
him carried a scythe,
"and I saw since he had risen,
"they too shall rise,
and from him and through him."
So, what death is behind this?
Death, death. Like
grim reaper, death?
Yeah.
Awesome.
Another Horseman.
Must be Thursday.
Bobby...
Why would death raise 15 people
in a podunk town like Sioux Falls?
I don't know.
You know, if death is behind this,
then whatever these things are...
it's not good.
You know what
we have to do here.
She doesn't remember
anything, you know.
What do you mean?
Being possessed,
me killing her...
her coming back.
Bobby...
No, no, don't "Bobby" me.
Just...
just listen, okay?
She hums when she cooks.
Yeah.
She always...
used to hum when she cooked.
Tone deaf as all hell, but...
And I never thought I
would hear it again.
Look, just read revelation.
The... the dead rise
during the apocalypse.
There's nothing in there
that says that's bad!
Hell, maybe it's the one good thing
that comes out of this
whole bloody mess.
And what would you
do if you were us?
I know what I'd do.
And I know what you
think you got to do.
But...
I'm begging you.
Please.
Leave her be.
So, what do you think?
There's nothing to think about.
I'm not gonna leave Bobby at home
with the bride of Frankenstein.
Then what do you want to do?
Just walk in there in front of
Bobby and blow her skull off?
If she decides that Bobby's face
is the blue plate special,
I'd like to be there.
Fine.
See what else we can find out.
Oops. Did I scare you?
No. No. No.
There's... nothing scary
about you at all.
Feel like some lunch?
Uh... I'm good. Thanks.
Come on, there's more pie.
I don't think that
Bobby wants me inside.
Guess it'll have to be
our secret then, huh?
Come on.
I'm gonna go out on a limb
and guess that you like pies.
Did you bake all these?
I don't know what it is.
Since I got back,
I can't stop baking.
Yeah, when do you
have time to sleep?
I don't.
Must be the excitement.
Or being dead.
I know you don't trust me.
Why would you say that?
Come on, Dean.
That's why you're here, isn't it?
Keeping an eye on me?
I know who you are.
Just like I know
Bobby's not the same
mild-mannered scrap
dealer I married.
You hunt things.
I... I'm a thing.
I get it.
So then you know that Sam and I
would never let anything
happen to Bobby.
He's like a father to us.
I understand.
And he's lucky to have you
looking out for him, Dean.
But you're not the only one.
Is that so?
I remember everything, you know.
When I died.
That demon taking over my body...
and the things it made me do.
And Bobby having
no choice but to...
well, you know what he did.
But I can see it in his
eyes when he looks at me.
The guilt.
It weighs on him.
So why don't you just
tell him you remember?
I'm gonna go out
on a limb here
and say you've
never been in love.
He's my husband.
My job is to bring him peace...
not pain.
Mrs. Jones?!
Ezra Jones?
Um... Ezra Jones?
W-what is it?
You think maybe you
could tell me from here?
Yeah. I'm gonna regret this.
Keep your damn voices
down. Karen's upstairs.
Oh, I'm sorry. We're a
little tense right now.
Who's old lady Jones?
- The first one to come up.
- First one to go bad.
- Ah, she was always a nutty broad.
- Nutty how?
Nutty like the way she ate
her husband's stomach?
Was that the level of
nutty she was in life?
No.
Look, Bobby, I feel for you.
But you have got to acknowledge
that you're not exactly
seeing this straight!
Bobby, whether
you admit it or not,
these things are turning.
We have to stop them. All of them.
- Time to go.
- What?
You heard me. Off my property.
Or what, you'll shoot?
If Karen turns, I will handle it...
my way.
This is dangerous.
I'm not telling you twice.
He's crazy.
It's his wife, Dean.
So he goes "Full
Metal Jacket" on us?
We're his family, Sam.
Look, man. Bigger fish, okay?
I mean, we got a bunch of zombies
about to turn this town
into a giant chew toy.
Yeah, and he's
alone in the house
making pie with one of 'em!
- All right. So?
- So?!
I'm gonna have to go back there
and... and... and kill her.
That's the only thing
I can think of.
If he sees you,
you're a dead man.
Well, then I guess I
won't let him see me.
Okay.
I'll... head to town
and rescue everyone. Should be easy.
Sounds like.
I'm gonna need some help.
What about the Sheriff?
Uh, last time I checked,
the Sheriff was pretty pro-zombie.
Well, I guess you'll just
have to convince her.
- How?
- I don't know.
You're just gonna.
There. Does that
feel better, honey?
I'm so hungry, mommy.
Oh, I know. I know.
Mommy's gonna make
you some soup, okay?
Okay.
I don't know what
else to tell you, doc.
We checked the
thermometer three times.
His temperature is 111 degrees.
- Mommy.
- Hold on, doc.
- I'm hungry!
- Can you take that in to him?
Dr. Dwight, it's Jody Mills.
Karen, stay away
from the windows.
Karen?
Karen?!
- I'm... I'm okay.
- Yeah?
I'm okay.
I just...
I... I just got to be dizzy.
You're burning up.
Oh, I'm okay.
I... I just need
something to eat.
And I'll be fine. Really.
I don't know how to
explain it, doctor.
That's... that's why
we're calling you. I...
Sean?
Owen?
Oh, my God.
- Let's go!
- No!
Go!
- My husband!
- Leave it! He's dead!
- That was not my son!
- You're right. It wasn't.
Listen, Sheriff.
Your town is in danger.
People are in danger,
and we need to help them now.
Can you do that for me?
Can you focus for me, Sheriff?
Sheriff?
How do we put them down?
Head shot.
We're gonna need weapons.
We can start by rounding
up everybody we can find.
Where is there a safe
place we can take people?
Jail.
Right.
Just, um...
Give me a minute.
I'm so hungry, Bobby.
I'll fix you something
to eat... in a minute.
I can feel it. It's happening.
It's gonna be all right.
No.
It's not.
I'm turning, Bobby.
You know I am.
It's okay.
- Do it.
- No way.
- Please.
- No.
I remember.
You remember what?
Everything.
The demon inside me.
You killing me.
I remember.
Then you know...
why I can't do it again.
I remember something else, too.
When I came back...
there was a man.
What do you mean, a man?
At the grave.
He was so thin.
Like a skeleton.
And he told me to
give you message.
Me?
W-why didn't you
tell me this before?
You've seen so much.
I just...
I just wanted to see you smile.
What was the message?
Bobby?!
All right, if I hand you a gun
and you see a dead person,
I don't care if it's your friend,
your neighbor, or your wife.
You shoot for the head.
That's the only way we survive.
Uh, you mind telling us
who the hell you are?
Friend of Bobby Singer's.
Town drunk.
No, I-I thought...
he was the town drunk.
Who told you that?
Bobby Singer.
Stay sharp.
I'll watch the front door.
You know, Bobby, if you
want to sit this one out...
Let's just get going.
Dean?
Dean?!
Dean!
Little help here?
- That's fine.
- Yeah, fine.
You got any more ammo? I'm low.
Yeah, we got plenty.
Just run back past the zombies.
It's in the van,
where we left it.
A simple "no" would have been fine.
What are they all
doing here, anyway?!
- I think I get it.
- What?
Oh, that ain't good.
I'm out.
- Me too.
- Come on!
Kind of a tight fit,
don't you think?
It's all right. They're idiots.
They can't pick a lock.
Don't you ever get
tired of being wrong?
I'm making this
stuff up as I go.
Sue me.
Get down!
Are you okay?
Well, if there's any
zombies left out there,
we can't find them.
How are the townspeople?
Pretty freaked out.
Hell, traumatized.
A few of them are
calling the papers.
As far as I can tell,
nobody's believed 'em yet.
Would you?
How are you holding up?
Is that everyone?
All but one.
So, thinking maybe
I should apologize
for losing my head back there.
Bobby...
you don't owe us anything.
Hey, look, I don't know squat
from shinola about love, but...
At least you got to spend
five days with her, right?
Right.
Which makes things about
a thousand times worse.
She was the love of my life.
How many times do
I got to kill her?
Are you gonna
be okay, Bobby?
You boys should know...
Karen told me
why death was here.
What do you mean?
I know why he took a
stroll through a cemetery
in the sticks of South Dakota.
He came for me.
What do you mean, you?
Death came for me.
He brought Karen back
to send me a message.
You, why you?
Because I've been helping you,
you sons of bitches.
I'm one of the reasons you're
still saying no to Lucifer, Sam.
So this was like a
hit on your life?
I don't know if they wanted
to take my life or...
my spirit.
Either way, they wanted
me out of the way.
But you're gonna be all right.
Right, Bobby?
Sync by yyets.Net
Edited by Scooby