Storm's coming.
And you boys, you are
smack in the middle of it.
Dad wants us to pick up where he left
off... saving people, hunting things.
Family business.
I'm gonna save as many people as we can.
Dean, you and I have seen things
most people couldn't even dream about.
If it's supernatural, we kill it.
End of story. That's our job.
No, Dean, that is not our job.
Our job is hunting evil.
They're all the same, Sam.
They're not human, okay?
We have to exterminate
every last one of them.
Our lives are weird, man.
You're telling me.
We're lost.
No.
This is a short cut...
Babe, it's just we've been on this road over
an hour, and we haven't seen a single car.
Molly, I know how to
read a frickin' map, okay?
We passed a gas station a while back.
Let's just go ask someone.
That was 40 minutes ago.
We're not turning around.
Come on.
Isn't this argument a little archaic?
Men can ask directions these days.
No, we can't.
It's against our genetic code.
Look, I know exactly where we are.
Oh, yeah? Where?
Highway 99, okay?
It cuts right through.
Highway 99, huh?
Okay, so we're taking the scenic route.
David.
It's our anniversary, and we're
spending it stuck in the car.
I know.
I'm sorry.
Let me make it up to
you, okay? Come here.
Stop. I'm mad at you.
Oh, come on, Molly.
Hey, you love me.
No, I don't.
You're a jerk.
David, I mean it.
Molly!
David?
Da... David?!
David?!
David?
Hello?
Is anyone here?
It's you.
You're okay.
I'm so sorry.
I didn't see you there.
Are you...
Are you hurt?
Sir?
Stop!
You've got to help me.
Please.
Please!
All right, all right.
Calm down, calm down.
Tell us what happened.
I-I swerved,
a-And we crashed.
And when I came to, the car was
wrecked and my husband was missing.
I went looking for him, but that's when the
man from the road, he... he started chasing me.
Did he look like he lost
a fight with a lawn mower?
How did you know that?
Lucky guess.
Ma'am, what's your name?
Molly.
Molly Mcnamara.
I think maybe you should come with us.
We'll take you back into town.
I can't.
I have to find David.
He might have gone back to the car.
We should get you somewhere safe first.
Then Dean and I will come back.
We'll look for your husband.
No.
I'm not leaving here without him.
Would you just take me
back to my car, please?
Of course.
Come on.
It's right over there.
I don't understand.
I'm sure this is where it was.
W-We hit that tree right there.
This... this doesn't make any sense.
Dean, we got to get out of here.
Greeley could show up at any second.
What are you gonna tell her.
The truth?
She's gonna take off running
in the other direction.
I know it sounds crazy, but
I crashed into that tree.
I don't know who could've taken it.
It was totaled.
Please. You have to believe me.
Molly, listen, we do believe you.
But that's why we want
to get you out of here.
What about David?
Something must have happened.
I have to get to the cops.
Cops... that's a great idea.
We'll take you down to
the station ourselves.
So just come with us.
It's the best way we can
help you and your husband.
Okay.
We're supposed to be in lake Tahoe.
You and David?
It's our five-Year anniversary.
Hell of an anniversary.
Right before, we were
having the dumbest fight.
It was the only time we ever really
argued... when we were stuck in the car.
Yeah.
I know how that goes.
You know the last thing I said to him?
I called him a jerk.
Oh, god.
What if that's the last
thing I said to him?
Molly...
We're gonna figure out what
happened to your husband.
I promise.
Did you? No.
I was afraid you'd say that.
This song.
What?
It was playing when we crashed.
She's mine.
What is that?
Hold on.
What are you doing?
What the...
What the hell just happened?
Don't worry, Molly.
Everything's gonna be all right.
Spoke a little too soon, Sammy.
I don't think he's gonna let her leave.
This can't be happening.
Well...
Trust me, it's happening.
Okay.
Thanks for helping, but I think
I got it covered from here.
Wait.
Molly, Molly, wait a minute.
Just leave me alone.
No. Please. You have to listen to me.
Just stay away.
It wasn't a coincidence
that we found you, all right?
What are you talking about?
We weren't cruising for chicks
when we ran into you, sister.
We were already out here.
Hunting.
Hunting for what?
Ghosts.
D... d... don't...
Sugar coat it for her.
You're nuts.
Really?
About as nuts as a vanishing
guy with his guts spilling out.
You know what you saw.
We think his name is Jonah Greeley.
He was a local farmer that died
15 years ago on this highway.
Just stop.
One night a year, on the anniversary
of his death, he haunts this road.
That's why we're here, Molly.
To try and stop him.
Now, I suppose this ghost
made my car disappear, too.
Crazier things have happened.
Huh?
You know what?
I'm all filled up on crazy.
I'm gonna get the cops myself.
I don't mean to be harsh, but I
don't think you're gonna get too far.
What is that supposed to mean?
Means that plan "a" was
trying to get you out of here.
Obviously that didn't go over too
well with, uh, farmer road kill.
Molly, we're telling the truth.
Greeley's not gonna let
you leave this highway.
You're s... you're serious
about this, aren't you?
Deadly.
Everyear, Greeley finds someone
to punish for what happened to him.
Tonight that person is you.
Why me?
I didn't do anything.
Doesn't matter.
Some spirits only see what they want.
So you're saying this
Greeley, he took my husband?
Oh, god.
Molly, look, we're
gonna help, all right?
But first, you got to help us.
Help you?
How?
This is it.
This is where I saw him.
Must have been his hunting cabin.
Seemed like a real sweet guy.
No markers or headstones outside.
You're looking for Greeley's grave?
Yeah.
Why?
So we can dig up the
corpse and salt and burn it.
Oh.
Sure. Naturally.
It's a way to get rid of a spirit.
And that'll save David?
This is what'll help both of you,
provided there's a corpse to be found.
So how do we find it?
Uh, not sure.
After Greeley died, his
wife claimed the body.
And that was the last anyone saw of her.
So good guess she brought him back here.
But they have a thousand acres.
He could be buried anywhere on 'em.
Is is really what you guys do.
You're like ghost busters.
Yeah.
Minus the jumpsuits.
This is a fascinating
conversation and all.
But this highway is only haunted once a year,
and we got till sun up to wrap this thing up.
What do you say we move it along, okay?
Great.
What are we looking for?
Greeley's house.
Maybe he's buried there.
Look for roads or paths or something.
Stay close.
Yeah.
Okay.
Molly?
Molly, help me.
David? David?
Whoops.
Hey!
Are you all right?
What has that son of a
bit chdone with my husband?
Just take it easy, all right?
You're gonna see David again.
You will.
Hey.
Follow the creepy brick road.
Go ahead.
That thing shoots rock salt?
Yep.
And plain salt keeps away spirits?
Simple remedies are always the best.
In most cultures, salt is a symbol of purity,
so it repels impure and unnatural things.
Same reason you throw
it over your shoulder.
You know, just once I'd like to
round the corner and see a nice house.
Any headstones outside?
Yeah, right.
Is it ever that easy?
I guess not.
You two check upstairs.
See if you can find any notes or
records telling us where he's buried.
I'll just check down here.
Great.
Look at this.
It's Greeley and his wife.
It's a love letter he wrote her.
My god, it's beautiful.
I don't understand how a guy like
this can turn into that monster.
Spirits like Greeley are,uh...
Like wounded animals.
Lost.
In so much pain, that they lash out.
Why?
Why are they here?
Well, there's some part of them that...
That's keeping them here.
Like their remains or, um...
Unfinished business.
Unfinished business?
Yeah.
It could be revenge.
Could be love.
Or hate.
Whatever it is, they
just hold on too tight.
Can't let go.
So they're trapped.
Caught in the same loops.
Replaying the same
tragedies over and over.
You sound almost sorry for them.
Well, they weren't
evil people, you know?
A lot of them were good.
Just...
Something happened to them.
Something they couldn't control.
Sammy's always getting a little J. Love
Hewitt when it comes to things like this.
Me, I don't like 'em.
And I sure as hell ain't
making apologies for 'em.
There's nothing downstairs.
Uh, just about every piece of
mail or receipt they ever had.
Looked through a couple, but
nothing about a grave so far.
What?
There's something behind here.
Here.
It's locked from the inside.
Smells like old lady in here.
And that would explain why.
Well, now we know why
nobody ever saw her again.
She didn't want to live without him.
Dean, give me a hand.
Really?
What are you gonna do?
We can't leave her like this.
Why not?
She deserves to be put to rest, Dean.
So...
So, if you manage to put
Greeley to rest, too...
What happens to them?
Lady, that answer is
way beyond our pay grade.
You hunt these things, but you
don't know what happens to them?
Well, they never come back.
That's all that matters.
After they let go of
whatever'skeeping them here, they...
They just go.
I hope someplace better,
but we don't know.
No one does.
What happens when you burn their bones?
Well, my dad used to say that was
like death for ghosts, you know?
But...
The truth is, we still don't know.
Not for sure.
Guess that's why we all
hold on to life so hard.
Even the dead.
We're all just scared of the unknown.
The only thing I'm
scared of is losing David.
I have to see him again.
I have to.
I think we should tell
her about her husband.
We can't.
Dean, it's cruel, letting
her pine for him like this.
I don't like keeping her in the dark.
It's for her own good.
I know you feel guilty,
butlet's just stick to the plan.
Let's get her out of here.
Then we'll tell her.
Tell me what?
What aren't you telling me?
It's about David.
You know what happened to him.
Molly Sam, don't.
Don't what?
Don't tell me because
I'll mess up your hunt?
You don't care about me or my husband.
That's not true.
Really?
Then whatever it is, tell me, please.
He's coming.
Stay with her...
He's got Molly!
This guy is persistent.
We got to find Molly.
We got to find Greeley's bones.
And, uh, no pressure or anything, but we
got less than two hours before sunrise.
Hey.
What do you got?
"February 6, 1992. "
That was like two weeks
before the accident, wasn't it?
Yeah.
It looks like the hunting cabin, but...
I swear there's a tree there
right where they're standing.
Should have thought of it.
What?
It's an old country custom, Dean.
Planting a tree as a grave marker.
You're like a walking
encyclopedia of weirdness.
Yeah.
I know.
Where's David?
What did you do to him?
You shouldn't worry about him anymore.
Oh, my god.
You should worry about yourself.
I didn't do anything to you.
Oh?
I know... I know about your wife.
Hurting me won't bring her back.
My wife is gone.
All I got left'shurting you.
P-Please.
Just let me go.
Go?
You're not gonna leave.
You're never gonna leave.
Go get Molly.
Oh, thank god.
Call me Dean.
This guy's really pissing me off.
Oh, baby, it's been a long night.
All right.
Let's get you out of here.
I'm not going anywhere until you
tell me what happened to my husband.
Molly...
All this time I've been looking
for him, and you knew that...
You knew that Greeley
killed him, didn't you?
He's dead.
No, Molly.
David's alive.
What?
You're sure?
I'm sure.
We'll take you to him.
Come on.
He's in that house right there.
I don't understand.
You will.
That's not...
It can't be.
What's happening?
Who is that?
That's David's wife.
I'm sorry, Molly.
15 years ago, you and your husband
it Jonah Greeley with your car.
What are you saying?
We're saying there isn't just
one spirit haunting highway 41.
There are two.
Jonah Greeley and you.
For the past 15 years, one night a year
you've been appearing on that highway.
No. That's not possible.
It was our anniversary...
February 22nd...
1992.
Yes.
Molly, it's 2007.
Oh, god.
All right. Tell me about highway 41.
12 accidents over 15 years.
Five of them fatal, all of them
happening on the same night.
So what are we looking
at... interstate dead zone?
Phantom hitchhiker? What?
Not quite.
Year after year, witnesses said
the same thing made 'em crash
A woman appearing in the middle of the
road being chased by a man covered in blood.
Two spooks?
Now, where is Molly buried?
She... she wasn't buried anywhere.
She was cremated.
So much for burning her bones.
Yeah, but then what's keeping her here?
Some spirits only see what they want.
David?!
David?
Stop!
You have to help me.
Dean, I don't think
she knows she's dead.
Please!
Open up!
Okay. All right, all right.
Just calm down.
Tell us what happened.
What are you gonna tell her?
The truth.
She's gonna take off running
in the other direction.
Some spirits hold on too tight.
Can't let go.
And Greeley?
Each year he punishes somebody
for his death... chasing them.
Torturing them.
And each year, that somebody is you.
But I don't remember any of it.
Because you couldn't
see the truth, Molly.
So that's why he won't
let me off the highway.
Because...
I killed him.
I killed us both.
Why didn't you tell me
when you first saw me?
Why wait until now?
You wouldn't have believed us.
And you needed me for bait.
Well, we needed you.
David.
Molly, we brought you
here so you could move on.
I have to tell him.
That you love him?
That you're sorry?
Molly, he already knows that.
Look, if you want to go in
there, we're not gonna stop you.
Yeah, but you are gonna
freak him right out.
For life.
David's already said
his good byes, Molly.
Now it's your turn.
This is your unfinished business.
What am I supposed to do?
Just...
Let go.
Of David.
Of everything.
You do that...
We think you'll move on.
But you don't know where.
No.
Molly, you don't belong here.
Haven't you suffer edlong enough?
It's time.
It's time to go.
I guess she wasn't so bad...
For a ghost.
You think she's really
going to a better place?
I hope so.
I guess we'll never know.
Not until we take the
plunge ourselves, huh?
Doesn't really matter, Dean.
Hope's kind of the whole point.
All right, Haley Joel.
Let's hit the road.