Storm's coming.
And you boys?
Your daddy?
You are smack in the middle of it.
Take your brother outside
as fast as you can!
Now, Dean! Go!
He wants us to pick up
where he left off.
Saving people, hunting things...
The family business.
Our whole lives have been searching
for this demon.
Samuel Colt made a gun.
They say this gun can kill anything.
We finally know who this demon's gonna be,
and now, we know how to kill it.
More and more demons are walking among us.
- You're not my dad.
- Dean, what the hell's going on?
I think he's possessed.
My plans for you, Sammy...
You, and all the children like you.
It's inside me. I can feel it.
Shoot me!
I can't hold on to it much longer!
- Why didn't you kill it?
- we still got the colt.
We still have the one bullet left.
Get back
or I'll kill you.
I swear to god.
You won't.
You're saving that bullet for someone else.
You want to bet?
Oh, my god!
Dad...
- did I do this?
- Dad...
Dean.
Dean...
Significant passenger,
space intrusion.
Unresponsive.
B.P. 180 over 50.
B.P. 100 over 15.
Heartbeat 95.
- Tell me if they're okay!
- you have to stay still.
Are they even alive!
Sam?
Dad?
Anybody?!
Shadow county, nurses' station.
How can I transfer your call?
Of course.
I transfer your call.
Excuse me.
Hi.
I, uh... I think I was in a car accident
with my...
dad and my brother.
I just need to find them.
Hello?
Sammy...
You look good...
considering...
Man, tell me you can hear me.
How's dad?
Is he okay?
Come on, you're the psychic.
Give me some ghost whispering or something.
Your father's awake.
You can go see him if you like.
Oh, thank god.
Doc, what about my brother?
Well, he sustained serious injury.
Blood loss,
contusions to his liver and kidney.
But it's the head trauma
I'm worried about.
There's early signs of cerebral edema.
Well, what can we do?
Well, we won't know his full condition
until he wakes up.
If,
he wakes up.
If?
- I have to be honest.
- Screw you, doc I'm waking up!
Most people with his degree of injury
wouldn't have survived this long.
He's fighting very hard.
But you need
to have realistic expectations, son.
Come on, Sam.
Go find some hoodoo priest
to lay some mojo on me.
I'll be fine.
Sam?
All right. Here.
Give them my insurance.
Elroy Mcgillicuddy?
And his two loving sons.
So...
what else did the doctor say about Dean?
Nothing.
Look...
if the doctors won't do anything,
then we'll have to, that's all.
I don't know. I'll find some...
hoodoo priest and lay some mojo on him.
We'll look for someone.
Yeah.
But, Sam...
I don't know if we're gonna find anyone.
Why not?
I found that faith healer before.
- That was one in A million.
- So what?
We just sit here with our thumbs up our ass?
No, I said we'd look.
All right? I'll check under every stone.
Where's the colt?
Your son is dying,
- and you're worried about the colt?
- we are hunting
this demon, and maybe it's hunting us too.
That gun may be our only card.
It's in the trunk.
They dragged the car to a yard off of i-83.
All right, you got to clean out that trunk
before some junk man sees what's inside.
I already called Bobby.
He's like an hour out.
He's gonna tow the Impala back to his place.
All right. You,
you go meet up with Bobby.
You get that colt and bring it back to me.
And you watch out for hospital security.
I think I got it covered.
Hey.
Here.
I made a list of things I need
that Bobby pick them up for me.
Acacia?
Oil of Abramelin? What's this stuff for?
Protection.
Hey, dad...
You know the demon?
He said he had plans
for me and children like me.
You have any idea what he meant by that?
No, I don't.
Well, you sure know something.
Oh, man.
Dean is gonna be pissed.
Look, Sam, this...
This just ain't worth a tow.
I say we empty the trunk,
and sell the rest for scrap.
No.
Dean would kill me if we did that.
When he gets better,
he's gonna want to fix this.
There's nothing to fix.
The frame's a pretzel. The engine's ruined.
There's barely any parts worth salvaging.
Listen to me, Bobby.
If there's only one working part,
that's enough.
We're not just gonna give up on...
Okay.
You got it.
Here...
Dad asked if
you could get this stuff for him.
What John want with this?
Protection from the demon.
What?
- Nothing. It's just...
- Bobby.
What's going on?
Come on, dad.
You got to help me.
I got to get better.
I got to get back in there.
I mean, you haven't called a soul for help.
You haven't even tried.
Aren't you gonna do anything?
Aren't you gonna even say anything?!
I've done everything
you have ever asked me.
Everything.
I've given everything I've ever had.
Now you're just gonna sit there?
You're gonna watch me die?
I mean, what the hell
kind of father are you?!
What is that?
I take it you didn't see that.
Hey!
I need some help in here!
I can't...
breathe.
Sammy, tell me
you can freaking hear me, man.
There's something in the hospital.
Now, you got to bring me back,
and we got to hunt this thing.
Sam!
You're quiet.
You think I wouldn't find out?
- What are you talking about?
- That stuff from Bobby.
You don't use it to ward off a demon.
You use it to summon one.
You're planning on bringing
the demon here, aren't you?
Having some stupid macho showdown!
- I have A plan, Sam.
- That's exactly my point!
Dean is dying, and you have a plan!
You know what?!
You care more about
killing this demon than you do
saving your own son!
- No, no, no. Guys, don't do this!
- Do not tell me how I feel!
- I am doing This for Dean.
- How?
How is revenge gonna help him?
You're not thinking about
anybody but yourself!
It's the same selfish obsession!
- Come on, guys, don't do this!
- That's funny,
I thought this was your
obsession too. This demon
killed your mother,
killed your girlfriend.
You begged me to be part of this hunt!
Now, if you killed that damn
thing when you had the chance,
- none of This would have happened.
- It was possessing you, dad!
- I would have killed you, too!
- Yeah,
and your brother would
be awake right now.
- Shut up, both of you!
- go to hell.
I should have never taken
you along in the first place.
- I knew It was A mistake.
- I said "shut up!"
Dude, I full-on swayzed that mother.
What is it?
Something's going on out there.
- all clear?
- Clear.
- still No pulse.
- no.
Still no pulse.
- Okay, let's go again. 360.
- Charging.
- all clear?
- Clear.
- Come on, Come on...
- still No pulse.
Clear.
- still Nothing.
- Okay, let's go again.
Charging.
All clear?
Get the hell away from me.
Stay back!
There's no change. Starting CPR.
I said get back!
Still nothing.
We have a pulse.
We're back into sinus rhythm.
Don't worry, Sammy.
I'm not going anywhere.
I'm getting that thing
before it gets me.
It's some kind of spirit,
but I could grab it.
And if I can grab it,
I can kill it.
Can't you see me?!
Why won't you look at me?!
Now what?
Somebody talk to me!
- Say something, please!
- Can you see me?
Yeah.
All right, just calm down.
What's your name?
Tessa.
Okay, good, Tessa. I'm Dean.
What's happening to me?
Am I...
Am I dead?
That sort of depends.
I don't understand.
I just came in for an appendectomy.
I hate to bear bad news, but...
I think there were some complications.
It's just a dream, that's all.
This is just
a very weird,
unbelievably vivid dream.
Tessa,
it's not a dream.
Then what else could it be?
You ever heard of an
Out-Of-Body experience?
What are you, some New-Agey guy?
You see me messing with
crystals or listening to Yanni?
It's actually a very old idea.
It's got a lot of different names.
Bilocation,
crisis apparitions, fetches.
I think it's happening to us.
If it is...
it means that we're spirits...
of people close to death.
So we're gonna die?
No.
Not if we hold on.
Our bodies can get better. You can
snap right back in there and wake up.
What do you mean you felt something?
I mean, it felt like...
like Dean.
Like he was there, just
out of eyeshot or something.
I don't know if it's
my psychic thing or what.
But do you think it's even possible?
Do you think his spirit could be around?
Anything's possible.
Well, there's one way to find out.
- where are you going?
- I got to
- pick something up. I'll be back.
- Wait, Sam.
I promise
I won't hunt this demon.
Not until we know Dean's okay.
I got to say, I'm impressed.
- With what?
- You.
Most people in your spot
would be jello by now, but
you're taking this pretty well.
Maybe a little better than me.
Don't get me wrong,
I was pretty freaked at first. But
now I don't know. Maybe I'm dealing.
So you're okay with dying?
No, of course not.
I just think whatever's
gonna happen is gonna happen.
It's out of my control. It's just...
fate.
That's crap.
You always have a choice.
You can either roll over and die, you
can keep fighting no matter what...
Room 237. Code blue. Dr. Christie
- Dean, where are you going?
- Just Wait here.
Give me another amp of epi, please.
Get away from her!
Still nothing.
All right. Let's call it.
Time of death...
5:11 p.m.
At least she's not suffering anymore.
Hey.
I think maybe you're around.
And if you are,
don't make fun of me for this,
but, um...
But there's one way we can talk.
Oh, you got to be kidding me.
Dean?
Dean, are you here?
God, I feel like I'm at a slumber party.
All right, Sam.
This isn't gonna work.
I'll be damned.
Oh, it's good to hear from you, man.
It hasn't been the
same without you, Dean.
Damn straight.
All right.
Dean, what?
H...
u...
hunt?
What, "hunting"?
Are you hunting?
Dean, it's in the hospital,
what you're hunting?
Do you know what it is?
One question at a time, dude.
What is it?
I don't think it's killing people.
I think it's taking them...
you know, when...
when their time is just up.
A reaper...
Is it after you?
If it's here naturally,
there's no way to stop it.
Yeah, you can't kill death.
Man, you're, uh...
I'm screwed, Sam.
No. No, no, no.
There's got to be a way.
Dad will know what to do.
Dad?
Hey, so dad wasn't in his room.
Where is he?
But I got dad's journal, so...
Who knows? Maybe there's
something in here.
Thanks for not giving up on me, Sammy.
Son of a bitch.
Hi, Dean.
You know, you read the
most interesting things.
For example, did you know that reapers
can alter human perception?
I sure didn't.
Basically they can make themselves
appear however they want...
Like, say...
a pretty girl.
You're much prettier than
the last reaper I met.
I was wondering when
you'd figure it out.
I should have known.
That whole "accepting fate" rap of yours
is far too laid-back for a dead chick.
But, you know, the mother and the body...
I'm still trying to figure that one out.
It's my sandbox.
I can make you see whatever I want.
What is this, like a
turn-on for you, huh?
- Toying With me?
- You didn't give me much choice.
You saw my true form,
and you flipped out.
Kind of hurts a girl's feelings.
This was the only way I
could get you to talk to me.
Okay, fine.
We're talking.
What the hell do you want to talk about?
How death is nothing to fear.
It's your time to go, Dean.
And you're living on
borrowed time already.
What the hell are you
doing down here, buddy?
- I Can explain.
- Yeah?
You're gonna explain to security.
Come on. You follow me.
Hey.
How stupid you think I am?
You really want an
honest answer to that?
You conjuring me, John? I'm surprised.
I took you for a lot of things,
but suicidally reckless
wasn't one of them.
I can always shoot you.
You could always miss.
And you only got one try, don't you?
Did you
really think you could trap me?
Oh, I don't want to trap you.
I want to make a deal.
Dean, are you here?
Couldn't find anything in the book.
I don't know how to help you.
But I'll keep trying, all right?
As long as you keep fighting.
I mean, come on, you can't...
You can't leave me here alone with dad.
We'll kill each other. You know that.
Dean, you got to hold on.
You can't go, man, not now.
We were just starting
to be brothers again.
Can you hear me?
Look, I'm sure you've
heard this before, but...
You got to make an exception.
You got to cut me a break.
Stage 3.
Bargaining.
I'm serious.
My family is in danger.
See, we're kind of in
the middle of this, uh...
war.
- and they need me.
- The fight's over.
- No, it isn't.
- It is for You.
Dean...
you're not the first soldier
I've plucked from the field.
They all feel the same.
They can't leave.
Victory hangs in the balance.
But they're wrong.
- the battle goes on without them.
- My brother,
he could die without me.
Maybe he will.
Maybe he won't.
Nothing you can do about it.
It's an honorable death,
a warrior's death.
I think I'll pass on
the 72 virgins, thanks.
I'm not that into prude chicks anyway.
That's funny.
You're very cute.
There's no such thing
as an honorable death.
My corpse is gonna rot in the
ground, and my family is gonna die.
No.
I'm not going with you.
I don't care what you do.
Well,
like you said...
There's always a choice.
I can't make you come with me.
But,
you're not getting back in your body.
And that's just facts.
So, yes,
you can stay.
You'll stay here for years...
Disembodied.
Scared.
And over the decades, it'll
probably drive you mad.
Maybe you'll even get violent.
What are you saying?
Dean.
How do you think angry spirits are born?
They can't let go,
and they can't move on.
And you're about to become one.
The same thing you hunt.
It's very unsinly,
making deals with devils.
How do I know this
isn't just another trick?
It's no trick.
I will give you the colt
and the bullet.
But you got to help Dean.
You got to bring him back.
Why, John, you're a sentimentalist.
If only your boys
knew how much their daddy loved them.
It's a good trade.
You care hell of a lot more
about this gun than you do Dean.
Don't be so sure.
He killed some people
very special to me.
But, still, you're right.
He isn't much of a threat.
And neither is your other son,
of course.
You know the truth,
right?
About Sammy...
and the other children?
Yeah.
I've known for a while.
But Sam doesn't, does he?
You've been playing dumb.
Can you bring Dean back?
Yes or no.
No.
But I know someone who can.
It's not a problem.
Good.
And before I give you the gun,
I'm gonna want to make
sure that Dean's okay,
with my own eyes.
Oh, John, I'm offended.
Don't you trust me?
Fine.
- So we have A deal?
- No, John, not yet.
You still need to sweeten the pot.
With what?
There's something else I want
as much as that gun.
Maybe more.
It's time to put the pain behind you.
And go where?
Sorry.
I can't give away the big punch line.
Moment of truth.
No changing your mind later.
So, what's it going to be?
What are you doing that for?
I'm not doing it.
What the hell...!
You can't do this!
Get away!
What's happening?!
Today's your lucky day, kid.
Dean!
Help! I need help!
I can't explain it.
The edema has vanished.
The internal contusions are healed.
Your vitals are good.
You got to have some kind
of angel watching over you.
Thanks, doc.
You said a reaper was after me?
Yeah.
How did I ditch it?
You got me.
Dean, you really don't
remember anything?
No.
Except this
pit in my stomach.
Sam, something's wrong.
How you feeling, dude?
Fine, I guess.
I'm alive.
That's what matters.
Where were you last night?
I had some things to take care of.
Well, that's specific.
Come on, Sam.
Did you go after the demon?
No.
You know, why don't I
believe you right now?
Can we not fight?
You know, half the time we're fighting,
I don't know what we're fighting about.
We're just butting heads.
Look, Sammy, I've...
I've made some mistakes.
But I've always done the best I could.
I just don't want to
fight anymore, okay?
Dad, are you all right?
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm just a little tired.
Hey, son, would you mind, uh...
Would you mind getting
me a cup of caffeine?
Yeah. Yeah, sure.
What is it?
You know, when, uh...
When you were a kid,
I'd come home from a hunt,
and after what I'd seen, I'd be...
I'd be wrecked.
And you...
You'd come up to me, and
you'd put your hand on my shoulder, and
you'd look me in the eye, and you'd...
You'd say, "it's okay, dad".
Dean.
I'm sorry.
Why?
You shouldn't have had to say that to me.
I should've been saying that to you.
You know, I put...
I put too much on your shoulders.
I made you grow up too fast.
You took care of Sammy.
You took care of me.
You did that.
And you didn't complain. Not once.
I just want you to know...
that I am so proud of you.
Is it really you talking?
Yeah.
Yeah, it's really me.
Why are you saying this stuff?
I want you to watch out for Sammy, okay?
Yeah, dad, you know I will.
You're scaring me.
Don't be scared, Dean.
Okay.
Dad?
No, no, no, it's our dad. It's our dad!
Okay. Let's try again.
An amp of atropine.
Come on...
Okay. Stop compression.
- Come on, Come on.
- still No pulse.
Okay. That's it, everybody.
I'll call it.
Time of death, 10:41 a.m.