Wendy, they're dead!
Brody, pull it together.
We don't have a chance, okay?
We have to get out of here now!
No, Brody.We are not leaving.
We have got to find my sister.
No!
No, I am getting out of here right now!
Brody!
Brody, get back here!
God, you son of a bitch!
Cut.
What the hell was that?
Thanks.
Here you go.
Thanks, Walter.
Don't mark that.
It's all good, Tara.
That was great.
Uh, let's do it again.
Uh, maybe we try dialing
up that scream, huh?
I know, I know.
I'm just -- I'm having
trouble with the tennis ball.
That is just for cg registration.
When ivan and the fx guys are done,
it is going to look terrifying.
You want to look at the
concept sketches again?
No, that's okay.
I'll find it.
I know you will, pumpkin, huh?
Okay.
Going again, everybody.
10-Minute reload for camera and sound.
No, man, I'm telling you.
Working alone behind the sets or after
wrap, I catch this weird vibe sometimes.
Like what?
Mmm, like something's watching.
Come on.
Hey.
Working on a movie like this?
Weird crap's bound to happen.
Frank thinks the stage is
haunted. Like, for real.
All I'm saying is, they call wrap,
I get done, and I get out of here.
Fast.
Guy is definitely off his meds.
Brody, come back.
You son of a bitch.
Brody, come back, you son of a bitch.
Hello?
Guys?
Come on.
It's not funny.
Okay.
Ha ha, very funny.
Hello?
Who's there?
Now, that's what I'm talking about!
First opened in 1927, the lot has been
in continuous operation for eight decades.
Hey, you know this is where
they filmed "Creepshow"?
Now to the right here is Stars Hollow.
It's the setting for the
television series "Gilmore Girls."
And if we're lucky, we might even
catch one of the show's stars.
Come on.
Let's finish the tour.
And then up to the right here, we have New York
Avenue, and that's where they shot "Lois & Clark."
Sammy, check it out.
It's matt damon.
Yeah.
I'm pretty sure that's not Matt Damon.
No, it is.
Well, Matt Damon just picked
up a broom and started sweeping.
Yeah, he was probably
researching a role or something.
Uh, I don't think so.
Hey, this way.
Uh, I think stage 9's over here.
Come on, man.
Let's keep going this way.
No, come on.
We got to work.
Golly.
Dude, you wanted to come to L.A.
Yeah, for a vacation!
I mean, swimming pools and movie stars!
Not to work.
This seem like swimming
pool weather to you, Dean?
It's practically canadian.
Yeah.
I just figured that, you know, after everything that happened
with madison, you could use a little R&R,  that's all.
Maybe I want to work, Dean.
Maybe it keeps my mind off things.
Okay, okay, all right.
So this crew guy, what,
did he ...he died on set?
Yeah, rumors spreading
like wildfire online.
They're saying the set's haunted.
Like "poltergeist"?
Could be a poltergeist.
No, no, no.
The movie "poltergeist."
You know nothing of your
cultural heritage, do you?
It was rumored that the set of "poltergeist" was
cursed, that they used real human bones as props.
Like, at least three of
the actors died in it.
Yeah, might be something like that.
All right, so this crew guy.
What's his name?
Frank Jaffe.
You got a death certificate
or a coroner's report?
Well, no, but, uh, it's L.A., You know?
That might not even be his real name.
But the girl who found him, she said
she saw something ... a vanishing figure.
What's the girl's name?
Uh, Tara Benchley.
Whoa, Tara Benchley?
From "feardotcom" and
"ghost ship" Tara Benchley?
Dude, why didn't you say so?
So now you're suddenly on board?
I mean, I'm a fan of her work.
It's very good.
No, look.
Don't get me wrong.
Everyone at this studio loves
the dailies, myself included.
We were just wondering if it could be...
You know, a little brighter.
Brighter?
Yeah, Jay, more color.
Mcg, you know what I'm saying.
You're the master of that stuff.
Brad, this is a horror movie.
Who says horror has to be dark?
It's just -- It's sort of
depressing, don't you think?
Uh, excuse me.
Uh, green-Shirt guy?
Yeah, yeah, you.Come here.
Can you get me a, uh,
smoothie from craft?
You want a what from who?
You are a P.A.
This is what you do.
Yeah, he, uh...
One smoothie coming right up.
What's a P.A.?
I think they're kind of like slaves.
They'll let anybody
in this business, huh?
6, 6, 6. Mark.
Ready!
Okay, why don't we take it
from, "come on, it'll be fun"?
And action.
Come on.
It'll be fun.
Dicta sunt explicabo.
God, I hate you so much right now.
Cut!
Very nice.
So?
No emf anywhere.
Great.
So, what do you think?
Well, I think being a P.A.Sucks, but...
But the food these people get?
Are you kidding me?
I mean, look at these things.
They're like miniature
philly cheesesteak sandwiches.
They're delicious.
Maybe later.
What did you find out
about the dead crew guy?
Uh, Frank Jaffe was just
filling in for the day.
Nobody here knew him or
where he lived or anything.
Oh, great.
So you found out about as much as I did.
Hey, guys.
Oh, hey.
They're wonderful.
Listen.
I did dig up some stuff
about stage 9's history.
Four people died messy here over the past 80
years, two suicides and two fatal accidents.
Any one of those could
be a vengeful spirit.
Yeah.
Just got to narrow it down more.
I'll get right on that.
Hey, are you supposed
to get one of these?
I..I don't really know what I'm doing.
First day?
Yeah, my big break.
You know, I know it's really uncool
to say this, but I'm a big fan.
I loved you in "boogeyman."
Oh, god.
What a terrible script.
Uh, but, thank you.
Yeah.
You found him, right?
The -- The
dead guy?
I'm sorry.
You probably don't
want to talk about this.
No, no, actually,
it's -- It's okay.
Nobody around here really
brings it up very much.
I think they're all scared I'm
gonna have some kind of breakdown.
That must have been awful.
What happened?
It was horrible.
There ... there was all this blood coming
from his eyes, from his mouth, and, uh...
I saw this, um...
What?
I saw this shape.
To tell you the truth, I
don't know actually what I saw.
I just know I saw it.
Thanks, Walter.
Uh, so this -- This crew
guy Frank, did you know him?
No, not that well.
That's funny.
It's like no one around
here actually knew the guy.
I got his picture.
You do?
Yeah.
I take polaroids of all the crew.
It's just one of those things
you do to kill time on the set.
Right there.
Son of a bitch.
Gerard st.James?
Yes?
You're still alive, and
you're not Frank Jaffe.
NO
You were -- You were desert soldier number 4
in "Metalstorm: The destruction of jared-Syn."
I was.
I knew I recognized you.
I am a huge fan.
I mean, your turn as the tractor-Crash
victim in "Critters 3" ...wow.
Hey, well, please.
Come in.
Thanks.
Yeah, it was the producers.
I mean, they brought me in
for the day to play Frank.
Just to fake your death?
Well, rumors of a haunted film set...
Free publicity, especially when you're making a horror
movie I mean, it's already all over the internet.
Yeah, we know.
These days, it's all about
new media, building buzz.
They say I'm the new "lonelygirl."
Who?
And the ghost Tara saw?
Projected on a screen of diffusion.
Isn't that kind of cruel...
Messing with their heads like that?
Hey, I just play the part.
I don't write the script.
Speaking of...
I'm playing willy in a dinner-Theater production
of "salesman" at costa mesa all next month.
Get a free pepper steak with the coupon.
Well, now, wait a second.
If you're seen in public,
won't that ruin the hoax?
Oh, please.
Frank and willy, , ,
totally different characters.
You know what?
Thanks very much, Mr. Saint.James.
It was just nagging at us.
But we're ...we're very glad,
you know, you're alive and well.
Yeah.
Absolutely.
I wanted to ask you.
What was it like working
with Richard Moll?
He's from "metalstorm."
He was Hurok, King
of the Cyclops people.
Gentleman's gentleman.
Yeah?
All right.
Pepper steak.
When we read from that book, we must
have brought them back...back from hell.
Now they're trying to use us...
It doesn't matter.
We're not going till we
find Wendy and her sister.
Got it?
Good.
Now, let's get busy.
Cut!
No good for sound.
I'm getting some kind of feedback.
Another costly sound delay.
All right, we're going
again for sound, people!
Thank you!
No, it's a great scene,
really ..Dynamite.
But I still got a few...
Not -- Not problems,
just questions.
Like what?
Well, for one thing. The rules
aren't really landing for me.
Like, the kids do this latin chant,
and that makes the ghosts show up?
Yeah.
If the ghosts are in hell,
how do they hear the chanting?
I mean, what, do they
have super hearing?
Well, it's a logic bump.
The rules don't track.
Marty, you're the writer.
What about throwing in an explainer?
Yeah, that'd be super.
I got to check some messages.
Suits.
Has mcg seen this?
I like the whole body-Paint,
black-And-White thing, but, gee, I...
I don't think those neck wounds
are really gonna read on-Camera.
They need to be red.
You know what I'm saying?
Hey, Jay!
I need to speak to makeup.
Yeah?
Wait up.
When we read from that book, we must
have brought them back ...back from hell.
I don't understand.
If they were in hell, how
could they hear our chanting?
They must have super hearing.
Wendy?
Oh, Mitch!
God, you're alive!
You won't get rid of me that easy.
Rumble, rumble, rumble!
Salt.
Okay, we need salt.
I read in that book that
it keeps ghosts away.
Kendra, logan, you guys check the back.
The poor bastard killed
himself, like, for real.
Shouldn't we shut it down or something?
We had a moment of silence
for him at breakfast.
He was just a studio guy.
Shh.
I love you.
I know.
I'm sorry.
Can we ...can we cut or something?
Uh, yeah.
Cut.
Cut!
That's a cut!
Only I get to say "cut."
Hey, what's up?
I'm just a little upset.
With everything that's been
going on, who can blame you?
I just can't wrap my head
around the dialogue, you know?
"Salt" -- Doesn't
that sound silly?
I mean, why would a
ghost be afraid of salt?
Okay, um...
Marty, what do you think?
Not married to salt.
What do you want?
We still sticking with condiments?
Mmm, it just sounds
different, not better.
What else would a ghost be scared of?
Oh, you got to be kidding me.
What would a ghost be scared of?
Maybe shotguns.
That makes even less sense than salt.
These people are idiots.
Walter's a little testy for a P.A., Huh?
How's it going in here?
Really good -- Tara has stepped up her performance,
and I think it's from the sense-Memory stuff.
Sense-Memory?
Yeah.
Dean, you know, when I ask how it's going
here, I'm talking about the case, right?
We don't really work here.
You know, I thought
you hated being a P.A.
I don't know.
It's not so bad.
I kind of feel like part
of the team, you know?
It's good.
Oh, taquito?
They're wonderful.
No.
Um, listen.
I conned my way into the morgue.
News reports are right.
Brad's a doornail
-- No question.
Copy that.
Sorry.What?
"Copy that"?
What did you say?
The news reports are right.
Brad's a doornail.
They're aware.
Who's aware?
Sorry.
What were you saying?
Uh, uh, the newspaper's right.
Brad's a doornail.
No question about it.
I guess it's a good
thing we didn't skip town.
Oh, come here.
I want you to hear something.
Copy that.
On my way.
Hey, Dave.
Can you play that thing
you were playing me earlier?
Sure.
Thanks.
It doesn't matter.
We're not leaving till we
find Wendy and her sister.
Got it?
Good.
Now, let's get busy.
E.V.P.
From the night of Brad's stage dive.
All of a sudden, I'm getting
electromagnetic readings up the wazoo.
For some reason, it's
a legit haunting now.
Well, whose ghost, Dean?
What's it want?
I think we should take a
look at Brad's death scene.
Now, where'd you get this dvd?
They're called dailies.
I got it from cindy.
She's kind of got this
thing going with drew.
He dubbed me an extra copy.
All right.
Here's where the guy
fell through the roof.
Right.
All right, here we go.
They must have super hearing.
Wait.
Go back, go back.
Right after -- Right
after -- Yeah, right.
Wait.
There.
It's like "3 men and
a baby" all over again.
Selleck, danson, and guttenberg,
and I don't know who played the baby.
What's your point?
There's a scene where people say that
the camera caught a ghost on film.
Apparently, in the background of one of the
scenes, there was this boy that nobody remembers.
Spirit photography.
I've seen her before.
Here.Check this out.
Yeah, go for ozzie.
No, I don't have a 20 on Tara.
I think she's 10-100.
Okay, copy that.
I'm sorry.
What were you saying?
Elise Drummond. Starlet
back in the '30s.
Had an affair with a studio exec.
He uses her up, fires
her, leaves her destitute.
Elise hangs herself from stage 9's rafters
right into a scene they're shooting.
Just like our man Brad.
So, what, she's got it
in for the studio brass?
Possibly.
I mean, it's a motive, and
Brad's death matches hers exactly.
We're digging tonight, aren't we?
That's a wrap, people!
6:00 A.M.Call for crew tomorrow.
Great work, everybody!
Mcg, you're a genius.
You're kickin' ass and taking names.
Good night, Jay.
Yeah.
Which way?
Over here.
Hey.
Yeah?
Hey, this map is totally
worth the 5 bucks.
Hey, we got to go check out Johnny
Ramone's grave when we're done here.
You want to dig him up, too?
Bite your tongue, heathen!
You know, Dean, what I
don't get is, why now?
I mean, after 75 years, Elise
Drummond suddenly goes homicidal.
You know, why this movie?
Well, maybe she's mad they're
making a scary ghost flick.
Is it really that scary?
Here we go.
Yahtzee.
I know.
No, I friggin' hate mcg's dailies.
I can't control the guy.
I'm telling you -- Next
one I'm directing myself.
What, you?
No, bob.
You I love.
You're a genius.
You're kicking ass and taking names.
Yeah, okay.
Yeah.
Talk to you later, babe.
Uh-Huh.
What a dick.
Oh, great.
Hey, guys!
Producer walking here!
Hello!
Hey!
Hey, pal.
Can you, uh, show me to the exit?
I can't see a damn thing here.
Hey!
Hey, putz.
I'm talking to you.
Somebody could get hurt here.
What the hell?
No!
They never forgive.
They never forget.
Mitch?
Ashley?
This summer, they're coming
back again to settle the score...
Again.
You out here?
Ashley and Todd
-- They're dead!
Wendy, they're dead!
These bastards aren't taking
us, not without a fight.
I am getting out of here right now!
Brody!
From the makers of
"Cornfield Massacre"...
"Monster truck, " "Charlie's angels"...
"Charlie's Angels 2: Full throttle"...
And "Hell hazers" comes a
new experience in terror.
We must have brought them
back ...back from hell. AGAIN
This film not yet rated
Rolled in with a giant fan.
Same thing happened to an electrician
back in '66 -- A guy named Billy Beard.
What the hell, dude?
I don't know.
It doesn't seem like Elise this time.
We already torched her.
Are we dealing with another ghost?
Maybe.
Yeah, but these things
don't usually tag-Team.
Everybody!
Gather around, okay?
I got an announcement to make.
Hold that for me.
Everyone!
Huddle in!
In light of Jay's accident last night and in cooperation with
the authorities, we're shutting down production for a few days.
I know, I know.
Look, I'm not going to lie to you.
We've had a few setbacks this week.
But we all know what Jay and
Brad wanted more than anything.
And that was to see "Hell Hazers 2: The
Reckoning" on screens all across America.
Now, we owe it to them to go on and to
pull together and make this damn movie, huh?
But... but ... but ... but
...but not ... not today.
Go home.
Someone will call you.
Wendy.
What, are you afraid of ghosts?
Come on.
It'll be fun.
Hey.
So, you find out where
the electrician's buried?
He wasn't.
Billy beard was cremated.
Great.
Now what?
No idea.
Anymore ghost cameos in the dailies?
Not in the first six hours.
You know.
Maybe the spirits are trying to shut
down the movie 'cause they think it sucks.
'Cause, I mean, it kind of does.
From, uh, "come on, it'll be fun"?
Come on.
It'll be fun.
Listen to the invocation.
Dean, that's the real deal a
necromantic summoning ritual.
What the hell is that
doing in a hollywood movie?
No, dear.
We're down for a few days.
It's cool, it gives me time to
pitch that time-Travel thing.
Yeah.
All right, well, look.
Get back to me on this, all right?
Seriously.
No, I'm serious.
Dude, are you serious?
'Cause I'm serious.
All right.
Cool.
Guys, we're all shut down.
What are you still doing here?
Yeah, uh...
Really sorry, man.
We -- We -- We
couldn't help ourselves.
We just had to tell you
that we read the script.
And?
Yeah.
It's, uh...
It's awesome.
Awesome.
Really awesome.
I know.
It's pretty rockin', right?
I'm glad you guys liked it.
Yeah.
I-I really liked all
the attention to detail.
Dude, right on.
That's my thing.
I mean, you know, color
me guilty, but that is me.
I'm a total detail buff.
No, I mean, the way you worked in all those Enochian
summoning rituals and all the authentic language and...
What, you mean that latin crap?
No, man.
That's Walter.
Walter Dixon, the original writer.
You like that garbage?
Wait, Walter --
The P.A.Walter?
No, he's not a P.A.
He's got a clause in his contract
that allows him to come on set.
But he wrote the invocations?
He wrote a wackjob screenplay.
There's no pace.
There's no love interest.
It's all wackadoo exposition.
I had to cut, like, 90% of it to make
it readable, another 10% to make it good.
Should have kept
Walter's original script.
It's actually pretty good.
Yeah.
And it reads like a how-To
manual of conjuration,
Like a textbook on how to summon ghosts
and get them to do whatever you want.
Yeah, like kill people.
Yep.
So let's say somewhere down the line,
Walter learned some pretty black magic.
Yeah, and let's say he's pissed at
these people for wrecking his movie.
Motive and means.
It's worth checking out.
So?
You wanted to meet?
Hey, I'm a little busy here, buddy.
I'm working on a script.
Oh, yeah.
You guys worked on it a lot.
It needed work.
Now, why couldn't we have
done this in my office?
You know, the history, the lore in
my draft was completely accurate.
We could have gotten it right for the first time ever
in this whorehouse of a town, but you tore it to shreds.
You replaced it with
cleavage and fart jokes.
It was real.
Who gives a rat's ass about real?
We're talking about ghosts here, Walter.
There's no such thing.
That's where you're wrong, martin.
Okay, nutjob...
End of meeting.
C oh, my god, no!
Please, no!
You ruined it, martin!
Everything I worked for!
Oh, god!
Walter!
Now you're gonna find out
what being a ghost is like!
Walter, please!
Walter, help me!
Help!
You are one hell of a P.A.
Yeah, I know.
What are you doing?
Could ask you the same thing, Walter.
Raising these spirits from the dead?
Making them murder for you?
That's playing with fire, Walter.
You don't understand.
You know what?
You're right.
I don't understand.
Wait, look.
You put your heart and soul into
something, years of hard work ... years.
And then they take it,
and they crap all over it!
And then -- And then they want
you to smile and say thank you.
Walter, listen.
It's just a movie.
That's it.
Look.
I got nothing against you, man.
You're not part of this.
Just please --
Please, just leave.
But martin's got to stay.
Sorry, can't do that.
It's not that we like him or anything.
It's a matter of principle.
Then I'm sorry, too.
Walter.
Walter,
pl-- Don't.
Sam!
Come on.
Come out to the coast.
We'll get together, have a few laughs.
Oh, man!
I can't frickin' believe this.
Ghosts are real.
What makes you say that?
But I don't understand.
How is Walter controlling them?
Probably that talisman.
What are you doing?
If film cameras pick
these suckers up, then...
Maybe, uh...
Dean, right there!
Hey!
Right there!
Here.
Get the idea?
Yeah.
All right, you hold them off.
I'm going after Walter.
I cannot believe there's an afterlife.
There's an afterlife, all right.
But mostly it's a pain in the ass.
There!
It's over, Walter.
TherE.
Okay, now no one can have it.
I wouldn't have done that if I were you.
Yeah?
Why not?
'Cause you just freed them.
We can't stop them now.
Walter, you brought them back...
Forced them to murder.
They're not going to
be very happy with you.
Yeah?
So, why not?
Oh, god.
There!
But I don't understand.
How come the spirits
appear in the camera phone?
The video must pick up their
frequencies in a way that our eyes can't.
Oh, God.
Right there!
Cut!
Oh, print that one.
That's in the movie.
Oh!
Loved it, kids,  loved it!
You find out there's an afterlife,
and this is what you do with it?
I needed a little jazz on the page.
You're one hell of a P.A.
Thank you.
Hi.
God, I love this town.