- Meg.
- Hi.
whoa, whoa!
- You were hunting with Jo?
- Yeah, for a while now.
The mooks have melted down
the gun by now.
Well, I hear differently.
And if you are still set
on the insane task
of killing the devil,
this is how we do it.
In chapter 33 of "supernatural,"
there was that girl, Bela.
She stole the colt
from you,
and then she "said"
she gave it to Lilith, remember?
- Yeah.
- Well, you know she lied, right?
- She never really gave it to Lilith.
- What?
Bela gives the colt
to a demon named, Crowley.
Crowley?
Oh.
Mr. Pendleton, I presume.
The name's Crowley.
I-in my negotiations,
I was, uh,
dealing with a very young,
attractive, uh, lady.
Yes. I know.
But you,
piggy banker...
You... are a big fish
and I wanted
to do you the honor
of sealing this deal
personally.
But she said the deal
would be sealed with a kiss.
That's right.
No, I mean, she's...
Your choice.
You can cling to six decades
of deep-seated homophobia
or just give it up,
and get
a complete bailout
of your bank's
ridiculous incompetence.
There are just things...
Going once...
No, I don't think so.
Going twice...
All right!
No!
Got him.
Supernatural Season 5 Episode 10
"Abandon All Hope"
The demon Crowley
is making a deal,
even as we speak, it's...
Going... down.
"going down"?
Right.
Okay, huggy bear.
just don't lose him.
I won't lose him.
Damn you.
Enjoy, the obscene wealth.
See you in 10 years.
I followed him.
It's not far, but...
It's layered in enochian
warding magic.
I can't get in.
That's okay. You did great.
We'll take it from here.
# everybody plays the fool
sometimes #
# there's no exception
to the rule #
# listen, baby #
# it may be factual,
may be cruel #
# I ain't lyin' #
# everybody plays the fool #
Yeah?
Hello? my car broke down.
I-I need some help.
I'll be down
in a minute.
Evening, pretty lady.
Get yourself
on in here.
I just need
to make a call.
You don't need
to call anyone, baby.
We're the only help
you're ever gonna need.
You know what, I...
I think I should wait
by my car.
We said get
your ass in here.
Nice work, Jo.
Thanks.
Okay. Shall we?
# everybody plays the fool #
# listen to me, ba...#
It's "Crowley," right?
So... the hardy boys
finally found me.
Took you long enough.
Do you have any idea
how much this rug costs?
This is it, right?
This is, what it's all about.
We need to talk.
Privately.
What the hell
is this?
Do you know how deep
I could have buried this thing?
There's no reason
you or anyone
Should know
this even exists at all.
Except that I told you.
You told us?
Rumours, innuendo...
sent out on the grapevine.
Why?
Why tell us anything?
I want you, to take
this thing to Lucifer
and empty it
into his face.
Uh-huh.
Okay,
and why exactly
would you want the devil dead?
It's called...
Survival.
But I forgot... you two,
at best, are functional morons.
Yeah, you're
functioning... morons.
Mor...
Lucifer isn't a demon,
remember?
He's an angel...
an angel famous for
his hatred of humankind.
To him, you're just...
filthy bags of pus.
If that's the way
he feels about you...
what can he think
about us?
But he created you.
To him, we're just servants.
Cannon fodder.
If Lucifer manages
to exterminate humankind...
we're next.
So...
Help me.
Huh?
Let's all go back
to simpler, better times.
Back to... when we could all
follow our natures.
I'm in sales, damn it.
So, what do you say?
What if...
I give you this thing...
And you go kill the devil?
Okay.
Great.
You wouldn't
happen to know
where the devil is,
by chance, would you?
Thursday.
Birdies tell me...
He has an appointment
in Carthage, Missouri.
Great.
Thanks.
Oh, yeah, right. You probably
need some more ammunition.
Uh, excuse me
for asking,
But aren't you kind of signing
your own death warrant?
I mean, what happens to you
If we go up against
the devil and lose?
Number one... he's gonna
wipe us all out anyway.
Two... after you leave here,
I go on an extended vacation
to all points nowhere.
And three... how about
you don't miss?!
Okay?!
Morons!
All right, big boy.
Let's go.
I think I'm starting
to feel something.
It's got to be
a trap, right?
Sam Winchester having
trust issues with a demon.
Well, better late than never.
Yeah, and thank you again
for your continued support.
You're welcome.
And, you know,
trap or no trap,
We got a snowball's chance,
we got to take it, right?
Yeah, I suppose.
Besides, I'm not sure
it is a trap.
Check it out.
Carthage is lit up
like a Christmas tree
With revelation omens.
And look at this
there's been six
missing persons reported
In town, since Sunday.
I think the devil's there.
Okay.
Look, when you think about it...
you can't come with.
Dean...
Look, I go against Satan
and screw the pooch...
Okay.
We've lost a game piece,
that we can take.
But if you're there...
Then we are handing the devil's
vessel right over to him.
That's not smart.
Since when have we ever
done anything smart?
I'm serious, Sam.
So am I.
Haven't we learned
a damn thing?
If we're gonna do this,
we're gonna do it together.
Okay.
That's, a stupid friggin' idea.
Boy, talk about
stupid ideas.
Good god.
True, that.
Mm.
- Hey.
So...
Dangerous mission
tomorrow.
Mm.
Guess it's time to...
Eat, drink, and...
you know...
Make merry.
Are you giving me the
"Last night on earth", speech?
What?
No.
If I was, would, uh...
w-would that work?
No.
Sweetheart, if this is
our last night on earth,
Then I'm going to spend it
With a little thing
I call, "self-respect."
If you're into
that kind of thing.
Everybody, get in here!
It's time for the line-up.
Usual suspects,
in the corner.
Oh, come on, Bobby.
Nobody wants
their picture taken.
Hear, hear.
Shut up.
you're drinkin' my beer.
Anyway...
I'm gonna need something
to remember your sorry asses by.
Ha!
Always good
to have an optimist around.
Bobby's right.
Tomorrow we hunt the devil.
This is our last night on earth.
You getting a signal?
No, nothin'.
Nice and spooky.
Place seem
a little empty to you?
We're gonna go
check out the PD.
You guys stay here,
see if you can find anybody.
Okay.
Ever heard of
a door handle?
Of course I have.
What is it, Cass?
This town's not empty.
Reapers.
"Reapers"? As in more than one?
They only gather like this
at times of great catastrophe...
Chicago fire,
San Francisco quake...
Pompeii.
Excuse me. I need to find out
why they're here.
Hello, brother.
Station's empty.
So is everything else.
Have you seen, Cass?
What?
He was with you.
Nope. He went after
the reapers.
Reapers?
He saw reapers, Where?
Well, kind of...
everywhere.
Lucifer.
So, I take it you're here
with the Winchesters.
I came alone.
Loyalty.
Such a nice quality to see
in this day and age.
"Castiel," right?
Castiel...
I'm told you came here
in an auto mobile.
Yes.
What was that like?
Um...
Slow.
Confining.
What a peculiar
thing you are.
What's wrong
with your vessel?
Yes, um...
Nick is wearing a
bit thin, I'm afraid.
He can't contain me
forever, so...
You...
You are not taking
Sam Winchester.
I won't let you.
Castiel.
I don't understand
why you're fighting me,
Of all the angels.
You really have to ask?
I rebelled, I was cast out.
You rebelled.
You were cast out.
Almost all of heaven
wants to see me dead,
and if they succeed,
guess what?
You're their new public
enemy number one.
We're on the same side,
like it or not, so...
Why not just serve
your own best interests?
Which, in this case,
just happen to be mine.
I'll die first.
I suppose you will.
Well, this is great. we've been
in town for 20 minutes.
We've already lost
the angel up our sleeve.
You think, uh...
you think Lucifer got him?
I don't know
what else to think.
There you are.
Meg!
You shouldn't have
come here, boys.
Yeah? well, I could say
the same thing for you.
Didn't come
here alone, Dean-o.
Hell hounds!
Yeah, Dean...
your favorite.
Come on, boys.
My father
wants to see you.
I think we'll pass. Thanks.
Your call.
You can make this easy,
or you can make it
really, really hard.
When have you known us
to ever make anything easy?
Run!
Dean!
Jo, stay back!
No!
Aaaaah!
All right. Okay, okay, okay.
Breathe, breathe, breathe.
I'm fine. I'm fine.
Boys, need some help here!
You all right?
Ohhh!
Ohh!
Ohhh...
It'll be all right. Okay?
You're gonna be all right.
Thank you.
How's she holding up?
The salt lines
are holding up.
Safe for now.
Yeah, safe
or trapped like rats.
Hey, you heard Meg.
Her father's here.
This is our one shot, Sammy.
We got to take it,
no matter what.
There we go.
Sam, some help here, please?
The number you dilled
is unavailable.
please try your call again...
Damn it, boys.
KC5 Fox Delta Oscar,
go ahead.
Bobby, it's Dean.
we got problems.
It's okay, boy.
that's why I'm here.
Is everyone all right?
No.
Uh, I-It's...
It's Jo. Bobby, it's pretty bad.
Okay. Copy that.
So now we figure
what we do next.
Bobby, I don't think she's...
I said,
"what do we do next," Dean.
Right.
Okay. Right.
Now... tell me what you got.
Before he went missing,
did Cass say how many reapers?
I-I don't know.
He said a lot of things, I guess.
I mean, does the number matter?
Devil's in the details, Dean.
Bobby, it's Ellen.
The way he was looking,
The number of places
Castiel's eyes went,
I'd say we're talking over a
dozen reapers, probably more.
I do not like
the sound of that.
Nobody likes the
sound of that, Bobby, but...
what... what does
that sound like?
It sounds like death, son.
I think Satan's in town
to work a ritual.
I think he's planning
to unleash death.
You mean like, as in this dude
and taxes are the only sure thing?
As in death... The Horseman,
the pale rider in the flesh.
"Unleash"?
I mean, h-hasn't death been
tromping all over the place?
I mean, hell, I died
several times myself.
Not this guy.
This is... this is
the angel of death,
Big daddy reaper.
They keep this guy chained
in a box 600 feet under.
Last time they hauled him up,
Noah was building a boat.
That's why the place
is crawling with reapers.
They're waiting
on the big boss to show.
You have
any other good news?
Well, in a manner of speaking.
I've been researching Carthage
since you've been gone,
Trying to suss out
what the devil
might want there.
What you just said drops the
last piece of the puzzle in place.
The angel of death must
be brought into this world
at midnight through a place
of awful carnage.
Now, back during the civil war,
there was a battle
in Carthage...
a battle so intense,
the soldiers called it
"The battle of hell-hole."
Where'd the massacre go down?
On the land of
William Jasper's farm.
I got the Winchesters
pinned down...
For now, at least.
What should I do
with them?
Leave them alone.
I-I'm sorry,
but are you sure?
Shouldn't we...
Trust me, child.
Everything happens
for a reason.
Well, Castiel...
You have some time.
Time to change your mind.
So, now we know
where the devil's gonna be,
we know when,
and we have the colt.
Yeah.
We just have to get past...
eight or so hell hounds
and get to the
farm by midnight.
Yeah, and that's after we get
Jo and Ellen the hell out of town.
Won't be easy.
Stretcher?
I'll see what we got.
Stop.
Guys, stop.
Can we, uh, be realistic
about this, please?
I can't move my legs.
I can't be moved.
My guts are being held in
by an ace bandage.
We got to...
We got to get our
priorities straight here.
Number one...
I'm not going anywhere.
Joanna Beth, you stop
talking like that...
Mom.
I can't fight.
I can't walk.
But I can do something.
We've got propane, wiring,
rock salt, iron nails...
Everything we need.
Everything we need?
To build a bomb, Sam.
No!
Jo... no.
You got another plan?
you got any other plan?
Those are hell hounds
out there, Dean.
They've got
all of our scents.
Those bitches will never
stop coming after you.
We let the dogs in,
you guys hit the roof,
make a break for
the building next over,
and I can wait here
with my finger on the button.
Rip those mutts
a new one.
Or at least get you a few
minutes' head start, anyway.
No, I... I won't let you.
This is why we're here, right?
If I can get us
a shot on the devil...
Dean, we have to take it.
No!
That's not...
Mom.
This might literally be
your last chance
to treat me like an adult.
You might want
to take it.
You heard her.
Get to work.
Okay, this is it.
I'll see you
on the other side.
Probably sooner than later.
Make it later.
Okay.
Mom, no.
Somebody's
got to let them in,
and like you said,
you're not moving.
You got me, Jo.
And you're right
this is important.
But I will not
leave you here alone.
Dean?
Get goin' now, boys.
Ellen?
I said go,
and, Dean...
Kick it in the ass.
Don't miss.
I will always love you, baby.
I...
Honey?
Jo...
It's okay.
That's my good girl.
You can go straight back
to hell, you ugly bitch!
I guess we know what happened
to some of the towns people.
Okay.
Last words?
I think I'm good.
Yeah. Me too.
Here goes nothin'.
Hey!
You wanted to see me?!
Well, Sam, you don't
need that gun here.
You know I'd never hurt you.
Not really.
Yeah?
Well, I'd hurt you.
So suck it.
Owww!
Where did you get that?
Now...
Where were we?
Don't feel too bad, Sam.
There's only five things
in all of creation
That, that gun can't kill,
and... I just happen to be
one of them.
But if you give me a minute,
I'm almost done.
You know...
I don't suppose you'd just
say "yes" right here and now?
End this whole
tiresome discussion?
That's crazy, right?
It's never gonna happen!
Oh, I don't know, Sam.
I think it will.
I think it'll happen soon...
Within six months.
And I think it'll
happen... in Detroit.
You listen to me,
you son of a bitch.
I'm gonna kill you myself.
You understand me?
I'm going to
rip your heart out!
That's good, Sam.
You keep fanning
that fire in your belly...
All that pent-up rage.
I'm gonna need it.
What did you do?
What did you do
to this town?
Oh, I was very generous
with this town.
One demon for
every able-bodied man.
And the rest of them?
In there.
I know... it's awful, but...
These horsemen
are so demanding.
So it was... women and children first.
I know what you must
think of me, Sam.
But I have to do this.
I have to.
You, of all people,
should understand.
Well, what's that
supposed to mean?
I was a son.
A brother, like you.
A younger brother,
and I had an older
brother who I loved.
Idolized, in fact.
And one day,
I went to him
and I begged him
to stand with me,
and Michael...
Michael turned on me.
Called me a freak.
A monster,
and then he beat me down.
All because
I was different.
Because I had
a mind of my own.
Tell me something, Sam.
Any of this
sound familiar?
Anyway...
You'll have to excuse me.
Midnight is calling
and I have a ritual to finish.
Don't go anywhere.
Not that you could
if you would.
Now, repeat after me.
We offer up our lives, blood, souls...
we offer up
our lives, blood, souls...
- To complete this tribute.
What?
They're just demons.
You seem pleased.
We're gonna win.
Can you feel it?
You cloud-hopping pansies
lost the whole damn universe.
Lucifer's gonna take over heaven.
We're goin' to heaven, Clarence.
Strange.
Because I heard
a different theory
from a demon
named Crowley.
You don't know Crowley.
He believes that Lucifer
is just using demons
to achieve an end,
and that...
once he does...
he'll destroy you all.
You're wrong.
Lucifer is the father of our race...
Our creator.
Your god may be a
deadbeat, but mine...
Mine walks the earth.
You can't gank demons, can you?
You're cut off
from the home office,
and you ain't got the juice.
So, what can you do,
you impotent sap?
I can do this.
Oh, hello, death.
Just received an update
as the governor has declared
a state of emergency
for Paulding County,
including the towns of Marion,
Fayetteville, and Carthage.
the storm system
has reportedly touched off
a number of tornadoes
in the area.
death tolls have
yet to be estimated.
but state officials expect
the loss of life and property
To be staggering.
Sync by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
Edited by Scooby