Something turned him
into a monster.
- What are we dealing with? do you know?
- Croatoan.
- A demonic virus?
- More like, demonic germ warfare.
What if we all have it?
what if we all go crazy?
Back in 1835, Samuel Colt made a gun.
They say this gun
can kill anything.
- I'm a vessel?
- You're the vessel.
You need my consent. Michael needs
my say-so to ride around in my skin.
Unfortunately, yes.
The answer's no.
- You know who I am?
- Lucifer.
You're the one, Sam.
You're my vessel.
That'll never happen.
- I know you don't trust me.
- So, what are you saying?
That I'm dangerous.
Maybe it's best we just
go our separate ways.
Hi, good evening, brother.
Is your soul rapture-ready?
Thank you, sir, god bless.
Good evening, folks.
is your soul rapture-ready?
Because what I'd like to
do is just show you
Exactly what god's love is for you.
Okay, god bless.
Excuse me, friend, but
have you taken time out
To think about god's plan for you?
Too friggin' much, pal.
We're talking about the colt, right?
I mean, as in the colt?
We are.
Well, that doesn't
make any sense.
I mean, why would the demons
keep a gun around
that uh, kills demons?
What? what did...
I didn't... I didn't get that.
You know, it's kind of funny,
Talking to a messenger of
god on a cellphone.
It's, you know, like watching
a hells angel ride a mo-ped.
This isn't funny, Dean.
The voice says I'm almost out of minutes.
Okay, all right.
I'm... I'm telling you, Cass,
The mooks have melted
down the gun by now.
Well, I hear differently.
And if it's true and if you are still set
on the insane task of killing the devil,
This is how we do it.
Okay. Where do we start?
Where are you now?
Kansas city.
Century, hotel room 113.
I'll be there immediately.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
no, no, come on, man.
I just drove like 16
hours straight, okay?
I'm human.
And there's stuff I got to do.
What stuff?
Eat, for example.
in this case, sleep.
I just need like four hours
once in a while, okay?
Yes.
Okay, so, you can pop in
tomorrow morning.
Yes.
I'll just...
...wait here, then.
Damn it, Cass, I need to sleep!
Dean, it's me.
Sam?
It's quarter past 4:00.
This is important.
So, you're his vessel, huh?
Lucifer's wearing you to the prom?
That's what he said.
Just when you thought you were out,
they pull you back in huh, Sammy?
So, that's it?
that's your response?
- What are you looking for?
- I don't know.
A-a little panic, maybe?
I guess, I'm a little numb
to the earth-shattering
revelations at this point.
What are we gonna do about it?
What do you want
to do about it?
I want back in, for starters.
- Sam...
- I mean it.
I am sick of being a puppet
to these sons of bitches.
I'm gonna hunt him down, Dean.
Oh, so, we're back to
revenge then, are we?
Yeah, 'cause that worked out
so well last time.
Not revenge,
redemption.
So, what, you're just
gonna walk back in
And we're gonna be
the dynamic duo again?
Look, Dean, I can do this.
I can. I'm gonna prove it to you.
Look, Sam...
It doesn't matter...
whatever we do.
I mean, it turns out that
you and me, we're the uh...
The fire and the oil
of the Armageddon.
You know, on that basis alone,
we should just pick a hemisphere...
Stay away from each other for good.
Dean, it does not
have to be like this.
- We can fight it.
- Yeah, you're right, we can.
But not together,
we're not stronger
when we're together, Sam.
I think we're weaker.
Because whatever we have between us...
Love, family, whatever it is...
they are always, gonna use it against us,
and you know that.
We're better off apart.
We got a better chance
of dodging, Lucifer and Michael
and this whole damn thing...
If we just go our own ways.
Dean, don't do this.
Bye, Sam.
Season 5 Episode 4
Little girl?
Little girl.
Are you hurt?
You know the not-talking thing
is kind of creepy, right?
Oh, crap.
# do you love me #
# I can really move #
# I'm in the groove #
# do you love me #
# now that I can da-a-a-nce #
# watch me, now, hey #
# work, work #
"August 1st, 2014."
That's never a good sign.
"Croatoan pandemic reaches, Australia."
I thought I smelled your stink
on this "back to the future" crap.
"president, Palin defends bombing of Houston."
Certainly a buyer's market in real estate.
Let's see what's happening in sports,
that's right... no more sports.
Congress revoked the right
to group assembly.
what's left of congress, that is.
- Hardly a quorum, if you ask me.
- How did you find me?
Afraid we had to tap some
unorthodox resources of late...
Human informants.
We've been making
inspirational visits
to the fringier Christian groups.
They've been given your image,
told to keep an eye out.
The bible freak outside the motel...
He, what, dropped a dime on me?
Onward, Christian soldiers.
Okay, well, good, great.
you have had your jollies.
Now send me back,
you son of a bitch.
Oh, you'll get back...
all in good time.
We want you to marinate a bit.
Marinate?
Three days, Dean.
Three days to see where
this course of action takes you.
What's that supposed to mean?
It means that your choices
have consequences.
This is what happens to the world
If you continue to
say "no" to Michael.
Have a little look-see.
Bobby?
Bobby, I'm coming in!
Oh no.
Where is everybody, Bobby?
"camp Chit-aqua."
Oh, baby, no.
Ohh no baby, what
did they do to you?
What the hell?
I should be asking that
question, don't you think?
In fact, why don't you
give me one good reason
Why I shouldn't gank you
right here and now?
Because you'd only
be hurting yourself.
That's very funny.
Look, man...
I'm no shape-shifter or
demon or anything, okay?
Yeah, I know. I did the drill
while you were out.
Silver, salt, holy water... nothing.
But you know
what was funny...
Was that you had
Every hidden lock-pick,
box cutter, and switchblade
that I carry.
Now, you want
to explain that?
Oh, and the, uh... resemblance,
while you're at it?
Zachariah.
Come again?
I'm you, from the tail end of 2009.
Zach plucked me from my bed
And threw me five
years into the future.
Where is he?
I want to talk to him.
I don't know.
- Oh, you don't know.
- No, I don't know.
Look, I just want to get back
to my own friggin' year, okay?
Okay.
If you're me...
Then tell me something
only I would know.
Rhonda Hurley.
We were, uh... 19.
She made us try on her panties.
They were pink
and satiny,
and you know what?
We kind of liked it.
Touché?
So, what... Zach zapped you
up here to see how bad it gets?
I guess.
Croatoan virus, right?
that's their endgame?
It's efficient, it's incurable,
And it's scary as hell.
Turns people into monsters.
Started hitting the major cities
about two years ago.
World really went
in the crapper after that.
What about, Sam?
Heavy-weight showdown in Detroit,
from what I understand,
Sam didn't make it.
You weren't with him?
No.
No, me and Sam,
we hadn't talked in...
Hell, five years.
We never tried to find him?
I got other people
to worry about.
Where you going?
I got to run an errand.
Whoa, you're just
gonna leave me here?
Yes.
I got a camp full of twitchy
trauma survivors out there
With an apocalypse
hanging over their head.
The last thing they need to see
is a version of "the parent trap."
So, yeah, you stay locked down.
Okay, all right, fine.
But you don't have to cuff me, man.
Oh, come on. you
don't trust yourself?
No.
Absolutely not.
Dick.
Hey, Dean. you got a second?
No. yes.
uh... I-I guess.
Hi, Chuck.
Hi.
So, uh, listen, we're pretty
good on canned goods for now,
But we're down
to next to nothing
On perishables and...
and hygiene supplies.
People are not gonna
be happy about this.
So, what do you
think we should do?
I-I don't know.
Maybe, uh, share?
You know, like at a kibbutz.
Wait a minute. Aren't you supposed
to be out on a mission right now?
Absolutely and I will be.
Uh-oh.
Whoa! geez!
Easy, lady!
- Risa.
You spent the night in, Jane's
cabin last night, didn't you?
Uh, what? I-I don't... did I?
I thought we had a "connection."
Well, I'm sure that we do.
Yeah?
- Hi, Risa.
- Screw you.
Oh, geez. I'm getting busted for
stuff I haven't even done yet.
What?
Uh, never mind.
Hey, Chuck, is... Cass still here?
Yeah.
I don't think, Cass is going anywhere.
So, in this way,
We're each a fragment
of total perception...
Just, uh, one compartment
In that dragonfly eye
of group mind.
Now, the key to this
total, shared perception...
It's, um... it's surprisingly physical.
Oh.
Excuse me, ladies.
I think I need to confer with
our fearless leader for a minute.
Why not go get
washed up for the orgy?
You're all so beautiful.
What are you, a hippie?
I thought you'd gotten
over trying to label me.
- Cass, we got to talk.
- Whoa, strange.
What?
You... are not you...
not "now" you, anyway.
No! yeah, yes exactly.
What year are you from?
2009.
Who did this to you? is it, Zachariah?
Yes.
Interesting.
Oh, yeah, it's friggin' fascinating.
Now why don't you
strap on your angel wings
And fly me back
to my page on the calendar?
I wish I could just,
uh, strap on my wings,
But I'm sorry... no dice.
What, are you stoned?
Uh... generally, yeah.
What happened to you?
Life.
Hey. hey! watch out!
Damn it.
I'm not gonna lie to you.
Me and him...
It's a pretty messed-up
situation we got going.
But believe me,
When you need to know
something, you will know it.
Until then, we all have work to do.
What the hell was that?
what the hell was that?
You just shot a guy in cold blood.
We were in an open quarantine zone...
Got ambushed by some,
Crotes on the way out.
Crotes... Croatoans.
One of them infected, Yager.
How do you know?
'cause after a few years of this, I know.
I started seeing symptoms
about a half an hour ago.
Wasn't gonna be long
before he flipped.
I didn't see the point
In troubling a good
man with bad news.
"troubling a good man"?
You just blew him away
in front of your own people.
Don't you think that
freaked them out a little bit?
It's 2014.
Plugging some crote...
it's called commonplace.
Trading words with my friggin' clone...
that might have freaked them out a little.
All right, look...
No, you look.
this isn't your time. It's mine.
you don't make the decisions, I do.
So, when I say stay in, you stay in.
All right, man. I'm sorry.
Look, I-I'm not trying to
mess you or... me...
Us up here.
I know.
It's just been a really wacky weekend.
Tell me about it.
What was the mission, anyway?
The colt?
The colt.
Where was it?
Everywhere.
They've been moving it around,
took me five years, but...
I finally got it.
and tonight...
...tonight, I'm gonna kill the devil.
So, that's it? that's the colt?
If anything can kill, Lucifer, this is it.
Great.
have we got anything
that can find, Lucifer?
Are you okay?
Oh, we were in, uh,
Jane's cabin last night.
And, apparently, we and...
Risa have a connection.
You want to shut up?
we don't have to find,
Lucifer, we know where he is.
The demon that we caught last week...
he was one of the...
big guy's entourage.
He knew.
So, a demon tells you
where Satan's gonna be,
and you just believe it?
Oh, trust me... he wasn't lying.
and you know this how?
Our fearless leader, I'm afraid,
Is all too well schooled in
the art of getting to the truth.
Torture?
Oh, so, we're... we're torturing again.
No, that's... that's good, classy.
What? I like "past you."
Lucifer is here.
Now, I know the block
and I know the building.
Oh good, it's right
in the middle of a hot zone.
Crawling with crotes, yeah.
You saying my plan is reckless?
Are you saying we, uh, walk in
straight up the driveway,
Past all the demons and the crotes,
- and we shoot the devil?
- yes.
Okay, if you don't like,
uh, "reckless,"
I could use "insouciant," maybe.
Are you coming?
Of course.
but why is he? I mean,
he's you five years ago.
If something happens to him,
you're gone, right?
He's coming.
Okay.
Well, uh... I'll get the grunts moving.
We're loaded and on
the road by midnight.
All righty.
Why are you taking me?
Relax, you'll be fine.
Zach's looking after you, right?
No, that's not what I mean.
I want to know what's going on.
Yeah, okay.
You're coming because I
want you to see something.
I want you to see our brother.
Sam?
I thought he was dead.
Sam didn't die in Detroit.
He said "yes."
"yes"?
Wait.
You mean...
That's right.
The big "yes."
To the devil.
Lucifer's wearing him to the prom.
Why would he do that?
Wish I knew.
But now we don't have a choice.
It's in him, and it's not getting out.
And we've got to kill him, Dean.
And you need to see it...
The whole damn thing,
how bad it gets...
so you can do it different.
What do you mean?
Zach said he was gonna
bring you back, right? to '09?
Yeah.
Well, when you get back home...
You say "yes."
You hear me? say "yes" to, Michael.
That's crazy.
If I let him in, then Michael fights the devil.
The battle's gonna torch half the planet.
Look around you, man.
half the planet's better than no planet,
Which is what we have now.
If I could do it over again,
I'd say "yes" in a heartbeat.
- So why don't you?
- I've tried!
I've shouted "yes"
till I was blue in the face!
The angels aren't listening!
They just... left... gave up!
it's too late for me, but for you
Oh, no. there's got
to be another way.
Yeah, that's what I thought.
I was cocky.
Never actually thought I'd lose.
But I was wrong.
Dean...
I was wrong.
I'm begging you.
Say "yes."
But you won't.
'cause I didn't.
Because that's just not us, is it?
So, you're really from '09?
Yeah, afraid so.
Some free advice?
You ever get back there,
you hoard toilet paper.
You understand me? hoard it.
Hoard it like it's made of gold.
'cause it is.
Thank you, Chuck.
Oh, you'll thank me,
all right. mark my words.
I'll see you around.
Yeah.
Okay.
Let me see those.
You want some?
Amphetamines?
It's the perfect antidote to that absinthe.
Mmm.
Don't get me wrong, Cass.
I, uh...
I'm happy that the stick
is out of your ass, but...
What's going on...
w-with the drugs
And the orgies and the love-guru crap?
What's so funny?
Dean, I'm not an angel anymore.
What?
Yeah, I went mortal.
What do you mean? how?
I think it had something to do
with the other angels leaving,
But when they bailed,
my mojo just kind of...
Shhrr!... drained away.
And now, you know,
I'm practically human.
I mean, Dean I'm all but useless.
Last year, broke my foot...
laid up for two months.
- Wow.
- Yeah.
So, you're human.
Well, welcome to the club.
Thanks.
Except I used to belong
to a much better club.
And now I'm powerless...
I'm hapless, I'm hopeless.
I mean, why the hell
not bury myself
In women and decadence, right?
It's the end, baby. that's
what decadence is for.
Why not bang a few gongs
before the lights go out?
But, then...
That's just how I roll.
There, second-floor window.
We go in there.
You sure about this?
They'll never see us coming.
Trust me.
Now, weapons check.
we're on the move in five.
Hey, uh... me.
Can I talk to you for a sec?
Tell me what's going on.
What?
I know you.
You're lying to these people and to me.
Is that so?
Yeah.
See, I know your lying expressions.
I've seen them in the mirror.
Now, there's something
you're not telling us.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Oh, really?
Well, I don't seem to be the only member
of your posse with some questions,
So, uh, maybe I'll just
take my doubts over to them.
Okay, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa. wait.
What?
Take a look around you, man.
This place should be
white-hot with crotes.
Where are they?
They cleared a path for us.
Which means
that this is...
A trap... exactly.
Well, then we can't go
through the front.
oh, we're not.
they are.
They're the decoys.
You and me... we're going
in through the back.
You mean you're gonna
feed your friends
into a meat grinder?
Cass, too?
You want to use their
deaths as a diversion?
Oh, man, something
is broken in you.
you're making decisions
that I would never make.
I wouldn't sacrifice my friends.
you're right, you wouldn't.
It's one of the main reasons
we're in this mess, actually.
These people count,
on you they trust you.
They trust me to kill the devil
and to save the world,
and that's exactly
what I'm gonna do.
No. Not like this, you're not.
I'm not gonna let you.
Oh, really?
Yeah.
Oh.
Hello, Dean.
Aren't you a surprise.
You've come a long way
to see this, haven't you?
Well, go ahead.
Kill me.
Kill you?
Don't you think that would be
a little... redundant?
I'm sorry.
It must be painful...
Speaking to me in this... shape.
but it had to be your brother.
It had to be.
You don't have to be
afraid of me, Dean.
What do you think
I'm going to do?
I don't know, maybe deep-fry the planet?
Why?
Why would I want to
destroy this stunning thing...
Beautiful, in a trillion different ways...
the last perfect handiwork of god?
You ever hear the story
of how I fell from grace?
Oh, good god. you're not gonna
tell me a bedtime story, are you?
My stomach's almost out of bile.
You know why
god cast me down?
Because I loved him,
more than anything
and then god created...
...you.
The little...
hairless apes.
and then he asked all of us
to bow down before you...
to love you more than him.
and I said, "father...
I can't."
I said, "these human beings
are flawed, murderous."
and for that...
God had, Michael cast me into hell.
Now, tell me...
Does the punishment fit the crime?
Especially when I was right?
Look at what 6 billion of you
have done to this thing.
and how many of
you blame me for it?
You're not fooling me
you know that?
With this sympathy-for-the-devil crap.
I know what you are.
What am I?
You're the same thing, only bigger.
The same brand of cockroach
I've been squashing my whole life,
an ugly, evil, belly-to-the-ground,
supernatural piece of crap.
The only difference
between them and you
Is the size of your ego.
I like you, Dean.
I get what the other angels see in you.
Goodbye.
We'll meet again soon.
You better kill me now!
Pardon?
You better kill me now.
Or I swear, I will find
a way to kill you.
and I won't stop.
I know you won't.
I know you won't say "yes"
to, Michael either.
and I know you won't kill Sam.
Whatever you do...
You will always end up here.
Whatever choices you make,
whatever details you alter,
we will always end up...
...here.
I win.
So, I win.
You're wrong.
See you in five years, Dean.
Oh, well, if it isn't the, ghost
of Christmas "screw you."
Enough.
Dean, enough.
You saw it, right?
you saw what happens.
You're the only person
who can prove the devil wrong.
Just say "yes."
How do I know that this whole
thing isn't one of your tricks?
Huh? some angel hocus-pocus?
The time for tricks is over.
Give yourself to, Michael.
Say "yes," and we can strike.
Before, Lucifer gets to, Sam.
Before billions die.
Nah.
"Nah"?
You telling me you haven't
learned your lesson?
Oh, I've learned a lesson, all right.
Just not the one
you wanted to teach.
Well, I'll just have to teach it again!
Because I got you now, boy,
and I'm never letting you...
Son of a...
That's pretty nice timing, Cass.
We had an appointment.
Don't ever change.
How did, Zachariah find you?
Long story.
Let's just stay away
from Jehovah's witnesses
from now on, okay?
What are you doing?
Something I should have
done in the first place.
Sam.
If you're serious and
you want back in...
...you should hang on to this.
I'm sure you're rusty.
Look man, I'm sorry.
I don't know. I'm...
whatever I need to be.
but I was, uh...
wrong.
What made you change your mind?
Long story.
The point is...
maybe we are each
other's Achilles' heel.
maybe they'll find a way
to use us against each other.
I don't know.
I just know we're all we've got.
More than that.
We keep each other human.
Thank you.
Really, thank you.
I won't let you down.
Oh, I know it.
I mean, you are the second-best
hunter on the planet.
So, what do we do now?
We make our own future.
Guess we have no choice.
Sync by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
Edited by Scooby