Look, dad's gone now.
We have to carry out his legacy.
And that means hunting down
as many evil sons of bitches
as we possibly can.
What the hell
just happened?
That's a devil's gate,
a damn door to hell!
How certain are you
that what you brought back
is 100% pure Sam?
Just tell me who you are.
It doesn't matter.
Just tell me who you are!
You're a demon.
I want to help you from time to time.
Why would you want to help me?
I could help you save your brother.
Back in 1835,
Samuel Colt made a special gun.
This gun can kill anything.
One more.
That's all for tonight, sister.
Come on.
Let me walk you to your car.
Father?
Andy?
Father, God's not with us.
Not anymore.
Andy, of course he is.
Why would you say that?
What's wrong?
He can't help us.
And if he can...
He won't.
Andy, wait!
Hey, what's up?
Might have found
some omens in ohio.
Dry lightning.
Barometric-pressure drop.
Well, that's thrilling.
Plus, some guy blows
his head off in a church
and another goes postal in a hobby shop
before the cops take him out.
Might be demonic omens.
Or just a suicide and a
psycho scrapbooker.
But it's our best lead sinclincoln.
Where in ohio? Elizabethville.
It's a half-dead factory
town in the rust belt.
There's got to be a demon
or two in south beach.
Sorry, hef. Maybe next time.
How's it going, bobby?
Slow.
I tell you, it's a little sad
seeing the colt like that.
The only thing it's good for now
is figuring out what makes it tick.
So what makes it tick?
So, if we want to go check
out these omens in ohio,
you think you can have that thing
ready by this afternoon?
Well, it won't kill demons by then,
but i can promise you it'll kill you.
All right. Come on,
we're wasting the daylight.
- See you, Bobby.
- Hey.
You boys run into anything... anything... you call me.
There's not much left for the insurance company.
It was a suicide.
I saw it myself.
Well, this shouldn't take long, then.
That's where andy did it.
It's the first time i'd seen him in weeks.
He used to come every sunday.
When did he stop?
Probably about two months ago
right around the time everything
else started to change.
Change how?
Let's just say this used to be a town
you could be proud of.
People... cared about each other.
Andy sang in the choir,
and then one day,
he just wasn't andy anymore.
It was like he was...
possessed?
You could say that.
Gambled away his money,
cheated on his wife,
destroyed his business.
Yes.
Like a switch had flipped.
Father, did you know the man
who killed those folks in the hobby shop?
Sure, tony perkins. Tony perkins.
Good man.
Would you say that his personality
suddenly changed one day, too?
I never thought about it that way, but... yes.
About the same time as andy
- about two months ago.
Well, thank you, father.
Appreciate your time.
Two months ago,
we open up the devil's gate,
all of a sudden this town
turns into margaritaville?
It's no coincidence.
Richie.
I don't believe it.
Hey. Dean... winchester, right?
This is my sister, uh, cheryl.
Hi, cheryl.
There.
Well, you know... stepsister.
Come on in.
This is my brother, sam.
Hey. How you doing? Not too bad.
How do you two know each other?
You were in school.
It was that succubus, right?
Yeah, yeah. Oh, man.
You should have seen the
rack on this broad.
Freakin' tragedy when
i had to ganch her.
Whoa, whoa. Wait. Who killed her?
If i remember, your ass was
toast until i showed up.
Oh, i forgot what a
comedian this guy was.
I told you then. I'll tell you again.
You're not cut out for this job.
You're gonna get yourself killed.
Talk to me.
Fyi, winchester... words hurt. Yeah.
No, it's not a good time, baby.
Later.
You find anything in this town, anyway?
Uh, no. I got nothing.
Oh, wait a minute. You mean as
in demons and whatnot?
Yeah.
No, i got nothing. Typical.
What about your sister back there?
Honestly, she definitely had the devil in her,
but she wasn't no demon,
you know what i'm saying?
Right. Seriously.
Church guy, hobby-shop guy...
they were lunch meat
by the time i got there.
Maybe they were possessed,
but i can't prove it.
Yeah, that's where we are, too.
Let's just say the demons are
possessing people in this town.
You know, raising hell.
But why would a demon
blow his brains out?
For fun? He wrecks one body,
moves to another.
Like taking a stolen car for a joyride.
Anybody else that fits the profile...
nice guy turned douche that's still breathing?
There's trotter. Who's that?
He used to be head of the rotary club.
Then he turned bastard all of a sudden.
Brought in the gambling, the hookers.
He practically owns this whole town.
Know where we could find him?
He'll be at his bar in a few hours.
I thought you said this was some
boarded-up factory town.
It is.
At least, it's supposed to be.
Well, what are we waiting for?
Let's do some research.
- Oh, richie. Look at you.
- Hey.
- Bringing satin back.
- Oh, you like this?
Try thai silk... canal street.
You have to pay $300 for
threads like these, easy.
Cost to me... forget about it.
How much is "forget about it"?
Ah, forget about it.
That's trotter over there.
He sits there all night.
Can't touch him.
So, what do we do now?
I don't know about you guys,
but i'm gonna do
a little investigating with that bartender.
Easy. Me and her, we got a little
somethin'-somethin' lined up for later.
Yeah, right.
Stings, don't it?
All right. I got to hit the head.
Release the hostages.
Be back in a few.
No way he gets a girl like that.
I mean, look at her.
You could fit that ass on a nickel.
You think so?
Oh. Sorry, padre.
Knew you boys would find your way here.
They all do.
No offense, but what are you
doing here, father?
Like it or not, you go where your flock is.
- Plus, the clergy drinks for free. - true.
And a certain bartender owes
me a confession.
Not in this lifetime, father.
I better see your butt on sunday.
Nickel or no nickel.
What can i get you boys?
What's your speciality?
I make a mean hurricane.
I guess we'll see about that.
You drink hurricanes?
I do now.
Hi, john.
Reggie. Everything okay with you?
I don't know.
I'm just not feeling myself today.
Hey, what are you doing?!
He slept with my wife.
That bastard slept with my wife!
Somebody call 911!
Too many cops here. I say we roll.
Just be cool.
Poor jerk. Only thing possessing
him was a sixer of pabst.
So, what's the deal, then?
People in this town getting
possessed or not?
I don't know. Maybe it is just what it is...
town full of scumbags.
Yeah. Maybe.
You boys ready for your mug shots?
The photographer's gonna be here in a few
and take your picture for the local paper.
Be an honor, officer. What a thrill.
Yep, time to go.
Wait a second. Wait a second.
What?
Where's richie?
So, how's a bartender afford a place like this?
My parents left it to me.
I don't come out here much...
mostly when i want to be alone.
Wow. This is, uh, charming.
You sure you wouldn't be more comfortable
in a bedroom or my motel room?
I mean, not for nothing, but,
you know, i got oils.
But i have toys.
Yeah, no. Toys trump oils.
You don't get, uh, scared down
here all by yourself?
Of course not.
Not when i've got a hunter to protect me.
Thanks.
You do realize there's red meat
within striking distance, right?
How many times i got to tell richie
he's gonna get himself in trouble?
Dean, you're assuming he's missing.
I mean, maybe he just bailed.
He's a moron.
He's a sweet moron,
but he's not a coward.
He wouldn't just bail. I got to go find him.
Meanwhile, i think i'm
gonna trail this trotter guy.
Yeah?
I don't know. Something about the
way he looked at me last night.
Maybe there is something going on here.
Cute piece.
Who are you?
It won't stop a demon,
if that's what you think.
How the hell would you know?
Oh, i don't know.
Call it an educated guess.
Well, ain't i lucky, then?
Found a subject for a test fire.
Luck has nothing to do with it.
But, hey, by all means.
Take your best shot.
Are you gonna stand
there like a pantywaist,
or are you gonna shoot me?!
That smarts a little.
What do you want?
Peace on earth.
A new shirt.
Now... do you want me to help
you out with that gun or not?
- Dean.
- Sammy.
- Yeah. Hey. I can't talk right now.
- You okay?
Yeah, i'm fine.
Just meet me at the bar
in 20 minutes, okay?
Sam!
I got to tell you...
every woman in this place
- they want to eat you up.
Anybody could have tackled that guy
and wrestled the gun away...
prevented mass murder.
Here's what i'm gonna do.
Normally, i charge $400 a night.
Why don't we call it an even deuce
and get the hell out of here?
What do i look like?
Cheapskate.
Did i just see you strike out with a prostitute?
How's that work?
I just told her i had a thing for the bartender.
It was pretty easy.
Who says the bartender's available?
That's a good question.
You got something going with
some guy about yea tall,
wears a sweat suit? Who?
No. My mistake.
What do you say you and me grab
a drink after your shift?
I say why wait...
when we can go right now?
What are you doing here?
I think maybe you know. Yeah?
Well, i think i'm calling the cops.
Cops?
Breaking and entering, assault...
you're in a peck of trouble, my friend.
Uh, well, i think i could probably explain it!
All right, back up!
Get back. Money's in the safe!
Take it and go.
I don't want your money.
I just got to be sure.
What kind of psycho are you?
Oh, god.
Uh, i'm sorry.
I think this was just a minor
misunderstanding?
How 'bout i just leave, cause...
you know, i'll take these.
I'll, uh, i'll leave this for, uh...
you, uh... have a nice day?
Looks like the maid's day off.
Everything okay?
Make yourself comfortable.
Oh, i forgot to mention...
richie was a friend of mine.
When i realized i could track the
GPS in his cellphone,
i swung by earlier.
Give him a proper burial.
It's better than rotting in
some skank's basement.
Whoops.
Tsk, tsk, tsk.
Isn't that a buzz kill?
Sorry, sister,
but you're going back to where you came from.
I don't think so.
What are you laughing at, bitch?
You're still trapped.
So are you... bitch.
Lose something?
All you demons have
such smart mouths.
It's a gift.
Well, let's see if you're smiling
when i send your ass back to hell.
Without your little exorcism book?
Hey, go ahead.
Having a little trouble there, sport?
Nice try, but i think you just
ordered a pizza.
I guess you should have paid
more attention in latin class.
I don't know what you're smiling about.
You're not going anywhere.
And, apparently, neither are you.
Yeah, but i got somebody
coming for me, and, uh...
he did pay attention in class.
Oh, right... sam.
Everyone says he's the brains of the outfit.
- Everyone? - sure.
You winchester boys are famous.
Not lohan famous, but, you know...
well, that's flattering.
I'll be sure to let sam know when he gets here.
If he shows up first.
What, you thought i was flying solo?
You shouldn't underestimate, dean.
It might be the death of you.
You can give me hard eyes all you want,
but the fact remains,
we just have to wait and
see who shows up first...
the cavalry or the indians.
You look kind of tense.
You know, i know a surefire way to relax.
Maybe later.
Excuse me.
What can i get for you?
Um, you remember the guy
i was with last night?
We sat right here.
The big hero who jumped on reggie.
Yeah, yeah. The... the big hero. Right.
Um, have you seen him around at all today?
Maybe. Depends.
D-depends on what?
Oh, my...
does everyone around here
have their hand out?
He left with casey about an hour ago.
Any idea where they went?
Her place... for bible study.
- You got an address?
- What's wrong with you?
You think i'm gonna give you a co-worker's address
just so you can go over there
and get your freaky peeping-tom rocks off?
Corner of piermont and clinton.
Have fun.
Why don't you relax?
Why don't you kiss my ass?
Why, dean, you're a poet. I had no idea.
Look, we won't have any
effect on the outcome of this.
We might as well be civil.
Civil, huh?
Killing richie... that was civil?
The guy was harmless.
That knife he pulled on me
didn't look so harmless.
A knife wouldn't hurt you.
No, but it would damage this body.
And casey has such a fine body,
i wouldn't want to see it ripped.
A demon with a heart. Wow.
Well, you know, there's a
bunch of dead people in town
that might disagree with you.
Hey, i didn't pull any triggers.
Yeah, you did something.
You want to know what i did
- what i really did?
I had lunch.
- Lunch? - me and trotter.
He had a cheeseburger, i had a salad,
and i just pointed out the
money that could be made
with a few businesses that
cater to harmless vice.
So trotter built it, and, man,
did they come.
Supposedly god-fearing folk,
waist-deep in booze, sex, gambling.
I barely lifted a finger.
- That's it?
- You don't get it.
All you got to do is nudge
humans in the right direction.
Some whiskey here, a hooker there,
and they'll walk right into hell
with big, fat smiles on their faces.
Your kind is corrupt, dean. Weak.
Our will's stronger. That's why we'll win.
And that's how it ends?
No.
That's how it begins.
Dean?
Sulfur.
So, demons take over.
I thought the meek shall inherit the earth.
Oh, according to your bible.
It's only a book, dean.
Not everyone would agree.
Because it's god's book?
Do you believe in god, dean?
I'd be surprised if you did.
I don't know. I'd like to.
Well, i don't see how you and your god
have done such a bang-up job.
War, genocide
- it's only getting worse.
This past century,
you people racked up a body
count that amazed even us.
It's our turn now,
and we're gonna do it right this time.
Don't be hopeful, dean.
You're not delivered.
It's only the wind.
Bobby, it's sam. We got a big problem.
I found some sulfur,
and now i can't find dean.
Call me as soon as you get this.
Hey, excuse me. They weren't there.
I guess you got to catch
your jollies another night.
Here. Why don't you have a drink and relax?
I don't want to relax.
What is it with the people in this town?
Suit yourself, princess.
Father.
Yes?
Um... can i talk to you for a sec?
You're piling it pretty high there, sweetheart.
I'm not sure i'm buying.
Why would i lie?
Demons lie.
Some do.
Some are true believers.
Believers in what?
You think humans have an
exclusive on a higher power?
You have a god?
Sure. His name's lucifer.
You mean the devil?
Your word, not ours.
Lucifer actually means "light bringer."
Look it up.
Once he was the most beautiful
of all god's angels.
But god demanded that he
bow down before man,
and when he refused,
god banished him.
Tell me, dean.
How do you like bowing
before lesser creatures?
Lucifer's really real?
Well, no one's actually seen him,
but they say that he made us into what we are,
and they say that he'll return.
Oh, yeah? And, uh, you believe that?
I've got faith.
So, you see?
Is my kind really all that different than yours?
Well, except that, uh, demons are evil.
And humans are such a lovable bunch.
Dick cheney.
- He one of yours? - not yet.
Let's just say he's got a parking
spot reserved for him downstairs.
.
Hey, speaking of downstairs...
what's it like down there?
What, hell?
Yeah.
That's right.
You booked a one-way ticket with that deal.
You're not gonna like it, dean.
And, um, judging from the trouble you've caused,
i don't think you'll be getting the presidential suite.
No, it's a pit of despair.
Why do you think we want to come here?
So, the... the bartender the other night, casey,
you know her pretty well?
Since she was in pigtails.
Well, um, she and my brother, they, uh...
they... left tonight.
Together.
Well, not that i approve,
but they are consenting adults.
Right.
I'm sorry. You said "brother."
I thought you were insurance investigators.
Right, right. Well, we are.
Um, it's like a family business, you know?
Anyways, um, so, i went to casey's apartment,
and they weren't there.
Um, i just have this feeling that they...
that they might be in trouble.
What kind of trouble?
Just trouble.
Please, father, i need your help.
Is there anything you
could tell me about casey...
anyplace she'd go, maybe?
Yes, there is a place.
Let me get my jacket.
No, wait, father. I can do this by myself.
Son, if casey's really in trouble,
then there's nothing to talk about.
Shall we go?
Kind of funny, don't you think?
You and me sitting here like
a couple of regular folk.
It's hilarious...
you know, in that apocalyptic sort of way.
You're all right, dean.
The others don't describe you that way.
But, you know, you're... you're likable.
A demon likes me.
Sorry, i don't know how to respond to that.
You could say thanks.
That deal you made to save sam...
a lot of others would mock you for it,
think it was weak or stupid.
I don't.
It's been kind of liberating, actually.
What's the point in worrying about a future
when you don't have one, huh?
Still, a year left.
You're not scared?
Not even a little?
Of course not.
So, insurance investigating.
You enjoy the work?
Yeah.
Yeah, i... like being able to help people.
Ever think about doing anything else?
Like what?
Mmm, anything.
You seem like a pretty smart kid.
Somehow i see you out in front of the pack.
You could do some great things.
I don't know.
I like doing what i'm doing, i guess.
Well, it's your life.
Does, um...
dean?
Yeah, dean.
Does he find trouble often?
Yeah yeah, dean finds his fair share.
Well, it's a good thing he has you...
his brother's keeper.
Why, dean, if i didn't know better,
i'd say that was lust in your eyes.
Well, it would be one
way to spend the time.
But i don't think you'd
respect me in the morning.
That's okay.
I mean, hey, i barely respect you now.
Hey, can i ask you a question?
I'm an open book.
So, the gate opened.
The demon army was let out.
What now, huh?
I'm not seeing a big, honking plan here.
Honestly, there was a plan.
Azazel was a tyrant,
but he held us all together.
Azazel?
You think his friends
just called him yellow eyes?
He had a name.
After you did him in, it all fell apart.
Sorry about that.
So, what? No chain of command?
There was.
It was sam.
Sam was supposed to
be the grand pooh-bah
and lead the big army,
but he hasn't exactly
stepped up to the plate, has he?
Thank god for that.
Again with god.
You think this is a good thing?
Now you've got chaos,
a war without a front,
hundreds of demons all
jockeying for power,
all fighting for the crown...
most of them gunning for your brother.
For the record,
i was ready to follow sam.
Dean?!
Looks like you win
dean!
Check that way
sam!
Dean?
Sammy, down here!
The basement caved in!
Dean. Hey, hold on, okay?
We're coming.
- Who's we?
- I'm here with the father.
Sammy, be careful.
- Bobby, you all right? - yeah.
How did you know where we...
go.
You heard the man. Go.
Stop!
You two?
For centuries.
We've been to hell and back, literally.
Leave him be.
Don't kill him. Let's just go.
Please.
Sam, wait!
Well, what do you think, bobby?
What we did here,
you think it made a difference?
Two less demons to worry about.
That's not nothing
but trotter's still alive.
Humans ain't our job.
Yeah, but you think
anything's really gonna change?
Maybe these people do just
want to really destroy themselves.
Maybe it is a losing battle.
Is that you or the demon girl talking?
Oh, it's me.
Demon is dead, and so is that
hot girl it was possessing.
Well, had to be done.
Sam was saving your life.
Yeah, but you didn't see it,
bobby. It was cold.
Bobby.
Yeah?
Back in wyoming,
uh, there was this moment
yellow eyes said something to me.
What did he say?
That maybe when sam came back
from wherever that...
maybe he came back different.
- Different how? - i don't know.
Whatever it was, it didn't sound good.
You think...
think something's wrong with my brother?
No.
Demons lie.
I'm sure sam's okay.
Yeah.
Yeah, me too.
Leaving so soon?
We haven't even had
a chance to celebrate.
Yeah, well, you can celebrate without me.
You're not gonna get all
pouty on me now, are you?
Come on!
You killed two demons today.
Yeah, well, maybe you don't care,
but i killed two humans, too.
Sam, you know what happens
when demons piggyback humans.
Chances are those two would
have died a slow, sticky death.
You probably did them a favor.
Did them a favor?
You're a cold bitch, you know that?
Yeah, and this cold bitch.
Has saved your ass a couple of times now.
Some respect might be nice.
Especially if you want me to help you out...
with dean and his little problem.
You know what?
You keep dangling that,
but last i checked,
dean's still going to hell.
Everything in its own time, sam.
- We're in a war. - right.
But for some reason,
you're fighting on our team.
Now, tell me, why is that again?
Go screw yourself. That's why.
I don't have to justify
my actions to you, sam.
If you don't want my help, fine.
Then give me the gun,
and i'll pass it on to
someone who will use it.
Maybe i'll just use it on you.
Go ahead, if that makes you happy.
It's not gonna do
much for dean, though.
So, what's it gonna be?
That's my boy.
This won't be easy, sam.
You're gonna have to do things
that go against that
gentle nature of yours.
There'll be collateral damage...
but, it has to be done.
Well, i don't have to like it.
No.
You wouldn't be sam if you did.
On the bright side,
i'll be there with you
that little fall angel
on your shoulder.