Dean: And these specific omens,
they're prelude to what?
The Four Horsemen.
- And which one rides the red horse?
- War.
Roger: You can't kill war, kiddos.
Oh, we know.
Sam: The ring. The ring.
Aaah!
War: You can't stop thinking about it...
ever since you saw it dripping
off the blade of that knife.
Blood, blood, blood.
Sam: I'm not some junkie!
Dean: I think that the
"Dean and Sam" story sucks!
It is not fun.
It's not entertaining.
It is a river of crap
that would send most people
howling to the nut-house!
Erica: How many people
do you have to save?
All of 'em.
How do you get up in the morning?
That's a good question.
Dean: I'm just tired, man
and I'm done.
I am just done.
[ crickets chirping ]
[ chuckles softly ]
[ both chuckle ]
First date.
I had a really good time tonight, Russell.
Alice...
[ chuckles ]
Can I see you again?
Sunday, maybe?
I just don't want to be alone
on Valentine's Day...
again.
I know what you mean.
[ chuckles softly ]
I'm sorry.
I just... I... I don't want you to think
I'm the type of person who...
No, I should apologize...
Mm!
Ugh!
[ both panting ]
Oh, god.
I respect the crap out
of you right now.
Shut up!
Ah! Ugh!
Your neck!
I think I bit you.
It's okay.
[ chuckles ]
[ crunching ] [ moaning ]
[ crunch ]
Ugh! I've been so alone.
So empty...
I know, me too.
I want you, Russell...
all of you... Inside me...
Yes.
[ crunch ]
Ugh!
[ chuckles ]
[ crunch ]
Aah!
Ugh!
Supernatural Season 5 Episode 14
"My Bloody Valentine"
[ sighs ]
So...
You were the one who found the bodies?
There was blood everywhere...
and... other stuff.
I think Alice was already dead.
But Russell wasn't?
I think he was, mostly,
except... he was still sort of...
chewing a little.
Oh.
Uh-huh.
How could two
people even do that?
Eat each other to death?
That's a really good question.
Now, the last few days,
did you notice her acting erratically?
How do you mean?
I mean, did she seem...
unusually hostile, aggressive?
[ chuckles ]
No way.
Alice never drank, never even swore.
She was a nice girl.
And I'm talking like, a nice girl,
like she still had her promise ring,
if you know what I mean.
She was a virgin?
No premarital.
I used to wonder how she did it,
I mean, you know, didn't do it.
It was her first date in months.
She was so excited.
Apparently, they were
both pretty excited.
How'd it go?
Um...
No EMF, no sulphur.
Ghost possession and demonic possession
are both probably out.
Hmm. That's where I
was puttin' my money.
Nope.
Well, then what then?
Oh, dude!
At the coroner's you
didn't see these bodies.
I mean, these two started eating
and, and they just... kept going.
I mean, their stomachs were full.
Like... like... Thanksgiving-dinner full.
Talk about co-dependent.
Well...[ sighs ]
I mean, we got our feelers out.
How much more can we do tonight.
[ inhales deeply ] All right.
I'm just gonna go
through some files,
you can go ahead and get going.
Sorry?
Go ahead. Unleash the Kraken.
See you tomorrow morning.
Where am I going?
Dean, it's valentine's day.
Your favorite holiday, remember?
I mean, what do
you always call it... uh,
unattached drifter Christmas?
[ scoffs ] Yeah.
[ sighs ] Oh, yeah.
Well... be that as it may.
I don't know,
guess I'm not feeling it this year.
[ scoffs ]
So you're not into bars
full of lonely women?
Nah, I guess not.
Ahh.
What?
It's when a dog doesn't eat,
that's when you know
something's really wrong.
Remarkably patronizing
concern duly noted.
Nothings wrong. We
gonna work or what?
Ouch! No me gusta.
Have you been proofing
this thing, Jimbo?
Sorry?
Tell me you are not checking
your cellphone again!
Man, she's got you on a leash.
I'm not on a leash, Brad.
She just wants to know where I am.
She just wants to know
that you're whipped.
It's not like that.
Oh, yeah. It's like...
[ mimics whip ]
Brad, just give me two minutes.
No, man. No.
I'm the project leader on this thing,
and I'm not gonna half-ass it
just 'cause my wingman
has gone mental
over some chick he
met, like, a week ago.
Janice: [ voice breaking ] Jim?
Holy crap.
Where were you?
I know.
It's just I had to...
You can't choose
work over me, Jim!
I won't, Janice.
I'm sorry...
Brad: Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Jimbo, due respect, but honestly bro...
[ mimics whip ]
What are we gonna do, Jimmy?
I don't know, baby.
Seems like whatever we do,
something in life is always
gonna keep us apart...
work, family, sleep.
Now prison, maybe...
[ thud ]
Maybe.
But I think I have an idea,
how we can stay together...
forever...
[ gunshots ]
[ cart wheels squeaking ]
[ heart beating ]
You okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Agent Marley, you just can't stay away.
Heard you tagged
another double suicide.
Well, I just finished closing them up.
Dr. Corman, this is my partner,
special agent Cliff.
Agent Cliff.
I've finished my pre-lims.
I pulled the organ sets and
sent off the tox samples.
Great. You mind if we
take a look at the bodies?
Not at all.
But like I said...
their... good-and-plenties
are already tupperwared.
Super.
Just leave the keys
with Marty up front.
And please, gentlemen,
refrigerate after opening.
Hey.
Be my valentine?
[ sighs ]
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa. Wait a second.
These hearts both have identical marks.
Check this out.
It looks like some kind of letter.
Oh, no.
What?
I think it's Enochian.
You mean like angel scratches?
So you think it's like
the tagging on our ribs?
Dean, I don't know.
Ah, hell.
Cass, it's Dean.
Yeah, room 31-C, basement level...
[ echoing ] St. James Medical Centre.
[ echoing ] I'm there now.
Yeah, I get that.
I'm gonna hang up now.
Right.
You're right, Sam. These
are angelic marks.
I imagine you'll find similar marks
on the other couples' hearts as well.
So, what are they? I mean,
what do they mean?
It's a mark of union.
This man and woman
were intended to mate.
Okay, but who put them there?
Well, your people call them "Cupid."
A what?
What human myth has
mistaken for "Cupid",
is actually a lower order of angel.
Technically it's a Cherub, third-class.
Cherub?
Yeah, they're all over the world.
There are dozens of them.
You mean the little
flying fat kid in diapers?
They're not incontinent.
Okay, anyways.
So, what you're saying is...
What I'm saying is a
Cupid has gone rogue,
and we have to stop him,
before he kills again.
Naturally.
Of course we do.
[ upbeat jazz plays,
indistinct conversations ]
So, what, you just happen to know
he likes the cosmos at this place?
This place is a nexus
of human reproduction.
it's exactly the kind of...
of garden the Cupid will
come to... to pollinate.
Wait a minute.
You're not hungry?
No.
What? I'm not hungry.
Then you're not gonna finish that?
He's here.
Where?
I don't see anything.
[ wind whistles ]
There.
Dean: You mean the same-sid
e-of-the-booth couple over there?
Meet me in the back.
Cass, where is he?
I have him tethered.
Zoda kama mahrana.
Manifest yourself.
So, where is he?
Oof!
Here I am! [ giggles ]
[ grunts ]
Help!
Oh, help is on the way.
Yes, it is. Yes, it is.
Hello, you!
[ laughs ]
- Ooh.
- Mmm.
[ grunting ]
This is Cupid?
[ strained ] Yes.
And look at you, huh?
- No.
- Yes!
Yes, yes, yes!
Is this a fight? Are we in a fight?
This is... their handshake.
- I don't like it.
- No one likes it.
Mmm. [ sighs deeply ]
What can I do for you?
Why are you doing this?
Doing what?
Your targets, the ones you've marked...
they're slaughtering each other.
What?
They are?
Listen, birthday suit,
we know, okay?
We know you been flittin' around,
popping people with your poison arrow,
making them murder each other!
What we don't know is why.
You think that I...
Well, uh...
[ voice breaking ] I don't know what to say.
[ sobbing ]
Sam: Should...
should somebody maybe...
go talk to him?
Yeah, that's a good idea.
Give 'em hell, Cass.
[ pats shoulder ]
Um... look.
We didn't mean to, um...
hurt your feelings.
Ugh!
Love is more than a
word to me, you know.
I love, love. I love it!
And if that's wrong, I
don't want to be right!
Yes, yes. Of course.
I, uh...
I have no idea what you're saying.
It's just on my appointed rounds.
Whatever my targets do after that,
that's nothing to do with me.
I-I was following my orders.
Please brother. Read my mind.
Read my mind, you'll see.
He's telling the truth.
[ sighs ] jiny Christmas. Thank you.
Wait, wait...
You said you were
just following orders?
Mm-hmm.
Whose orders?
Whose orders..?
Heaven, silly. Heaven.
Why does heaven care
if Harry meets Sally?
Oh mostly they don't. You know,
certain bloodlines, certain destinies.
- Oh, like yours.
- What?
Yeah, the union of
John and Mary Winchester...
Very big deal upstairs, top
priority arrangement. Mmm.
Are you saying that you
fixed-up our parents?
Well, not me, but... yeah.
[ chuckles ] Well, it wasn't easy, either.
Ooh, they couldn't stand
each other at first,
but when we were
done with them...
perfect couple.
- Perfect?
- Yeah.
They're dead!
I'm sorry, but...
the orders were very clear.
You and Sam needed to be born.
Your parents were just, uh...
meant to be.
A match made in heaven
heaven!
Son of a bitch!
Where is he?
Where'd he go?!
I believe you upset him.
Upset him?!
Dean, enough!
What?
You just punched a Cupid!
I punched a dick!
Um...
Are we gonna talk about
what's been up with
you lately or not?
Or not.
You said you wanted to hear about
any other weird ones.
Okay.
[ sighs ]
Lester Finch.
Pulled his records.
Looks like this gentleman used
to weigh 400 pounds or so,
till he got a gastric bypass,
which brought down
his weight considerably.
But then for some reason, last night,
he decided to go
on a Twinkie binge.
So, he died from a Twinkie binge?
Well, after he blew out the
band around his stomach,
he filled it up till it burst.
When he could no longer swallow,
he started jamming the
cakes down his gullet
with a...
with a toilet brush,
like he was ramrod ding a cannon.
[ sighs ]
So, what do you make of it?
I'd say that it was
a very peculiar thing to do.
Hey.
So, uh, this guy was
not marked by Cupid,
but his death is definitely suspicious.
Yeah, well, I just went
through the police blotter,
and counting him,
that's eight suicides since Wednesday
and 19 O.D'S...
that's way out of the
seasonal batting average.
Yeah, if there's a pattern here,
it ain't just love.
It's a hell of a lot bigger than we thought.
Yeah, all right. I'll see you in 10.
Yep, okay.
[ heart beating ]
[ beating continues ]
Ugh! Ugh!
I know what you are, damn it.
Aaah!
I could smell you.
Winchester.
[ beating continues ]
Aah!
[ grunts ]
[ panting ]
What the hell does a demon
got to do with this, anyway?
[ sighs ] Believe me, I got no idea.
You okay?
Yeah, yeah. I'll be all right.
Let's crack her open.
What's the worst that
could happen, right?
Whoa!
What the hell was that?
Castiel: It's a human soul.
It's starting to make sense.
Now, what about that makes sense?
And when did you start eating?
Exactly.
My hunger... it's a clue, actually.
- For what?
This town isn't suffering
from some love-gone-wrong effect.
It's suffering from hunger.
Starvation, to be exact...
specifically...
famine.
Famine?
A-as in The Horseman?
Great.
Th-th-that's freaking great.
I thought famine meant starvation,
like as in, you know, food.
Yes. Absolutely.
But not just food.
I mean, everyone seems to
be starving for something...
sex, attention, drugs, love...
Well, that explains
the puppy-lovers
that Cupid shot up.
Right.
The Cherub made them crave love,
and then famine came,
and made them rabid for it.
Okay, but what about you?
I mean, since when do angels
secretly hunger for white castle?
It's my vessel... Jimmy.
His, uh, appetite for red meat
has been touched
by famine's effect.
So, famine just rolls into town
and everybody goes crazy?
"And then will come famine
riding on a black steed."
"He will ride into the land of plenty..."
"and great will be The Horseman's hunger,
for he is hunger."
[ bells jingle ]
"His hunger will seep
out and poison the air."
[ labored ] Hungry.
Famine is hungry.
He must devour the
souls of his victims.
So, that's what was in the briefcase,
the Twinkie dude's soul?
Lucifer has sent his
demons to care for famine,
to feed him, make
certain he'll be ready.
Ready for what?
To march across the land.
[ flies buzzing ]
[ bells jingle ]
Hungry.
Sam Winchester, the vessel...
he's here.
Where?
At the hospital.
We fought, but he got away.
I...
I got this off him.
Good. Yes.
After lunch.
Now, where is it?
Sorry?
[ laughing ] The one who
loves cream cake so much.
Where is his soul?
I am sorry. No. The...
Winchester took the case from me.
Uh, he had the knife.
I...
I lost it.
But I'm hungry!
I'll get another. I-I won't be 10 minutes.
Hungry! Now!
[ sighs deeply ] Delicious!
Famine?
Yes.
So, what, this whole town
is just gonna eat, drink,
and screw itself to death?
We should stop it.
Yeah, that's a great idea.
How?
How did you stop the
last Horseman you met?
War got his mojo from this ring.
And after we cut it off,
he just tucked tail and ran.
And everybody that was affected,
it was like they woke
up out of a dream.
You think famine's
got a class ring, too?
I know he does.
Well, okay.
L-let's track him down
and get to chopping.
Yeah.
[ sighs ]
[ echoing ] What are you, the ham-burglar?
[ echoing ] I've developed
a taste for ground beef.
[ heart beating ] Well, have you
even tried to stop it?
I'm an angel. I can
stop anytime I want.
Whatever.
Sam, let's roll.
[ panting ] Dean...
I, um...
I can't.
[ grunts ] I can't go.
What do you mean?
I think it got to me, Dean.
I think I'm hungry for it...
Hungry for what?
You know.
Demon blood?
You got to be kidding me.
You got to get him out of here.
You got to beam him
to, like, Montana,
anywhere but here.
It won't work. He's already infected.
The hunger is just
gonna travel with him.
Well, then, what do we do?
You go cut that bastard's finger off.
You heard him.
But, Dean...
Before you go, you better...
[ exhales sharply ]
you better lock me down.
But good.
[ handcuffs click ]
All right, well, just hang in there,
we'll be back as soon as we can.
Be careful,
and... hurry.
[ heart beating ]
[ sighs ]
[ indistinct conversations ]
Hey, Marty.
Is Dr. Corman around?
You haven't heard?
Heard what?
Guy's been dry for the last 20 years,
but this morning, he
left work, went home,
and drank himself to death.
- It's famine.
- Pardon?
Would you give us a minute, please?
Sure.
Thanks.
Crap!
I really kind of liked this guy.
They haven't harvested his soul yet.
Well, if we want to
play "follow the soul"
to get to famine,
our best shot starts
with the doc, here.
[ heart beating ]
[ panting ]
[ bag crinkling ]
Are you serious?
These make me...
[chuckles] very happy.
How many is that?
I lost count.
It's in the low hundreds.
[ whistles ]
What I don't understand is...
where is your hunger, Dean?
Huh?
Well, slowly but surely,
everyone in this town is
falling prey to famine,
but so far, you seem unaffected.
Hey, when I want to drink, I drink.
When I want sex, I go get it.
Same goes for a
sandwich or a fight.
So...
you're saying you're
just well-adjusted?
God, no. I'm just well-fed.
Look there.
[ engine turns over ]
[ grunting ]
Ugh!
Guys?
[ wood scrapes ]
Guys, what happened?
I don't think it worked.
I think I'm still...
still hungry.
Look at this.
Someone trussed you up for us.
Boss says we can't kill you...
but I bet we can
break off a few pieces.
Ugh!
[ slurping ]
Get him off! Get him off!
Wait your turn.
[ engine shuts off ]
Demons.
You want to go over the plan again?
Hey, happy meal.
The plan?
I take the knife, I go in,
I cut off the ring hand of famine,
and I meet you back
here in the parking lot.
Well, that sounds foolproof.
This is taking too long.
[ oil bubbling ]
Cass!
Cass.
The other Mr. Winchester.
What did you do to him?
You sicked your dog on me.
I just threw him a steak.
So this is your big trick?
Huh?
Making people cookoo for cocoa puffs?
Doesn't take much... hardly a push.
Oh, America... all-you
can-eat, all of the time.
Consume, consume.
A swarm of locusts in stretch pants,
and yet, you're all still starving
because hunger doesn't
just come from the body,
it also comes from the soul.
It's funny, it doesn't seem
to be coming from mine.
Yes.
I noticed that.
Have you wondered why that is?
How you could even
walk in my presence?
Well, I like to think
It's because of my
strength of character.
I disagree.
[ grunting ]
Yes.
I see.
[ electricity crackling, wind whistling ]
[ chuckles ]
That's one deep, dark
nothing you got there, Dean.
Can't fill it, can you?
Not with food or drink.
[ laughing ] Not even with sex.
Oh, you're so full of crap.
Oh, you can smirk and joke
and lie to your brother,
lie to yourself, but not to me!
I can see inside you, Dean.
I can see how broken you are,
how defeated,
you can't win,
and you know it.
But you just keep fighting,
just... keep going
through the motions.
You're not hungry,
Dean because inside,
you're already...
dead.
Sam: Let him go.
Famine: Sam...
Sammy, no!
Stop!
No one lays a finger on
this sweet little boy.
Sam, I see you got
the snack I sent you.
You sent?
Don't worry. You're
not like everyone else.
You'll never die from
drinking too much.
You're the exception
that proves the rule,
just the way...
Satan wanted you to be.
So...
cut their throats.
Have at them!
Sammy, no!
Please, be my guest.
[ rumbling ]
[ demons choking, gagging ]
[ breathing heavily ]
No.
Well...
fine.
If you don't want them...
then I'll have them.
[ gasps ]
[ wind whooshes ]
I'm a Horseman, Sam.
Your power doesn't work on me.
You're right.
But it will work on them.
Aahh!
[ heart pumping ]
[ panting ]
Sam: [ screaming, gasping ] Help! Help! Dean!
Guys, if you're out there, please.
Help!
That's not him in there.
Not really.
- Sam: Dean, help me. Cass!
- I know.
Dean, Sam just has to get
it out of his system.
Then he'll be...
Listen, I just, uh...
I just need to get some air.
[ water dripping, steam hissing ]
[ voice breaking ] Please...
I can't...
I need some help.
Please.
Sync by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
Edited by Scooby