Ladies and gentlemen,
step around. Step around.
Come on. Gather around.
We'll show you
a little way to make
a little easy money today.
You understand
what I'm saying?
These are the blacks.
Don't follow the blacks.
You wanna follow the queen.
Know why?
'Cause she's red
and that means she is hot.
You gotta find the queen.
Find the queen.
The first of the day
is free to play.
Who wants to play?
You look interested, my man.
You wanna step on up?
Come on now.
Who wants to play?
Oh, what about you, sweetie?
You're cute.
Come on up.
All right.
Come on here and play.
Cute girls win money.
You look lucky.
Now, you look lucky.
Now, follow the queen.
Here we go,
ladies and gentlemen.
Follow the queen.
Ain't no Helen Mirren,
but this queen is for you!
Which one? Which one?
Which one is it?
It's right there.
Right there?
(WHOOPS)
Beginner's luck.
I'll tell you what.
It takes a woman
to know a woman.
It takes a lady
to find a queen.
There you go...
Wanna double up?
All right.
All right,
we've got a chancer.
We got a chancer.
All right. Here we go.
Here we go.
All you gotta do
is find your queen.
You will not win again.
All right.
Here we go. Here we go.
Find your queen.
Where is she?
Can you find her?
Right there.
This one? Oh, my...
She is killing me here.
Taking all my money.
Anybody else wanna get behind
the good-luck girl?
I can do it.
You can do it?
All right. You're next.
Just give me a chance
to recover and
get my money back
or else I'm gonna be out here
sleeping on the street.
Here we go.
All right? Ready?
This is the last time.
I'm not messing
with you no more.
You're taking
all my money, girl.
I'm not messing
with you no more.
Here we go. One more chance.
This is your last chance.
You're gonna follow
the queen, baby.
Follow the queen.
Where's she at?
Just one time.
I'll show you one time
and there she is.
Boom. Boom. Boom.
Pick a card.
I can't decide.
What do you mean?
Just pick a card.
Just make a decision.
I can't decide.
Come on. Any card will do.
Left? Right? Center?
I don't know.
Do you want the right?
I...
The left?
The center?
I don't know. I...
Move out the way and just
let somebody else play then?
I can't decide. I can't.
You wanna flip
a coin for it?
What's wrong with me?
MAN: Is she okay?
Scariest 30 seconds
of my life.
I couldn't do anything.
It's like I couldn't
move inside my head.
It's called abulia.
The inability to
make a decision
or exercise will.
Is it going to happen again?
It's part of a TIA.
A transient ischemic attack.
Blood was cut off to a section
of your frontal lobe.
Is it like a stroke
or something?
A little.
What drugs have you
taken recently?
No drugs.
Toxins are
another possibility.
You might have been exposed
to something at work,
for instance.
No real job right now.
Exposure can build up
over time
and lie dormant for a while.
What was your last job?
Pet store.
Exotic pets?
Tropical fish.
And before that?
Unemployment.
And before that,
I sold subscriptions
on the phone.
And before that,
unemployment.
Before that,
I worked at Jeans Gone Wild.
Before that, unemployment.
Before that, I walked dogs.
And before that...
Loss of free will. I like it.
Maybe we can get
Thomas Aquinas
in for a consult.
What caused the TIA?
Arteries are clear.
No sign of a clot.
Could have dissolved.
Most likely came
from her heart.
We should do a bubble study.
Clots are unlikely
in a 28-year-old
who's not on the pill.
It's probably a vasospasm
caused by drugs.
I don't think so.
She goes from job to job.
Maybe there's some kind
of ADD here.
Help us pinpoint
where the neurological...
She goes from job to job
because she's a scam artist.
She works just long enough
to qualify for unemployment,
then gets fired
and gets high.
I still don't think
it's drugs.
Did you check
for infection?
LP showed nothing.
No fever.
White blood count is normal.
Could be toxic exposure.
You're the one always saying
it must be drugs.
You figure she's a minority,
she must be stoned?
You know that's what I...
She seems like a nice girl.
FOREMAN:
You haven't met her!
She was pregnant at 15,
dropped out of high school.
She's a real overachiever.
CHASE: Come on.
Cut her some slack.
Her baby died of SIDS.
This isn't some
romantic story
about a nice girl
scarred by tragedy.
She's a drug-using scam artist
On the other hand,
the tox screen just came back.
She's clean.
You're wasting my time.
He's wasting...
Second ex-Mrs. Wilson
want money?
I am no longer
paying alimony.
She wanted
her independence,
so she got her
realtor's license.
Market's doing badly.
She wants money.
She's moving into a condo.
She wants...
She wants me
to take Hector.
Pool boy?
Dog.
No longer interested.
We got him
on our honeymoon.
So I'm like
the other parent.
But I can't take him.
My hotel doesn't allow dogs.
Besides, I'm always here.
I asked Cuddy
to a play Thursday.
(CHUCKLES)
Oh, you... Okay.
She said she was busy.
And you didn't believe her,
so you bribed a janitor,
broke into her computer,
checked her appointments...
I asked her as a test.
What would you have learned
if she'd said yes?
A lot about bondage.
She was busy for me
but not for you.
She's not interested
in play qua play.
She's interested in you.
No. I'm not getting
sucked into the vortex
of your insanity again.
Don't pass me
notes in class.
Don't tell me to
ask her to the prom.
You cannot
see her socially.
You're leading her on.
I'll consider that.
After I take her
to the Hockney exhibit.
On Thursday.
See, she is busy.
It's not a date.
She enjoyed the play.
I enjoyed her
enjoying the play.
The woman works hard.
It's nice to see her relax.
So all this enjoying
is an act of charity.
I'm keeping the receipts
for tax purposes.
What's life
without the ability
to make stupid choices?
She needs her free will.
Find out why her brain froze
before she can't decide
to take her next breath.
You find the toxins.
You run your bubble study.
You won't find anything but
I'll get the office to myself.
There's a lot of porn
piling up on the Internet.
Doesn't download itself.
Eric? Eric!
Hello, Mr. Foreman.
Dr. Chase. How are you?
Good.
You're lucky
you caught us, actually...
I'll meet you outside.
Hey, Dad. I've got to go.
Why are you here?
Everything okay?
Good as ever.
We're staying at a hotel
down the street.
You didn't bring Mom with you?
It's gonna be her
60th birthday in a few days.
I know. We talked
about it on the phone.
You said you couldn't
come home.
You didn't have to come.
You haven't been home
in eight years.
She should see you,
while she still
knows who you are.
Dad. I've talked to her
on the phone.
She only knows
who I am sometimes.
Sometimes
is important.
So what's up with your dad?
Didn't know he was
gonna be in town?
No.
Building this old, could be
toxic exposure anywhere.
Asbestos, mold,
the coloring agents
in the old wallpaper.
Or it could be drugs.
I thought we ruled out...
Clean tox screen means
drugs didn't cause the TIA.
Drugs can be laced
with toxic substances.
Arsenic, rat poison.
The drugs wash out
of her system,
the toxins stick around.
Exposure could come about
any number of ways.
There's no reason to assume
it was through drug use.
Absolutely.
Except for the crack pipe.
I'll test her blood
for arsenic and rat poison.
Yeah. Yeah.
You'd like that,
wouldn't you?
And your dad asked you out
for dinner?
I'll do the tests.
You're stuck with your family.
You like Hockney?
You heard about that.
The pop stuff or
the Venezuelan pictures?
That's a trick question.
Yes. But you have no idea
how it's a trick.
I like art.
I'm open to new things.
What's the problem?
You're going to a gallery
to see Venezuelan pictures
that don't exist.
But you won't go
to a play with me. Why?
House, why is my social life
suddenly red hot?
One minute I'm mushing along
with the huskies as usual
and suddenly
it's global warming.
You think you saw
somebody else pick up
a toy from the sandbox
and suddenly you want it.
Is that why you said no?
Maybe I just want a friend
and I thought Wilson
was a safe choice.
I'm not safe? Cool.
James Wilson is never
the safe choice.
We're going to a gallery.
We're not getting married.
Sure, you say that now.
He always marries them
in the end.
Is that Eric? Eric!
Oh!
Oh, baby. Baby!
I wanted to find that
picture I took at your
high school graduation.
I had it reframed.
It's in one of these
suitcases, but I don't know...
You can show it to me later.
Your father wants to know
if you've been praying.
You don't have to just
come out with it like that.
But I only want to know
if you're happy.
Sure. I'm okay.
You like it here?
You have friends?
Yeah.
Everything is great, Mom.
That's why I brought
the picture for you.
I remember
when you were little
you liked to look in
the back of the math book
because you knew
even though it made
no sense then,
by the end of the year
you'd understand it all.
That's why
you brought the picture?
You wanted to look ahead,
to see how far you'd go.
Now you're a grown man,
I thought you might
like to look back
to see how far you've come.
It all makes sense now.
Doesn't it?
(CHUCKLES)
That isn't mine.
(COUGHING)
It was in your closet.
It belongs to this guy
who used to live with me.
You might want to let him know
he's got arsenic poisoning.
We should get
a sample of his hair
so we can see
the extent of it.
But I don't do...
I don't do drugs.
(COUGHING)
Get a crash cart in here!
Respiratory arrest!
Are you sure
it isn't from the arsenic?
Dr. Foreman said
I was poisoned.
Your hair showed
only a trace amount.
Not enough to damage
your lungs like this.
We need you
to stay still now.
Six-millimeter cuts
starting at the apices.
Also, I just wanted
to let you know
should you change your mind,
I'll be available.
Aren't you getting tired
of hearing me say it?
I have no intention
of going out with you,
of having sex with you,
of doing anything with you.
Except work.
We don't have to make
a big deal about it.
I just thought
I'd let you know.
I decided Tuesdays would be
a good day to do that.
You did not suddenly
fall in love with me.
You were looking for something
and I happened to be
standing...
Cameron, it's fine.
No need to go on about it.
Advancing through
the lung bases.
We need to put this
behind us.
Understood.
But you keep bringing it up.
You're the one
who's still talking.
Look, I'm not demanding
anything from you.
I'm not following you home.
I've got no expectations.
A gentle, polite reminder
once a week
is hardly stalking.
There's a mass.
Just outside the lingula.
Biopsy shows
there are white blood cells
in the walls
of the blood vessels.
They're not supposed
to get past the bouncers.
Got to be autoimmune,
something lymphocytic.
White blood cells
are attacking her own body.
Only question is,
what kind of autoimmune?
Doesn't matter what kind.
It always matters what kind.
Treatment's always steroids.
Treatment is always boring.
Diagnosis...
Okay.
It's affecting
the larger blood vessels.
Gotta be giant cell arteritis.
I'll start her on steroids.
It's affecting
the smaller blood vessels.
Gotta be lupus vasculitis.
I'll start her on steroids.
It's affecting...
Yeah. Got it.
Start her on steroids.
Good idea.
Told you. That was boring.
I gotta go out.
Why?
Wilson's got a date.
BONNIE.: It's got
15-foot ceilings.
It's got an open floor plan.
(CHUCKLES)
You know, I can't believe
you called me.
Hey. I need a condo.
Didn't you and Wilson have
your first date around here?
Wow! You remember
where our first date was?
I didn't think
you were paying attention.
Really? He's my best friend.
Our first date was in Boston.
Oh.
Not quite as close
to here as I remember.
But we're not here
to talk about him.
Absolutely not.
Wait till you see the kitchen.
All-granite countertops.
Since I wasn't paying
attention back then,
what was it like dating him?
So this is Hockney?
No.
I don't know what happened.
I'm sure you don't.
I never knew your tastes
were so eclectic.
Oh, the Hockney exhibit
finished on April 20th.
I thought it was May 20th.
Okay. My bad.
This is not somewhere
I'd bring someone on a date.
Not that this is a date.
Obviously.
I was just thinking...
He's doing landscapes
on multiple canvases now.
And they're kind of peaceful
and you're always so busy...
Wow.
(CHUCKLES)
I don't think I've ever
seen you embarrassed before.
Oh, it was never a date.
I was coming off
a bad relationship
and he said we could
go out as friends.
You know, just go see plays,
go to a museum.
I didn't think
you liked Trenton.
Love it.
So he'd say it's not a date
but then he'd jump you.
Oh, no. He meant it.
James Wilson,
carefully calibrating
his level of protectiveness
for your individual needs.
Did you just compare
Wilson to a tampon?
(CHUCKLES) No.
It was very endearing.
He really just wanted
to be a friend.
So I jumped him.
The bedroom's through here.
CUDDY: That's such a bad idea.
There's no way that
won't cause damage
to the large intestine.
Are you keeping us here
to torture me?
Is that a bicycle pump?
That's what I'm saying.
It's like walking
into a sticky trap.
And once you're the focus
of all that attention,
it's addictive.
This unit's kitchen's
got a chef's oven.
I cook a lot. Go on.
But it's the emotional stuff
that really sucks you in.
He's just so
knight-in-shining-armor,
you know?
Always there to support you,
until one day he's not.
But by then you're hooked.
Hey, do you think that
you could talk to him
about taking the dog?
He's the only one
that Hector really
gets along with.
Hey, we're here to talk
real estate, not Wilson.
So you're saying
if you'd actually had sex
before you connected
emotionally, you'd have
gotten over him.
(CHUCKLES) Oh, yeah.
Seems weird, right?
'Cause sex with James
is fantastic.
Nobody works harder
to give a woman
what she wants.
It's got six burners.
The chef's oven.
Right.
(LUPE COUGHING)
How you feeling?
That wasn't my crack pipe.
You told me. Are you tired?
I just took a hit off it
a couple of times.
What's wrong with
having a little fun?
Your personal life
is none of my business.
You don't like me though,
do you?
That's your imagination.
I've seen every kind
of drug abuse.
No offense,
but you don't even
stand out of the pack.
I'm betting you got money
in the same place
you got attitude.
You know,
people who quit drinking
and people who lose weight.
They think they're better
than the people that couldn't
and because you got
out of the projects,
you think that
anybody who didn't
is weak and stupid.
I'm not judging you.
Now take a breath.
The only difference
between me and you
is that I made
some bad decisions
and you made some good ones.
You make bad decisions
every day of your life.
Stop doing drugs.
Stop having fun.
Go back to school
and get your GED.
Yeah, where's the money
coming from?
The system's not set up
for people like me.
What are you staring at?
Your eyes.
There's yellow in the sclera.
Her liver's failing.
Without a transplant,
she'll be dead
in the next 48 hours.
We should increase
her immunosuppressants
and target more specifically.
Add methotrexate.
Yeah, let's do more
of what's not working.
This isn't an
autoimmune disease.
Her white blood cells
are attacking her body.
That's autoimmune.
FOREMAN: First brain,
then lungs, now liver.
All getting worse
and all in two days.
It's moving too fast.
It's gotta be cancer.
Lymphomatoid granulomatosis.
It's rare even
by our standards
but it fits her symptoms.
Explains why the steroids
aren't working,
poor fingernail growth.
A lot of people
have bad fingernails.
A lot of people don't have
three organ systems
shutting down.
Her blood vessels are
taking this thing everywhere.
She needs total
body radiation.
We can't do anything
until we can confirm...
Running those
immunochemistries
could take a week.
She'll be dead by the time...
That doesn't make
radiation any safer.
Okay.
Suppose Chase
and Cameron are right.
Suppose it's an
autoimmune disease.
What's the biggest danger
of total body radiation?
It suppresses
the immune system,
which is what
we're trying to do
with the steroids anyway.
I don't usually
put out on my first date
but I gotta say
that is a rad move.
Get her consent.
Start the radiation.
The patient's
not too thrilled with me.
I'll get her consent.
Foreman's got
personality issues,
so you're gonna step in?
Patient doesn't like Foreman.
I'm interested.
Fatigue, hair loss,
possibility of damage
to the lungs, infertility.
All possible side effects
of radiation.
Why don't you like
Dr. Foreman?
(COUGHING)
He thinks he's better
than he is.
How good is he?
I don't know.
Can we get back
to what's wrong with me?
There's a small
possibility of leukemia
at some time in the future.
Hardly worth mentioning.
You can't say he thinks
he's better than he is
if you don't know
how good he is.
No one's as good
as he thinks he is.
I am.
You might also get cataracts.
Sign here.
I don't know.
You're telling me
how dangerous this is.
We're saving your life.
We're that good. Sign there.
I can't decide.
Would you rather
a pencil or a pen?
Who's the better James Bond,
Sean Connery or Daniel Craig?
You see?
That's not even a decision.
It's happening again.
I can't. I can't.
(PANTING)
(MACHINE BEEPING)
(ALARM BEEPING)
Up her blood thinners
and get her down to Radiology.
The attack will be over
in 20 minutes.
Then she'll wanna sign this.
Bonnie called last night
to talk about the dog.
Your name came up.
Good Lord!
How do you still have teeth?
She's the worst realtor
in New Jersey.
What is this? Escalation?
I go out with Cuddy,
you hook up with my ex?
I don't even know what
that's designed to do.
You're an addict.
I'm saving you from yourself.
By condo shopping?
Thank you.
If I can figure out
where you keep going wrong,
then I can nip this
Cuddy thing in the bud
before she becomes
the fourth ex-Mrs. Wilson.
Yes. I was worried there was
no way to stop that train.
You have to have sex
with Cuddy.
Wait. To stop the train?
Bonnie said I'm bad in bed?
Huh?
Yeah. She also said
that if she'd slept with you
before she liked you
then it would've made it
easier to handle
when you turned
into the sorry bastard
who left her alone.
I told her you were
wasting her time,
by the way.
You think that's
gonna stop her?
The woman's the worst
realtor in New Jersey.
How do you feel?
Weak.
Sleeping a lot.
CAMERON: That's normal
after radiation.
FOREMAN: Deep breath.
(GROANS)
A little queasy, too.
When I feel sick to my stomach
I always want
vanilla ice cream.
It's soothing.
It's best to stick
with liquids for now.
(SHUSHING)
I'm getting a murmur.
Oh, my arm! It's hurting me!
Take it off! Take it off!
(SCREAMING)
Oh, my God!
(CONTINUES SCREAMING)
CAMERON: Pain is the issue.
Just the pressure
of the BP cuff
was enough
to start her screaming.
That's not cancer.
It sounds like...
Sounds like she's septic.
A lot of things
can cause pain.
How much pain?
Too much.
It's not cancer.
It's not autoimmune.
It's an infection and
we fried her immune system.
CHASE: But she had no fever.
Her LP was clear.
Do an echo.
Confirm it's in the heart.
And then I'll tell our patient
that we just killed her.
I'll tell her.
(DOOR OPENS)
Hi. You haven't been
returning my phone calls.
I'm busy.
Well, but if you
have half an hour
a little later this afternoon,
I just found this unit
ten minutes from here.
It hasn't been
on the market yet.
I'm off the market for condos.
James was right?
I never had
the teeniest chance
of selling you anything?
Of course he was right.
Wilson doesn't stop
giving good advice
just 'cause you're divorced.
He's compulsive about
remaining on good terms
with his exes.
Do you wanna know why
I named that dog Hector?
No. Let's keep it a mystery.
Because even when
he was a puppy,
he was the worst-tempered dog
we'd ever seen.
He was supposed
to be house-trained.
He'd pee on the carpet
every morning.
When we had people over,
he had to nip at their ankles.
"Hector does go rug"
is an anagram
for "Doctor Greg House".
That's how early
in the marriage
I resented you.
Wow. Did I ever waste money
on that place setting.
James at least
had the decency
to feel guilty
when he hurt me.
Whereas I didn't hurt you.
I didn't even marry you,
cleverly hoping to avoid
moments like this one.
You always needed him and
he was always there for you.
If you keep yelling,
I'll think you'll owe me sex.
You knew he had a wife
waiting at home.
You didn't care.
Now, I'm not saying
you broke up the marriage,
but you didn't help.
First, "Hector does go rug"
is a lame anagram.
You want a better one
for Gregory House?
"Huge ego. Sorry."
Second, find a new career.
You're never gonna
sell anybody
if you let them
control the agenda.
And third,
I don't owe you anything.
I'm not Wilson.
I'm not gonna buy a condo
just to make you feel better.
WILSON: You okay?
Yeah.
Tell me how to do this.
House says
people thank you after.
It's not typical.
I already killed this woman.
All I can do now
is not make
any more mistakes.
First of all, stop thinking
you can minimize the hurt.
A lot of people are afraid
of the word "dying."
If you pussyfoot around it,
she's not going to
read your mind.
Okay.
No, it's not.
When you look in her face,
you're gonna feel
the instinct to temporize.
Crush it.
Yeah.
Then wait.
Give her time
to process the news.
Let her know
you'll be with her
through all of it.
Wait till she's
done thinking,
till she meets
your eyes again.
Then if you feel
it's appropriate,
you can touch her.
Maybe put your hand
on her arm like this.
Let her know
she's still connected
to another human being.
You've got this down
to a science.
You're freaking out.
I told you...
Give her what she needs.
What she doesn't need
is a doctor who's
not there with her
because he made
the wrong call.
You are freaking out.
You should be freaking out.
I won't let her see it.
Let her see it.
Hey.
How come no mask?
We think...
You have an infection.
Didn't the radiation work?
It did what it was
supposed to do.
You're dying.
What do you mean?
Like things are bad and
that someday I'm gonna...
How much time?
We can't know exactly.
A year?
Less than a year?
Less than 24 hours.
I don't understand.
Why are you saying this to me?
You're trying to scare me?
Why would you do that?
I'm sorry.
It's true.
How bad is this cancer?
Yesterday you thought
I had a chance.
You don't have cancer.
You came in with an infection.
We didn't catch it.
What kind of infection?
Doesn't matter.
(SIGHS)
Radiation was the worst thing
we could have done.
We destroyed
the part of your body
that was fighting it off.
It's spread to your heart.
Then give me drugs.
They have drugs
for infections.
Antibiotics work
with the immune system,
but your immune system
is nonexistent
because of the radiation.
If it's my heart,
you can get me a new heart.
People have heart transplants
all the time!
It wouldn't help.
The infection's everywhere.
There's nothing
anybody can do.
(SIGHS)
I'm so sorry.
We'll call your grandparents.
Get the hell away from me!
Get out!
(GROANS)
CAMERON: I think it's broken.
Nothing like a melodramatic
gesture to solve everything.
We were wrong, too.
Steroids wouldn't
have helped her.
I didn't not help her.
I actually pulled the trigger.
There's nothing left
for you to do.
One of us could
go home with...
You're trying to
make me feel better?
Yeah.
I killed a woman.
Don't you think
it's appropriate
I feel like crap
for at least a little while?
It won't help her.
Where is he?
He went to the ICU.
What are you doing?
Prepping for an aspiration.
We still don't know
what infection...
It's not gonna help her.
It's not gonna hurt her.
Well, it is gonna hurt her
but it's not gonna...
No.
This'll just take
a few minutes.
I'll grab a piece
of an abscess,
some pus...
You really don't care.
You really don't care
why she's gonna be dead.
She's gonna be dead because...
What?
What did we screw up?
What did we miss?
I need to know.
You'll have to wait.
We're moving her back
to her room.
Patients who've had
total body radiation
have to stay in ICU.
ICU isn't going to help her.
Let's give her some privacy.
What do you want?
Want to see
if I'm dying on schedule?
Or do you want me
to tell you it's all right,
I'm okay with it?
I'd like your forgiveness.
I don't expect it.
Good.
'Cause this isn't like you
ran your cart into mine
at the supermarket.
No.
Your grandparents
haven't arrived yet.
If they don't make it on time,
is there anything
you'd like me to tell them?
I never really knew them.
You got any friends
you want me to call?
It's the middle of the night.
They're not the kind
of friends you ask
to help you move,
never mind watch you die.
I never did much.
No kid to leave behind.
When I go, the world's
not gonna be any different.
Kind of a relief for you, huh?
You were right about me.
Yeah? Which time?
I had a problem with you.
But you were wrong, too.
I've made some bad decisions.
Stole cars. Robbed houses.
Killed a woman.
(CLEARS THROAT)
But then I got another chance.
Left home, went to college,
entered a whole other world.
And there's some part of me
I can't get rid of,
always thinks,
if I'm not the smartest,
if I'm not the first,
everywhere I go
they'll figure out
I'm not supposed to be here.
They'll send me back.
You know that's
not gonna happen.
You're out.
I'll never be out of there.
When I came home
that last Christmas
I was in college,
it was like the rooms
felt so small.
It was suffocating.
But when I was standing
on the stoop saying goodbye,
my mom put her arms around me.
That was...
That was the last time
I ever felt at home.
I only put distance
between you and me
because I know
there isn't any.
You were right about me, too.
That stuff about
the system being
against people like me...
I know it's crap.
I mean, it's true
but it's also crap.
I just wasn't ready
to try again.
But I always thought
I was young.
I had time.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Aren't you ever gonna leave?
No.
(RINGING)
Yeah?
Time of death, 3:35.
Do whatever you want.
(FOLLOW THE LEADER PLAYING)
You wanna go and get drunk?
No, thanks.
I've got paperwork.
Listen, I don't...
I don't know what I believe
but sometimes I need to think
there's something out there
paying attention.
So when I can't
talk to anybody,
I talk to God and pretend
somebody's listening.
We were all wrong. You know?
Even House was wrong.
I know.
(FOLLOW THE LEADER
CONTINUES PLAYING)
(INAUDIBLE)
I got your consent.
Her bra hook.
What?
She scratched herself
with her bra hook.
That's how
the infection got in.
Staph aureus.
She died from a simple
staph infection?
That and some bad decisions.
I'll be outside.
Go home.
Have a few drinks.
Go to sleep.
Get up tomorrow.
And do it all over.
Only better.
If you need absolution,
go to a priest
or give alms to the poor.
Whatever ritual comforts you.
I killed her.
Yeah. Me, too.
This wasn't,
"Oh, I should've thought
of that idea sooner."
This wasn't messing up
a dosage!
We see a disease rushing down
on someone like a train,
we can't always get them
out of the way!
But this wasn't that.
No.
And you'll do it again.
For a lot of doctors,
this would be
a once-in-a-lifetime mistake.
But we're not
a lot of doctors.
And we'll save more patients
than the guy down the street
but a few of the ones
that he'd save
by doing what
everyone else does,
we will lose.
So you're giving me numbers.
Because they don't lie.
I can't forgive you, Foreman.
Because there's
nothing to forgive.
(DOOR CLOSES)
What did you tell him?
That guilt is irrelevant.
You wanna get
something to eat?
Can't.
Got a dog waiting at home.
What's wrong?
(SIGHS)
I did something bad, Mom.
I hurt somebody.
It wasn't your fault.
It was.
Then I forgive you.
I forgive you.
I can see from your face
you'd never hurt anybody
on purpose.
Do you know who I am, Mom?
It's Eric.
Of course.
My little boy's name is Eric.