I'm okay. Let's just go home.
You're getting checked out.
I tripped on the ice.
Eight other kids tripped.
This is embarrassing.
You said you were just gonna
hang with your friends.
I turn around,
and you're out there
on the ice.
I'm fine.
You don't know that.
You fell awkwardly.
No, I didn't.
You don't know how to fall.
I'm 16.
I've been falling a lot.
I think I'm getting
the hang of it. And I checked.
(MUSIC PLAYING ON STEREO)
(MUSIC STOPS)
And now the doctors
are gonna check.
You don't think that
you're overreacting?
I don't need you
to fix every booboo.
Then stop getting them.
I was just playing around
with my friends.
I was having fun.
You know you can't do that.
Oh, I can't have fun.
You know what I mean.
I'm going to have
a talk with your friends.
No!
They need to stop.
No, I don't want you
freaking them out.
Fine. Fine, we'll go to the
hospital, but they're going
to tell you that I'm fine,
and they're going to tell you
that you don't need to
worry about...
(TRUCK HORN BLARING)
Mom!
Mom?
Hello?
Mom, you gotta wake up.
No one's coming. Mom!
WOMAN.: 911,
what's your emergency?
We got into an accident
along the Canal Road
just outside Kingston.
My mom's unconscious.
Are you hurt?
I'm fine.
Mom? Mom?
Where's Foreman?
He's down here somewhere.
"Somewhere." Very helpful.
Do you have any idea
when he's getting out tonight?
Sometime.
I realize you can't predict.
I just thought you might be
able to estimate.
It's Valentines Day.
I've planned
a surprise getaway.
Get away.
Is my mom okay?
She's gone to surgery.
Foreman, your girlfriend
wants to know if you're
available for Valentine's.
Act surprised.
What are you doing down here?
There's a snowstorm.
ER's short-staffed.
We're all supposed to be here.
You're supposed to be here.
You're an ass. Act surprised.
This could sting a little.
Can we hurry this up?
Make sure that...
Take your time.
What's your name?
Hannah Morganthal.
You have CIPA,
No, I don't.
We have to do x-rays to
make sure you don't have
internal injuries,
blood tests to make sure
no infections.
EEG for neurological anomalies
and biopsy a spinal nerve.
Congenital insensitivity
to pain is one of the rarest
conditions on the planet.
There's only been
about 60 documented cases.
Yeah, and I have seven reasons
to think that
she's one of them.
She says she's not.
And that's reason number one.
She knew what it was
without us telling her.
Two, she's still wet from
the snow. She's not shivering.
That's odd,
unless she can't sweat
or feel hot and cold.
The ambulance was warm.
I want to see my mother.
Three, scarring around
the lips and tongue.
When she was a baby,
she chewed on herself
without feeling it.
I fell through a window
when I was a kid.
Four, when you cleaned
the wound,
she flexed into the cleaner
instead of away from it.
It's hard to fake pain
when you've never felt it.
It takes an imaginative leap,
Ms. Morganthal.
That's one of them Jew names.
Ashkenazis are a
higher-risk group.
On the other hand,
she says she doesn't have it,
and she'd be dead by now
if she'd never been diagnosed.
They killed our Lord.
You're gonna trust them?
She wants to see her mom.
She admits having CIPA,
she knows we're not
letting her go anywhere
without a battery of tests.
You said you had
seven reasons.
I pulled a number
out of the air.
What, five isn't enough?
Five lame reasons aren't.
I'm taking her to
see her mom as soon as...
I can hit her again
if six isn't enough.
Do the tests.
Need to bail on the ER.
I got a case.
Why are you wearing perfume?
Is this a real case
or one of those imaginary
cases that happen
when you're bored?
CIPA.
CIPA is a diagnosis.
Diagnoses happen
at the end of cases.
She's got no idea
what's going on in her body.
There's bound to be
something wrong.
In other words,
she could be
perfectly healthy,
but you're curious
about someone who
can't feel pain
because you always feel pain,
so you want to go exploring.
She was in a car accident.
She needs x-rays,
blood tests, EEG,
nerve biopsy.
I also note that,
although snow is coming down
in sheets this morning,
you left your hat at home,
and you used earmuffs.
Do your tests,
except for the...
So while everyone else
was just worrying
about getting in,
you were concerned
with hat head.
Blind dates are
never a good idea.
Only reason to wear a scarf
like that is as a beacon
to identify you in a crowd.
Do your tests,
except for the nerve biopsy.
I need the nerve biopsy.
You'd risk paralyzing her.
It's neurological.
You have no evidence of that.
She tripped.
Do you have any evidence,
other than the fact
that a typically clumsy
CIPA patient tripped
on an icy day?
If the EEG reveals a problem,
we can talk then.
Could have left the scarf
at home and just told him
you'd be wearing
a look of desperation.
Spiking on leads C-3 and O-2.
She could be going into
a seizure.
HANNAH: Hello?
I think there's
a simpler explanation.
You're not gonna
find anything. I'm fine!
I want to see my mom!
So sedate her.
She won't consent.
She's a teenager.
No dad.
Mom's still in surgery.
What do you want us to do?
Hold her down?
Well, only until you
inject her with a sedative.
Then you can let her go.
We tried.
Seriously?
She's strong and doesn't care.
We'd have broken something
before we can get her
to sit still enough
to inject her.
So break her arm.
She won't mind.
You're cranky.
I'm in pain.
Come on,
let's go break her arm.
Nurse Shortie, your biznitch,
how long are you going to
waste her time?
I'm so glad
we're walking somewhere.
Another 60 feet,
and this conversation is over.
When you guys are
out of this program,
Cameron will find somebody,
Chase will find
eight somebodies,
and you'll be alone.
Thirty feet.
You'll date, and you'll date,
but you're the ultimate
Darwinian. You have to
fight for everything.
Anybody else
would just slow you down.
Yeah.
I'm still with her, aren't I?
I can only imagine it's
because she hasn't given you
an excuse to break up,
and you don't have the guts
to recognize your own reality.
I want to see my mother.
Hi again.
I'm sure I could say this
without being condescending,
but then you'd get
the false impression
that I respect you,
so you're a kid,
you're scared,
you're stalling, grow up.
I'm not scared.
I'm never scared.
See? How juvenile was that?
You can't feel pain.
Nothing left but pleasure.
Why don't you tell me
how wonderful that is?
It sucks.
Better than being
in pain all the time.
Get in the chair.
Every morning,
I have to check my eyes
to make sure
I didn't scratch a cornea
in my sleep.
Oh, God, stop.
I'm in a pool of tears here.
I can't cry.
Neither can I.
Every morning,
I check my eyes for jaundice
in case the Vicodin's
finally shot my liver.
I can't run anywhere
without examining all my toes
for swelling.
I can't run.
Boys can't hold me
for too long
because I can overheat.
Girls can't hold me
for too long because
I only pay for an hour.
I need an alarm on my watch
to remind me to
go to the bathroom.
Know how many humiliating
experiences before
I thought of that?
Bathroom is 50 feet
from my office.
Every drink of water,
I weigh the pros and cons.
After everything I do,
I self-check.
Mouth, tongue,
gums for cuts, count teeth,
check temperature,
fingers, toes and joints
for swelling,
skin for bruises.
I got shot.
I sat on a stove
when I was three.
Want to see the coil marks?
Yeah.
You think I'm lying?
You think I would just want to
check out your tuchus,
as your people would say?
Put her in the chair
and run the damn test. If she
moves again, give her nitrous.
You weren't shot because
of leg pain. You were shot
because you're a jerk.
Some think
the two are connected.
(WOMAN CHATTERING ON PA)
He didn't have to do that.
Yeah, he did.
I'm sick?
No, your EEG was normal.
X-ray showed no break.
Blood tests showed
no infections.
Urine indicated no...
Hannah?
Call a code! Oh, God.
Need ice packs
and cooling blankets.
Got saline in there?
She's not flushed.
She's not sweating.
You must be...
She has a temperature of 105.
Wow, she's actually sick.
We got her temperature
down below boiling.
It could be infection.
No, LP showed normal proteins
and no white blood cells.
High bilirubin.
Could be a liver problem.
Nope, transaminases
were normal.
Could be drugs.
She's smoked pot
since she was 11.
No again.
Tox screen was clean.
We're doing
this case backwards.
We do the tests,
and then she gets sick?
Maybe we did something to her.
Maybe she got
sick after the tests.
We should rerun them.
And biopsy a spinal nerve.
You want to risk paralysis
because she's got a fever?
I want to risk paralysis
because I don't know
what's causing the fever.
If it's neurological...
It's a fever.
In a CIPA patient. Obviously
things are a little different
in her upstairs wiring.
And have been since
the day she was born.
Yeah, it's much more likely
that whatever it is
was cleverly waiting
and hiding
until you guys
were done testing.
Where are you going?
You're all against this,
right?
And you're all gonna stand
on principle and refuse
to do it, right?
I'm going to get
Cuddy's approval.
CAMERON: How long are we going
to keep Hannah in the dark
about her mother?
CHASE: Long as possible.
Side airbags
should be standard.
I'm sure she'll agree.
She should know
her mother's situation.
Breaking that news
is that surgeon's problem.
Any word from House?
No.
Well, maybe Cuddy will say no.
Cuddy never says no.
That's not true.
Nobody ever says no.
We don't say no.
You don't say no.
He'll come back.
He'll browbeat us.
He'll give us seven reasons,
and eventually we'll fold.
We all will, not just me.
The only way
we can avoid biopsying
this kid's spine
is to find the answer
some other way.
All the tests were negative.
We need a better history.
How much more paperwork
do you need?
We've got pediatric records,
a few dozen ER records,
our own admission
questionnaire.
What's the first question?
Insurance coverage.
Okay, second question.
Just make your point.
"Where does it hurt?"
If we knew where it hurt,
we could diagnose her.
You do know CIPA means
she can't feel pain.
No, CIPA means she's
insensitive to pain.
She still has
scattered nerve fibers
that could conduct pain,
but the signals don't make
it to the brain.
What if we give her more
pain signals,
a lot more pain signals?
Maybe some of them
will make it through.
You want to torture her?
No.
Yes, we do this
to anybody else, it's torture.
Doing it to her
is no different
than pricking a finger.
We keep poking sharp sticks
into her,
eventually we'll find the part
that's already tender.
So what does
a Dean of Medicine do?
Oh, can we please
not talk about that?
I will talk about
anything else. I'm just trying
to get away from work.
Metaphorically,
because geographically,
the coffee place
around the corner from
the hospital probably isn't
the furthest you could get.
Well, the snow!
The roads are clearing,
but it's a good place
to beat a retreat from.
You usually expect
your dates to go wrong?
Experience has taught me
to have an escape route.
Well, low expectations,
that's in my favor.
Whatever happens,
I need you to understand
that there are
certain aspects to my life
I'm not happy about.
Need a nerve biopsy.
And you had to come here
personally to tell me that?
And how did you even know
I was here?
I had to bring the file,
and this was the most
noncommittal location
in walking distance.
You left your car keys
in your desk. Greg House.
You two must have met online.
Either that,
or you've got a friend
who secretly hates you.
Don Herrick.
Yeah, we connected through
SingleBallroomDanceLovers. Com.
Why would he volunteer
that information?
Why would I hide it?
You didn't tell him that
anything he said would be
held against you?
So what line of work
are you in?
Auto maintenance,
changing oil and filters.
Great, 'cause my place
overcharges. Can't trust
anything you guys say.
Where are you located?
In 14 states.
I own Eastern Lube.
Most CIPA complications
are infection,
and she's got a fever.
LP? Urine?
Clean. Normal.
Same with
the white-blood-cell count.
Cancer?
Nothing on the scan.
I think it's her nerves
messing with
the temperature control.
Amyloid, sarcoid,
there's a lot of candidates.
I want a biopsy.
Fine, if that's what
you need, go get it.
(LOUDLY) He seems a lot nicer
than that one from
WiccaNeedsADaddyFigure. Com.
CHASE: One of these is warm,
and the other is very hot.
Start here.
Move to the hot one.
Just a few seconds, then back.
We're gonna monitor activity
in your brain while you do it.
If you feel any response
to the heat, it could
indicate a vascular problem.
How's my mom doing?
She's okay.
Do you feel anything?
No.
What does "okay" mean?
She's still in surgery.
They tell me it's going okay.
Can you take your hand out?
And you didn't
ask anything else?
Take your hand
out of the water.
What's going on
with my mother?
Hannah!
You just got
second-degree burns.
I'll be fine. What's going on
with my mother?
Is she gonna die?
They said she's okay.
Surgery this long
is typical when there are
internal injuries.
FOREMAN: Naloxone and
kinase proteins in.
And that's gonna make
me feel pain?
I didn't feel anything when
you guys screwed this thing
into my head.
It'll replace missing
chemicals in your nerves,
heighten sensitivity.
We're gonna be drilling
directly into your skull.
A response should
indicate sarcoma.
What does it feel like?
It hurts.
I'm sorry.
Bone pain is the worst
there is, so you need
to let me know as soon
as you feel anything.
She's ready.
So, what, I just sit here
while you guys
drill a hole in me?
You wanna talk?
Just you and your mom, huh?
You two must be pretty close.
We were, until I got arrested.
Third time.
Drugs?
Fights.
You got an advantage.
Not really.
Never know when to stop.
You piss a lot of people off,
or are you just trying to
piss off your mom?
Those are pretty much
the only two choices you have.
Hannah? You want us to stop?
Stop the drill!
(SCREAMING)
It's okay. What did you feel?
Where did you feel it?
Hannah, I need to know
how it hurt.
Hannah!
I am so tired of this.
Did you know
that the new nurse from
Cardiology is sleeping
with that weird lawyer
from the board?
The guy with 11 fingers?
He has 11 fingers?
How do you not notice that?
The nurse used to be a man.
She's not anymore?
But we can't talk about that.
I thought we were.
We were supposed
to talk about that.
I came here to talk
about that, but on the way up,
I ran into Cameron.
You've got a CIPA patient?
Tranny nurse
is more interesting.
Oh, it's way more interesting,
but instead I've got to be
your damn conscience.
I'm tired of being your
conscience. I don't enjoy
being your conscience.
No one enjoys...
You're studying her.
She's actually sick.
Which you found out
after you took her on.
I was curious.
Since I'm not a cat,
that's not dangerous.
I don't think that metaphor
was designed to actually
warn cats.
You don't care
about her illness.
You care about CIPA,
which means your focus is
gonna be on getting
your answers, not hers.
Thank you.
Forewarned is forearmed.
What do you think
you're gonna figure out?
Do you think her lack of pain
is somehow the answer
to your pain?
I think if you'd stop
talking to Cameron,
then right now we could be
ranking nurses
in order of do-ability.
I need you.
What did
the nerve biopsy show?
Never did it.
Well, then do it.
Can't.
Why?
She's gonna jump off
the lobby balcony.
You think I can catch her?
Get away from me!
I'm not gonna hurt you.
Yes, you are.
You're just jealous
I can do anything.
Hannah, you're having
a paranoid delusion.
I don't believe you.
Did you think she would?
This is real.
You want me to be in pain.
You even said so.
If we wanted to hurt you,
we'd let you jump.
Just let me see my mother.
Fine, we'll take you
to our OR observation room.
I don't believe you!
Your mother is fine.
I just spoke to her surgeon.
I don't believe you!
Hannah, what do you
want from us?
What do you want us to do?
I can't feel my legs.
You're trying to pull
the same stunt
twice in 10 minutes.
I'm not pretending.
They don't hurt.
They're just... They're...
Anything?
We're not looking for pain.
Anything at all? Pressure?
Nothing.
You have six broken bones,
a fever, a concussion,
erratic heart rhythms
and a complete lack
of sensation below the waist.
I feel fine.
Is my mother
out of surgery yet?
Not yet.
This is excellent.
The paranoia seems
to have dissipated,
but her vitals keep
getting worse.
She could be dead in hours.
But if you're gonna die
a miserable, lingering death,
pain-free is the way to do it.
Are we sure the fall
didn't cause the paralysis?
The paralysis caused the fall.
Spine's clean.
No vertebral fractures
or spinal cord compression.
Even better.
The nuttiness and paralysis
mean there's definitely
a neurological component.
Could be a nerve disease.
Which is why we need to look
at the nerve that
you didn't biopsy.
There are other tests.
HIV? Syphilis?
She was negative for all STDs.
Vascular?
No, ANA was negative.
Cerebral clot? No, MRI was...
Thyroid storm.
Makes sense given her
glucose reaction was slow,
and potassium's down.
Yeah, I'll check with
an endocrinologist.
Bennett's on call.
Perfect.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
No.
Need a consult.
I already okayed
your nerve biopsy.
Need an endocrinologist.
Bennett's on call.
Won't pick up.
His cell phone must be broken.
Mine's working.
Had to give you the file.
I assume you're thinking
thyroid storm. Have you
done a hormone panel?
Normal.
TSH was on the low side.
Is that a cheery fire
I hear crackling nearby?
No, what about CPK enzymes?
Elevated, 275.
People light fires
for themselves,
but then they don't deny it.
He's here?
CPK isn't high enough.
Potassium's what
you'd expect because of
the bronchodilators.
Oh, my God!
You're not wearing a bra.
It's not thyroid storm.
You just met him.
I like him,
and I like sex.
Do I need to stitch
a letter on my tops?
No. Might be worth
taking out an ad
in the local papers.
Do you like me, House?
I was on the phone
with Bennett 15 minutes ago.
His cell phone's working.
Your MO is to avoid me
at all costs,
and suddenly you need my input
on every move you make.
I can only assume
it's because I'm on a date.
When we met, I noticed...
You noticed he was a Shriner
because of the way
he parted his hair.
You noticed he was a mama's
boy because of the way
he blinked his left eye.
I'm not interested.
I'm not impressed.
There are only two reasons
anyone would want to
screw with me tonight.
Either they're an
altruistic decent person
who's worried about
my well-being, or they
want me for themselves.
You left out the third option.
Evil bastard who just wants
to mess with
other people's happiness.
Good night, House.
We won't be bothered again.
It's late. I should go.
Why?
I part my hair on the left,
and I'm a Shriner?
You heard the conversation?
I'm not interested in him.
I don't blame you.
I only said those things
so that he wouldn't come back.
I don't really care
about my job. I do it well.
I provide a service,
but my goal was always
to make enough money
to do the things
I really like.
Music, travel...
I like those things, too.
You like them,
but they're not
really important to you.
I don't know whether
it's House, your job, or
you just thrive on conflict,
but you should hear yourself
when you're talking to him.
Nothing else in the world's
going on. You're focused,
confident, compelling.
Don't take this the wrong way,
but I'd like to go out
with that woman.
I can get her on the phone.
Where did you go?
She's getting worse.
It's not thyroid storm.
Give me a spinal nerve.
There are still other tests.
She just said
the girl is getting worse.
You really want to wait?
CAMERON: We'll be risking
infection, maybe make
the paralysis worse.
It is worse, and we're
making it worse than worse?
Do the biopsy.
We could paralyze her
and get no useful information.
Do the biopsy.
If you're thinking
peripheral neuropathy,
we should take a nerve
a little further away
from the spine.
A little further
from the truth.
We're talking paralysis.
There's a good chance
the spine is relevant.
If this thing is progressing,
it could kill her in hours.
Give me back my papers.
Is he asking
for a spinal nerve?
How did you know?
Give us a minute.
Did you know they recently
found a protein that
speeds up nerve growth?
Fascinating stuff.
If you put that protein
with the insulation
from a spinal nerve,
you could grow your
own little garden.
If that spinal nerve...
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
if it happened to come
from a person with CIPA,
I can grow pain-free nerves
and graft them into my own
leg. What an evil plan!
You'd have to be
on immunosuppressors for life.
Risk of infection,
shorter lifespan...
Shorter but normal.
Usually jealousy expresses
itself by trying to destroy
what someone has.
You're more ambitious.
You actually want to
change medical fact
to get this thing...
Medical fact
changes all the time.
You're risking
your patient's life.
That's how medical fact
changes.
A doctor risks...
To serve their
patient's health,
not their own.
This is medically justified.
Are you sure? Are you sure
that you're the right one
to be making this call?
Biopsy whatever nerve
you figure you could
safely get at.
God, Wilson's annoying.
Past 3:00 a.m.
On Valentine's Day night.
I assume you had
a date with Wendy.
She'll survive.
She knows the deal.
You're lucky.
I know.
Someday, when there's time,
I would like to actually
have a social life.
Someday? Come on.
If there's one thing
a good-looking woman
can have whenever she wants,
it's a social life.
You mean a sex life.
There's nothing wrong
with a little companionship
until the real thing
comes along.
I had the real thing.
Forgive me
if I don't want to settle.
Right.
What does that mean?
Nothing.
You think I didn't have
the real thing?
I have no idea what you had.
And yet you're judging it.
It's late. I'm cranky. Sorry.
I didn't have the real thing.
How could you even know?
You married a dying man.
You thought,
"Six months, a year,
it'll be tough,
"but then I'll recover,
and I'll have
the rest of my life."
It's like willingly getting
the flu or joining
the Peace Corps, short-term.
Wow, you nailed it.
It's basically like
a wasted weekend.
The sacrifices you made were
huge, but they were at the
height of your love for him.
Commitment is only commitment
because it has no
expiration date.
You stand next to someone
and watch them floss for
30 years like my parents have,
then ask for sacrifices.
That's how you know
the real thing.
Cameron, I wasn't
criticizing you.
People who avoid commitment
are people who know
what a big thing it is.
This isn't right.
CIPA can't cause
this much degeneration.
A few nerve fibers we
teased out of the center
have some insulation left,
but the insulation
around the bundles
has been stripped bare.
Means the damage
must be coming
from the outside in.
Which means it's secondary
demyelination, which means
the source is somewhere else,
which tells us it's not
a nerve disease.
It's something systemic
that's affecting the nerves,
which means that we need to...
Where are you going?
Kid's mom is
finally out of surgery.
I'll be right back.
So what?
Hannah should see her.
Yes, immediately after
we're done chatting
about saving her life.
Most likely causes
are metabolic.
They found brain swelling.
They're prepping her mother
for another surgery.
Again, so what?
Get a nurse to take the kid.
There are more
than 60 different
metabolic conditions
that could account for what
she's got. There's only
three of you guys.
She's scared.
She should be.
She'll die if
we don't diagnose her.
So diagnose her.
Mom?
How bad is it? Are you okay?
I'm okay, Mom.
I'll get better.
I always get better.
Are you checking yourself,
your temperature?
Mom, could you just let it go?
You shouldn't be worrying.
Baby, I'm sorry.
I should have seen
that car coming.
No, Mom, I did this
to myself. I screwed up.
You were right.
You were right,
and I was wrong.
No. No.
I shouldn't have gone out
on the ice. I shouldn't
have fallen down,
and I shouldn't have made you
rush me to an ER
for the 10th time this year.
(MONITOR BEEPING)
Mom?
You okay?
They have to take her
back to surgery.
Hannah, your BP is way up.
We need to get you some rest.
My hand's wet.
You're crying.
I can't cry.
My head's killing me.
So what does the pain tell us?
No tingling or itching,
so we can rule out...
It tells us nothing.
It wasn't physical pain.
It was emotional.
Exactly. What were they doing
when she got the headache?
Saying goodbye.
You said they were arguing.
They weren't really arguing.
She was just frustrated.
What were they arguing about?
Whose fault it was.
Peripheral neuropathy,
fever and intermittent
paranoia.
Lots of metabolic conditions
can explain those things.
What if we add guilt?
Guilt? As a symptom?
Alzheimer's can
cause euphoria,
pain causes depression,
and B12 deficiency
causes guilt, along with
all that other stuff.
If she felt guilty, she
wouldn't be making her
mother's life miserable.
She wouldn't be getting
in fights, getting arrested.
Maybe she's fighting
because she feels guilty.
She's showing her mom
she can take stupid risks
and still be safe.
Means mom can let go.
CHASE: Which is rational.
If guilt is a symptom,
it's caused by the illness,
not by a thought process,
and it would have to be new.
Couple years ago,
she was a model student.
This is pointless.
If the headache
was caused by guilt,
she has a B12 deficiency.
If it's just because
she was sad,
it's meaningless.
How the hell do we
test for that?
We don't.
Give her a shot of B12.
When she gets better,
I was right.
We already did.
ER gave her B12 when
she was admitted,
part of a multivitamin
supplement.
Apparently, she's just sad.
Why are you still here?
Trying to get a couple pages
into a drug trial.
Paperwork's due tomorrow.
Why are you here?
Still haven't figured out why.
No, I meant here,
in my office.
Just dumped a cool B12 theory.
Moved on to leukemia.
Very pedestrian.
I'm not happy.
Her white-blood-cell
count was low.
The ones she's got,
it's just a lot of
eosinophils.
The immunoglobulin
E-level's borderline.
If you want to be 100% sure,
check the bone marrow.
The team's doing
a biopsy right now.
It turns out the
weird lawyer knew
that she used to be a man.
And he's cool with that?
Turns out that his
previous girlfriend
also used to be a man.
Yeah.
Is it possible for you
to just watch me eat,
or do you get some primeval
thrill out of beating
the other hunters to the food?
See you later.
You still haven't figured out
that I don't need sedation?
It's so you don't move
during the procedure.
Is that nitrous?
What, are you
trying to kill her?
We gave her nitrous
during the EEG.
That's what made this thing
rear its ugly...
What thing?
B12 deficiency.
Are you having déja vu?
We've had this conversation.
She was given B12.
She didn't get better.
Because someone else ate it.
Get an abdominal MRI.
What? What are you doing?
Don't touch me!
See? There's she goes.
Another paranoid delusion.
At the rate she's going
downhill, forget the MRI.
We need an OR.
Leave me alone!
Occupied!
Her hernia can wait.
Help! They're trying
to kill me!
Okay, you can either believe
that we really are
trying to kill her,
or you can assume
she's suffering from
a medical condition.
Seeing as this is a hospital,
and we're all dressed
like doctors,
and there are easier ways
to kill somebody...
Bev, help them.
I'm gonna need iodine,
scalpel numbers 10 and 15,
forceps and a largish
salad bowl.
Okay, hold her down.
Come on, weenie,
she's in a cast.
Swab.
Fifteen.
You're not gonna
anesthetize her?
Relax.
It's just a magic trick.
(SCREAMING)
She's faking it.
We're not falling
for it this time.
Okay, keep that retracted.
Forceps.
Lake fishing can be fun.
It can bring the generations
together.
But if you don't cook
that trout or perch well,
you'll be giving
room and board to this fellow,
and by "free board,"
I mean all the B12
you can take in.
I could have a tapeworm in me?
Not likely.
You'd be in a lot of pain.
It's gotta be 25 feet long.
Damn it.
World record's over 60.
Hannah, wake up.
Somebody here to see you.
She's got limited motion
on her left side.
You might have
to take care of her
for a while.
You don't feel it,
but you're about to rip
your stitches out.
Take care of yourself.
Then you can take care of her.
You haven't gone home.
Sorry I screwed up
Valentine's day.
I'm dating a doctor.
I'd be an idiot
to expect anything else.
I did get you a gift. MGH.
Best teaching hospital
in Boston.
You want to be
a nurse practitioner?
That's as good as it gets.
I made a few calls,
and you're in if you want in.
This is why you've been
helping me get my surgical
hours for accreditation.
I thought you wanted...
Stupid.
You've got 10 feet of
personal space around you.
I step forward, you step back.
I've shared
a lot of things with you.
Which is why
you're breaking up with me.
You can't stand to be close.
Wendy, you think
I'll stay with you
because you're angry with me?
I'm upset
because I care.
Only you'd expect
an argument to be rational,
you and that
ass boss of yours.
Well, you could ask her
for the spinal nerve.
She's got no reason
to give it.
She owes you.
The hospital will
send her a bill.
I'm just saying, if you want
to do it, do it while
her B12 is still low.
Guilt can be your friend.
Breakfast?
Yeah.
Happy Valentine's Day.
Holiday that only applies
to people who are
already paired up.
For everyone else,
it's Wednesday.
Wow, thank you for
that dash of cold water.
Don't get me wrong.
I still think true love's
out there.
It's just very far away,
possibly in another galaxy.
We may need to develop
faster-than-light travel
before we can make contact.
So I'm thinking
we should have sex.
That makes sense.
Despite the wisdom
of pop songs,
there's no point putting
our lives on hold
until love comes along.
We're both healthy and
busy people. We work together
so it's convenient.
Like microwave pizza.
And of all the people
I work with,
you're the one
I'm least likely
to fall in love with.
Like microwave pizza.
The point here is to
make things simpler,
not more complicated.
Someday, there'll be time
to get serious about someone.
Meanwhile, we already had
sex once and didn't
get weird about it, so...
I get it. I get it.
So what if I'm offended
by your judgment?
Then you're not the man
I'm looking for.