ANNOUNCER: As the riders
begin Lap Two, Jeff Forster
is leading the pack.
They're jockeying
for position, now...
This is so cool.
Did we miss anything?
They've got, like,
1 1 laps to go.
We gotta find a good place
where he can see the sign
when he goes by.
Wait up, kids!
ANNOUNCER: There is
a strong chase pack forming
led by Vernonski...
At this point in the race,
things are still
too close to call.
It's anybody's race,
but Forster looks...
T urn six. Come on.
(WHEEZlNG)
ANNOUNCER:
Mike Larson has made
a nice break from the pack
and has closed the gap
on Forster and the lead group.
(CROWD CHEERlNG)
That's it. Up there.
Can you see anything?
Did you bring his inhaler?
Crap!
I think it's in the car.
I'll go get it.
(WHEEZlNG)
Are you okay?
Your dad's gonna
be right back...
I can see him.
He's right up front.
Honey, you're wheezing.
Here they come.
Go, Jeff! Yeah!
(GASPlNG)
You're number one!
He doesn't look so good.
ANNOUNCER:
Ladies and gentlemen,
Forster is down.
Yeah!
We need to talk.
Oh, God. Are you pregnant?
'Cause I really wanna
finish high school.
You have to renew
your credential.
They're good
for two more months.
Three weeks.
And the paperwork
takes forever.
Your application,
your malpractice insurance,
criminal records check.
And you know
that's gonna take
some explaining.
You know, our relationship
was way better when
we were sleeping together.
Why did we stop doing that?
Did you get married?
Yeah. Otherwise I'd be on you
like red on rice.
Look, rice isn't...
Oh, I get it.
You're also behind
on your dictations.
I don't do dictations.
Cameron does them,
or somebody.
And you can't have your sole
female employee
doing your clerical work,
which you'd know
if you'd attended
the required
sexual harassment seminars.
Now, I'm gonna pause
so you can make a crack
about harassment.
Joke killer.
House, got a patient.
Sorry. Can't play anymore.
My mom's calling me.
We just admitted
a world-class cyclist.
You gotta fire Stacy.
Yeah, I'll get
right on that.
Jeff Forster,
respiratory arrest
at 30 miles per hour.
She's loading me up
with pointless paperwork.
Well, you're way behind
on your pointless paperwork.
O2 sats are in the...
She's hostile.
You know me,
hostility makes me
shrink up like a...
I can't think of
a non-sexual metaphor.
She's gonna stand
over my desk with a ruler,
checking my spelling...
ER checked
for lung infiltrates.
Nothing there.
Professional athletes,
Cuddy. It's like watching
an old movie at 2 a.m.
Reliving all the
classic moments.
The part where
he denies it's drugs.
The part where the good guys
ride in, tests a-blazing,
prove that it is drugs.
Oscar clip. He can't imagine
how they got into his body.
It's so familiar,
so comforting.
She can't handle
working with me.
Oh, right. Yeah.
She's still got a thing
for you, making it
impossible for her to deal.
It makes perfect sense,
except for the pronouns.
Anyway, thanks for getting me
out of that meeting.
He's not denying
the drugs.
I'm thinking
he's actually sick.
Jeff Forster, this is...
I'm a doctor.
You're a sick person.
And you are a loved one.
Actually, manager.
We've been together
for 7 years.
So what's the drug du jour
on the bike circuit
these days?
Still erythropoietin,
or are you guys
just chugging battery acid?
There's no way I'd touch EPO.
(GASPlNG)
Too many guys
stroking out and dying.
Damn.
10 bucks for the ticket,
six for the popcorn.
I do straight blood doping.
Plot twist.
That's a very daring
confession.
We've got confidentiality,
right?
Assuming I'm more ethical
than your client.
So, injecting yourself
with donor red blood cells
for fun and profit.
Any other tricks
up your sleeve?
Well, nothing much
recently.
I'm in town
for a charity ride,
so it didn't matter if I won.
The kids just needed
to see me.
If you go slower,
they see you longer.
Let's say that our health
could be affected by things
we did before last Friday.
Well,
I usually sleep
in a Hyperbaric Chamber.
I've been pumping up
electrolytes with an lV drip.
Anabolic herbal supplements,
amphetamines and diuretics.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
But why would you be sick?
I know that doping has risks.
I know that it's
outside the rules.
But I do what I have to
to kick ass at my job.
Don't you?
Dr. House is a firm believer
in good old-fashioned
hard work.
This guy
doesn't even get sick
like a regular person.
Instead of a list of symptoms
and no cause,
we have a list
of possible causes
for one symptom.
Is the symptom death?
Respiratory distress.
Insanity doesn't cause it.
I looked it up.
It's the doping.
Injecting extra red cells
boosts your endurance level
but it also
thickens your blood.
Thick blood equals clots
equals respiratory distress.
Not with a clean
spiral chest CT.
The guy's sleeping
in a Hyperbaric Chamber.
Over-oxygenation
can cause cell damage,
and if the cells
in the lungs
are damaged...
That'd cause pulmonary edema,
which he doesn't have.
The supplements
he's been taking
contain yohimbe
which can cause
nerve paralysis.
Tox-screen was normal.
All the tests were normal.
There's no clot,
no edema, and yet
he still can't breathe.
So there's something in here
that we can't see.
(GROANS)
Air.
Come to Papa.
This guy's been
injecting himself
how many times a day?
All it'd take is
one slip of the needle
to cause an air embolus.
So, air is keeping him
from breathing air.
Well, let's go with that
for the irony.
Get a VQ scan
and check his veins
for bubbles.
Xenon 133.
It's just radioactive enough
for us to track the air
moving through your lungs.
Was my accident
on the news?
Yeah, you made
Plays of the Week.
A few more of those,
and cycling will be
as popular as NASCAR.
We inject similar stuff
into your blood
so we can watch it circulate.
If you accidentally
injected a bubble,
we'll see good air flow
but poor blood flow.
I'm careful, man.
With all due respect, man,
I doubt there's anything
wrong with you that you
didn't do to yourself.
There's this kid in oncology,
she's got a picture of Jeff
above her bed.
Mickey Mantle
was an alcoholic.
At least he hit
his own home runs.
He didn't physically
alter himself.
We take drugs
to help us fall asleep,
to stay awake...
Yeah, but we don't
make careers out of who
can stay awake the longest.
Really? Ever been to, oh,
I don't know, med school?
Guys, he plays a game
for a living. Who cares?
You don't even like sports.
He's making
millions of dollars
ripping off fans.
Anyone who thinks
they should pay a guy money
because he can
throw a ball really far
or pedal really fast
deserves to be ripped off.
Yeah, stupid, stupid kids.
I've got an uncle.
He can spit a cherry pit
50 yards.
He's working part-time
at a lube shop.
Life isn't fair.
(BEEPlNG)
Maybe it is.
CHASE: You were right.
Now, there were
three wasted words.
There is a bubble in his lung.
We should do a Swan-Ganz
catheterization.
I love when you do
both sides of the
conversation.
It's like white noise.
It's very peaceful.
Is there a light
somewhere that goes on
when I have food?
Green for food,
orange for beverages,
red for impure thoughts.
That bulb burns out
every two weeks.
How's your biker?
Pumped an air bubble
into a vein in his lung.
The things people do.
Doping, Vicodin...
Hey, you're talking about me,
aren't you?
I'm just trying to function.
He's trying to win himself
some little yellow jerseys.
Oh.
What?
Trouble in paradise.
2 o'clock.
Your 2 o'clock
or my 2 o'clock?
There.
She seems perfectly happy.
Obviously they
huddled in the hall and
worked up this circus act
on the off chance
you'd be in here.
She was unbelievably pissy
three hours ago.
Hmm.
Pissy with you,
happy with her husband.
Yes, there can only be
one possible explanation
for that.
When she's angry
she gets sarcastic.
When she's annoyed
she's funny.
But when she's frustrated
she gets pissy.
Yes, yes,
I'm with you so far.
She's miserable with Mark
because he's not me.
So she's gotta make me
not me,
so she makes
my professional life
miserable.
If I can't do my job...
You really, really
need to get some...
Oh, I get some
"some" all the time.
It's why I always need
to borrow some money.
Hi, James.
Greg, you gotten
to that paperwork?
I've been pissy.
Pardon me?
I've been busy.
When you save someone's life,
they owe you forever.
You're right. Take Stacy.
Oh, wait, she'd probably
just leave you all over again.
How's your recovery going?
Gotten around to the
small muscles yet?
It's not the size
of the muscle,
it's where you get to put it.
My goodness, it's like
watching Oscar Wilde and Noel
Coward in the third grade.
Excuse us.
How awkward was that?
What's he doing here anyway?
He's got physio
Tuesdays and Fridays.
Mark is in group therapy
for people coping with
disability.
He was thinking about
developing a drug addiction,
but that would be stupid.
Hey, you're...You, again.
WlLSON: You're not gonna
make some joke about
Mark being in therapy?
What's there to say? He's
doing the responsible thing.
I'm sure he's got
a lot to deal with.
You're making me nervous.
MOlRA: Every time
an athlete goes down,
you guys assume it's drugs.
Look, the doctors say
it's probably acid reflux.
Yeah, look, call me tomorrow.
There's a good chance
he'll be released.
Okay. Bye-bye.
So, is this fixing him?
If his acid reflux isn't worse
than we thought, yeah.
I gotta be in Spain
in four days.
Shouldn't be a problem.
Great.
If I could just
find the little bugger,
should be able to suck it out.
My legs feel weak.
You're under mild sedation
for the test. It'll wear off.
CHASE: There it is.
Got it.
Fantastic,
I'll pack his things.
Not yet. I wanna monitor him
for a couple of hours,
make sure he's okay.
Give him time
to sign a picture for me,
maybe even a jersey.
"To Doctor Chase,
I owe you everything."
(STAMMERlNG) It doesn't
have to be that personal.
Not too many eBay shoppers
named Doctor Chase, huh?
Still trying to unload
the Barbara Walters spit cup.
MOlRA: Here you go.
Seriously,
anything's fine.
Jeff!
CHASE: You all right?
Jeff, can you swallow?
What makes a guy
start drooling?
Chase, were you wearing
your short shorts?
Muscle fatigue
in his neck and jaw.
He's obviously
got something worse
than an air embolus.
Why?
Because you don't
drool from your lungs?
Maybe the problem
is not the embolus itself.
Maybe it's the treatment.
Maybe you hit a nerve,
literally.
The embolectomy was clean.
His legs were tired, too.
I thought it was
from the sedation,
but if not,
it means he's got
something systemic.
Which means it would have
nothing to do with
the stunts he's been pulling.
Lupus or polymyositis.
It explains the progressive
muscle weakness.
It could be ALS.
He's too young for that.
Some type of
muscular dystrophy?
He's too old for that.
So what would be
just right, Goldilocks?
HOUSE: Full blood workup,
including ANA for lupus.
And get a muscle biopsy.
Find out if we're talking
myopathy or neuropathy.
I'm late for my session.
Session?
It's all a part
of the process.
You get angry
and then you get...
Yeah. I'm right on schedule.
So, when am I gonna be done?
No, I need to know,
'cause I got plans to make.
When can I safely
book a game of squash?
MARK: When am I gonna
stop being angry?
Not today.
I've come for the healing.
Dr. Harper, as you know,
I have a bum leg.
What you don't know is
I'm upset about it.
I need to talk.
You know House.
You know we have a history.
You've been
telling me for years
that I should come by.
Here I am. Hi, guys.
HARPER: I've got
a Thursday group.
Poker night.
Monday morning?
Book club.
Well, look, if it's a problem,
I'll just go deal with my rage
privately.
Wait.
If you two could
resolve this tension,
you could really
help each other.
I'm tired of fighting.
So either I say yes
or I'm the jerk?
Oh, God, I know that feeling.
I took the muscle specimen
from Jeff's thigh.
I figured that's where
we'd have the best chance
at finding something.
The most painful place
to cut into.
I assume
that's caffeine-free.
Wouldn't want to be
artificially boosting
your performance.
Don't start her up again.
Caffeine's legal.
All about the rules, eh?
It's a bike race,
a completely
arbitrary set of rules
that everyone complies with
for no other reason than that
some committee says
that they should.
But that's the point.
That's what the game is.
So, if you
break an arbitrary rule,
Cameron damns you to hell.
But if you break a rule
that actually has a reason
that's designed
to protect people,
Cameron develops
a crazy crush on you.
House doesn't pretend
to be some golden boy.
He does it to help people,
not to glorify himself.
So why don't you report Jeff
to the biking authorities?
Ethics.
Well, you
wouldn't be doing it
to glorify yourself.
You'd just be trying
to make a better world.
At least you can
still get around
on your own.
Yeah, I know.
But you're starting to walk.
You're gonna get better.
You have a job,
a way to be productive.
And you have a wife.
Which gives greater meaning?
A wife could
make things harder, too,
I suppose.
This isn't about Stacy.
When it happened to me,
Stacy was great.
She kept telling me
not to rush it.
I never believed her.
She means it.
I know, but...
Stacy. She shouldn't
have to wait, right?
And you know
she feels it, too.
There's more time at work.
There's more satisfaction
from work.
She didn't get married
to be a nursemaid.
She wants a man.
How the hell could she
have loved a manipulative
son of a bitch like you?
That's an interesting
question.
Maybe she was attracted
to different things
in the two of us.
She left you.
But why was she with me
to begin with?
She made a mistake.
Maybe it's that simple.
Or maybe she saw
something in me,
something she doesn't get
from you.
I'm not an ass.
Maybe she wanted an ass.
She obviously did once.
Either he goes or I go.
You think
that's the kind of thing
you can just turn off?
Get him out of here!
Dr. House,
cancel your book group.
You're coming on Mondays.
Here's my new theory.
The drooling's another
competitive edge.
Nobody can draft behind it.
The road gets slick.
He's the only one
not racing in the rain.
He can barely move
his arms and legs.
Paralysis?
No, just general weakness.
Muscle biopsy is negative
for polymyositis.
And ALS
and muscular dystrophy.
FOREMAN: ANA for lupus,
also negative.
CAMERON: Maybe his bike shorts
are just on too tight.
So, by your rationale,
House shouldn't use a cane.
He should just drag
his bum leg around
as God intended?
House has a handicap.
All he's aiming for
is normality.
CHASE: And who decides
what's normal?
What if we find a drug
that makes people live
20 years longer?
Should we ban that
because it's not normal?
Jeff doesn't want normal.
He wants superpowers.
So why is he normal?
Oh, God, you too?
He's shooting
for extraordinary.
So why is everything
so ordinary?
I mean, this guy's breathing,
drinking and injecting himself
with everything he can find
to amp up his body chemistry,
and yet every test is normal.
He's artificially raising
his red blood count,
so why isn't it raised?
Maybe his count is raised.
Maybe what's normal for us
is out of whack for him.
Can't slip anything by you.
FOREMAN: Well, if that's true,
his white cells are up, too.
Which would point
to some kind of infection.
Muscle weakness, exhaustion.
He could have encephalitis.
That's kind of a long shot.
HOUSE: Yeah.
But it's been over an hour
since we've poked the patient
with something sharp.
So, get a lumbar puncture
and order broad-spectrum
antibiotics.
CUDDY:
No, it's not about judging.
It's just that
on a dating service
you should post a photo.
I have to go.
I am so sorry to bother you.
Nope, not a problem.
I was just accounting.
I'm Jeff Forster's manager.
He's been here a whole day,
and it doesn't seem
like we're any closer
to a diagnosis.
Jeff Forster.
A whole day, huh?
Mmm-hmm.
I was just wondering
if I could help
speed things up.
Your client's
had a muscle biopsy,
a full blood workup
and he's scheduled
for a lumbar puncture
at 10 a.m. tomorrow.
Jeff is in the Lucas Wing.
If Mr. Lucas showed up
needing a lumbar puncture,
would he have to
wait until tomorrow?
Mr. Lucas is dead.
Good.
Then there's an opening.
Jeff is used to doing
whatever he has to
to be first, isn't he?
It's been
very lucrative for him.
He feels it's important
that he give something back.
I hear you've been
raising funds for your
nuclear medicine department
or whatever.
(RASPlNG) Thank you, guys,
for working so late.
Glad to be here.
FOREMAN: The lumbar puncture
will tell us what kind of
infection you've got.
In the meantime,
we're administering
antibiotics.
Do you like being a hero?
It's a living.
You don't feel
a sense of responsibility?
There's kids out there
that worship you.
When I was a rookie
on the tour,
I got a letter
from a guy in Wisconsin.
He wanted me
to send a note to his son.
He said he worshipped me.
You know what worship means?
I looked it up.
It means to love
unquestioningly
and uncritically.
(GASPlNG)
So the kid
doesn't even know me,
but he loves me
unquestioningly
and uncritically.
So you decided
to take advantage of that.
What should I have done?
"Dear sir, I'm just a guy
"who rides a bike pretty good.
"You and your kid
are out of your minds."
My arms feel funny.
(CLEARS THROAT)
(RETCHlNG)
The sats are dropping.
He's in respiratory arrest.
He can't be. We fixed that.
Apparently not.
HOUSE: So glad we cured
his respiratory arrest.
It freed him up to develop
respiratory arrest.
LP was negative
for encephalitis.
The white count's
still the same,
but the red count's
fallen to 29%.
What was my theory yesterday?
That I screwed up
the embolectomy.
We'll get a chest x-ray
to check.
I didn't screw up.
Why would you...
How can you
be so petty, Chase?
He's down a quart.
Either he's losing blood
because you nicked something
or he's just
not producing blood,
in which case,
we're talking acute anemia
combined with
a muscular disorder.
Paraneoplastic syndrome?
Either you screwed up
or he's got cancer.
I think I should
start smoking again.
You want a medical opinion
supporting that decision?
The symptoms started
as soon as I quit.
Symptoms meaning diarrhea.
A lot of diarrhea.
10 or 1 2 times a day.
It's really embarrassing.
I'm a flight attendant and...
Well, on the up side,
my hiccups are gone.
You went to his group.
Well, you were the one
who was all, "Greg, you need
to confront your feelings."
That was five years ago.
Well, I've been pissy.
Fine, you don't want help.
Does that mean
nobody should get it?
Mark's looking for help
because, what, he's
resentful, overwhelmed?
I'm asking because I care.
Not about him.
You still wanna jump me,
so you don't care
whose marriage...
Listen,
I can get my rocks off
any time I want.
What I don't seem
to be able to do
is my job
without you hanging over
my shoulder.
(SCOFFS)
How many packs?
A bit over one a day,
but they were lights,
and I quit.
You used to go out with her?
Yeah.
What was I thinking?
I'm talking about the gum
you're chewing to replace
smoking as an oral fixation.
How many packs?
Six, maybe seven.
(DOOR OPENS)
I'm trying to protect you.
Cuddy and I may be
the only people stopping you
from jumping off a cliff
just to prove that you...
You're pissy.
Oh, I am angry!
Pissy.
You only get pissy
when you're frustrated.
Shut up.
Okay, I'm wrong.
This is unbelievably
difficult for Mark,
which you should know.
Which you should be
able to summon up
some level of empathy for.
Right. The crippled boys.
We should start a band.
I have a good thing with Mark.
We are handling this
the best way we know how.
And none of this has
anything to do with me?
No, nothing, except that
you can't or won't
just let it go.
Let it go.
You're being poisoned.
By gum?
Sugarless gum uses sorbitol
as a sweetener.
We use sorbitol as a laxative.
This will tell you
if he's got cancer
in his blood?
If he does, we'll see
abnormal cells in the marrow.
How long
will the tests take?
I'll get them in
as soon as I can.
And if he
doesn't have cancer,
what else could it be?
It's possible some damage
was done during one of
the tests we gave him.
So either one of your doctors
screwed up a simple procedure
or he's got cancer.
We can't know
anything for sure
until the biopsy comes back.
(LABORED BREATHlNG)
WlLSON: It stings, I know.
MOlRA:
No, he wants the tube out.
I can't do that, Jeff.
WlLSON: If you wanna
say something, you've gotta
write it down. Okay?
Here.
If it's cancer, it's possible.
WlLSON: There's no way
to know for sure.
Phone not working?
One of the morgue attendants
asked me to bring this to you.
Wonder why they're calling me.
Yeah, me too, actually.
I was wondering why the Times
was returning your call.
You a doctor
or the bicycle police?
He's cheating.
He shouldn't get away with it.
Have you actually
told them anything yet?
You worried
about the precedent?
I'm worried about you.
You gonna turn me in?
No.
He's made a mistake.
Revealing the truth
doesn't undo it.
Kids love him, and he's not
who they think he is.
It's not right.
Who cares if he's
what he says he is?
Who the hell is?
If love is based on lies,
does that mean
it's not a real feeling?
It doesn't bring
the same pleasure?
Are we still talking
about the patient?
Have you ever cheated?
Well, I have.
You wanna punish him?
Good for you.
But you can't do it
without punishing
the people who love him.
Is that how you justified
lying to your wives?
I always told them.
Well, he's negative
for bleeds.
Congratulations, Chase.
It's cancer.
Clean him up
and let oncology have him.
It's their party now.
He doesn't have cancer.
Biopsy shows he's got
pure red cell aplasia.
There's no way PRCA
could manifest so suddenly.
Unless it's drug-induced.
He's lying about
not being on EPO.
Why would he lie?
What does it matter?
People lie
for thousands of reasons.
But there's always a reason.
Philosophically interesting,
medically irrelevant.
Unless he's not lying.
You've got a leak.
The press is all over
the Jeff Forster story.
On the off chance
that one of you was
stupid enough to call
from your own office, I'm
pulling your phone records,
including your cell phones.
I assume if I point out
the fact that you have
no right to do that,
you'll interpret that
as a sign of guilt?
Wilson's chatty,
plus he's got
two ex-wives to support.
You want me to tell him
he's fired?
Until we figure out
who's behind this,
I'm sitting in with you guys.
You have the ethics
of a 4-year-old. I'm gonna
treat you like one.
How am I supposed
to practice medicine with a
lawyer sitting on my shoulder?
Responsibly.
You know I can't do that.
Cameron.
I'm not the leak.
Somebody once told me
that everybody lies,
and since
you're the only people
who know he has cancer...
He doesn't have cancer.
CUDDY: The point is,
you're his medical team.
He's threatening to sue.
HOUSE: Why would Cameron
leak cancer?
How does cancer
make the guy look bad?
He's on EPO.
Your anemia is caused
by pure red cell aplasia.
This is gonna hurt,
but we gotta talk.
What the hell are you doing?
He'll be fine, sort of.
(COUGHlNG)
I just don't have time
to watch him
write out answers.
PRCA comes in two varieties,
chronic and acute.
Since it came on fast,
you have the acute version.
He doesn't have cancer.
Is the good news.
The bad news is
pants are on fire.
Acute PRCA is caused by drugs,
most commonly, EPO.
Ready, and action!
But I haven't used EPO.
Okay, but this time,
with more anger.
Remember, this guy's
accusing you of cheating.
I haven't used that stuff.
I believed it.
It was simple, it was pure.
Did you believe it?
I guess it's silly
to cast someone
after the first audition.
Why don't you do a reading?
Give me that.
He doesn't do EPO.
What did you think?
It's a different way to go,
but, I don't know,
I just didn't buy it.
Does she handle
any of your injections?
You think
I'm giving it to him?
Test him.
Gee, that's a great idea.
I sure hope that EPO's not
one of those drugs that's
undetectable after six hours.
Hey, you know
what we can test for?
Phone calls.
Take her cell phone.
Push the redial button.
Even money says
you'll be connected
to the newspaper
that leaked your cancer story.
Okay.
Okay, I should have
told you.
It's not just about
the races, Jeff.
It's about your image, okay?
If you come back
from cancer, those sponsors
will be all over you.
Okay, so I messed up. Okay?
But I did not give you EPO.
That stuff could kill me.
(MlMlCKlNG lNCOHERENTLY)
Come on,
give her a break.
She was only doing
what she has to
to advance her career.
Don't you have that tattooed
on your tushie?
I would never do
anything to hurt you.
Who are you gonna believe,
the manager you've trusted
for years?
(HOUSE RAZZlNG)
I've been to college.
(GASPlNG)
You're fired.
Okay.
You're basing this
whole diagnosis, everything,
on the idea that I was
slipping him illegal drugs.
You're gonna kill him.
If Doctor House is so sure,
why do you need to stay?
He's a very cautious man.
Your breathing's better.
Let the prednisone do its job.
Get some sleep.
(GASPlNG)
Jeff?
(BEEPlNG)
FOREMAN:
His red blood cell count
plummeted to 16%.
He passed out,
had to be resuscitated, and
he still can't move his legs.
That's not possible.
The drugs should be
flushing out of his system.
Can't leave
if they don't exist.
The EPO use explains
every one of his symptoms.
He's been lying and cheating,
and now it's coming back
to bite him.
The only problem
with that theory is
it's based on the assumption
that the universe
is a just place.
If it were, then his
poor manager wouldn't have
been fired for no reason.
Lambert-Eaton.
His chest was clear.
CHASE: So we run
an electromyography test.
You're still not explaining
the PRCA.
What's his red count now?
I had to give him
a blood transfusion.
He's back around 30.
He needed a transfusion?
Well, he was losing blood,
so, I thought maybe
he needed blood.
Go forth and scan his neck.
His neck?
Or repeat everything I say
in question form.
She came into the clinic
and yelled at me.
Then she left, she came back
and yelled some more.
Hmm.
Yelling.
That might be a clue.
I know what the yelling means.
It's the coming and going
I find interesting.
It's not rational.
Anger is not rational.
Some anger is.
She could have
pulled me aside,
screamed at me privately.
Her beef is simple
and well founded.
But she was out of control.
You're having fun, aren't you?
She's in my face.
I need to know why.
Professional reasons.
Why else?
Do you really think
this is going to end well
for anyone?
After this,
let's scan some other
totally random body parts.
50 bucks says
we find something.
(FOREMAN SNlCKERS)
Find what?
Don't have a clue. We on?
No way.
No. We'll find something.
We found a thymoma.
How'd you know
to look in his neck?
Thymoma's usually present
in the chest.
I knew it wasn't
in his chest.
All we've done
since he checked in
is look at his chest.
All the more reason
not to think...
There are two types of PRCA.
Acute comes on suddenly,
chronic takes its time.
We all thought Jeff's
was acute because it happened
right in front of us.
But what if it'd been there
for months, maybe years?
There's no way.
It would have kept him
from racing.
With that kind of anemia,
he would have needed
constant...
Blood transfusions.
Which he was getting
in convenient
blood doping form.
He was treating himself
without even knowing it.
Up to half of patients
with chronic PRCA
have a thymoma.
And up to half of patients
with a thymoma...
I've always
wanted to do this.
I'm not getting any better.
Does that mean I'm...
You are healed. Rise and walk.
Are you insane?
In the Bible,
people just say, "Yes, Lord,"
and then start right in
on the praising.
First you tell me
I've got cancer.
And then you tell me
that my manager...
What did you do?
No, "What did you do, Lord?"
Thymoma is a tumor
on the thymus gland.
He's a bit of a wimp,
but he hangs with
the tough guys.
PRCA and an autoimmune disease
called myasthenia gravis.
MG causes muscle fatigue
including respiratory problems
and difficulty swallowing.
And it can hit you
that fast?
The treatment for PRCA
is blood transfusions.
The treatment for MG
is hyperbaria.
You were doing both
as part of your regular
freak show.
When you took a break,
everything went to hell,
which is not
an uncommon reaction
in Jersey.
So, the whole thing
with my manager...
Oops. No, no EPO.
This has nothing to do
with anything you did.
You can let her know
she's in the clear.
I could.
Or 10% of a Nike contract
is a hell of a lot of cash.
You don't need your thymus.
If we take it out,
everything else is manageable.
Manageable?
I thought you just cured me.
Uh-uh.
This is just diagnostic.
Tensilon erases
the symptoms of MG
for five or six minutes.
(GASPlNG)
Sometimes less.
This is exactly
why I created nurses.
Clean up on Aisle Three!
If you've come
to search my office,
you should wait 10 minutes.
I'll be out of your hair.
Here, start with my purse.
Just save me some mints.
What do you wanna know?
My sex life with Mark?
My guilt over
crippling your damn leg?
Or are you just here to gloat
because you weren't the leak?
I want to apologize.
Maybe I've
been punishing you
for a little too long.
And maybe you've been
punishing me.
If we're going to
work together,
I need to know.
Do you hate me
or do you love me?
Either way, I think
we've got a problem.
I hate you and I love you.
And I love Mark.
And you don't hate him.
No.
So what do we do?
We deal with each other.
Right.
That plan's been
working great so far.
It'll get better.
It'll get easier.
Why?
I don't know.
That's what my therapist
tells me.
JEFF ON T V.: In the
professional cycling world,
we are subject to
what seems like
constant witch-hunts
and finger-pointing.
But I want to thank Dr. House
and the excellent medical team
here at Princeton-Plainsboro.
My hope is that this diagnosis
will put to rest any rumors
that I would ever...
He needs blood transfusions
every two weeks,
which means
he can dope all he wants.
He's got a doctor's pass.
It's medicinal.
He got away with it.
Mmm-hmm.
He cheated and won a game.
Life's more complicated than
who gets to the finish line
first.
I fell in love
with my husband's best friend.
Near the end,
I was at the hospital
every day,
and Joe would come by
after work.
We'd go for walks
and try to talk each other
through it.
We kind of clung on
to each other.
My wife
wasn't dying.
She wasn't even sick.
Everything was fine.
But I met someone who
made me feel funny.
Good.
And I didn't want to
let that feeling go.
What happened to you?
How can anyone
go through that alone?
You can't control
your emotions.
No.
Just your actions.
You didn't do it, did you?
You didn't sleep with him.
I couldn't have
lived with myself.
You'd be surprised
what you can live with.
Hey.
I need you to open a door.
It's not allowed.
(STAMMERlNG) Yeah,
I was having therapy
in here today
and I left my cane.
Sorry.
Dude,
I'm crippled.