Sam, Dean, Pamela Barnes,
best damn psychic in the state.
Don't you recognize me? But we were so close.
Alastair.
Anna: lilith is trying to break the 66 seals.
Lucifer will bring the apocalypse.
Well,I don't know when it happened,
But the sam I knew,he's gone.
The lies,the secrets --
What else aren't you telling me?
You're holding me back.
I'm a better hunter -- Stronger,smarter.
I can take on  demons you're too scared to go near.
You know I didn't mean the things I said back there,right?
That it was just the siren's spell talking?
Of course. Me too.
So,we're good? Yeah,we're good.
Okay,okay,now,come on,you tell me --
Why kick that field goal?
Because it's called football.
No,it's called fantasy football,
And those 3 points screwed me.
Seriously,jim,you need to get a life.
Hey,guys,got any change?
Sorry,pal.
How about your wallets?
No problem. Take it easy,all right?
Just give me the wallets!
Hold on,man.
Jim!
Jim! Jim!
Call 911 -- Now!
Come on.
Hey.
Don't move. Don't move,man.
I feel okay.
You're not even bleeding.
Give me a hand.
How you even alive right now?
I don't know.
www.SUBTITULOS.es
-DIFUNDE LA PALABRA-
Foro de Series:
www.SERIES.es
Sam: no,no,no,you're right,
it's definitely weird.
Okay,bobby,thanks.
What's up?
[ Sighing ] oh.
Bobby found something in wyoming.
A job?
Maybe.
Small town,no one's died in the past week and a half.
That so unusual?
Well,it's how they're not dying.
One guy with terminal cancer strolls right out of hospice,
Another guy gets capped by a mugger
And walks away without a scratch.
Capped in the ass?
"Police say mr. Jenkins was shot
In the heart at point-Blank range by a 9mm."
An not a doughnut?
Locals are saying it's a miracle.
Okay.
It's got to be something nasty,right?
I mean,people making deals or something.
You think?
What else would it be?
I don't know.
All right,get that to go.
Come on.
What?
Sure you want me going with you?
Why uldn't I? I don't know.
I don't want to be holding you back or nothing.
Dude,I've told you a hundred times,
That was the siren talking,not me.
Can we get past this?
Yeah,we're past it.
Jim: now,you two said you were bloggers?
Yes,sir. Flooredbythelord.Com.
All of god's glory fit to blog.
[ Clears throat ] um...
Some of the people around town are saying
What happened to you was a miracle.
It was. Plain as day.
How can you be so sure?
How else do you explain it?
The doctors can't.
There's a bullet in my heart,
And it's pumping like a piston.
Well,how do you explain it?
Look,honestly,I was nobody's saint --
Not exactly father of the year,either.
Okay.
But when that guy shot me and I didn't bleed a drop?
I just knew the lord was giving me a second chance.
Is that so?
I had this feeling --
Like angels were watching over me.
I wouldn't expect you guys to understand.
Ll,we'll just have to try.
You wouldn't have happened to have swung by a crossroads
In the past week or so?
No.
Maybe you met someone...
With black eyes?
Or red?
Who'd you guys say you were again?
Never mind. Thank you for your time.
Hey.
Anything?
That cancer survivor?
He was clinically dead,
His wife pulled the plug,
And now he's taking her out for their 20th anniversary.
Any sign of a deal? No.
What about you? Found anyone dying around here?
Not since cole griffith.
He dropped 10 days ago.
It was the last death I could find.
So,what are you thinking?
Eh,maybe it is what the people say it is.
[ Scoffs ] miracles?
Dean,our experience,
When do miracles just happen?
Well,there's no deals.
There's,uh,no skeevy faith healers.
I mean,these souls
Just ain't getting dragged into the light.
Maybe 'cause there's no one arou to carry them.
What do you mean?
Well,grim reapers -- That's what they do,right?
Shlepp souls?
So,if death ain't in town --
Then nobody's dying.
So what? The local reaper's on strike?
Playing the back nine?
I don't know,sam.
Well,then,let's talk to somebody who might.
Well,last I checked,huggy bear ain't available.
No,dude,the kid. The kid?
The kid's a doornail. Exactly.
Look,if he was the last person to die around here,
Then maybe he's seen something.
We should talk to him.
I love how matter-Of-Fact you are about that.
Strange lives.
You sure this is gonna work?
No.
But if his spirit's around,this should smoke him out.
What? This job is jacked,that's what.
How so?
You want me to gank a monster or torch a corpse,
Hey,let's light it up,right?
But this?
If we fix whatever this is,
People are gonna start dropping dead.
Good people.
Look,I don't want them to die,either,dean,
But there's a natural order.
You're kidding,right? What?
You don't see the irony in that?
I mean,you and me,we're like the poster guys
Of the unnatural order.
All we do is ditch death.
Yeah,but the normal rules
Don't really apply to us,do they?
We're no different than ady else.
I'm infected with demon blood.
You've been to hell.
Look,I know you want to think of yourself
As joe the plumber,dean,but you're not.
Neither am I.
The sooner you accept that,the better off you're gonna be.
Ah,joe the plumber was a douche.
You gonna help me finish this?
Man: hey!
What are you doing here?
Uh,just...
Take it easy.
What the hell is this?
Okay,this -- This --
This is not what it looks like.
Really?
'Cause it looks like devil worship.
What? No!
No,this is not devil worship.
This -- This is -- This --
This is,uh...
I don't have a good answer.
Look,we're leaving.
You're not going anywhere...
.Ever again...
...sam.
Alastair.
I thought you got deep fried,extra-Crispy.
Nah.
Just the pediatrician I was riding.
His wife's still looking for him.
It's hilarious.
Anyway...
No time to chat.
Got a hot date with death.
Dean!
Alastair: you're stronger,sam.
You've been soloflexing with your little slut?
You have no idea.
How you doing?
I'm in pain,that's how I'm doing.
I think I have a concussion.
You want some aspirin?
No thanks,house.
So,demons,huh?
Yeah. So much for miracles.
And what the hell happened with alastair again?
I told you,he tried to fling me or whatever,
And it didn't work,so he bailed.
Well,how come he couldn't fling you?
He chucked you pretty good last time.
Got no idea.
Sam, do me a favor.
If you're gonna keep
your little secrets,
I can't really stop you, But
just don't treat me
like an idiot, okay?
What? Dean,
I'm not keeping secrets.
Mm-Hmm.
Whatever.
So, did you go back
and q-And-A the dead kid?
Didn't have to.
Bobby called.
He did some digging.
And?
He thinks I'm right.
Local reaper's gone.
Not just gone --
Kidnapped.
By demons?
Why?
Listen to this.
"And he bloodied death
under the newborn sky --
Sweet to taste,
but bitter when once devoured."
Swanky.
What the hell's that mean?
Well, it's from a very obscure,
very arcane version Of revelations.
Which means
what I think it means?
Basically, you kill a reaper
under the solstice moon --
Tomorrow night, by the way --
You got yourself a broken seal.
How do you ice a reaper?
You can't kill death.
I don't know.
Maybe demons can.
Where the hell are the angels is what I
want to know. We could use their help for once.
It looks like we're gonna have to
Take care of this one ourselves.
What are we gonna do, Just swing in
and save the friendly neighborhood reaper?
You got a better idea,
I'm all ears.
Dean,
reapers are invisible.
The only people that can see them
Are the dead and the dying.
Well, if ghosts are the only ones
That can see them...
Yeah?
...then we become ghosts.
You do have a concussion.
Sounds crazy, I know.
It is crazy.
How?
I can't even begin to tell you
how crazy you two are.
Well, pamela, you're a sight
for sore eyes.
Aw, that's sweet,
grumpy.
What do you say
to deaf people?
Which one of you brainiacs
Came up with astral projection?
Yo.
Of course.
Chachi.
- Chachi.
- So, let's be clear --
You want to rip your souls
out of your bodies
And take a little stroll
through the spirit world?
Mm-Hmm.
Do you have any idea how
heavy-Duty insane that is?
Maybe, but that's
where the reaper is, so...
So, it's nuts.
Not if you know
what you're doing.
You don't know
No, but you do.
Yeah, I do.
And guess what?
I'm sick of being hauled Back into
your angel-Demon, soc-Greaser crap.
Look, I'd love to be kicking back with
a cold one, Watching "judge judy," too.
Nice.
- More blind jokes?
- You know what I mean.
We're talking the end of
the world here, okay?
No more tasseled leather pants,
no more ramones cds,
No more nothing.
We need your help.
Tell me something,
geniuses.
Even if you do break into
the veil And you find the reaper,
How you gonna save it?
With style and class.
You're gonna be two walking pieces of
fog Who can't touch or move anything.
You'll be defenseless,
hotshot.
I seem to recall a bunch of ghosts
Beating the crap out of us.
Yeah, they had plenty
of time to practice.
Well, then, I guess
we got to start cramming.
Wow, couple of heroes.
All right.
Lie down.
Close your eyes.
Animum vult decipi,
ergo decipiatur.
Vis, vis, vis.
Okay, guys.
That's it.
Showtime.
Well, nothing like
shooting blanks.
What's plan "b"?
Oh, I'm so feeling up
demi moore.
All right, so,
I'm assuming you're somewhere
over the rainbow.
Remember, I have to
bring you back.
I'll whisper the incantation
in your ear.
You have got a great ass.
What'd she --
What'd she say?
That was wild.
Am I making you
uncomfortable?
Get out of me.
You're such a prude.
Come on.
Oh, man, we've been
spooking this town for hours.
No demons,
no black smoke.
I say we hit victoria's secret
And get our peep on, huh?
Hey, hey, hey, 3:00.
Kid in the window.
Am I crazy or is he looking at us?
It's 'cause
we've seen him before.
- We have?
- Newspaper.
Cole griffith, the last person
to die in this town.
Cole?
It's mom.
Your dad thinks I'm crazy.
Are you here?
A picture frame fell over.
I could have sworn
it was you, baby.
Are you still here with me?
Oh, my god!
Stop!
How are you doing that?
- Who are you?
- Relax, cole. It's okay.
How do you know my name?
Look, this isn't gonna
be easy to hear,
But you're dead.
You're a spirit.
Us too.
Yeah, thanks, haley joel.
I know I'm dead.
What do you want?
We just want to talk.
About what?
I was outside all morning.
They tell you to be careful
when it's cold.
Cold air can cause
an asthma attack?
But then I was in my room.
It happened so fast.
I called out for my mom,
but nothing came out.
Everything started spinning,
And then I was just standing there,
Looking down at my body.
And that's when you saw the man?
Creepy, old guy in a black suit.
He wanted me to go with him, But...
...I didn't want to go.
Reaper.
How'd you get rid of him?
I didn't.
The black smoke did.
Black smoke?
It was everywhere.
I hid in the closet,
And when I came out,
it was gone, and so was he.
Do you know
where the smoke went?
No.
But I know where it is.
They're back.
Who?
Another reaper.
Hey! Hey! Wait!
We need to talk to you!
Dean.
Do I know you?
We go way back.
You don't remember me?
Honestly, if I had a nickel For
every time I heard a girl say that...
You're gonna have to
freshen my memory.
Tessa.
That's one of my names,
yeah.
So, you do know her.
From the hospital
after the accident.
The accident with dad?
So, this is the reaper
that came after you.
Yeah.
Well, this was fun.
Now, if you'll excuse me --
Wait, wait, wait, wait,
you can't --
- You can't take the kid.
- Why?
Demons are in town,
that's why.
They've already snatched
your reaper pal.
The kid knows where.
- So?
- So, you should shag ass.
For all we know, they could try
and snatch you, too.
Except that this town
is off the rails,
And someone has to set it straight.
Yeah, we understand that, But
these are special circumstances.
What? Your whole
angel-Demon dance-Off?
I could care less.
I just want to do my job.
Right, yeah, and, look,
we want to help you do your job.
- So, if you would just bail town --
- No.
Well, then, could you hold off
until we fix this?
Please.
All right, but just so we're clear,
When I start reaping again,
I'm starting with the kid.
Understood.
I'll find him.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
What are you gonna say to him?
Whatever I have to.
This all must be pretty overwhelming, huh?
Pretty scary, too.
the worst is my mom.
Must be hard seeing her like this.
She's always coming in here,
Talking to me,
telling me how sad she is.
I knock some stuff over
to let her know I'm here,
But she only gets sadder.
Well, you might want to ease
up On the flying soccer balls.
I'm not telling you where the smoke is.
Hey.
What if I told you
that if you helped me...
You wouldn't have to leave here -- Ever?
What about the one downstairs?
Tessa? Oh, she wouldn't bother you.
No reaper would.
You could just stay here with your
family For as long as you wanted.
You can do that?
Yeah, you bet I can do that.
You swear?
I swear.
I'll tell you,
life is funny.
What do you mean?
You and me -- Together again.
Are you -- Are you making a move on me?
You're the one that got away, dean.
You'd be surprised how
little that happens to me.
Can I tell you something
between you and me?
Who am I gonna tell?
After our little, uh, experience...
For that whole year,
I felt like I had this...
Hole in my gut...
Like I was missing something.
I didn't know what.
Do you know what it was?
It was you.
The pain of losing my father and sammy.
I just...
I wish I had gone with you for good.
But I guess things are different now.
What?
The angels on your shoulder?
So, you know about that, huh?
Well, hey, don't get me wrong.
I mean, most the ones I've
met are dicks with wings.
But still...
You know, I've done things.
Horrible things.
And someone upstairs Still
decided to give me a second chance.
It just makes me feel...
I don't know.
Hey, guys.
Hey, cole.
I'm tessa.
I'm not going to hurt you.
It's okay, cole. Just
tell them what you told me.
I saw the black smoke at my funeral.
At the cemetery?
At the funeral home.
It was everywhere.
You doing that?
No.
Tessa!
Cole, you okay?
Well, how the hell are
we supposed to fight that?
I don't know. Learn some ghost moves?
By tonight?
Yeah, sure. I'll meet
you back at mr. Miyagi's.
Who's mr. Miyagi?
It's not gonna move if
you don't concentrate.
I am concentrating.
Ah, here we go, baby.
You pull a muscle?
All right, yoda, let's see what you got.
Dude!
You are so amityville.
This isn't even the good stuff.
See? If you want to hit something,
You just got to get mad.
Yeah, got it.
Now you try. Hit me.
Uh, I think I'll stick To just
picking on somebody my own size.
Hit me as hard as you can.
Dude, I'm not gonna do "fight
club" with a 12-Year-Old.
All right, cut it out.
Make me.
Whoa. Whoa, you got to teach us that.
This looks like "new jack city."
Can nobody can see this?
Maybe it's demon invisible ink --
Only see it in the veil.
Any idea what it's for?
We'll find out.
Dude, check me out.
You know, this ghost thing -- It's --
It's kind of rad.
It's iron.
Boys...
...find the place okay?
Rock salt's not so much fun anymore, is it?
Alastair...
You bastard.
Well, go on.
Why don't you try some of
your mojo on me now, hotshot?
It's hard to get it up When
you're not wearing your meat, huh?
Go to hell.
Ah, if only I could,
But they just keep sending me
Back up to this arctic craphole.
To kill death?
No, to kill death twice.
It takes two to break a seal.
I figured another one
would show up, though.
They're like lemmings.
By the way,
it's, uh, good to see you again, dean.
You can shoot us all you want,
but you can't kill us.
Ah, that so?
Anyhoo...
Moon's in the right spot.
The board is set.
Let's get started,
shall we?
You're gonna kill
a reaper with that?
It's little on the nose,
don't you think?
Is it?
An old friend lent it to me.
You know, he doesn't really
ride a pale horse,
But he does have
three amigos.
And they're just jonesing
for the apocalypse.
??? Pays to have friends
in low places,
Don't you think?
Hic cruor messorius,
Illud sigillum,
Quod luciferem
reverendum obstringit,
Aperiat ut resurgat!
No!
Stop!
hic cruor messorius...
I know you're here.
What's the matter,
you reeking son of a bitch?
You afraid of a skirt?
Vis, vis --
Ah!
Ah! Son of a bitch!
...illud sigillum,
Quod luciferem
reverendum obstringit,
Aperiat ut resurgat!
Bye-Bye.
Where's your brother?
I'll go find him.
You get out of here.
Animum vult decipi, ergo...
Pamela!
Aah!
What's so funny?
I can't die --
Not in this town.
Look.
Pamela --
Quit your worrying, grumpy.
How about
you make me a drink, huh?
You need a doctor.
Make me a drink, Sam.
You can't run...dean.
Not from me.
I'm inside that angst-Y,
little noggin of yours.
What the hell?
Guess again.
what ???
You and Sam
just saved a seal.
We captured alastair.
Dean, this was a victory.
Well, no thanks to you.
What makes you say that?
You were here the whole time?
Enough of it.
Well, thanks for your help
with the rock salt.
That script on the funeral home --
We couldn't penetrate it.
That was angel-Proofing?
Why do you think I recruited you
and Sam in the first place?
You recruited us?
That wasn't your friend bobby
who called, dean.
It wasn't bobby
who told Sam about the seal.
That was you?
If you want our help,
Why the hell didn't you just ask?
Because whatever I ask,
You seem to do
the exact opposite.
So, what now, huh? The people in this town,
They just gonna start dying again?
Yes.
These are good people.
What, you think you can
make a few exceptions?
To everything
there is a season.
You made an exception for me.
You're different.
Dean?
I could use your help.
Hey, cole.
Tell your brother
thanks for nothing.
Look at her, cole.
Do you see how unhappy she is?
That's why I want
to stay with her.
As long as
she can feel you,
She'll be in pain,
Because she can't let go,
Because you won't
let go of her.
Why won't anybody tell me
what's on the other side?
Maybe nobody wants
to ruin the surprise.
That's not an answer.
she won't answer you, cole.
Reapers never do.
But trust me...
Staying here is a whole lot worse
Than anything over there.
Why?
Because one day,
your family will be gone,
And there will be
nothing left here for you.
It's okay to be scared.
I'm not scared.
We're all scared.
That's the big secret.
Are you coming?
Oh, I'm sure I'll be there
sooner than you think.
Look out for that boy.
Look out for yourself, Dean.
What do you mean?
I've been around death
from the get-Go.
You know what I see most?
Lies.
"He's in a better place."
"At least they're together now."
You all lie to yourselves, Dean,
'Cause like you said,
Deep down,
you're all scared.
Stop lying to yourself, Dean.
What?
The angels have something good
in store for you...
A second chance.
Really?
'Cause I'm pretty sure...
Deep down...
You know something nasty's
coming down the road.
Trust your instincts, Dean.
There's no such thing
as miracles.
What are you saying?
Imum vult decipi,
ergo decipiatur.
Vis, vis, vis.
Hey,
we just got to talk
to tessa, that's all --
Get her to hold off reaping
till we get you better.
I'm pretty sure
she's started up again.
What happened?
Dean, where's tessa?
She's...
Pamela,
I'm so sorry.
- Stop.
- You don't deserve this.
Yeah, I don't.
I told you I didn't want
anything to do with this.
Do me a favor?
Tell that bastard bobby singer
to go to hell For ever introducing me
to you two in the first place.
Take it easy, pamela.
If it's any consolation,
you're going to a better place.
You're lying.
But what the hell, right?
Everybody's got to go sometime.
Come here.
I know what you did
to that demon, Sam.
I can feel
what's inside of you.
If you think
you have good intentions,
Think again.
Pamela?
Pamela!
What did she say to you?
www.SUBTITULOS.es
-DIFUNDE LA PALABRA-