- Hell hounds.
- Yeah, Dean. Your favorite.
I can't fight, I can't walk.
But I can do something.
I got everything we
need, to build a bomb.
- What are we doing?
- We're hunting ghosts.
You know who
does that, crazy people.
We, are insane.
Tomorrow we hunt the devil.
This is our last night on earth.
Take this thing to Lucifer
and empty it into his face.
You know I'd never hurt you.
You listen to me, you son of a bitch.
I'm gonna kill you myself.
I'm going to rip your heart out!
That's good, Sam.
You keep fanning that fire in your belly...
All that pent-up rage.
I'm gonna need it.
The nurses tell me
That, uh, you're not taking your medication.
You want to tell me why?
Susan?
The pills make me sleepy,
But I can't...
If I sleep, it'll come.
You mean the monster.
Now, we have talked about this.
But it killed Annie.
Susan, you're schizophrenic.
Your mind plays... tricks on you.
You get confused.
Sometimes you see things.
I know what I am.
Like I can see my dead son
standing right behind you...
I know he's not real.
But the monster... it is real.
Annie was your room-mate,
And what happened
to her was painful...
for all of us.
Perhaps it's easier for
you to conjure up a monster
Than to face how tragic
her suicide really was.
I can hear it at night,
In the walls.
Please.
you have to believe me.
Susan...
There is no such thing as monsters.
Oh, my god!
Help me!
They're starting early tonight.
Hurry!
Wait! Don't
pay attention to her!
It's coming!
Help me!
Aaah!
Supernatural
Season 5 Episode 11 "Sam, Interrupted"
You were referred to me by a Dr.
Babar in Chicago.
That's right.
Isn't there a children's
book about an elephant
named Babar?
I don't know.
I don't have any elephant books.
Look, doctor, I-I think that...
The doc was in over his head with this one
'cause my brother's, uh...
Okay, fine. Thank you.
That's... that's really not necessary.
Why don't you tell me how
you're feeling, Alex?
I'm fine.
I mean, okay, a little depressed, I guess.
All right. Any idea why?
Probably because I
started the apocalypse.
The apocalypse?
Yeah, that's right.
And you think you started it.
Well, yeah.
I-I mean
I killed this demon, Lilith...
and I accidentally freed Lucifer from hell.
So, now he's topside,
and we're trying to stop him.
W-who is?
Me. And him.
And, uh, this one angel.
Oh, you mean like a...
like an angel on your shoulder?
No, no. His name's Castiel.
He wears a trench coat.
See what I mean, doc?
I mean, the kid's been beating
himself up about this for months.
The apocalypse wasn't his fault.
It's not?
No.
There was this other demon... Ruby.
She got him addicted
to demon blood.
I mean, near the end, he was
practically chugging the stuff.
My brother's not evil.
He was just...
High.
Yeah?
So, could you fix him
up so we can get back
To traveling around the
country and hunting monsters?
Emma...
Cancel my lunch.
Dr. Fuller would like to see
you both under observation
for a couple of days.
Both, me too?
Yes, sugar. The doctor
thinks that would be best.
All right. I'm just gonna
give you a little check-up.
All right, look, nurse Latched,
let's get one thing straight...
I've seen "cuckoo's nest," so don't try
any of that soul crushing
authoritarian crap on me.
Hmm?
Okey-dokey.
All right, you can go ahead
and take down your pants.
Wait. Mm.
What? What... what for?
How was your silk wood shower?
Okay.
Yeah. Good. Yeah.
Good, um... good water pressure.
Did the nurse...
She was very thorough.
Yeah. Yeah good, good. Yeah.
I can't believe I let
you talk me into this.
Hey, it's the least we could do.
Martin saved dad's arse more
times than we can count.
He's a great hunter.
Was, until Albuquerque.
Besides, I-I just figure it's
best we keep busy. That's all.
Better than what?
Nothing.
Okay, look um...
Last few weeks, you kind
of been worrying me.
Oh, come on Sam. Stop.
Look, just because
we're in the looney bin.
doesn't give you the
right to head-shrink me.
Dean. Ellen and Jo dying...
yeah, it was a freakin' tragedy, okay?
But I'm not gonna wallow in it.
Dean, you always do this.
You can't just keep this crap in.
Watch me.
Oh, there he is.
Sam.
Dean.
Wow.
Wow, you boys got big.
You look good.
Thanks. You do too, Martin.
Well, thanks for coming.
Yeah.
In the old days,
I could've taken care of this thing
With both hands t-tied
behind my back
but...
Well, now...
What do you think it
is that we're hunting?
I don't know yet.
A ghost, demon, monster.
Animal, vegetable, mineral.
Hospital's had five deaths
in the last four months.
Doctors keep calling it suicides,
but they're wrong.
So you've seen this thing?
Has anyone seen this thing?
Well, a couple of patients have,
uh, had glimpses,
but that's not a lot to go on.
Are they reliable?
Oh, sure. Why wouldn't they be?
Gee, I don't know.
I know you boys think I'm
a bag of loose screws.
Well, you wouldn't be wrong,
but I wouldn't have called you
Unless there was something here.
I can feel it in my gut.
We believe you.
Have you checked any of the bodies,
found signs of an attack?
Well, uh, no.
I don't, uh...
I don't go around dead b-b...
b-bodies any more.
Dr. Fuller: Alex, Eddie.
Well, I'm glad to see
you're making friends.
Why don't you and
Mr. Creaser join us for group?
Please. Right this way.
Actually, I'm going to be putting you
in the afternoon group.
What? Why?
Well, to be frank, uh,
The relationship that you
have with your brother
seems dangerously codependent.
I think a little time apart
will do you both good.
All right, so, who would
like to start us off?
Anyone else?
Ooh, ooh, ooh!
All right, Ted. Calm down.
I am calm,
and I'd very calmly
like to talk about the
monster that's hunting us.
Ted, we're not going to
have that discussion again.
It's not good for group.
I agree.
You know what else
isn't good for group?
A monster eating all our faces off!
All right, fine. Thank you.
- Now, anyone else.
- I saw it!
When it killed Susan!
I did, too. It had big lobster claws.
No, it didn't!
Yeah, and it was an alien,
like on "x-files."
Stop it!
Stop helping! Listen to me!
We're all dead!
That's enough!
There is no monster.
Now, Ted, do you need me
to call the orderlies...
Or can you behave?
Behave.
King me!
Eddie?
I'm Dr. Erica Cartwright.
I've been assigned your case.
You're my shrink?
Well, lucky me.
And you're my
paranoid schizophrenic
With narcissistic
personality disorder
and religious psychosis.
Lucky me.
Hmm.
Can we talk?
Yes.
I've actually got some
questions for you.
What a coincidence.
I've got some for you, too.
well then, quid pro quo, Clarice.
Okay, Hannibal. I'll go first.
How many hours a
night do you sleep
Three or four every
couple of nights.
What can you tell me about
the recent suicides in here?
They were tragic.
But you haven't
noticed anything strange,
You know, like, I don't know,
black smoke, sulfur?
No. Why? What's that
supposed to mean?
Demon signs.
I hunt demons,
monsters... that kind of thing.
How many drinks
do you have a week?
Well, I gotta sleep
sometime, so, uh... let's say
What's seven days times...
somewhere in the mid-50s.
You ever feel any,
uh, any cold spots
or get a chill walking
through the hospital?
Not that I can
remember, If I had?
It means there's a ghost around.
Okay.
When was the last time you were
in a long-term relationship?
Define "long-term."
More than two months.
Never.
Have the patients reported
seeing anything weird?
In here? all the time.
Right.
So...
...Let's talk about your father.
Dean. Hey.
You okay?
I just got "thraped."
So, no, I am not okay.
- Tell me you found something.
- Yeah.
A guy says he saw the creature.
We should talk to him.
Want to meet back here in an hour?
Yeah, the sooner we
take care of this thing,
the sooner we can get going.
This place gives me the creeps.
Hi.
I'm Wendy.
Uh-huh.
Maybe this place isn't so bad after all.
Dude...
You cannot hit that.
Oh, so torn.
About time. Nurses
are on their rounds
we got, like, 15, 20 minutes.
Where is this guy?
Room 306.
Oh! Geez!
Hurry up! Come on! Hurry up!
Back off, Dean!
Hey.
Yeah. I found something.
- What do you got?
- Right here.
Um... Give me a hand.
All right.
This hole goes all the
way through to his brain.
What does that mean?
Let's find out.
Seriously?
You might want to keep watch.
Dude!
Look... his brain's been sucked dry.
That's fascinating.
Somebody's coming.
What are you boys doing in here?
Pudding!
All right. Come on, you two.
Crazy works.
Are those original Gacys?
I painted those.
Back on point, please.
- Um so whatever this thing is...
- It's good.
...I-it slurpees your brain...
sucks you dry.
Yeah, then it makes the
deaths look like suicides.
Any ideas?
Yeah.
A bad one.
What is it?
Well, I bet you a chicken dinner
it's what we're up against.
A wraith.
They crack open skulls
and feed on brain juice.
- You ever tangle with one before?
- Never.
Never wanted to, neither.
So how do we kill it?
Silver.
You so much as touch a
wraith with the stuff,
And the skin will crackle.
Now, that's the good news.
The bad news is...
They can pass as humans.
It could be any Peter, Paul,
or Mary in the joint.
Fantastic. So how
do we find it?
A-a mirror.
Lore says a wraith will show
its true form in a mirror.
Okay, well, we just
got to spot-check
every patient and
every staff member.
Okay. Yeah.
But, I mean, what's it
doing in a mental hospital?
A nut house...
It's... it's... I's a
perfect captive victim pool.
Sure.
Who... who's gonna
believe a patient
when they say
they saw a monster?
It's the perfect hunting ground.
What's up, doc?
You tell me.
Hunting.
A wraith, actually.
Could be anybody.
So... I could be a monster?
No. You're clean.
Why you?
Why me what?
Why do you have
to hunt monsters?
Why not let someone else do it?
I can't find anybody else that dumb.
It's my job.
Somebody's got to
save people's asses.
Yours included.
So, is there a quota?
How many people
do you have to save?
All of 'em.
All of them?
You think you have
to save everyone?
Yep. Whole wide
world of sports.
How?
Believe me, whatever you've got,
I've heard weirder.
It's the end of the world, okay?
I mean, it's the damn
biblical apocalypse.
And if I don't stop
it and save everyone,
Then no one will,
and then we all die.
That's horrible.
Yeah, tell me about it.
I mean, apocalypse
or no apocalypse,
Monsters or no monsters,
That's a crushing weight
to have on your shoulders.
To feel like six billion
lives depend on you.
God.
How do you get
up in the morning?
That's a good question.
Hello, Eddie.
Doc.
All right.
I had to raid three nurses'
stations to get these.
They're only silver-plated,
but they should work.
Oh, no, no, no.
Not today, sweetheart.
Come on. Keep walking.
I...
I want him now.
He's larger.
Hmm.
You've had worse.
Fuller is on call tonight,
So we'll have to hit
him after lights out.
All three of us.
What? No!
Martin, we got to
get past the security,
past the orderlies,
and then cut the
boss man's throat, okay?
It's gonna suck start to finish,
but we could use the backup.
No, I can't.
I can't.
We know what
happened in Albuquerque.
You don't know the half of it.
God... I used to be just like you two.
I used to think I was invincible.
And then...
Well, I found out I'm not.
Martin. You are still a hunter.
No, I'm not!
I'm useless!
Why do you think I checked myself
into the hotel California?
I'd give anything to help you boys.
I would.
But I-I can't.
I'm sorry. I can't.
He's still in the building.
You take the west wing. I'll take the east.
Aah!
No! No!
Look at his arm!
The cut's not burning!
It's not him!
It's not him.
You okay?
No.
No, I'm not okay.
I... I...I...
I am...
Awesome!
They give you something?
Oh, yeah.
They... they gave me everything.
It...
It's spectacu... lacular.
You always were a happy drunk.
Dean...
The doctor wasn't a wraith.
I know.
I don't understand it.
I mean, I saw it in the mirror.
It wasn't human.
Or you're seeing things.
Maybe... m-maybe,
maybe you're going crazy.
I'm not crazy.
Well, come on.
I mean, you've been at least...
Half crazy for a long time,
since you got back from hell...
or since before that, even.
And we're in a...
we're in a mental hospital.
Ma-maybe... maybe
you finally cracked.
You know, maybe...
maybe now you
are really, for-real crazy.
I made a mistake. That's all.
I'll find the thing.
Okay. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
I know. I know.
It's okay. Hey.
Hey, look at me.
It's okay...
'cause you're my brother...
And I still love ya.
Mm.
Boop.
You missed our session today.
I'm a little busy.
Still hunting that wraith?
People are dying.
People die all the time.
Look, lady, why don't you just let
me do my job, maybe save your life?
It's not my life that
I'm worried about.
Oh, my go... I am fine, okay?
I'm fine.
Come on. Even you
don't believe that.
All this pressure that you're
putting yourself under,
all this guilt... it's killing you.
You can't save everybody.
You can't.
Hell, these days, you
can't save anybody, Dean.
- What'd you say?
- The truth, Dean.
You got Ellen and Jo killed.
You shot Lucifer, but
you couldn't gank him.
You couldn't stop
Sam from killing Lilith,
and, oh, yeah, you
broke the first seal.
All you do is fail.
Did you really think that you,
Dean Winchester,
With a G.E.D. and a
give-'em-hell attitude,
were gonna beat the devil?
Please.
The world is gonna burn,
and there is nothing
that you can do about it.
Who are you?
How do you know that stuff?!
Hey. Settle down.
Tell me!
I said settle down.
Who are you...
Who is she?
Who?
What are you, blind?! Her!
Pal, there's nobody there.
I'm not real, Dean.
I'm in your head...
'cause you are going crazy.
Just leave me alone.
You asked to see me?
Yeah. Thanks.
I, um...
I just wanted to apologize.
l feel horrible about
what I did to you.
I thought you
were a monster.
I know that.
The question is, why?
I-I was...
It doesn't matter, um...
Because after what
happened last night,
I-I had a...
Moment of clarity.
Um...
I realized there's no
such thing as monsters.
Well, I'm... Glad to
hear you say that.
But honestly?
Monsters are the least
of your problems.
People can learn to
live with delusions,
but the anger I saw in you.
I...
You hurt those two men, and
you were going to kill me.
The look in your eyes
when you came after me...
I...
It was like you were
barely even human.
Like a man possessed.
I know.
Please...
Just...
Could you give me a second chance?
Well, this isn't a prison.
You'll be allowed to
go to the day room.
Under supervision.
Thank you.
But if there is one more outburst,
I will transfer you to a facility
that is equipped to
handle violent patients,
and believe me, they will
be far, far less forgiving.
Dean. Hey.
Whoa. What's wrong?
It's not the demon blood, Sam.
It never was.
What?
The problem was you.
It was always you...
The lies, your arrogance,
that black spot on your soul.
Now we're all gonna
die because of you.
It's all your fault!
You killed all of us!
Pathetic freak!
You evil son of a bitch!
Loser!
We're all gonna die! Freak!
Freak!
Aah!
Leave me alone!
Leave me alone! No!
Stop it! Leave me alone!
Leave me alone! I didn't do it!
Get off of me! Leave me alone!
Aah! No!
Leave me alone!
What's happening?
Martin, martin, it's me! It's Dean!
Oh. Sorry.
You... you look like hell, boy.
I feel... I feel like it, too.
Where's Sam?
Lock down.
He went crazy, thank god.
What?
I'm going crazy, too.
I'm seeing things.
I'm hearing things.
W-we both are.
Crazy is the clue.
W-what do you mean?
- Dean?
- Crazy is the clue.
Y-you said that. What?
I mean, the things that
me and Sam have done,
The... the stuff we've seen...
We're gonna end up
going guano eventually,
Probably end up like a
couple of drooling nut bags.
No offense.
None taken.
But me and him freaking
out on the same day?
I mean, it... it... it's got to be the...
- The monster.
- What?! Where? Where?
No, not... no, there's nothing there.
Look...
What if this thing
doesn't just feed on the insane?
What if it makes people insane?
Is that possible? Does,
does that seem real?
Well, I-I'm... I'm not
the most reliable source
On what is "real,"
But it sounds... makes sense.
Okay.
Okay, so... s-so we got infected.
You know, something
shot us up with crazy.
You know, something...
Maybe...
Maybe it was the ghost of my dad.
No.
Focus on the wraith, Dean.
- Focus!
- Right, the wraith. The wraith.
Okay, so the wraith... the wraith.
It... it poisoned us.
It...
Maybe with venom, you
know, by t... by touch.
Or... or... or venom
or, um, saliva.
Wendy.
Wendy?
Wendy! Wendy slobbered
all over me and Sam!
That's how we got infected!
Dean!
I can't step on the cracks.
Is this real?
Oh, it is, sugar.
It's very real.
Aaah!
She's still alive!
There's two patients,
in Wendy's room.
They attacked me.
Dean? Can you hear me?
Dean!
You've got to get out
there and kill that thing.
I'll take care of her.
I-I can't.
You have to. You
have no choice, son.
Go!
Dean, run!
Run!
Hey! Let me go!
No.
You are far too angry to be
out there in the real world.
- You!
- Of course it's me.
I got to say, you hunters don't
exactly live up to your rep.
I mean, Martin's a
wreck. He's harmless.
And you and your
brother come in here,
talking tough about killing monsters?
Kind of made you easy to spot.
Then all it took was a touch...
and you were mine.
Oh, I love it in here.
This place is my own
personal five-star restaurant.
Mmm.
Crazy brains... they get soaked
in dopamine and adrenaline
and just all sorts of
hormones and chemicals
that make them delicious.
And the crazier they are,
the better they taste.
You did this to me!
Well... I helped.
But that rage?
No, no, no, no. That's all you.
I don't make crazy. I just
crank up what's already there.
You build your own hell.
But I give you the legos.
And when you're ripe...
I make all of your problems disappear.
You get away from him!
Do you really think this is
gonna end well for you, kiddo?
No.
But I'm crazy, so what the hell.
Aaaah!
Are you still crazy?
Not any more than usual.
- We got to get out of here.
- Yeah.
Well, looks like Tom Cruise
was right, shrinks suck.
What are you doing?
Sam, are you okay?
No.
No, the wraith... what about her?
She was right.
No, she wasn't. She's dead, okay?
Let's hit the road. I need a drink Or 12.
Most of the time I can hide it,
But... I am angry.
I'm mad at everything.
I used to be mad at you and dad,
Then Lilith, now it's Lucifer.
A-and I make excuses. I blame,
Ruby or the demon blood.
But it's not their fault.
It's not them. It's me.
It's inside me.
I am mad all the time...
and I don't know why.
Stop.
Stop it.
So what if you are?
What are you gonna do,
take a leave of absence?
You gonna say yes to Lucifer?
What?
No, of course not. I...
Exactly.
And that's exactly
what you're gonna do.
You're gonna take all that crap,
and you're gonna bury it.
You're gonna forget about it...
Because that's how we keep going.
That's how we don't
end up like Martin!
Are you with me?
Come on, man.
I'm with you.
Good.
Let's get the hell out of here.
sync by honeybunny
Sync by sh84adi
www.addic7ed.com
Edited by Scooby