Dad wants us to pick up
where he left off...
saving people,
hunting things.
The family business.
THEN
I have these nightmares,
and sometimes they come true.
Come again ?
I dreamt about Jessica's death
before it happened.
A vision.
Started out as nightmares.
Then he started having them
while he was awake.
The closer I get to anything involving
the demon, the stronger the visions get.
The demon said he had plans
for me and the children like me.
Do you have any idea
what he meant by that ?
No, I don't.
Max, your abilities...
they started six,seven months ago, right ?
How'd you know that ?
'Cause that's when
my abilities started.
The same thing
killed our mothers.
You and I are chosen.
- For what ?
- I don't know.
The thing I don't get is why.
I guess because we're so alike ?
Max is nothing like you.
Sam, Max is a monster.
He's already killed two people.
Now he's gunning for a third.
Did he say anything
to you ?
No.
Nothing.
NOW
Hello ? Yeah.
All right.
- Afternoon, Dennis.
- Hey, Doc.
I'd like to look at a gun.
Yeah, right, Doc.
Seriously ?
That one.
Okay.
That's a turkey hunter.
12-gauge. Pump-action.
Don't leave enough
turkey behind, if you ask me.
What, uh, what sort of shells
does it use ?
Right here.
I'm taking the boys up to the
cabin this weekend, if you're, uh...
I mean, if you think you might
like to take up the sport.
Thanks, but no.
You know guns make me nervous.
Always have.
This one goes in here, right ?
Whoa. Doc !  No, no, you can't load a weapon
on the premises. It's illegal !
- It's okay, Dennis.
- No, no.
It's okay, Dennis.
It's all gonna be...
...okay.
Doc !
What's going on ?
No, no, it's okay.
It's okay.
It's all gonna be...okay.
Sam, come on, zip it up.
Let's hit the...
road.
What ?
-=www.ydy.com/bbs=-
proudly presents
sync:YTET- cflily
-=www.ydy.com/bbs=-
SUPERNATURAL
Season 02 Episode 05
I don't know, man.
Why don't we just chill out, think about this ?
What's there to think about ?
Just don't know if going to the roadhouse
is the smartest idea.
Dean, it's another premonition.
I know it.
This is gonna happen, and ash can tell us where.
Plus it could have some connection with the demon.
- My visions always do.
- That's my point.
There's gonna be hunters there.
I don't know if...
if going in and announcing
that you're some supernatural freak
with a demonic connection
is the best thing, okay ?
So I'm a freak now ?
You've always been a freak.
SIMON SAID
Damn, little lady,
that was my room money.
Then I guess you're taking
a truck nap tonight.
I'd have checked the high scores
before you put your money down.
Went and got yourself
hustled, Ed.
Just can't stay away, huh ?
Yeah, looks like.
How you doing, Jo ?
- Where's ash ?
- In his back room.
- Great.
- And I'm fine.
Sorry. He's we're kind of
on a bit of a timetable.
Ash ?
The conditions that led
to the sharpsville tragedy...
hey, Ash ?
Hey, Dr. Badass ?
Sam. Dean.
Sam and Dean.
Hey, Ash,
um, we need your help.
Hell, then,
guess I need my pants.
BLUERIDGE
So, I got a match. It's the logo
for the blue ridge bus lines.
Guthrie, Oklahoma.
Okay. Do me a favor. Check guthrie for any
demonic signs or omens or anything like that.
You think the demon
is there ?
Yeah. Maybe.
- Why would you think that ?
- Just check it, all right ?
No, sir, nothing.
No demon.
All right.
Try something else for me.
Search guthrie for a house fire.
It would be 1983.
Fire's origin would be a baby's nursery,
night of the kid's 6-month birthday.
Okay, now, that is just weird, man.
Why the hell would I be looking for that ?
'Cause there's a pbr
in it for you.
Give me 15 minutes.
What ?
- R.E.O. Speedwagon ?
- Damn right, R.E.O.
Kevin Cronin sings it
from the heart.
He sings it from the hair.
There's a difference.
That profile you've got Ash
looking for ?
Your mom died the same way,
didn't she...
the fire in sam's nursery ?
- Look, Jo, it's kind of a family thing.
- I could help.
I'm sure you could, but we got to handle
this one ourselves.
Besides, if I ran off with you,
think your mother might kill me.
You're afraid of my mother ?
I think so.
We have a match.
We got to go.
All right, Jo, see you later.
And even as I wander
I'm keeping you in sight
you're a candle in the window
on a cold, dark winter's night
and I'm getting closer
than I ever thought
I mi-ight
you're kidding, right ?
I heard the song somewhere. I can't get it
out of my head. I don't know, man. What do you got ?
Andrew Gallagher.
Born in '83, like me.
Lost his mother in a nursery fire
exactly six months later,
also like me.
You think the demon
killed his mom ?
Sure looks like it.
How did you know
to look for this guy ?
Every premonition I've had,
if they're not about the demon,
they're about the other kids
the demon visited.
Like Max Miller.
Remember him ?
Yeah, but Max Miller
was a basic little psycho.
Point is he was killing people, and I was having
the same type of visions about him.
And now it could be happening all over again
with this gallagher guy.
- How do we find him ?
- I don't know.
No current address,
no current employment.
Still owes money on all his bills...
phone, credit, utilities.
Collection agency flags ?
Not in the system.
They just let him take a walk ?
Seems like it.
There's a work address
from his last w-2 about a year ago.
Let's start there.
You won't get anything out of Andy, guys.
I'm sorry, but they never do.
"They" ?
You're debt collectors, right ?
Once in a while,
they come by.
I don't know what andy says to them,
but they never come back.
Actually,we're lawyers
representing his great-aunt Lita.
She passed god rest her soul...
but left andy a sizable estate.
Yeah. So, are you
a friend of his ?
I used to be, yeah.
I don't see much of andy anymore.
- Andy ?  Andy kicks ass, man.
- Is that right ?
Yeah.
Andy can get you into anything.
He even got me backstage
at aerosmith once. It was beautiful, Bro.
How about busing a table
or two, Webber ?
Yeah, you bet, boss.
Look, if you want to find him,
try orchard street.
Just look for a van
with the barbarian queen painted on the side.
Barbarian Queen.
She's riding a polar bear.
It's kind of hard to miss.
I'm sorry. I'm starting to like this dude.
That van is sweet.
- What's wrong ?
- Nothing.
Sam, you look like
you're sucking on a lemon.
This Andrew Gallagher...
he's the second guy like this we've found, Dean.
Demon came to them when they were kids.
Now they're killing people.
We don't know what Andrew Gallagher is.
Could be innocent.
My visions haven't
been wrong yet.
What's your point ?
- My point is I'm one of them.
- No, you're not.
Dean, the demon said he had plans for me
and children like me.
Yeah ?
Maybe this is his plan.
Maybe we're all a bunch of psychic freaks.
Maybe we're all supposed
to be...
- killers ?
- Yeah.
So the demon wants you out
there, killing with your minds ?
Give me a break.
You're not a murderer, Sam !
You don't have it
in your bones.
No ?
Last I checked,
I kill all kinds of things.
Those things
were asking for it.
There's a difference.
Got him.
that's him, that older guy.
He's the shooter.
Well, you keep on him.
I'll stick with Andy.
- Hey !
- Hey.
- This is a cherry ride.
- Yeah. Thanks.
Man,you know, '67...
impala's best year, if you ask me.
This is a serious classic.
You know, I just rebuilt her, too.
Can't let a car like this one go.
Damn straight.
- Hey. Could I have it ?
- Sure, man.
Sweet.
Hop right in there.
There you go. Very nice.
- Take it easy.
- All right.
Hello ?
Yeah.
Dean,
Andy's got the impala !
I know ! He just sort of asked me for it,
and I let him take it.
You what ?
He full-on obi-wan'd me.
It's mind control, man.
I kept him
out of the gun store.
I thought he was okay.
I thought he was past it.
At least...
I should've
stayed with him.
Andy !
What's up, dog ?
Andy.
What are you doing here ?
D-dr. Jennings.
He's dead.
Oh, no, I-I'm sorry.
I don't know.
I-I...
I just I was upset,
and I wanted to see you.
Well, I'm glad you did.
I,um...
I missed you.
Oh, you know what ?  Some guys were here
this morning, looking for you.
What guys ?
Thank god !
I'm sorry, baby.
I'll never leave you again.
At least he left
the keys in it.
Yeah.
Real samaritan, this guy.
It looks like he can't work his mojo just by
twitching his nose. He's got to use verbal commands.
The doctor had just gotten off his cellphone
when he stepped in front of that bus.
Andy must've called him
or something.
- I don't know. Maybe.
- Beg your pardon ?
I just don't know
if he's our guy, Sam.
You had O.J. Convicted before he got out
of his bronco,and you have doubts about this ?
He doesn't seem like
the stone-cold killer type. That's all.
And O.J. Was guilty.
Either way,how are we gonna
track this guy down ?
Not a problem.
Not exactly
an inconspicuous ride.
Let's have a look.
Oh, come on.
This is this is magnificent.
That's what this is.
Not exactly a serial killer's
lair, though.
There's no clown paintings
on the walls
or scissors stuck
in victims' photos.
I like the tiger.
Hegel ? Kant ?
Wittgenstein ?
That's some pretty heavy reading, Dean.
Yeah, and,uh...
Moby Dick's bong.
You know, one day I'd love
to just sit down
and eat something that
I didn't have to microwave at a minimart.
What I don't get is the motive.
The doctor was squeaky clean.
Why would andy waste him ?
If it is Andy.
- Dude, enough.
- Why ?
The doctor was mind-controlled
in front of a bus.
Andy just happens to have
the power of mind control. You do the math.
I don't think the guy
has it in him.
How the hell
would you know ?
Why are you bending over
backwards defending him ?
'Cause you're not right
about this.
About Andy ?
Hey ! You think
I haven't seen you two ?
Why are you following me ?
Well, we're lawyers.
A relative of yours has...
- tell the truth !
- That's what...
- we hunt demons.
- What ?
Demons and spirits. Things your worst nightmares
wouldn't even touch.
- Sam's my brother.
- Dean, shut up.
I'm trying. He's psychic,like you.
Well, not really like you.
He thinks you're a murderer,
and he's afraid he's gonna become one himself
cause you're all part of something that's terrible.
I hope to hell that he's wrong,
but I'm starting to get scared he might be right.
Okay, you know what ?
Just leave me alone.
All right ?
What are you doing ?
Look, I-I said, leave me alone.
Get out of here !
Just start driving and never stop !
Doesn't seem to work
on me, Andy.
What ?
You can make people do things,
can't you ?
You can tell them
what to think.
That's crazy.
All started a year ago,
didn't it ?
After you turned 22. Little stuff at first,
then you got better at controlling it.
How do you know all this ?
'Cause the same thing happened to me, Andy.
My mom died in a fire, too.
I have abilities, too.
You see, we're connected,
you and me.
Just...
just get out of here !
Why did you tell the doctor
to walk in front of a bus ?
What ?
- Why did you kill him ?
- I didn't.
Hello ?
Sure.
I can do that.
Hey !
- Lady,what are you doing ?!
- It's gonna be okay.
Lady, no. No !
Sam ?  What is it ?
I didn't do anything
to him.
A woman.
A woman burning alive.
What else you get ?
A gas station.
A woman is gonna kill herself.
What does he mean,
"going to" ?
Shut up.
She gets triggered by a call
on her cell.
- When ?
- I don't know.
As long as we keep our eyes
on this son of a bitch, he can't hurt her.
- I didn't hurt anybody !
- Yeah, not yet.
Go.
No. Not you.
You're staying here
with me.
Hey, it's me. She's dead.
Burned up,just like you said.
When ?
Minutes before I got here.
The smell hasn't even cleared.
What's up with your visions ?
This wasn't even a head start.
I can't control them.
I don't know what the hell is going on.
You were with andy when this whole
thing went down, so it can't be him.
It's got to be
somebody else.
That doesn't make any sense.
What else is new ? I'll dig around here,
see what else I can find.
You get these premonitions
of people about to die ?
That's impossible.
A lot of people would say the same
thing about what you do.
- Death visions ?
- Yeah.
Dude, that sucks.
When I got my mind thing,
it was like a gift.
It was like I won
the lotto.
But you still live
in a van.
I don't get it. You could have anything
you ever wanted.
Yeah, but I-I got
everything I need.
So you're really
not a killer, huh ?
That's what I've been trying
to tell you.
That's good.
That means there's hope
for both of us.
Victim's name
was Holly Beckett. 41. Single.
- Who is she ?
- Never heard of her.
I called ash on the way over.
He came up with a little something.
Apparently Holly Beckett gave
birth when she was 18 years old,back in 1983...
same day you were born, Andy.
Andy, were you adopted ?
Well, yeah.
You were ?
And you neglected to mention that ?
It never really came up.
I mean, I never knew my birth parents,
and,like you said,
my adopted mom died when I was a baby.
Do you think this Holly woman
could actually be...
I don't know. Tried to get a copy of the birth
records, but they're sealed in the county office.
Well, screw that.
Probably shouldn't have
let you kids in here.
No. It'll all be fine,
all right ?
Just go get a cup of coffee,
These aren't
the droids you're looking for.
Awesome.
- I got it.
- Yeah ?
Yeah.
Andy, it's true.
Holly Beckett
was your birth mother.
Does anyone have a vicodin ?
Dr. Jennings
was her doctor, too.
I mean,
he oversaw the adoption.
You have a solid connection
to both of them.
- Yeah, but I didn't kill them.
- We believe you.
- Yeah.
- But, uh, who did ?
I think I got
a pretty good guess.
Holly Beckett gave birth
to twins.
I have an evil twin.
Holly put you and your brother
up for adoption.
And you went to the gallagher
family, obviously,
and your brother went to
the weems family from upstate.
Andy, how you doing ?
Still with us ?
Um...what was
my brother's name ?
Here.
Um, Ansem Weems ?
- He's got a local address.
- He lives here ?
Let's get a look at him.
Got his picture coming over
from the dmv right now.
Hate to kick you
while you're freaked.
Take a look at that.
- Hey, Trace ?
- Yeah ?
You and Andy, you guys went together
for a while, didn't you ?
Yeah, Webber, why ?
I don't know. Just wondering.
I was wondering how you felt about him these days.
I mean, I've seen you guys together.
It seems like there's still something there.
Were you guys ever,
like,serious ?
Um...no.
Come on, Trace.
Tell the truth.
All right, Andy, tell us everything you know
about this guy.
I don't know much. Webber shows up one day
like eight months ago,
acting like he's my best friend
in the world.
He's kind of weird, like trying
too hard,you know ?
He must've known you guys
are twins.
Why did he change his name ?
Why not tell you the truth ?
Sam ?
- Sam ?
- Oh, god !
Sam ?!
Sam !
Hey. Hey !
I take my ladies here.
They like it.
Well, I mean, I like it,
so, of course, they do, too.
Please.
I just want to go home.
Stop crying.
Hey.
I get it.
I see what you see in Andy.
I mean,he's a genius.
The books he reads...
he's gonna be a great man
someday.
But he is my family,
not yours.
You can't have him.
You're not gonna have anything
after tonight.
Dean,
you should stay back.
No argument here. I had my head screwed with
enough for one day.
- I'm coming with you.
- Andy...
that's tracy out there,
and I'm coming.
Okay.
Ch-chslower.
Tracy...
I want you to listen to me
very carefully, okay ?
When we're done here...
...I want you to head over
to the edge of that dam, okay ?
Okay.
And when you get there...
...you're gonna think
you can fly.
And you're just
gonna step right off.
You you can fly, can't you ?
Yeah.
I think so.
You might get scared,
but I want you to say
that it's okay.
Just tell yourself,
"everything is okay."
Get out of the car !
Now !
You really don't want
to do this.
Trace, give me your hand.
Come here, come here.
I couldn't control myself.
Hey ! Don't move.
Don't move !
- No ! No !
- I will kill you !
Andy ! Hey, hey, hey ! No !
No ! I'll handle this !
I will kill you !
Andy, listen to me !
Just listen to me !
Tracy, stop !
I said, stop it !
- How did you do that ?
- Practice, Bro.
If you just practiced,
you would know.
Sometimes...
you don't need to use your words.
If you have to,
all you need is this.
Sometimes the headache
is worth it.
You twisted
son of a bitch !
Back off, Andy !
Or tracy is gonna do a little flying.
Aren't you, Trace ?
I'm stronger than you.
I can do it.
Okay, okay. Okay.
All right,just...
please don't hurt her.
Don't be mad at me, okay ?
I know. It's all wrong.
I didn't mean for this
to happen. It's just...
Tracy...
she's trying
to come between us.
- You're insane.
- She's garbage !
Man, they all are !
We can push them.
We can make them do whatever we want !
Are you really...
are you really this stupid ? Is it...
you learn you got a twin,
you call him up,
you go out for a drink.
You don't start
killing people !
I wanted to tell you
for so long, Bro, but...
he didn't let me.
He said I had to wait until the time...
- who ?
- The man with the yellow eyes.
What are you talking about ?
He came to me...
in my dream.
He said I was special.
He told me he's got
big plans for me.
Wait till you see
what's in store, Andy, for both of us.
See, he's the one who told me
that I had a brother, a twin.
Why did you kill
our mother ?
And why Dr. Jennings ?
Because they split us up !
They ruined our lives,
Andy !
We could've been together
this whole time
instead of alone.
I couldn't let them do that.
I couldn't let them get away with that.
No.
I see you.
Bye-bye.
*************
And you all saw it happen.
Yeah.
We did.
Look at him.
He's getting better at it.
She won't even
look at me.
Yeah,
she's pretty shaken up.
No,it's...
this is different.
This is...
I never used my mind thing
on her before, before last night.
She's scared of me now.
Andy, I hate to do this,
but, um...
we have to get out of here.
Here.
I wrote down my cell.
You don't have to be alone in this, all right ?
If anything comes up, you can call me up.
Wh-what am I supposed
to do now ?
You be good, Andy...
or we'll be back.
Looks like I was right.
- About what ?
- Andy.
He's a killer after all.
No, he's a hero. He saved his girlfriend's life.
He saved my life.
Bottom line,
last night he wasted somebody.
Yeah, but he's not
a foaming-at-the-mouth psycho.
He was just...
he was pushed into that.
Webber was pushed, too,
in his own way.
Max Miller was pushed.
Hell,I was pushed by Jessica's death.
What's your point, Sam ?
Right circumstances,
everyone is capable of murder everyone.
Maybe that's what the demon is doing...
pushing us, finding ways to break us.
We don't know what the demon
wants, okay ?
Quit worrying about it.
You know, I heard you before,dean,
when andy made you tell the truth.
You're just as scared
of this as I am.
That was mind control ! It's like being roofied
man. That doesn't count.
- No,I-I'm calling do-over.
- What are you, 7 ?
Doesn't matter. We just got to keep doing
what we're doing,
find that evil son of a bitch,
and kill it.
Yeah. I guess.
Hello ?
Ellen.
What's going on ?
Yeah. We'll be right there.
Jo ?
Go pull up
another case of beer.
- Mom...
- now. Please ?
So, you, uh, you want to tell me
about this last hunt of yours ?
- Nope.
- Not really.
No offense.
Just kind of a family thing.
Not anymore.
I got this stuff from ash.
Andrew gallagher's house burned down on
his 6-month birthday, just like your house.
You think it was the demon both times, don't you ?
You think it went after Gallagher's family ?
- Yeah, we think so.
- Sam.
- Why ?
- None of your business.
You mind your tongue
with me,boy.
This isn't just your war.
This is war.
Something big and bad is coming, and it's
coming fast, and their side holds all the cards.
Now, at best, all we got is us...
together.
No secrets or half-truths here.
There are people
out there
like Andy Gallagher...
like me...
and, um...
we all have some kind
of ability.
- Ability ?
- Yeah.
A psychic ability.
Me, I have, um...
I have visions...
premonitions. I don't know.
It's different for everybody.
The demon said he had plans
for people like us.
What kind of plans ?
We don't really
know for sure.
These people out there,
these psychics, are they dangerous ?
No.
Not all of them.
But some are.
Some are very dangerous.
How many ?
We've been able to track
a clear pattern so far.
They've all had house fires
on the night of the kid's 6-month birthday.
That's not true.
What ?
Webber or ansem weems
or whatever his name is...
I looked at his files,
and there was no house fire.
There's nothing
out of the ordinary.
Which breaks pattern.
So if there's any others like him,
there would be nothing
in the system,
no way to track them
all down.
And so who knows how many
of them are really out there ?
- Jo, honey ?
- Yeah ?
You better break out
the whiskey instead.
-=www.ydy.com/bbs=-
proudly presents
sync:YTET-cflily
-=www.ydy.com/bbs=-
SUPERNATURAL
Season 02 Episode 05