Zachariah:
I was on the fast track once.
Employee of the month,
every month. Forever.
And then they assigned me you.
I can't close the
deal on a couple
of pathetic flannel wearing maggots.
Everybody's laughing at me.
We're John Winchesters sons.
I've got brothers?
Adam doesn't have to be cursed.
Sam: He's a Winchester.
He's already cursed.
Sam: You're not Adam.
You've never been Adam.
You're a ghoul.
You can't kill the devil
and you're losing faith
in yourself, your brother.
God was your last hope.
Are you gonna do
something stupid?
Like what?
Like Michael stupid.
Whatever you're thinking
of doing, don't do it.
I have to.
[big-band music plays]
Let me guess.
Pink-slipped?
That obvious, huh?
[chuckles]
Takes one to know one.
"Outsourcing."
What was your crime
against humanity?
[chuckles]
Deal of the millennium.
Couldn't even get the one
simple "yes" I needed.
Got to nail that
bottom line, right?
Hear that.
All they care about
upstairs, ain't it?
Results, results, results.
They don't know.
They're not down on
the ground, in the mud,
Nose to nose with all
you pig-filthy humans.
Am I right?
Absolutely... filthy what?
I mean, whatever happened
to personal loyalty?
How long have I worked
for these guys?
Five millennia? Six?
Seems like it, don't it?
Damn straight, it does.
Two more.
Zach.
Stuart.
What are you gonna do next, Stuart?
Hell, I don't know.
Maybe something to
do with the Internet.
Yeah?
[rumbling]
Whoa.
Earthquake?
No.
My boss.
[high-pitched whine]
Ah!
Aah!
Aaah!
[both screaming]
Go ahead...
[chuckles]
get it over with.
I'm ready.
[screaming continues]
Wait
What?
Yes! Anything, of course.
Just... just put me back in.
You won't regret it.
Thank you.
Thank you!
[rumbling, whining stop]
[sighs]
Ah.
Back in business, boys!
"Oh when the saints go marching in"
"Oh when the saints..."
Season 5 Episode 18
"Point of No Return"
Sending someone
a candy-gram?
How'd you find me?
You're gonna kill
yourself, right?
It's not too hard to figure out
the stops on the farewell tour.
How's Lisa doing, anyways?
I'm not gonna kill myself.
No?
So, Michael's not about
to make you his Muppet?
What the hell, man?
This is how it ends?
You just... walk out?
Yeah, I guess.
How could you do that?
How could I?
All you've ever done
is run away!
And I was wrong every
single time I did.
[exhales sharply]
Just... please...
not now.
Bobby is working
on something.
Oh, really... what?
You got nothing,
and you know it.
[sighs]
You know I
have to stop you.
[sniffs]
Yeah, well, you can try.
But just remember,
you're not all hopped up
on demon blood this time.
Yeah, I know...
[sighing]
but I brought help.
Yeah, no,
this is good, really.
Eight months of turned pages
and screwed pooches,
but tonight... tonight's
when the magic happens.
You ain't helping.
Yeah, well, why don't you let me
get out of your hair, then?
What the hell
happened to you?
Reality happened.
Nuclear's the only option
we have left.
Michael can ice the devil,
save a boatload of people.
But not all of them.
We got to think
of something else.
Yeah, well, that's
easy for you to say.
But if Lucifer burns
this mother down
and I could have done
something about it,
guess what... that's on me.
You can't give up, son.
[scoffs]
You're not my father.
And you ain't in my shoes.
What is that?
That's the round I mean
to put through my skull.
Every morning,
I look at it,
and I think...
"maybe today's the day
I flip the lights out."
But I don't do it.
I never do it.
You know why?
Because I promised you
I wouldn't give up!
[groans softly]
Cass, you okay?
No.
What's wrong?
Somethings happening.
Where?
[both grunting]
[grunting]
I'm gonna get a beer.
Do you mind?
Help.
Bobby: Boys!
Who is it?
That's our brother.
Wait a minute.
Your brother... Adam?
Cass, what the hell?
Angels.
Angels... why?
I know one thing
for sure.
We need to hide him now.
[groans]
[panting]
- Where am I?
- Sam: It's okay.
Just relax.
You're safe.
Who the hell are you?
You're gonna find this a little...
a lot crazy, but we're
actually your brothers.
It's the truth.
John Winchesters our father, too.
See, I'm Sam.
Yeah, and I'm sure
that's Dean.
I know who you are.
- How?
- They warned me about you.
- Who did?
- The angels.
Now, where the hell
is Zachariah?!
So, why don't you just
tell us everything?
Start from the beginning.
Well, I was dead
and in heaven...
except it... it, uh,
kind of looked like my prom.
And I was making
out with this girl.
Her... her name
was Kristin McGee.
Yeah, that sounds like heaven.
Did you get to third base?
[clears throat]
Just, uh... just keep going.
Well, these... these angels,
they popped out of nowhere,
and they tell me
that I-I'm chosen.
For what?
To save the world.
How you gonna do that?
Oh, me and some archangel
are gonna kill the devil.
What archangel?
Michael.
I'm his, uh, sword
or vessel or something.
I don't know
[chuckles]
Well, that's insane.
Not necessarily.
How do you mean?
Maybe they're moving
on from you, Dean.
Well, that doesn't make sense.
He's John Winchesters bloodline,
Sam's brother.
It's not perfect,
but it's possible.
You got to be kidding me.
Why would they do this?
Maybe they're desperate.
Maybe they've
wrongly assumed
Dean would be brave enough
to withstand them.
All right, you know what?
Blow me, Cass.
Look. No way.
After everything
that's happened. [chuckles]
All that crap
about destiny,
suddenly the angels
have a plan "B"?
Does that smell right to anybody?
You know, this has been
a really moving family reunion,
but, uh,
I got a thing, so...
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
No, no, no. Sit down.
Just listen, okay?
Please.
It's unbelievable.
Now, Adam...
The angels
are lying to you.
They're full of crap.
Yeah, I don't think so.
Really? [scoffs] why not?
Um, 'cause they're angels.
They tell you they were gonna
roast half the planet?
They said the fight might
get pretty hairy,
but it is the devil, right?
So, we got to stop him.
Yeah, but there's
another way.
Adam: Great. What is it?
Well, we're working
on the power of love.
- How's that going?
- Not good.
[sighs]
Look, Adam...
you don't know me from a hole
in the wall, I know...
but I'm begging you.
Please, just trust me.
Give me some time.
Give me one good reason.
Because we're blood.
You got no right
to say that to me.
You're still John's boy.
No, John Winchester
was some guy
who took me to a
baseball game once a year.
I don't have a dad.
So, we may be blood,
but we are not family.
My mom is my family...
and if I do my job,
I get to see her again.
So, no offense, but she's the
one I give a rat's ass about,
not you.
Fair enough.
But if you have one good memory
of dad... just one...
then you'll give us
a little more time.
Please.
[sighs]
Sam:
Going somewhere?
Out for a... beer.
Great, we got beer.
Have a seat.
Great.
[sighs]
You know, you pitch this whole
dewy-eyed romance thing...
but the truth is,
I'm on lock-down, aren't I?
[sighs]
Adam...
[clears throat]
you may not believe it,
but dad was trying
to protect you...
keeping you from all this.
Yeah, well, I guess
the monster that ate me
didn't get that memo.
You remember that?
Oh, yeah.
Still, trust me.
The one thing worse
than seeing dad once a year...
was seeing him all year.
Do you know how full
of crap you are?
- What?
- Really.
You see, it was me and
it was my mom, that's it.
She worked the graveyard
shift at the hospital.
I cooked my own dinners,
I put myself to bed.
So, you can say whatever
you want about our dad,
but the truth is,
I would have taken anything.
All right?
[exhales sharply]
Look, if we had known
we had a brother...
Well, you didn't, so...
We would have found you.
Look, I can't
change the past.
I wish I could.
But from here on out...
What...
we gonna hop in
the family truckster?
Pop on down
to Wally world?
[scoffs]
Tell you one thing...
attitude like that,
you'd fit right in around here.
Well, Cass, not for nothing...
but the last person
who looked at me like that...
I got laid.
Uh, why don't you, uh,
go keep an eye on Adam?
Is this really necessary?
Well [chuckles] I mean,
we got our hands full, Dean...
a houseful of flight risks.
I'm not letting him do it.
- Who, Adam?
- No, I'm... I'm not, either.
No, you're not getting me.
Oh, no, no,
I "get" you perfectly.
But I'm not letting you do it either.
That kid's not taking a bullet for me.
- Dean...
- I'm serious.
I mean, think about how many
people we've gotten killed, Sam.
Mom, dad...
Jess, Jo, Ellen...
should I keep going?
It's not like
we pulled the trigger.
We might as well have.
I'm tired, man.
I'm tired of fighting
who I'm supposed to be.
Well, do you think maybe
you could take a half a second
and stop trying to sacrifice
yourself for a change?
Maybe we could actually
stick together?
I don't think so.
Why not?
Dean, seriously.
Tell me... I-I want to know.
I just...
I-I don't believe.
In what?
In you.
I mean, I don't...
I don't know whether
it's gonna be demon blood
or some other demon
chick or what, but...
I do know they're gonna
find a way to turn you.
So, you're saying
I'm not strong enough.
You're angry... you're self-righteous.
Lucifer's gonna wear you
to the prom, man.
It's just a matter of time.
Don't say that to me...
not you...
of all people.
I don't want to...
but it's the truth.
And when Satan takes you over,
there's got to be
somebody there to fight him,
and it ain't gonna be that kid.
[chuckles]
So, it's got to be me.
[door creaks open]
[door slams, locks]
How's he doing?
[exhales sharply]
How you doing?
[sighs]
[glass shatters]
Dean?
Cass.
Where's Cass?
Blown to Oz.
Look, I'll get Dean.
He couldn't have
gone too far.
- Just watch Adam.
- How?
You may have noticed, he's got
a slight height advantage.
Then cuff him to your chair.
I don't know.
Just watch him.
[door opens]
[door closes]
Your mom's not coming, you know.
[sighs]
This is the park
where your mom took you
on her day off, right?
She's not coming...
not yet.
But she will... soon.
You're Zachariah, right?
I am.
You weren't where you
were supposed to be, kid.
Yeah, I know.
Can't quite zero in
on you, either.
So, let me take
a wild guess...
you're with Sam and Dean?
Yeah.
Didn't we tell you
about them?
So, you know you can't
trust them, right?
You know Sam
and Dean Winchester
are psychotically, irrationally,
erotically codependent
on each other, right?
[sighing]
I don't know.
They said a few things about you.
Really?
Trust me, kid.
When the heat gets hot,
they're not gonna give
a flying crap about you.
Hell, they'd rather
save each other's sweet bacon
than save the planet.
They're not your family.
Understand?
Now...
you want to see
your mom again or not?
The end is nigh!
The apocalypse is upon us!
The angels talk to me,
and they asked me
to talk to you!
- The apocalypse...
- Hey!
I'm Dean Winchester.
Do you know who I am?
Dear God
I'll take that as a yes.
Listen, I need you to pray
to your angel buddies
and let them know
that I'm here.
Our father,
who art in heaven.
Hallowed be thy name.
Castiel:
You pray too loud.
[grunts]
What, are you crazy?!
I rebelled for this?!
[both grunting]
So that you could
surrender to them?
Cass! Please!
I gave everything for you.
And this is what
you give to me.
[coughing]
Do it.
Just do it!
[spluttering]
Bobby, what do you mean,
"Adam is gone"?
Should I say it in Spanish?
He's gone how?
What the hell, Bobby?!
Watch your tone, boy
He was right in front of me,
and he disappeared
into thin air.
Because the angels took him.
What the hell
happened to him?
Me.
What do you mean,
the angels took Adam?
You branded his ribs, didn't you?
Yes. Adam must have tipped them.
- How?
- I don't know.
Maybe in a dream.
Well, where would they
have taken him?
I see you and your brother
share the same refined palate.
Ah.
So, uh...
we ready?
For what?
What do you mean,
for what? For Michael.
Oh.
Right...
about that.
Look, this is never easy,
but I'm afraid...
we've had to terminate
your position at this time.
Excuse me?
Hey, don't get me wrong,
you've been a hell of a sport,
really... good stuff.
But the thing is,
you're not so much
the "chosen one" as you are...
a clammy scrap of bait.
No, but what about the
stuff that you said?
I'm supposed to fight the devil.
Mm, not so much.
Hey, if it's
any consolation,
you happen to be the
illegitimate half brother
of the guy we do care about.
That's not bad, is it?
So, you lied...
about everything.
We didn't lie.
We just avoided certain truths
to manipulate you.
Oh, you son of a bitch.
Hey, how do you think I feel?
I'm the one that's got to put up
with that dumb, slack-jawed
look on your face.
Kid, we didn't
have a choice.
The Winchesters
got one blind spot,
and it's family.
See, Sam and Dean, they're gonna
put aside their differences...
and they're gonna
come get you-
and that is gonna put Dean
right... here.
Right where I need him.
This is the night, kid!
Our night.
Michael's seen it.
The tumblers finally
click into place
and it's all
because of you.
And me. But who's keeping score?
Yeah, I'm not gonna
let you do this.
Cool your jets, Corky.
Sit down.
We're doing it together.
Plus, you still
get your severance.
You still get
to see your mom, okay?
Why should I believe you?
You know what?
I keep hearing this.
But what I want to
be hearing is this...
[vomits]
Yeah.
[vomiting]
That's better.
Sam:
How you feeling?
[groans]
Word to the wise...
don't piss off
the nerd angels.
So, how's it going?
Adam's gone.
The angels have him.
Where?
The room where they took you.
You sure?
Cass did a recon.
And?
And the place is
crawling with mooks...
pretty much a no-shot-in-hell,
hail-Mary kind of thing.
Ah, so the usual.
What are you gonna do?
For starters...
I'm bringing you with.
Excuse me?
There are too many of them.
We can't do it alone,
and, uh, you're pretty much
the only game in town.
Isn't that a bad idea?
Cass and Bobby think so.
I'm not so sure.
Well, they're right.
Because either it's a trap
to get me there,
to make me say yes...
or it's not a trap
and I'm gonna say yes anyway.
And I will.
I'll do it... fair warning.
No, you won't.
When push shoves,
you'll make the right call.
You know, if
tables were turned...
I'd let you rot in here.
Hell, I have
let you rot in here.
[scoffs]
[inhales sharply]
Yeah, well...
I guess I'm not that smart.
I-I don't get it... Sam,
why are you doing this?
Because...
you're still
my big brother.
Where the hell are we?
Van Nuys, California.
Where's the beautiful room?
In there.
The beautiful room is in
an abandoned muffler factory
in van Nuys, California?
Where'd you think it was?
I-I don't know... Jupiter?
A blade of grass...
not van Nuys.
Tell me again why
you don't just grab Adam
and shazam the hell
out of there?
Because there are at least
five angels in there.
- So? You're fast.
- They're faster.
I'll clear them out.
You two grab the boy.
This is our only chance.
Whoa, whoa, wait. You're gonna
take on five angels?
Yes.
Isn't that suicide?
Maybe it is.
But then I won't
have to watch you fail.
I'm sorry, Dean.
I don't have the same faith
in you that Sam does.
What the hell are
you gonna do with that?
[water dripping]
[grunts]
[groaning]
[panting]
What are you waiting for?
Come on.
Adam, hey. Hey.
You came for me.
You're family.
Dean, it's a trap.
I figured.
Dean, please. Did you really
think it would be that easy?
Did you?
Sam!
You know what I've learned
from this experience, Dean?
Patience.
Adam?
Let him go,
you son of a bitch.
I mean, I thought
I was downsized for sure,
and for us, a firing...
pretty damn literal.
[chuckles]
But I should have
trusted the boss man.
It's all playing out
like he said...
You, me... your
hemorrhaging brothers.
[vomiting]
You're finally ready, right?
You see things our way.
You know there's
no other choice.
There's never
been a choice.
Stop it.
Stop it right now!
In exchange for what?
Damn it, Zachariah.
[gagging]
Stop it, please.
[panting]
I'll do it.
I'm sorry, what was that?
Okay, yes.
The answer is yes.
Dean!
Do you hear me?
[voice breaking]
Call Michael down, you bastard!
[panting]
How do I know
you're not lying?
Do I look like I'm lying?
[rumbling]
He's coming.
Of course, I have a few conditions.
What?
A few people whose safety
you have to guarantee
before I say yes.
Sure, fine.
Make a list.
But most of all...
Michael can't have me
until he disintegrates you.
What did you say?
I said...
before Michael gets one piece
of this sweet ass...
he has to turn you
into a piece of charcoal.
[chuckles nervously]
You really think Michael's
gonna go for that?
Who's more important
to him now?
You...
or me?
You listen to me.
You are nothing but a maggot
inside a worm's ass.
Do you know who I am...
after I deliver you to Michael?
Expendable.
[chuckles]
Michael's not gonna kill me.
Maybe not.
But I am.
[rumbling increases]
[glass shattering]
- Can you walk?
- Yeah.
Okay, come on.
Come on, move it!
No!
Dean, help!
Come on, help me.
[grunts] Ah.
Dean, help!
Adam: Dean!
Dean: Hold on. We'll get you out.
Just hold on.
Adam, can you hear me?
[panting]
Adam?
You think Adam's okay?
Doubt it.
Cass either.
But we'll get 'em.
So?
"So"... what?
I saw your eyes.
You were totally
rockin' the "yes" back there.
So... what changed your mind?
Honestly?
The damnedest thing.
I mean, the world's ending...
the walls are
coming down on us...
and I look over to you
and all I can think about is,
"this stupid son of a bitch
brought me here."
I just didn't want
to let you down.
You didn't.
You almost did...
but you didn't.
[chuckles]
I owe you an apology.
No, man.
No, you don't.
Just... let me say this.
[sighs]
I don't know if it's being
a big brother or what. But...
you know, to me,
you've always been
this snot-nosed kid
that I've had to keep
on the straight and narrow.
I think we both know that
that's not you anymore.
I mean, hell... if you're grown-up
enough to find faith in me...
the least I can do
is return the favor.
So, screw destiny
right in the face.
I say we take the fight
to them. Do it our way.
Sounds good.
-- Sinc By Rafael UPD --
www.addic7ed.com
Edited by Scooby