Dean!
Lisa.
You know how I never
mentioned my job?
This is my job.
Ben wouldn't be alive
if it wasn't for you.
You're welcome to stay.
I can't.
It's not my life.
There is someone besides Michael
strong enough to take on Lucifer.
- And who's that?
- God.
I'm gonna find god.
I'm Joshua.
You... talk to god?
He knows that the apocalypse
has begun.
He just doesn't think
it's his problem.
- Not his problem?
- He's finished.
Just another deadbeat dad
with a bunch of excuses, right?
Maybe Joshua was lying.
I don't think he was.
You son of a bitch.
I believed...
We'll find another way.
We can still stop all this, Dean.
How?
I don't know
But we'll find it, you and me.
We'll find it.
- Drive faster, Dean.
- I can't!
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm amazing.
You ever seen that many?
No. No way.
Not in one place.
What the hell?
Damn it!
Well, that's something
you don't see every day.
You two all right?
Peachy.
Be careful. It's... dangerous around here.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Wait, wait.
No need to thank us.
No, hold up a sec!
Who are you?
We're the sacrament
Lutheran militia.
I'm sorry... the what?
I hate to tell you this,
but those were demons,
and this is the apocalypse.
So... buckle up.
Season 5 Episode 17
"99 Problems"
Looks like we're in
the same line of business.
Yeah, and among colleagues.
That's a police-issued shotgun.
That truck is, uh...
inspired.
Where'd you guys
pick up all this crap?
You know, you... pick
things up along the way.
Guys, come on.
This whole corner of the state
is nuts with demon omens.
We just want to help, that's all.
We're on the same team here.
Just talk to us.
Follow us.
Dylan, it's a church.
Headphones off.
Yes, ma'am.
Who would have thought the
apocalypse could be so romantic?
Marriage, family... it's a blessing.
Especially in times like this.
So hold on to that.
Wedding?
Seriously?
Yeah.
We've had eight
so far this week.
Congratulations!
So, Rob tells me
you boys hunt demons.
Uh... yes, sir.
You missed a few.
Yeah, tell us about it.
Any idea why they're here?
They sure seem to like us, though.
Follow me, gentlemen.
So, you're a preacher.
Not what you expected, huh?
Well, dude you're packing.
Strange times.
Is that a 12-year-old
packing salt rounds?
Everybody pitches in.
So, the whole church?
The whole town.
A whole town full of hunters?
I don't know whether
to run screaming or buy a condo.
Well, the demons were killing
us. We had to do something.
So why not call
the national guard?
- We were told not to.
- By who?
Come on, padre.
You're as locked and loaded
as we've ever seen.
And that exorcism was enochian.
Someone's telling you something.
Look, I'm sorry.
I, uh, I can't discuss it.
- Dad, it's okay.
- Leah...
It's Sam and Dean Winchester.
They're safe.
I know all about them.
You do?
Sure.
From the angels.
The angels.
Awesome.
Don't worry. They can't see you here.
The... marks on your ribs, right?
So, you know all about us
because angels told you?
Yes, among other things.
Like the snappy little
exorcism spell.
And they show me where
the demons are gonna be
before it happens,
how to fight back.
She's never been wrong.
Not once.
- She's very special.
- Dad.
Let me guess... before
you see something,
you get a really bad migraine,
you see flashing lights?
How'd you know?
'cause you're not the
first prophet we've met.
But you are the cutest.
I mean that with
total respect, of course.
You've reached
the voicemail of...
I don't understand. Why do
you want me to say my name?
Cass. Hey. Uh, it's me.
So, we are
in blue earth, Minnesota,
and, um, we could use a little help.
I... hope you get this.
Busy night.
I'm telling you,
since the end started,
it's been like
one long last call.
- That round's on me.
- Thanks.
So, did you
get a hold of Cass?
Yeah, I left him
a message, I think.
So, uh, what's your theory?
Why all the demon hits?
I don't know.
Gank the girl prophet, maybe?
What?
Just, these angels
are sending these people
to do their dirty work.
Yeah, and?
And they could
get ripped to shreds.
We're all gonna die, Sam.
In like a month... maybe two.
I mean it.
I mean, this is
the end of the world.
But these people
aren't freaking out.
In fact, they're running to
the exits in an orderly fashion.
I don't know that...
that's such a bad thing.
Who says they're all gonna die?
Whatever happened
to us saving them?
Something I said?
Paul, what's going on?
Leah's had another vision.
Want to go to church?
You know me...
downright pious.
3 miles off Talmadge Road.
5 miles.
There are demons gathered.
I... don't know
how many, but a lot.
Thank you, Leah.
So, who's gonna join me?
Wouldn't miss it.
Someone's got to cover Rob's ass.
We're in, padre.
Thank you.
I'd like to offer a prayer.
Our father in heaven...
Yeah, not so much.
help us to fight in your name.
We ask that you protect
us from all servants of evil.
Guide our hands
in defeating them...
and deliver us home safely.
Thank you. Amen.
I guess that's what it's like, huh?
What?
Having backup.
Dean! Sam!
Yo.
Hey.
So, um, is... is that...
Is that cool if I get
a ride back with you guys?
Hey, you saved my
ass twice already.
One more time,
you can drive.
You have a beer?
Hey.
You earned it.
Don't tell your mom.
Oh, believe me... I will not.
No.
Ma'am, we're just, um, very sorry.
You know...
this is your fault.
Jane.
Come on.
I wish I knew what to say.
But I don't.
I'm so sorry, Jane.
Rob...
there are no words
Dylan...
I don't know why this happened.
I don't know why
any of this is happening.
I got no easy answers.
But what I do know is...
Leah? Leah, honey?
Leah, honey?
Honey?
it's okay, sweetie. It's okay.
Dad, it's Dylan.
Just rest a minute, huh?
No, listen.
Dylan's coming back.
Jane, Rob...
it's going to be okay.
You'll see Dylan again.
When the final day
comes, judgement day,
he'll be resurrected, and
you'll be together again.
We'll all be together...
with all our loved ones.
We've been chosen.
The angels have chosen us
and we will be given
paradise on earth.
All we have to do is follow
the angels' commandments.
No drinking, no gambling,
no premarital sex?
Dean, they basically just outlawed
90% of your personality.
Yeah, well, whatever.
When in Rome.
So, uh... you're cool with it?
I'm not cool. I'm
not, not cool. It's...
look, man,
I'm not a prophet.
We're not locals.
It's not my call.
I'll catch up with you.
This a bad time?
In general.
But now's okay.
Angel stuff really
takes it out of you, huh?
Can't complain. I
know you have it worse.
So... what's on your mind, Dean?
Don't take this
the wrong way, but...
are you on the level?
About what
About paradise.
What about it?
I want to know what
the angels are telling you.
Everything.
Well...
And you can skip
the rainbows.
There's gonna be a prizefight,
and... it's gonna get bad.
But after we win...
And we will...
the planet gets handed
over to the chosen,
and... it's finally peaceful.
No monsters, no disease, no death.
You're just...
with the people you love.
'Course, that's if you can
get past the velvet rope.
Must be nice... being chosen.
Well, Dean...
you're chosen.
Yeah,
more like cursed.
Must be hard.
Being the vessel of heaven
and having no hope.
Hey.
So, what happened to, uh,
"the apocalypse is good for business"?
Oh, yeah.
Right up until Leah's angel pals
banned the good stuff.
Help me kill some inventory?
Sure.
Don't get me wrong.
I grew up here. I love this town.
But, uh...
well, these holy rollers...
Yeah, yeah.
I, uh, I noticed you're
not the praying type.
Yeah, well, between you and me,
neither are half those guys.
Couple of months back,
they were all in here,
Getting wasted, banging the nanny.
Now they're all warriors of god.
Cheers.
Look, there's sure as hell demons.
And maybe there is a god.
I don't know. Fine.
But I'm not a hypocrite.
I never prayed before,
and I ain't starting now.
If I go to hell, I'm going honest.
How 'bout you?
What about me?
Not a true believer, I take it?
I believe, yeah.
I do.
I'm just...
pretty sure god stopped
caring a long time ago.
Where you been?
Drinkin'.
Huh, you rebel.
I'd have had more, um...
but it was curfew.
Right.
You hear they shut
down the cell towers?
No. That's, uh, news to me
Yeah.
No cable, internet.
Total cut-off from the
"corruption of the outside world."
Huh.
Don't you get it?
They're turning this place
Into some kind of
fundamentalist compound.
No, I get it.
And all you got's a "hmm"?
What's wrong with you?
I get it. I just don't care.
What?
What difference does it make?
It makes a hell of a...
At what point does this
become too far for you?
Stoning, poisoned cool-aid.
The angels are toying
with these people.
Angel world, angel rules, man.
And since when is that
okay with you?
Since the angels got the
only lifeboats on the Titanic.
I mean, who exactly is supposed to
come along and save these people?
It was supposed to be us.
We can't do it.
So, what, you... you want to...
you want to just
stop fighting, roll over?
I don't know, maybe.
Don't say that.
- Why not?
- 'Cause you can't do this.
Actually, I can.
No, you can't. You
can't do this to me.
I got one thing... one
thing keeping me going.
You think you're the only one
white-knuckling it here, Dean?
I can't count on anyone else.
And I can't do this alone.
Dean.
I got to clear my head.
It's past curfew.
Leah. What's wrong?
Daddy, can I talk to
you for a second?
Of course.
Leah, honey, w-wha is it?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
They're just so angry.
- Who's angry?
- The angels.
Why are they angry?
They said...
they said that we
can't go to paradise.
What?
But we're doing
everything they say!
They said they gave
clear commandments,
but some people aren't listening.
Who, Leah?
I got your message.
It was long, your message.
And I find the sound
of your voice grating.
What's wrong with you?
Are you...
drunk?
No!
Yes.
What the hell happened to you?
I found a liquor store.
And?
And I drank it.
Why'd you call me?
Whoa. There you go. Easy.
Are you okay?
Don't ask stupid questions.
Tell me what you need.
T-there have been these...
these demon attacks.
Massive, right on
the edge of town
and we can't figure
out why they're...
Any sign of angels?
Sort of.
They've been speaking
to this prophet.
Who?
This girl, Leah Gideon.
She's not a prophet.
I'm pretty sure she is.
Visions, headaches... the whole package.
The names of all the prophets...
they're seared into my brain.
Leah Gideon, is not one of them.
Then what is she?
Please, guys. Guys.
I'm not gonna tell you again.
Take a breath, both of you!
You come on my property,
spouting some kind of crazy...
I'm sorry, Paul!
There's no other way!
Come on! What country is this, huh?
Need a hand, padre?
Just, everybody cool
down for a minute!
"Cool down," eh? My friends are
trying to run me out of town.
Do you think I should cool down?
I'm sorry, Paul. It is not our choice.
Oh, come on. That's bull.
You got to go...
for everyone's sake!
We grew up together.
I stood up at your wedding!
Yes, you did, but that was then.
And now you're
standing against the flock.
That's not true. I fight with you.
This is a town of believers, Paul.
You are not a believer.
Don't make this hard for us.
Hard for you?
No.
This is my home.
You want me out of here?
You'll have to drag me out.
- Rob!
- Whoa, whoa! You don't wanna do this.
Get out of my...
- No, no, no.
- Everyone stop!
No one's gonna stop me
from seeing my son again.
Paul!
We went out looking for...
You all right?
Yeah, it's... it's not my blood.
- Paul's dead.
- What?!
- Jane shot him.
- It's starting.
What's starting? Where the hell
have you been?
On a bender.
- Did he... did you say "on a bender"?
- Yeah.
He's still pretty smashed.
It is not of import.
We need to talk
about what's happening here.
Well, I'm all ears.
Well, for starters...
Leah is not a real prophet.
Well, what is she, exactly?
The whore.
Wow. Cass, tell us
what you really think.
She rises when Lucifer walks the earth.
"and she shall come,
bearing false prophecy."
This creature has the power
to take a humans form,
read minds.
Book of revelation calls her
"The whore of Babylon."
Well, that's catchy.
The real Leah was
probably killed months ago.
What about the demons
attacking the town?
They're under her control.
And the enochian exorcism?
Fake.
It actually means
"you, um, breed with
the mouth of a goat."
It's funnier in enochian.
So the demons smoking
out... that's just a con?
Why, what's the endgame?
What you just saw...
innocent blood spilled in god's name.
You heard all that heaven talk.
She manipulates people.
To slaughter and kill
and sing peppy little hymns.
Awesome.
Her goal is to condemn as many
souls to hell as possible,
and it's... just beginning.
She's well on her way
to dragging this whole
town into the pit.
All right.
So, then, how do
we go pimp of Babylon
all over this bitch?
I only wanted to...
did I make it worse?
did I make the angels angry?
Jane.
The angels... they understand.
What you did was
for the greater good.
Yes.
We all liked Paul.
But he was a sinner,
and he would have
taken us down with him.
You saved us.
Thank you.
How can that be okay?
She killed him.
That sin is so much greater...
It's not a sin to strike down evil.
But how can the angels...
You always taught me
we have to have faith.
The whore can be killed with that?
It's a stake made from
a cypress tree in Babylon.
Great. Let's ventilate her.
It's not that easy.
'Course not.
The whore can only be killed
by a true servant of heaven.
- Servant, like...
- Not you,
or me.
Sam, of course, is an abomination.
We'll have to find someone else.
The angels...
I don't know why they've chosen us.
But they have.
And today...
today, they told me
the most important thing yet.
Tonight, at midnight...
I'm sorry.
It's just that we knew
this day would come,
and it's here...
the final judgement.
Now, we need to do this right.
We don't have much time.
The angels said we're not ready.
There are still a few elements
that need to be taken care of.
Sinners.
Now, uh, now,
everybody calm down.
Just hold on.
Leah, you're scaring
these people.
Now, I don't want us to panic,
but we have to hurry.
- Stop it.
- I've been given instructions, names.
Wait. Let's go.
What are you doing? Stop it!
You're gonna get somebody killed.
Let me go.
Or the next sinner
I name will be you.
Pastor David Gideon.
Yeah. Who are you?
I'm an angel of the lord.
Yeah, sure.
What the hell was that?
Yeah, he wasn't lying
about the angel thing.
Have a seat, padre.
We got to have a chat.
No.
She's my daughter.
I'm sorry, but she's not.
She's the thing that
killed your daughter.
That's impossible.
But it's true.
And deep down, you know it.
Look, we get it...
it's too much.
But if you don't do this,
she's going to kill a lot of people
and damn the rest to hell.
It's just...
- why does it have to be me?
- You're a servant of heaven.
- And you're an angel.
- Poor example of one.
Heads up.
How many should I take?
You?
You should probably
just down the whole bottle.
Thanks.
Yeah, don't mention it.
Yeah, I've been there.
I'm a big expert on deadbeat dads,
so...
Yeah, I get it.
I know how you feel.
How do you manage it?
On a good day,
you get to kill a whore.
Rob, Jane, please!
Come on, it's me!
- It's Elise!
- Sorry. Really.
But you know
we have to do this.
We're putting them
in the storage unit.
No! No!
- No, please.
- You're wrong.
- Jane, is that everyone?
- Yeah.
Okay, then.
Get the kerosene.
What?
There are kids in there.
The angels named
them for a reason.
Jane...
your son needs you to do this.
Daddy! Don't hurt me!
Gideon, now!
Gideon! Wait, no!
Help me! He's a demon!
Light the kerosene.
Come on! Come on!
Please. Like you're
a servant of heaven.
Let me go!
This is why my team's gonna win.
You're the great vessel?
You're pathetic, self-hating, and faithless.
It's the end of the world.
And you're just gonna sit back
and watch it happen.
Don't be so sure, whore.
But, uh... I don't understand...
how are we supposed to
get to paradise now?
I'm sorry.
Pretty sure you're headed
in a different direction
Gotcha.
Come on.
Yeah.
Dean, how did you do that?
What?
Kill her.
Long run of luck held out, I guess.
Last I checked, she
could only be ganked
by a servant of heaven.
Well, what do you
want me to tell you?
I saw a shot, I went for it.
All right. Here we go.
Watch your head, now.
Are you gonna do
something stupid?
Like what?
Like Michael stupid.
Come on, Sam.
Give me a break.
How's the head?
I'm seeing double.
But that may be the painkillers.
You'll be okay.
No.
Where you going?
I'm just gonna grab some clan
bandages out of the trunk.
Relax.
Hold it right there. How's that?
Damn it! Dean!
Dean!
Dean?
Hi, Lisa.
I didn't have your number, uh, so...
No. No, it's okay.
I'm... I'm... Just surprised.
How's Ben?
Good.
Good. He's at baseball.
You moved.
It's a... nice house.
Dean, you didn't come
all the way here
to talk about real estate.
You all right?
No, not really.
What is it
Look, I have no illusions, okay?
I know the life that I live...
I know how that's
gonna end for me.
Whatever. I'm okay with that.
But I wanted you to know...
that when I do
picture myself happy...
it's with you...
and the kid.
Wow.
I mean, you don't
have to say anything.
No, I... I mean, I know.
I know.
I want to.
Come inside. Let
me get you a beer.
I wish I could.
Take care of yourself, Lisa.
No, no. Wait, wait.
You can't just drop a bombshell
like that and then leave.
I know.
I'm sorry.
But I don't have a choice.
Yeah, you do. You do.
You can come inside and let me
get you a beer. We can talk.
Lisa, wait a minute.
Things are about to get really bad.
Like how?
Like your kind of bad?
Worse.
Next few days, the crap
you're gonna see on your TV,
it' s gonna be
down right trippy.
Scary.
But I don't want you to worry,
because I'm making
arrangements for you and Ben.
Arrangements?
Whatever happens,
you're gonna be okay.
What do you mean?
What are you talking about?
The people that I'm gonna see next,
they're not gonna
get anything from me
without agreeing
to a few conditions.
Just... just come inside, please.
And whatever you're thinking
of doing, don't do it.
I have to.
Just stay an hour.
At least say bye to Ben.
Ah, it's better if I don't.
Good-bye, Lisa.
-- Sync by kuniva --
www.addic7ed.com
Edited by Scooby