You think I'll take
one look at a demon
and suddenly fall off the wagon?
As if after everything,
I haven't learned my lesson.
Well, have you?
This is my girlfriend, Jessica.
No! Jess!
So, what are you gonna do?
You just gonna live
some normal, apple-pie life?
Not normal, Safe.
I'm a vessel?
You're the vessel,
Michael's vessel?
The answer's no.
Where's, Cass?
The archangel smote
the crap out of him.
How are you...
Alive?
That's a good question.
I just wish I could save people,
like I used to.
What... you mean when you were
all hopped up on demon blood?
Your plan to kill, Lucifer.
It's foolish, it can't be done.
I have the solution.
I'm gonna find god.
Try New Mexico.
I hear he's on a tortilla.
I killed two angels this week.
I rebelled and I did it, all of it... for you
and you failed.
I'm in no shape to be hunting.
Maybe it's best we just
go our separate ways.
Well, I think you're right.
Hey, baby.
I missed you.
Jessica?
I'm dreaming.
Or you're not.
What's the difference? I'm here.
I miss you so much.
I know.
I miss you, too.
What are you doing, Sam?
What do you mean?
Running away.
Haven't we been
down this road before?
No.
It's different now.
Really?
Last time, I wanted to be normal.
This time... I know I'm a freak.
Which is all a big ball of semantics.
You know that.
No.
Even at Stanford you knew.
You knew there was
something dark inside of you.
Deep down maybe, but... you knew.
Baby, that's what got me killed.
No.
I was dead from the
moment we said hello.
No.
Don't you get it?
You can't run from yourself.
why are you running now?
Why are you here, Jess?
Would you believe I'm actually
trying to protect you?
From what?
You.
Sooner or later, the past
is gonna catch up to you,
Like it always does.
You know what happens then?
People die.
Baby, the people
closest to you die.
Well, don't worry, because
I won't make that mistake again.
Same song, different verse.
Things are never
gonna change with you.
Ever.
[ lynyrd skynyrd's
"simple man" plays ]
Hi, I'm detective, Bill Buckner.
Yes, how can I help you, detective?
I'm here about those patients,
the exsanguinated ones.
Eat it, twilight.
God!
Don't do that.
Hello, Dean.
Cass...
We've talked about this.
Personal space?
My apologies.
How'd you find me?
I thought I was flying
below the angel radar.
You are.
Bobby told me where you were.
Where's, Sam?
Me and Sam are taking
separate vacations for a while.
So... did you find god yet?
More importantly, can I have
my damn necklace back, please?
No, I haven't found him.
That's why I'm here.
I need your help.
With what... a god hunt?
I'm not interested.
It's not god, it's someone else.
Who?
It's an archangel.
The one who killed me.
Excuse me?
His name is, Raphael.
You were wasted by
a teenage mutant ninja angel?
I've heard whispers
that he's walking the earth.
This is a rare opportunity.
For what... revenge?
Information.
So, what... you think if you find this dude,
he's just gonna spill god's address?
Yes.
because we are gonna trap
him and interrogate him.
You're serious about this.
Yes.
So, what... I'm, Thelma and you're, Louise,
and we're just gonna hold hands
and sail off this cliff together?
Give me one good reason
why I should do this.
Because you're, Michael's vessel,
And no angel will dare harm you.
Oh, so I'm your bullet shield?
I need your help...
Because you are the only one
who will help me.
Please.
All right, fine.
Where is he?
Maine.
Let's go.
Whoa, whoa!
What?
Last time you zapped me someplace,
I didn't poop for a week.
We're driving.
Hey, Keith you play?
That depends... what are we playing for?
World peace.
Oh, is that all?
Can I ask you something?
Shoot.
You finish that, uh,
crossword puzzle in the kitchen?
Uh, I-I guess. Why?
The New York Times
Saturday crossword?
Was it?
Uh-huh.
You blow into town last week,
you don't talk to anybody.
You're obviously highly educated.
- You're like this...
- riddle wrapped inside an enigma
wrapped inside a taco?
Here's what we play for.
When I win, you buy me dinner
and tell me your life story.
Sounds fair.
Very misteri-oso.
Freak hail, lightning strikes
I like it.
Locals say what started
as a torrential hailstorm
late this afternoon
suddenly turned to
massive lightning strikes.
that triggered the fire now
consuming more than 20 acres
here along the route 17 corridor.
county officials are advising
all Hawley residents
to prepare for what could
become mandatory evacuations.
Damn.
Is it me, or does it seem
like the end of the world?
We're here why?
A deputy sheriff
laid eyes on the archangel.
And he still has eyes?
All right, what's the plan?
We...
Tell the officer that he
witnessed an angel of the lord.
Then the officer will tell us
where the angel is.
Are you serious?
You're gonna walk in there
and tell him the truth?
Why not?
Because... we're humans.
And when humans want something
really, really bad...
We lie.
Why?
Because... that's how
you become president.
Deputy, Framingham?
Hi.
Alonzo Mosely, FBI.
This is my partner, Eddie Moscone.
Also, FBI.
He's, uh, he's new.
Mind if we ask you
a few questions?
Yeah sure, talk here, though.
Hearing's all blown to
hell in this one.
That happen recently?
Yeah... the gas-station thing.
That's why you're here, isn't it?
Yes, it is.
Do you mind just, uh, running us
through what happened?
Well, call came in...
Disturbance out at the
pump 'n' go on route 4.
What kind of disturbance?
Would not have believed my eyes
if I hadn't seen it myself.
We're talking a riot... full-scale.
How many? 30, 40.
In all-out, kill-or-be-killed combat.
Any idea what set them off?
It's angels and demons, probably.
They're skirmishing
all over the globe.
Come again? what did he say?
- Demons.
- Nothing.
Demons you know, drink adultery.
We all have our demons, Walt, right?
I guess.
Anyway... what happened next?
Freakin' explosion, that's what.
Oh, they said it was one
of those underground gas tanks,
But, uh... I don't think so.
Why not?
It wasn't your usual fireball.
it was, um...
Pure white.
Yeah.
Gas station was leveled.
Everyone was...
It was just horrible.
Then I see this one guy,
kneeling there,
Real focused-like.
Not a damn scratch on him.
You know him?
Donnie Finnerman... mechanic there.
And let me guess,
he just, uh... vanished into thin air?
Uh, no, kolchak.
He's down at, St. Pete's.
St. Pete's.
Thank you.
I take it that's not, Raphael anymore.
Just an empty vessel.
So, is this what I'm looking at
when, Michael jumps my bones?
No, not at all.
Michael is much more powerful.
It'll be far worse for you.
Sam?
Hey, Bobby, how you doin'?
Well, I ain't runnin'
any marathons, but...
I'll live.
Where are you?
Uh, Garber, Oklahoma.
I found a town up the road
showing some revelation omens.
What omens?
All right, listen to this.
"and upon his rising,
There shall be hail and fire
mixed with blood."
Well, ain't that delightful.
Yeah.
We already got hailstorms and fires.
I'm guessing blood
can't be too far behind.
Okay.
What?
There a reason you're calling?
Dean didn't tell you?
He told me.
Yeah, well... so I just thought
You might want to find out
who's in the area,
Put a man on this.
Okay, let me see
if I can think of
the best hunter who might be
in the immediate vicinity.
oh... that'd be you.
I can't, Bobby.
I'm sitting this one out.
- Sam...
- I got to go.
- I'm so sorry.
- Hold on. Sam.
Where have you been?
Jerusalem.
Oh. how was it?
Arid.
What is that?
It's oil.
It's very special and very rare.
Okay, are we gonna... trap
Raphael with a nice vinaigrette?
No.
So, this ritual of yours,
when's it got to go down?
Sunrise.
Tell me something you keep
saying we're gonna trap this guy,
But isn't that kind of like
Trapping a hurricane
with a butterfly net?
No. it's harder.
Do we have any chance
of surviving this?
you do.
So, odds are, you're a
dead man tomorrow?
Yes.
Oh.
Well, last night on earth.
What, uh... what are your plans?
I just thought
I'd sit here quietly.
Dude come on, anything?
Hmm? booze, women?
you have been with a
woman before, right?
Or an angel, at least?
You mean to tell me
you've never been up there
Doing a little cloud-seeding?
Look, I've never
had occasion, okay?
All right.
Let me tell you something.
There are two things
that I know for certain.
One, Bert and Ernie are gay.
two, you are not
gonna die a virgin.
not on my watch.
Let's go.
[ bob luman's "let's think
about living" plays ]
Hey, Sam.
Sam!
"Sam"? what happened to "Keith"?
W-what?
He called you, Sam.
Yeah, uh... Sam's my middle name.
"Keith Sam"?
Man, I'm sorry.
Well actually, it's uh, Samuel,
So it's not quite as dumb as it sounds.
Are you guys friends?
Huntin' buddies with his dad.
But, Samuel here
is quite the hunter himself.
Wow.
You kill deer and things?
Yeah, "and things."
Uh, why don't I
get you guys some drinks?
Sorry. didn't mean
to bust you back there.
No, it's uh, it's all right.
So, what's up?
Well, Bobby called.
And?
You were right...
Major demon block party going on.
But why? what are they up to?
Don't know yet.
Bobby told us
you were off limits.
That true?
Yeah, that's right.
Well, that's fine
in theory and all,
But we could really use
all hands on deck here.
I know you could.
But I can't, I'm sorry.
Why not?
It's personal.
Look, Sam no offense, but uh,
what baggage is so heavy,
It can't be stowed away for
the freakin' apocalypse, huh?
Like I said...
Yeah.
You're sorry.
Heard you the first time.
Okay.
Suit yourself.
More for us, then, right?
Good luck.
But, hey... beers are on you
when we get back.
Yeah, you bet.
So, your parents were drunk
when they named you,
And you shoot, Bambi?
I-it's a... long story.
That is it.
Enough with the, kung-fu,
wandering-the-earth thing.
I'm gonna buy you dinner,
and we're gonna talk.
Lindsey, I can't.
No, the only way to avoid
bloodshed is to say yes.
hey.
Relax.
This is a den of iniquity.
I should not be here.
Dude, you full-on rebelled
against heaven.
Iniquity is one of the perks.
Show-time.
Hi, what's your name?
Cass!
his name is, Cass.
what's your name?
Chastity.
Chastity?
- Mm-hmm.
- Wow.
Is that kismet or what buddy, huh?
well, he likes you,
and you like him, so...
Dayenu.
Mm. come on, baby.
Oh, hey, listen.
Take this.
If she asks for a credit card, no.
Now, just stick
to the basics, okay?
Do not order off the menu.
Go get her, tiger.
Don't make me push you.
Cheers to you.
Aaaaaaaaaah!
Get out of my face!
No! leave me alone!
Bastard! screw you, jerk!
I'll kill you!
Screw you, too!
god!
Ohh! jerk!
What the hell
did you do?
I don't know.
I just looked at her
in the eyes
And told her
it wasn't her fault
That her father, Gene ran off.
It was because he hated his job
at the post office.
Oh, no man.
What?
This whole industry
runs on absent fathers.
It's... it's the natural order.
We should go, come on.
What's so funny?
Oh, nothing.
Whew.
It's been a long time
since I've laughed that hard.
Oh, it's been more than a long time.
Years.
So...
you gonna tell me who those guys
back there really were?
And don't say
"hunting buddies."
Okay, um...
We used to be in the same business together.
What business?
How's your salad?
Witness protection, right? you're mafia?
I'm not mafia.
Okay. I get it.
I don't mean to pry. My bad.
I used to be in business
with my brother.
Truth is, I was...
pretty good at the job.
But... I made some mistakes.
You know, I-I did some stuff
I'm not so proud of.
And people got hurt.
a lot of people.
What was your poison?
Sorry?
Come on.
You were hooked on something.
I know the look.
Three years sober.
You work in a bar.
So do you.
Look, "Keith"...
I don't know you,
And I'm the last person
to be giving advice,
But I do know that...
No one has ever
done anything so bad,
They can't be forgiven.
That they can't change.
When the oil burns,
No angel can touch
or pass through the flames,
Or he dies.
Okay.
So we trap him
in a steel cage of holy fire.
But, uh, one question...
How the hell
do we get him here?
There's... well, almost an
open phone line...
Between a vessel
and his angel.
One just has to know how to dial.
I'm here, Raphael.
Come and get me,
you little bastard.
Just out of curiosity, what is
the average customer wait time
to speak to an archangel?
Be ready.
Well, that's a day
I'll never get back.
Dean, wait.
Castiel.
Raphael.
I mean, I thought you were
supposed to be impressive.
All you do is black out the room?
And the eastern seaboard.
It is a testament
to my unending mercy
That I don't smite you
here and now.
Or maybe you're full of crap.
Maybe you're afraid
That god will bring, Cass
back to life again
and smite you, you candy-ass skirt.
By the way... Hi, I'm Dean.
I know who you are.
and now, thanks to him,
I know where you are.
You won't kill him.
You wouldn't dare.
but I will take him to, Michael.
Well, that... sounds terrifying.
It does.
But, uh, I hate to tell you...
I'm not going anywhere with you.
Surely you remember, Zachariah
giving you stomach cancer.
Yeah, that was...
that was hilarious.
Yes, well...
he doesn't have anything
close to my imagination.
Oh, yeah?
I bet you didn't imagine one thing.
What?
We knew you were coming,
you stupid son of a bitch.
Hey, don't look at me.
it was his idea.
Where is he?
God?
Didn't you hear?
He's dead, Castiel.
Dead.
Bar's closed.
Hey.
Is there something
you want to tell me, Sam?
What?
No.
You sure about that?
I-I don't...
Geez.
Are you okay?
Where are Reggie and Steve?
Oh, Steve's good.
He's, uh...
His guts are laying roadside
Outside the Hawley five-and-dime.
I'm sorry.
"sorry" don't cut it, Sam.
What do you
want me to say?
The truth.
Okay, fine.
Let me give you
some of my own, then.
We go into town, we
capture ourselves a demon,
And we get jumped by 10 more.
Steve bought it.
I'm sorry.
Saying it twice don't make it so, Sam.
But you see, this demon he, uh...
He told us things.
crazy things, things about you, Sam.
Demons lie.
Yeah?
I'm gonna ask you one last time.
The truth.
Now!
Lindsey!
What's going on?
But there's no other explanation.
He's gone for good.
You're lying.
Am I?
Do you remember the 20th century?
Think the 21st is going any better?
You think god would have
let any of that happen
If he were alive?
Oh, yeah?
Well, then who invented
the Chinese basket trick?
Careful.
That's my father you're
talking about, boy.
Yeah, who would be so proud
to know that his sons
started the friggin' apocalypse.
Who ran off and disappeared.
Who left no instructions
and a world to run.
So daddy ran away and disappeared?
He didn't happen to work
for the post office, did he?
This is funny to you?
You're living in a godless universe.
And?
What... you and the other kids
Just decide to throw an
apocalypse while he's gone?
We're tired.
We just want it to be over.
We just want...
...paradise.
So, what... god dies
and makes you the boss,
And you think you can do
whatever you want?
Yes.
And whatever we want, we get.
Let's just take it easy, okay?
Put the knife down.
It's true.
What the demon said... it's all true.
Keep going.
Why?
Are you gonna hate me any less?
am I gonna hate myself any less?
What do you want?
I want to hear you say it.
I did it.
I started the apocalypse.
If god is dead, why have I returned?
Who brought me back?
Did it ever occur to you
that maybe, Lucifer raised you?
No.
Think about it.
He needs all the rebellious angels he can find.
You know it adds up.
Let's go.
Castiel.
I'm warning you.
Do not leave me here.
I will find you.
Maybe one day.
but today, you're my little bitch.
What he said.
What is that?
what do you think it is?
It's go juice, Sammy boy.
Get that away from me.
away from you? wrong.
this is for you.
Hell, if that demon
wasn't right as rain.
Down the hatch, son.
You're insane.
Look, here's what's gonna happen.
You're gonna drink this, hulk out,
And you're gonna waste
every one of those demon scum
That killed my best friend.
Or she dies.
You wouldn't do that.
It's funny how watching your
best friend die changes that.
Come on. You know you want it, Sam.
Just reach out and take it.
Mmmm!
There, was that really so bad?
Ahh! ahh!
Go.
Don't think we won't be back.
Don't think I won't be here.
Hey, man, you okay?
Look, I'll be the first to tell you
That this little crusade of
yours is nuts, but...
I do know a little something
about missing fathers.
What do you mean?
I mean there were times
when I was looking for my dad
When... all logic said that he was dead.
But I knew, in my heart...
That he was still alive.
Who cares what some
ninja turtle says, Cass?
what do you believe?
I believe he's out there.
Good.
Then go find him.
what about you?
what about me?
I don't know.
Honestly?
I'm good.
I can't believe I'm saying that, but I am.
I'm... I'm really good.
Even without your brother?
especially without my brother.
I mean, I spent so much time
Worrying about
the son of a bitch.
I mean, I've had more fun
with you in the past 24 hours
Than I've had with, Sam in years.
And you're not that much fun.
It's funny.
You know, I've been so
chained to my family.
But now that I'm alone...
Hell, I'm happy.
So...
This is your life now?
You think you can
just live forever
With your head
buried in the sand?
I love you, Jess.
God knows how much I miss you, too.
But you're wrong.
people can change.
There is reason for hope.
No, Sam.
There isn't.
How can you be so sure?
Because you freed me.
That's right.
You know who I am.
Lucifer.
You are a hard one to find, Sam.
Harder than most humans.
I don't suppose you'll
tell me where you are?
What do you want with me?
Thanks to you, I walk the earth.
I want to give you a gift.
I want to give you everything.
I don't want anything from you.
I'm so sorry, Sam. I-I really am.
But, Nick here is just an improvisation.
Plan "B."
He can barely contain me without
spontaneously combusting.
What are you talking about?
Why do you think
you were in that chapel?
You're the one, Sam.
You're my vessel.
My true vessel.
No.
Yes.
That'll never happen.
I'm sorry, but it will.
I will find you.
And when I do...
you will let me in.
I'm sure of it.
You need my consent?
Of course. I'm an angel.
I will kill myself
before letting you in.
And I'll just bring you back.
Sam.
My heart breaks for you.
The weight on your shoulders.
What you've done.
What you still have to do.
It is more than anyone could bear.
If there was some other way...
But there isn't.
I will never lie to you.
I will never trick you.
but you will say yes to me.
You're wrong.
I'm not.
I think I know you better
than you know yourself.
Why me?
Because it had to be you, Sam.
It always had to be you.
Sync by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
Edited by Scooby