Dad wants us to pick
up where he left off
Saving people, hunting
things, the family business.
Night, love.
Hey, dean.
Daddy!
Hey, buddy.
Sammy?
Mary!
Dean, this is my girlfriend, jessica.
Here's to sam and his
awesome lsat victory.
What would I dowithout you?
Crash and burn.
No!
I'm not gonna just ditch the job.
Screw the job, man.
I'm sick of the job anyway.
I mean, we don't get paid.
We don't get thanked.
The only thing we get's bad luck.
Yeah?
There's a cop car outside.
You think it's for us?
I don't know.
I don't see how.
We ditched the plates, the credit cards.
They're leaving.
False alarm.
See?
Nothing to worry about.
Yeah, being fugitives is
a freaking dance party.
Hey, man, chicks dig the danger vibe.
So, you got anything yet?
Are you kidding me?
How could I?
You got me sifting through 50
square miles of real estate.
Well, that's where all
the victims disappeared.
Yeah, well, I got diddly-Squat.
What about you?
Just one thing --I'm
pretty sure of it now.
We're hunting a jinn.
A freaking jinni?
Yep.
You think these suckers
can really grant wishes?
I don't know.
I guess they're powerful enough, but not
exactly like barbara eden in harem pants.
Jinn have been feeding
off people for centuries.
They're all over the koran.
My god.
Barbara eden was hot, wasn't she?
And way hotterthan
that "bewitched" chick.
Are you even listening to me?
Yeah.
So, where do the jinn slair up?
Ruins, usually.
Bigger the better -More places to hide.
I saw a place a couple milesback.
I'm gonna check it out.
Wait.No, no, no.
Come pick me up first.
No, I'm sure it's nothing.
I just want to take a look around.
Dean?
Sam.
What's going on?
I don't know.
I don't know where I am.
What?
What happened?
Well, the jinn -It attacked me.
The gin?
You're drinking gin?
No, ass-Hat, the jinn,
the scary creature.
Remember?
It put its hand on me, and then
I woke up next to some hot chick.
Who -Carmen?
Who?
Dean, you're drunk.
You're drunk-Dialing me.
I am not drunk.
Quit screwing around.
Look, it's late.
Just get some sleep, and
I'll see you tomorrow, okay?
Wait, sam!
Sam!
"CRIMINAL LAW & PROCEDURE"
Lawrence?
What the hell?
Honey?
What are you doing up?
Hey.
Carmen.
Carmen, uh, I just, uh
oh, you can't sleep, huh?
Yeah.
Well, why don't you come back to bed, and
let's see if I can do anything to help.
Sure.
Yeah.
In a minute.
You go ahead.
Okay.
Don't stay up too long.
No.
Dean.
Mom?
What are you doing here?
Are you all right?
I don't know.
Well, come inside.
Carmen just called and said you
just took off all of a sudden.
Carmen?
Right.
Let me ask you a question.
When I was a kid, what did you
always tell me when you put me to bed?
I don't understand -Just
answer the question.
I told you angels
were watching over you.
I don't believe it.
Honey, you're scaring me.
Now, just tell mewhat's going on.
You don't think that wishes
can -Can really  -What?
Forget it.
I'm just --I'm
happy to see you.
That's all.
You're beautiful.
What?
Hey, when I was young,
was there ever a fire here?
No, never.
I thought there was.
I guess I was wrong.
Dad's on a softball team.
Dad's softball team
--That's -That's funny to me.
He loved that stupid team.
Dad's dead?
And the thing that killed him was A...
A stroke.
He died in his sleep.
You know that.
That's great.
Excuse me?
That's great that he went peacefully.
I mean, it --It sure
beats the alternative.
You've been drinking.
No, I haven't, mom.
I'm gonna call carmen and have
her come pick you up, okay?
Wait, no, no.
Don't do that.
I want to stay here.
Why?
Because I miss the place.
It's okay.
You got to bed, okay?
Are you sureyou're all right?
I think so.
Okay.
Get some rest.
I love you.
Me too.
Hey, it's me.
I can't get to the phone right now.
Well, I don't think I've
seen you in my class before.
Are you kidding me?
I love your lectures.
You --You make
learning fun.
So, what can I do for you?
What can you tell me about jinns?
A lot of muslims believe
the jinn are very real.
They're mentioned in the koran  yeah,
yeah, yeah, get to the wish part.
What about it?
Do you think they can really do it?
Uh, no.
No, I don't think they can really do it.
You understandthese
are mythic creatures.
Yeah, no, I know.
I know.
But I mean in the stories -Say you had a
wish, but you never even said it out loud,
Like that a loved one never died or
that something awful never happened.
Supposedly, yes.
I mean, they have godlike power.
They can alter reality however
they want -Past, present, future.
Why would the jinn do it?
What, self-Defense?
Or maybe it's not really evil.
Son?
You been drinking?
Everybody keeps asking
me that, but, uh, no.
Who'd have thought, baby?
We're civilians.
This is the best sandwich ever!
Thank you.
I tried to get aholdof sam earlier.
Where is he?
Uh, he'll be here soon.
Good.
I'm dying to see him.
Sweetie, I-I
--Don't get me wrong.
I am thrilled you are hanging out here all of
a sudden, but, uh, shouldn't you be at work?
Work?
At the garage?
Right.
The garage.
That's where I work.Yeah.
No, I-I-I've
got the day off.
Good thing.
That lawn looks like it
could use some mowing.
You want to mow the lawn?
Are you kidding me?
I'd love to mow the lawn.
Knock yourself out.
You'd think you've never
mowed a lawn in your life.
I don't believe it.
Jessica.
Good to see you, too, dean.
I can't breathe, okay?
Sammy.
Hey, look at you.
You're with jessica.
I don't believe it.
Yeah.
Where'd you guys come from?
We just flew infrom california.
California.
Stanford, huh?
Law school, I bet.
I see you started off mom's
birthday with a bang, as usual.
Wait.
Mom's birthday
--That's today?
Yeah, yeah, dean, that's today.
That's why we're here.
Don't tell me you forgot.
Well...
That looks awesome.
All right.
To mom.
Happy birthday.
Thank you.
I was really worried
about youlast night.
Oh, I'm good.
I'm really good.
Okay.
What do you say later we
get you a cheeseburger?
Oh, god, yes.
How did I end up with such a cool chick?
I just got low standards.
All right.
Jess and I actually have another
surprise for mom's birthday.
Uh, you want to tell them?
They're your family.
All right.
What?
Tell me what?
Oh, my god!
That's so wonderful. Thank you.
Congratulations.
I just wish your dad were here.
Yeah, me, too.
Congratulations, sammy.
Thanks.
I'm really gladyou're happy.
So, dean, what was all
that back at the restaurant?
Oh, I thought I saw someone.
I'm sure it's nothing.
Well, I had a lovely birthday.
Thank you.
Good night.
Night.
Yeah, well, I'm beat.
Ready to turn in?
Sure.
Night, guys.
Wait a second.
Come on.It's not even 9:00 yet.
Let's go have a drink or something.
Yeah.Yeah, maybe another time.
Come on, man.
Look at us, huh?
We both have beautiful
women on our arms.
You're engaged.
Let's go celebrate.
Guys, can you excuse us?
I want to talk to my brother for a sec.
Sure.
Thanks.
Come on, carmen.
Come here.
What?
Okay.
What's gotten into you?
What do you mean?
I mean this whole warm,
fuzzy, ecstasy-Trip thing.
I'm just happy for you, sammy.
Yeah, right.That's another thing.
Since when do you call me "sammy"?
Dean, come on.
We don't talk outside of holidays.
We don't?
Well, we should.
I mean, you're my brother.
"You're my brother"?
Yeah.
That's what you said when you snaked my atm card or when you
bailed on my graduation or when you hooked up with rachel nave.
Who?
Uh, my prom date
--On prom night.
Yeah, that doeskind of sound like me.
Well, hey, man, I'm
sorry about all that.
No, look, it's all right, man.
I just -You know, I'm
not asking you to change.
I just, uh
--I don't know.
I guess we just don't really
have anything in common, you know?
Wait.
Yes, we do.
What?
Hunting.
Hunting?
I've never been hunting
in my life, dean.
Yeah, well, then we should go sometime.
I think you'd be great at it.
Get some rest.
My favorite.
I guess you know me pretty well.
Afraid so.
You all right?
Sammy and I --We
don't get along.
Well, you don't really
spend a lot of time together.
I just think you don't know
each other all that well.
For the record, he doesn't
know what he's missing.
I can fix things with sam.
I can make it up to him...
To everyone.
Okay.
What's gotten into you lately?
This isn't gonna make
a lick of sense to you.
But I kind of feel likeI've
been given a second chance.
And I don'twant to waste it.
You're right.
It doesn't make any sense.
You know, I get it.
Get what?
Why you're the one.
Well?
Whatever's gotten into you, I like it.
Oh, come on!
Don't do this to me now.
I've got to get ready for work.
You got to work now?
I told you.
I've got the night shift on thursday.
You work night sat the, uh......
Hospital.
I'm dating a nurse.
That is so respectable.
The olive oil must have a purpose here.
Yeah.
Yeah?
I'll take the olive oil, and we'll
put just a touch of olive oil in, okay?
That's all.
Can't make any mistakes
with this machine.
Now, for liquid, I could use water, but
I'm gonna use a little spinach jui-1%.
No.
Why I said the child nee
And today marks the anniversary of the
crash of united britannia flight 424.
Indianapolis residents held a candlelight vigil in memory
of the 108 passengers and crew who lost their lives.
Oh, no.I stopped that crash.
All of them...
Everyone that you saved,
everyone sammy and I saved......
They're all dead.
And there's this woman
that's haunting me.
I don't know why.
I don't know what the
connection is -Not yet, anyway.
It's like my old life is coming after me or
something, like it doesn't want me to be happy.
Of course, I know what you'd say.
Well, not the you that played softball,
but you'd say, "go hunt the jinn."
It put you here.
It can put you back.
Your happiness or all those
people's lives -No contest."
Right?
But why?
Why is it my job to save these people?
Why do I have to be some kind of hero?
What about us, huh?
What, mom's not supposed
to live her life?
Sammy's not supposed to get married?
Why do we have to
sacrifice everything, dad?
It'S...
Yeah.
That was so easy I'm
embarrassed for you.
Dean?
What the hell are you doing here?
I was looking for a beer.
In the china cabinet?
That's mom's silver.
Sam.
What, you broke into the
house to steal mom's silver?
It's not what it looks like, okay?
I didn't have a choice.
Oh, really?
Why?
What's so damn important that you
got to steal from your own mother?
You want the truth?
Yeah.
Yeah, I do.
I owe somebody money.
Who?
A bookie.
I lost big on a game.
I got to bring him the cash tonight.
I can't believe we're even related.
Sam, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry that we don't get along.
And I wish to hell I
could stay and fix it.
But I got to do this.
People's lives depend on it.
What are you talking about, dean?
Nothing.
Forget it.Just, uh...
Hey, tell mom I love her.
Dean.
I'll see you, sammy.
Get out of the car.
I'm going with you.
You're just gonna slow me down.
Tough.
This is dangerous,
and you could get hurt.
And so could you.
Sam
Look, whatever stupid thing you're about to
do, you're not doing it alone, and that's that.
I don't understand.
Why are you doing this?
Because you're still my brother.
Bitch.
W-What are you calling mea bitch for?
You're supposed to say "jerk."
What?
Never mind.
What's in the bag?
Nothing.
Nothing?
Yeah, nothing.
Fine.
You don't want to do that.
Oh, really?
What the hell is this?
Blood.
Yeah, I can see that it's blood.
What the hell is it doing in here?
You don't really want to know.
No, I do really want to know.
I really, really do.
Well, you're gonna find
out sooner or later.
I needed a silver knife
dipped in lamb's blood.
You needed a silver knife
Why?
Because there's this creature,
a jinn, and I have to hunt it.
Okay, um, stop the car.
I know how it sounds.
Great.
Just stop the car.
It's the truth, sam.
There are things out there in the dark.
There are bad things.
There arenightmare things.
And people have to be saved, and if
we don't save them, then nobody will.
I want to help you.
I really, really do.
But you're having some kind of
psychotic breakdown, so I just  I wish.
What the hell was that, dean?
That was my phone.
I'm not going to a rubber room,
sammy, and we got work to do.
I was just tryingto help you out, dean.
I don't want youto get yourself hurt.
You protect me?
Yeah!
Oh, that's hilarious.
Why don't you just sit tight and
try not to get us both killed?
Where are we?
Well, we're not in kansas anymore.
Illinois.
And you thinksomething's in there?
I know it is.
See?
There's nothing here, dean.
Look, carmen's got to be
worried sick about you, dean.
Come on.
Let's just go.
What the hell is that?
Stick behind me and
keep your mouth shut.
What the hell?
It's her.
Dean, what's going on?
Where's my dad?
No.
Sleep.
This is real?
You're not crazy?
She didn't know where she was.
She thought she was with her father.
What if that's what the jinn does?
It doesn't grant you a wish.
It just makes you think it has.
Look, man, that thing
could come back, all right?
Dean, please.
What if I'm like her?
What if I'm tied up in here some place?
What if all this is in my head?
I mean, it could, you know
Maybe it gives us some kind of supernatural
acid and then just feeds on us slow.
No, dean, that doesn't make sense, okay?
What if that's why she
keeps appearing to me?
She's not a spirit.
It's like more and more I'm catching
flashes of reality -You know,
Like I'm in here somewhere, I'm catatonic, and I'm
taking all this stuffin, but I can't snap out of it.
Okay.Look.Yeah, you're right.
I was wrong.
You're not crazy, but we
need to get out of here fast.
I don't think you're real.
Did you feel that?
You feel this?
I'm real.
This is not an acid trip.
I'm real, and that thing is gonna
come down here and kill us for real.
Now, please.
There's one way to be sure.
What are you doing?
It's an old wives' tale.
If you're about to die in
a dream, you'll wake up.
No, no, no.
That's crazy, all right?
Maybe.
You're gonna kill yours
or I'm gonna wake up.
One or the other.
Look, this isn't a dream, all right?
I'm here with you now, and you
are about to kill yourself, dean.
No, I'm pretty sure......
Like 90% sure, but I'm sure enough.
Wait!
Why'd youhave to keep digging?
Why couldn't you have
left well enough alone?
You were happy.
Put the knife down, honey.
You're not real.
None of it is.
It doesn't matter.
It's still better than anything you had.
What?
It's everything you want.
We're a family again.
Let's go home.
I'll die.
The jinn will drain the life
out of me in a couple of days.
But in here, with us, it'll
feel like years, like a lifetime.
I promise.
No more pain, no more fear.
Just love and comfort and safety.
Dean...
Stay with us.
Get some rest.
You don't have to
worryabout sam anymore.
You get to watch him live a full life.
We can have a future
together, have our own family.
I love you, dean.
Please.
Why is it our job to save everyone?
Haven't we done enough?
I'm begging you.
Give me the knife.
I'm sorry.
Dean!
Dean.
Oh, god.
Come on.
Hey, wake up.
Wake up, damn it.
Auntie em.
There's no place like home.
Thank god.
I thought I lost youfor a second.
You almost did.
Oh, god.
Let's get you down.
Sam!
She's still alive.
Sam.
I got you.
We're gonna get you out of here, okay?
Okay.
Uh, well, thank you
so much for the update.
Okay, bye.
That was the hospital.
The girl's been stabilized.
Good chance she's gonna pull through.
That's good.
Yeah.
How about you?
You all right?
Yeah, I'm all right.
You should have seen it, sam.
Our lives.
You were such a wussy.
So, we didn't get along, then, huh?
No.
Yeah.
I thought it was supposed
to be this perfect fantasy.
It wasn'T.
It was just a wish.
I wished for mom to live.
Mom never died, we never went hunting,
and you and me just never, uh -You know.
Yeah.
Well, I'm glad we do.
And I'm glad you dug yourself out, dean.
Mo st people wouldn't
have had the strength.
They would've stayed.
Yeah, lucky me.
I got to tell you,
though, man -You had jess.
Mom was gonna have grandkids.
Yeah, but, dean, it wasn't real.
I know.
But I wanted to stay.
I wanted to stay so bad.
I mean, ever since dad...
All I can think aboutis
how much this job's cost us.
We've lost so much.
And we've sacrificedso much.
But people are alivebecause of you.
It's worth it, dean.
It is.
It's not fair, and, you know, it
hurts like hell, but it's worth it.