Dad wants us to pick up where he left off
"saving people, hunting things, the family business.
THEN
you know the truth about sammy.
I've known for a while.
You get premonitions of people about to die?
Death visions?
Yeah.
The demonon said he had plans for me.
Do you have any idea what he meant by that?
no !
I want you to watch out for Sammy,okay?
Did he say anything to you?
No.
I can't talk about this to Sammy.
I've got to keep my game face on.
You're on edge, you're erratic!
except for when you're hunting.
'cause then,you're downright scary.
"the truth is,i'm not handling it very well.
you're tail spinning,man,"and you won't let me help you.
NOW
no,no,no,no.
no,you're not gonna -- no,i swear!
it's not in me!
"oh,god.
we're all gonna die.
maybe he's telling the truth.
he's not him --not anymore.
"stop it!
ask her!
ask the doctor!
it's not in me!
i...
just...
"i can't tell.
no,please,don't.
don't.
i've got no choice.
it's not in me.
Don't,don't,please!
sam?
-=www.ydy.com/bbs=-
Proudly Presents
sync: zhiyao
Supernatural
Season 2 Episode 9
continue on OR 224 WEST
there are only two townsin the u.s.named rivergrove.
how come you're so sure !it's the one in oregon?
the wawaa picture.
"okay,what else?
i saw a dark room,some people,and a guy tied to a chair.
and i ventilated him?
yeah.
you thought there wassomething inside him.
"a demon?"was he possessed?
I don't know.
all your weirdo visions are always tied to "the yellow-eyed demon.
was there any black smoke?
did we try to exorcise him?
no.
nothing.
you just plugged him.
that's it.
well,i'm surei had a good reason.
i sure hope so.
what does that mean?
i'm not gonna "waste an innocent man.
i wouldn't.
i never said you would.
fine.
look,we don't "know what it is.
but whatever it is,that guyininhe chair is a part of it.
so,let's find himand see what's w wt.
fine.
"CROATOAN"
he was there.
"morning.
can i help you?
yeah.
billy gibbons,frank beard.u.s.marshals.
what's this about?
we're looking for someone.
a young man,early 20s.
"he'd have a thin scar right below his hair line
what did he do?
we're actually looking for someone else,but we think this young man can help us.
he's'sot in any kind of troubleor anything.
not yet.
"i think maybe youknow who he is,master sergeant.
my dad was in the corps.he was a corporal.
"whwh company?
"echo-2-1.
so,can you help us?
duane tanner's "got a scar like that.
but i know him.
good kid."keeps his nose clean.
oh,i'm sure he does.
do you know where he lives?
with his family, up xx way !
thank you.
hey.
!"croatoan"?
yeah.
roanoke.
lost colony.
ring a bell?
dean,did you pay any attention "to history class?
yeah.
the shot heard "around the world.
how bills become laws.
that's n n school.
"that's "schoolhouse rock.
" "whatever.
roanoke was oneof the first "english colonies in america -- !
late 1500s.
oh,yeah,yeah,!
i do remember that.
the only thing "they left behind was a single word carved in a tree.
"croatoan.
" yeah,and there were theories
indian raid,disease -- "but nobody knows what really happened.
they were all just gone,wiped out overnight.
you don't thinkthat's what's going on here.
"whatever i saw in my head,it sure wasn't g gd.
but what do you think could do that?
well,i mean,like i said,all your weirdo visions are always tied to theyellow-eyed demon somehow,so...
we should get help.
bobby.
ellen,maybe.
yeah,that's a good idea.
"i don't have a signal.
i don't either.
"the line's dead.
"i'll tell you one thing -- if i ias gonna "massacre a town,that'd be my first s sp.
ya?
"hi,looking for duane tanner.
"he lives here,right?
"he's my brother.
cawe talk to him?
he's not here right now.
do you know where he is?
yeah,he wenenon a fishing trip up by roslyn lake.
your parents home?
yeah,they're inside.
jake,who is it?
hi,u.s.marshals,sir.
"we're looking for your s s duane.
he's not in trouble,is he?
we just need to ask him a couple routine questions.
when is he due back from his trip?
i'm not sure.
well,"maybe your wife knows.
"no,i don't know.
she's nohere right now.
well,"your son said she was.
did i?
she's getting groceries.
so,when duane gets back,"there's a numberwhere he canet ahold of you?
oh,no,we'll just check inwith you laterer !
that was kind of creepy,right?
"a little too step ford?
"big-time.
it's okay,mom.
it's not gonna hurt.
put down!
Hello?
"hello?we need a doctor here.
mrs.tanner,what happened?
"she's been attacked.
dr.lee?
[it's okay.
bring her in.
"okay.
hey.
is that...
mr.tanner?
was he attacked,too?
"uh,no,actually,he did the attacking,"and thenhe got himself shot.
shot?
yeah.
"and who are you?
u.s.marshal.
i'd show you my badge,but...
oh,sorry.
bring him back here.
wait,you said jake helped him?
your son jake?
they beat me.
tied me up.
i don't believe it.
pam.
"beverly,do you have any idea !
whwhthey would act "this way?
any history of chemical dependency?
no,of course not.
"i don't know why.
one minute,they were my husband and my son,and the next,they had the devil in them.
we've got to talk.
those guys were whackedout ofofheir gourds.
what do you think,"mass possession?
if it is a possession,there could be more.
god knows how many.
"it could be likea freaking shriner convention.
of course,that's one wayto wipe out a town -- !
you take it "from the inside.
"we didn't see any "of the demon smoke with tanner or any of the other usual signs.
something g rned him into a monster.
you know,if you would have taken out the other one,!
there would be one less to worry about.
i'm sorry.
i hesitated.
it was a kid.
no,it was an "it."
it's not the best time "for a bleeding heart,sam!
how's the patient?
terrible.
what the hellhappened out there?
We don't know.
you just killed "my next-door neighbor.
we didn't have a choice.
"maybe so,!
but we need the county sheriff. I need the corner
the phones are down.
i know.i tried.
tell me "you've got a police radio.
yeah,we do,but it crapped outjust like e erything else.
i don't understand what is hahaening.
how far is it "to the next town?
it's about 40 miles down to sidewinder.
i'm gonna go down thereand see if i can find some help.
"my partner will stick aroundand keep you guys safe.
safe f fm what?
we'll get back to you "on that.
what?
his lymphocyte percentage is pretty high.
his body was fighting off a viral infection.
really?
wh kind of virus?
i can't say for sure.
an infection could have made h h act like that?
some can cause dementia,"but not that kind of violence.
and besides,s,i've never heard of one that did this to the blood.
"did what?
there's thth weird residue.
if i didn't know better,!
i'd say it was sulfur.
sulfur.
hey.
sorry.
road's closed.
yeah,i can see that.
what's up?
quarantine.
quarantine?
what is it?
don't know.
"something going around out there.
who told you that?
county sheriff.
is he here?
no.
he called.
say,why don't you get out of the car,and we'll talk a little?
well,you are a handsome devil,but i don't swing g at way,sorry.
i'd sure appreciatatit "if you got out of the car,just for a quick minute.
yeah,i bet you would.
i don't understand.
are you saying my husbandand jake had a disease?
that's what we're trying to find out.
now,during the attack,!
do you remember -- !
did you have anynyirect contact "with their blood?
oh,my god.
you don't thinki've g g this virus,do you?
beverly,i don't know what to think,"but with your permission,"we'll take a blood sample.
hands where i can see them!
son of a -- !
get out of the car!
out of the carar crap.
all right.easy there,big guy.
- put it down!put it down! - lower it now!
are you one of them?
no,are you?
no!
you could be lying!
so could you!
all right.all right.
we could do this all day.all right.
let's just take it easybefore we kill each other.
what's going on withthverybody?
i don't know.
"my neighbor,mr.rogers
you've got a neighbor "named mr.rogers?
not anymore.
he came at me with a hatchet.
i put him down.
"he's not the only one.
"i mean,it's happeningto everyone.
i'm heading to doc's place.
there's still "some people left.
i'm getting the hell out.
there's no way out.
they got the bridge covered.
don't believe you.
"fine,stay here.
be my guest.
well,this ought to be "a relaxing drive.
what if we all have it?
what if we all go crazy?
you've got to stay calm.
all we can do is wait.
the marshal "is bringing help.
"i can't.
i've got to go.
pam?
no,you don't understand.
my boyfriend's out there.
i've got to make sure he's okay.
hey,hey,hey,wait.
wait,please.
look,i know you're upset,all right.
but it's saferif you sy here for now.
help is coming.
there they are.
Sammy,Open up!
"did you guys get to a phone?
roadblock.
"i'm gonna have a word.
doc's inside.
all right.
"what's going on "out there,dean?
i feel like chuck heston in "the omega man.
sarge is the only sane personi could find.
what are we dealing with?do you know?
yeah,doc thinks it's a virus.
okay,great.
what do you think?
i think she's right.
really?
and i think the infected are trying to infect otherswith blood-to-blood contact.
Oh, I guess this better, the virus leaves traces of sulfur in the blood.
a demonic virus?
"more like demonic germ warfare.
at least it explains why i've been having visions.
"it's like a biblical plague.
you don't knowhow right you are,dean.
"i've been pouring "througugdad's journal.
"i found something about the roanoke colony.
dad always had a theory "about "croatoan.
he thoughtit was a demon's name -- sometimes known as daevaor reshef -- "a demon of plague and pestilence.
well,that's terrific.
why here?why now?
i have no idea.
but,dean,who knows "how far this thing can spread?
we've got to get out of here.
"we've got to warn people.
they've got one.
in here.
what do you mean?
the wife -- she's infected.
we've got to take care "of this.
we can't just leave her "in there.
my neighbors -- "they were strong.
the longer we wait,the stronger she'll get.
"you're gonna kill beverly tanner?
doctor,could there "be any treatment?
"some kind of cure "for this?
"can you cure it?
"i don't even knowwhat "it" is.
it's a matter of timebefore she breaks through.
you can't shoot her like an animal.
sam.
what are you doing?
mark,it's them.
they locked me in here.
they tried to kill me.
"they're infected,not me.
please,mark.
you've known me all your life.
please.
are you sure she's one of them?
yeah.
oh,god!
is ththe any on me?am i okay?
you're clean.you're okay.
why are we staying here?
please,let's just go.
"we can't,'cause those things are everywhere.
"oh,god.
why is this happening?
she's right about one thing.
we can't stay here.
we've got to get out of here,get to the roadhouse,let people know what's'soming.
that's a good point.
"Night of the living dead" didn't exactly end pretty
How much do we got a choice?
"lots of folks "up here are good with rifles.
"even w wh all your hardware,we're easy targets.
"so,unless yououe got some explosives...
we could make some.
let me in,pleasas !
it's duane tanner.
oh,thank god.
duane,you okay?
that's the guy that i...
yeah.
"who else is in here?
easy there,chief.
hey,doc,give duanea good once-over,would you?
pam?
"who are you?
never mind who i am.
doc.
yeah,okay.
duane,where you been?
i was on a fishing tripup by roslyn.
i came back this afternoon.
i saw roger mcgill being dragged "out of his house by people we know.
they stataed cutting himwith knives.
i ran.i've been hidingin the woods ever since.
has anybodyseen my mom and dad?
"awkward.
"you're bleeding.
where did you get thth?
i was running.i must have tripped.
tie him up.
therers rope in there.
- wait - sit down!
sorry,duane.he's right.
we've got to be careful.
careful?about what?
did they bleed on you?
no.what the hell?no!
doc,any way to know for sure?any test?
"i've studied bevevly's blood "work backwards and forwards.
My mom?
it took three hours for the viruruto incubate.
"sulfur didn't appearin the blood until then,!
so,no,there would be no way of knowing.
not until "afr duane...
turns.
dean,i've got to talkto you.
now.
"sit in that chair over there.
this is s vision,dean.
it's happening.
"yeah,i figured.
you can't kiki him.all right.not yet.
we don't knowif he's infected or not.
think we're pretty damn sure.
guy shows up out of nowhere,cut on his leg,"his whole familyis infected.
we should keep him tied up,and we should wait and see
For what? for him to hulk out,infect somebody else?
no,thanks.can't take that chance.
look,man.
i'm not happy about this,but it's a tough job,and you know that.
it's supposed to be tough.
It's supposed to be tough, Dean!
We're supposed to struggle with this.
"whatoes that buy us?
a clear conscience,"for one.
it's too late for that.
what the hellhas happened to you?
what?
you might kill an innocent man,and you don't even care.
you don't actlike yourself anymore.
you're acting likeone of those things out there.
hey.
open the damn door.
dean!
don't t it,dean!
don't!
no,no,no,no.
no,you're not gonna
no,no,i swear!
"it's not in me!
"oh,god.
we're all gonna die.
maybe he's'selling the truth.
no,he's not him --not anymore.
ask her!ask the doctor!
it's not in me!
i...
just...
"i can't tell.
please,don't.
don't,please.
i ear it's not in me.
it's not in me,i swear.
i swear,it's not in me.
don't.don't.
i've got no choice.
damn it.
it's been "over four hours.
duane's blood is still clean.
i don't think he's infected.
"i'd like to untie him,if that's all right.
sure.
you knkn "i'm gonna ask you why.
yeah,i know.
"so,why?
why didn't you do it?
we need more alcohol.
how are you hohoing up,pam?
good.
it will all be over soon.
in fact...
"i've been waitingfor this the whole time.
"for what?
"to get you alone.
she bled on him
he's got the virus.
doctor,check his wound again,would you?
what does she need to "examine him for?
"you saw what happened.
did her bloodactually enter your wound?
"come on,"of course it did!
we don't know that for sure.
we can't take a chance.
you know what we have to do.
nobody is shooting my brother.
He's not gonna be your brother much longer.
You said it yourself!
nobody's shooting anyone.
"you were gonna shoot me!
You don't shut your pie hole,
I still might.
dean,they're right.
i'm infected.
"just give me the gun,"and i'll do it myself.
forget it
dean,i'm not gonna become one of those things.
we've still got some time.
time for what?
i understand he's your brother,and i'm sorry.
but i've got to take careof this.
you make a move,you'll be deadbefore you hit the ground.
Do I make myself clear?
what are wesupposed to do?
get the hell out of here.that's what.
take my car.
you've got the explosives.
there's an arsenal i ithere.you two go with him.
you got enough firepowerto handle anything now.
what about you?
dean,no.
no.
go with them.
this is your only chance.
"you're not gonnaget rid of me that easy.
"no,he's right,man.
"come with us.
okay,it's your funeral.
i'm sorry.
thanks for everything,marshals.
oh,acacally,we're noreally marshals.
i wishwe had a deck of carar or a foosball tableor something.
dean,don't do this.
just get the hell out "of here.
no way.
give me my gun and leave.
for the last te,"sam,no.
this is the dumbest thing "you've ever done.
i don't know about that.
remember that waitress "in tampa?
dean,i'm sick.
"it's over for me.
it doesn't have to be "for you.
no
no,you can keep going.
who says i want to?
what?
i'm tired,sam.
i'm tired of this job...
this life...
this weighton my shoulders,man.
"i'm tired of it.
"so,what?
"so,you're jt gonna give up?
i mean,you're just gonna lay down and die?
- look,dean,i know this stuff with dad had - you're wrong.
it's not about dad.
i mean,part of it is,sure -- !
then,what is it about?
you better come see this.
there's no one.
"not anywhere.
they've all just vanished.
well,it'seen five hours,"and your blood'sstill clean.
i don't understand it,but i think yododged a bullet.
but i was exposed.
how could i not be infected?
i don't know,but you're just not.
i mean,when you compare itwith the tanner samples -- what the hell?
what?
eir blood --there's no trace of the virus.
no sulfur.
nothing.
the sarge and i are getting the hell out of here.
heading south.
"you should come.
i'd better get over to sidewinder,get the authoritiesup here.
if they'll believe me.
take care.
what about him?
he's gonna be fine.
no signs of infection.
hey,man,don't look at me.
"i've got no clue.
i swear,i'm gonna lose sleep over this one.
"i mean,why here?why now?
where the hell "did everybody go?
it's not like "they just freaking melted.
"why was i immune?
yeah,you know what?that's good question.
you know,i'm already "starting to feel like this is the one that got away.
do you mind pulling over up ahead there?
all right.
i've got to make a call.
no phone out here.
"i got it covered.
"what the hell is that?
it's over.you'll be pleased.
"i don't think any more tests are necessary.
"the winchester boy -- !
definitely immune as expected.
yes,of course.
"nothing left behind.
so,last night -- !
you want to tell me what the hell you were talking about?
"what do you mean?
what do i mean?
i mean you said you were tired of the job and that it wasn'tjust because of dad.
forget it.
no,i can't.no way.
"i thoughtwe were both gonna die.
you can't hold that "over me.
you can't pull that crapwith me,man.
you're talking.
and what if i don't?
"then i guess i'll just have to keep asking you till you do.
i don't know,man.
i just think maybe we ought to...
go to the grand canyon.
what?
"yeah,you know,"all thth driving back and forthacross the country
do you know i've neverbeen to the granancanyon?
or we could go to t.j.or hollywood -- see if we could ba lindsay lohan.
you're not "making any sense.
i just think we shouldtake a break from all this.
whwhdo we got to get stuckwith all the responsibility?
"why can'twe live life a little bit?
why are you "saying all this?
no,no,no,no,no.
dean,you're my brother,all right?
so,whatever weight "you're carrying,let me helpa little bit.
"i can't.i promised.
who?
dad.
what are you talking about?
right before dad died...
he told me something.
he told me something about you.
what?
dean,what did he tell you?
-=www.ydy.com/bbs=-
Proudly Presents
sync: zhiyao
Supernatural
Season 2 Episode 9