Storm's coming, and you boys...
You are smack in the middle of it.
You know the truth about
Sammy and the other children.
Andrew Gallagher. Ava Wilson.
I didn't hurt anybody. Not yet.
Max, your abilities started
seven months ago, right?
How'd you know that?
The same thing killed our mothers.
You and I were chosen.
For what? I don't know.
I saw this guy die
days before it happened.
You can make people
do things, can't you?
You can tell them what to think.
Cherry ride. Can I have it? Sure, man.
You must be one of us.
Who? The psychics.
Screw you, buddy, 'cause
i'm a secretary from peoria,
And i'm not part of anything.
This demon tells me they have soldiers
To fight in this coming war
Psychics fighting on hell's side.
The yellow-Eyed man tells me
to do things -- Awful things.
He told me he's got big plans.
Maybe this is his plan. Maybe
we're all supposed to be --
What, killers? Give me a break.
No one's heard anything about Ava.
She's just -- Into
thin air, you know?
Sulfur. Ava.
Demon's been here.
If something bad's
coming, it's coming fast,
And their side holds all the cards.
We can't run from this,
and you can't protect me.
Damn it, Sam, this whole thing
is spinning out of control.
Hey, don't forget the
extra onions this time, huh?
Dude, i'm the one who's
gonna have to ride in the car
With your extra onions.
Hey, see if they got any pie.
Bring me some pie!
Bring me some pie.
Sam?
Sulfur
Sam!
Sammy!
Andy? Sam.
What are you doing here? I don't know.
What am I doing here? I don't know.
Where are we?
Andy, look, calm down.
I can't calm down.
I just woke up in
freaking frontier land.
What's the last thing you remember?
Honestly, my fourth bong load.
It was weird.
All of a sudden,
There was this really
intense smell, like a...
Like sulfur?
How did you know that?
Dean.
Your brother -- Is
he -- Is he here?
I don't know where he is.
I don't know if he's...
Hello?
Woman: no! Help me!
Okay, okay, i'm here.
We're gonna get you out, all right?
Just hold on a second.
All right, one second.
Ava? Oh, my god! Sam!
Hey.
So, I guess you guys know each other.
Yeah.
How did you -- I
mean, how did --
Ava, have you been here this whole time?
What whole time? I just woke
up in there a half an hour ago.
Well, you've been gone for five months.
My brother and I have been
looking for you everywhere.
That's impossible 'cause
I saw you two days ago.
You didn't. I'm sorry.
But that makes no sense. It's...not...
Oh, my god! My fianc? Brady.
If I've been missing for that
long, he must be freaking out!
Well...
Oh!
Hey.
Andy -- Also
freaking out.
Okay.
What's happening?
Well, I, uh...
I don't really know yet,
but I know one thing.
I know what the three
of us have in common.
Man: hello? Anybody there?
Maybe more than three.
Wait.
Hello?
Hey!
Hey, you guys all right?
Think so.
I'm Sam.
I'm Jake. Lily.
Are there any more of you?
No.
How did we even get here?
A minute ago, I was in san diego.
Well, if it makes you feel any better,
I went to sleep last
night in Afghanistan.
Let me take a wild guess.
You two are both 23?
We all are, and we all have abilities.
What?
It started a little over a year ago.
You find you can do things
you didn't think were possible.
I have visions. I see
things before they happen.
Yeah, me too.
And I can put thoughts into people's
heads -- Like, make them do stuff.
Oh, but don't worry. I don't
think it works on you guys.
Oh, but get this -- Um,
I've been practicing,
Training my brain,
like meditation, right?
So now it's not just
thoughts that I can beam out,
But images, too --
Like, anything I want.
It's like bam! People, they see it.
This one guy I know -- Total
dick -- I used it on him.
Gay porn all hours of the day.
It's just like...
You should have seen
the look on his face.
You go, "simon says give me
your wallet," and they do?
You have visions? That's great.
I'd kill for something like that.
Lily, listen, it's okay.
No, it's not.
I touch people. Their hearts stop.
I can barely leave my house.
My life's not exactly improved.
So screw you. I just want to go home.
And we don't?
Don't -- Hey,
gs, come on.
Look, whether we like it
or not, we're all here,
And so we all have to deal with this.
Who brought us h here?
It's less of a "who."
It's more of a "what."
What does that mean?
It's, uh...
It's a demon.
This is it -- All demonic signs
and omens over the past month.
Are you joking? There's nothing here.
Exactly.
Come on, there's got to be something.
What about the normal,
low-Level stuff --
You know, exorcisms, that kind of thing?
There's nothing. It's completely quiet.
How are we supposed to look for
Sam, close our eyes and point?
Sam: Ash, what do you got?
Okay, listen. It's a
bit negatory on Sam.
Come on, man. You got
to give us something.
We're looking at a
3,000-Mile haystack here.
Listen, Dean. I did find something.
Well, what?
I can't talk over this line, Dean.
Come on, I don't have time for this.
Make time, ok, cause this..
What's up? What's going on?
Not only does this
Almost definitely help you
find your brother, this is...
It's huge.
So get here now.
I guess we're going to the roadhouse.
Come on.
So, we're soldiers in a demon
war to bring on the apocalypse?
When you put
it like that --
And we've been picked? Why us?
I'm not sure, okay?
But look, I just know --
Sam. I'm sorry.
Psychics and spoon-Bending
is one thing, but demons?
It sounds crazy. It
doesn't just sound it.
I don't care what you think.
If we're gathered here together,
that means it's starting.
The only thing I got to do is
stay away from wackjobs, okay?
I've heard enough. I'm
better off on my own.
Fyi -- So
are you.
Jake, hold on.
Jake!
Hello?
It's all right. Don't be scared.
Are you lost?
Hello?
Get back!
Just so you know...
That was a demon.
And that thing?
I'm not sure, but I
think it was an achiri --
A demon that disguises
itself as a little girl.
Still doesn't tell us where we are.
Andy, you with me or what?
Give me a minute.
I'm still working
through "demons are real."
I've seen that bell before.
I think I know
where we are now --
Cold oak, south dakota.
The town's so haunted,
every single resident fled.
Swell. Good to know we're
somewhere so historical.
Why in the world would that
demon or whatever put us here?
I'm wondering the same thing.
You know what? It doesn't matter.
The only sane thing to do here
is get the hell out of dodge.
Wait, hold on.
Lily, the only way out
is through miles of woods.
Beats hanging out with demons.
Lily, we don't know what's going on yet.
We don't even know how
many of them are out there.
Yeah, he's right.
We should --
Don't say "we." I'm not part of "we."
I have nothing in
common with any of you.
Okay, look.
I know --
You don't know anything.
I
to--
I accidentally touched my girlfriend.
I'm sorry.
Whatever.
I feel like i'm in a nightmare,
And it just keeps
getting worse and worse.
I've lost people, too.
I have a brother out there right now.
He could be dead, for all I know.
We're all in bad shape,
but i'm telling you,
The best way out of this
is to stick together.
Fine.
We're looking for iron, silver,
salt -- Any kind of weapon.
Salt is a weapon?
It's a brave, new world.
Hopefully, there's food in your world,
'Cause i'm freaking starving.
What the hell?
My god.
You see Ellen?
No.
No Ash, either.
Oh, Ash, damn it!
Hey, you all right?
Yeah, i'm just...
I don't know --
A little dizzy.
A-Are you sure it's
not some kind --
What, some kind of freaky vision thing?
No, more like I'd just
kill for a sandwich.
I haven't eaten since...
Well, who knows.
No,
it's --
Don't worry, i'm fine,
Except for every single
thing that's happening.
You guys, I found something!
Salt.
That's great, Andy.
Now we all can s--
Where's Lily?
Lily?
Lily!
Oh, my god!
Okay, that -- That's
officially just...
Sam, she's dead! She's dead!
You said we were chosen for a reason.
That is not chosen. That's...killed.
Okay, you know, we
have to get out of here.
I second that emotion.
Not sure that's an option.
Lily was trying to leave.
The demon's not gonna
let us get away that easy.
We got to gear up for the next attack.
Oh, gear up? Yeah.
Okay, well, i'm not a
soldier. I can't do that!
Look, if you want to stay
alive, you're gonna have to.
Let's go.
Oh, okay.
I'll get her down.
You know...
I was just thinking about how
much Dean would help right now.
I'd give my arm for a working phone.
You know, you may not need one.
I, uh, I mean, I've never
tried it long-Distance before.
Do you have anything of Dean's on you,
Like something he touched?
Uh...
I got a receipt. Will that work?
Yeah.
D. Hasselhoff?
Yeah, that's Dean's signature.
It...
It's hard to explain.
All right.
This is...
What the hell did Ash know?
We got no way of knowing where
Ellen is or if she's even alive.
We got no clue what
Ash was gonna tell us.
Now, how the hell are we gonna find Sam?
We'll find him.
Dean? No!
Unh!
What was that?
I don't know. Headache?
You get headaches like that a lot?
No.
It must be the stress.
I could have swore I saw something.
What do you mean?
Like -- Like a vision?
Like what Sam gets? What? No.
I'm just saying.
Come on, i'm not some psychic.
Unh! Oh, god! Dean?!
Dean?
Are you with me?
Yeah, I think so.
I saw Sam. I saw him, Bobby.
It was a vision.
Yeah.
I don't know how,
but -- But yeah.
Whew!
That was about as fun as
getting kicked in the jewels.
What else did you see?
Uh, there was a bell.
What kind of bell?
Um, like,
a big --
A big bell with some
kind of engraving on it.
I don't know.
Engraving?
Yeah.
Was it a tree --
Like, an oak tree?
Yeah, exactly.
I know where Sam is.
I-I'm not superman or anything.
It's no big deal.
You were in afghanistan
when this started?
I started getting headaches,
Then, uh, there was this accident.
This guy flipped his
vehicle on a bad road,
Got pinned underneath.
I lifted it off him like it was nothing.
E-Everybody said it was
a fluke adrenaline thing.
But then you did it again, right?
Bench-Press 800
pounds, stone-Cold calm.
I never told anybody, of course.
It's just too crazy.
Yeah, well, crazy's relative.
I'm starting to get that.
Yeah.
By the way, I, uh,
appreciate what you're doing.
What am I doing?
Keeping calm, keeping them calm,
Especially considering how
freaked to hell you really are.
I've been in some deep
crap before myself.
I know the look.
Want to know the truth?
I got this brother, right?
And he's always telling me how
he's gonna watch out for me,
How everything's gonna be okay,
like I've been telling them.
Yeah.
I don't know if I believe it this time.
I mean, the size
of what's coming --
It's bigger than anyone's ever seen.
I mean, it's gonna get bad,
and I-I don't know if --
If we're gonna make it.
It doesn't matter if we believe it.
Only matters that they do.
My horoscope said I shouldn't
have gotten out of bed.
How you doing?
Holding up?
I'm okay.
What about you?
Not so okay.
Why us, Sam?
What did we do to deserve this?
Just lucky, I guess.
If it wasn't for bad luck,
wouldn't have no luck at all.
Just can't wait for this all to be over
So I can just pretend it never happened.
Just want to curl up with
Brady and watch bad tv.
What is it?
Sam, do you
Know something that I don't?
Look, Ava.
I'm sorry. I wish I didn't
have to tell you this
Tell me what?
When the demon broke in
to your house to take you,
Your fianc?Didn't make it
I'm sorry.
No, it's...
Jake, behind you!
Howdy, Sam.
I'm dreaming.
What do you say you and
I take a little walk?
You're awfully quiet, Sam.
You're not mad at me, are you?
I'm gonna tear you to shreds, I swear.
When you wake up, tiger,
you give it your best shot.
Where's my brother?
Quit worrying about Dean.
I'd worry more about yourself.
What, you gonna kill me?
I'm trying to help you.
That's why we're talking.
You're the one i'm rooting for.
What's that supposed to mean?
Welcome to the miss america pageant.
Why do you think you're here?
This is a competition.
Only one of you crazy kids is
Gonna make it out of here alive.
I thought we were
supposed to be --
Soldiers in a coming war?
That's true. You are.
But here's the thing.
I don't need soldiers.
I need soldier. I just need the one.
Why?
I couldn't just come out
and say that, could I, Sam?
I had to let everyone think
they had a fighting chance.
But what I need...
Is a leader.
To lead who?
Oh, I've already got my army
-- Or I will soon, anyway.
You son of a bitch.
Honestly, i'm surprised
you hadn't guessed.
I mean, why do you think so many
children flamed out already --
Max Miller and Andy's
brother -- What's his name?
They weren't strong enough.
I'm looking for the best and
brightest of your generation.
My generation?
Well, there's other generations,
But let's just worry about yours.
That's why i'm here, Sam.
I want to give you the inside track.
You're tough, you're
smart, you're well-Trained,
Thanks to your daddy.
Sam.
Sammy...
You're my favorite.
You ruined my life. You
killed everyone I love.
The cost of doing business, i'm afraid.
I mean, sweet, little jessica...
She just had to die.
You were all set to marry
that little, blond thing,
Become a tax lawyer with
two kids, a beer gut,
And a little mcmansion in the suburbs.
I needed you sharp, on the road,
Honing your skills
-- Your gifts.
What about my mom?
That was bad luck.
Bad luck.
She walked
in on us --
Wrong place, wrong time.
What does that mean?
It wasn't about her. It was about you.
It's always been about you.
What?
Well...
Okay, you caught me
in a charitable mood.
I'll show you.
Look familiar? It should.
Relax, Sam. This is just
a high-Def instant replay.
Enjoy the show.
John.
Mom.
Is he hungry?
Shh.
Okay.
Wait, mom.
Mom!
What did I just tell you,
Sam? She can't hear you.
This isn't real.
What the hell are you doing to me?
Better than mother's milk.
Does this mean I have...
Demon blood in me?
Answer me!
It's you.
She knew you.
No.
No!
I don't think you want
to see the rest of this.
Sam, wake up.
Ava's missing.
I'll take the barn and the hotel.
You take the houses. All right.
Meet back here in 10 minutes, okay?
Ava, where'd you go?
Didn't you hear us yelling?
Yeah, I heard you.
What are you doing?
Holy...
Ah! Aah!
Aah!
Sam, I just found him like this!
What happened?
I don't know.
How did that thing get in?
Where were you?
I just went to get some
water from the well.
I was only gone, maybe,
like, two minutes.
You shouldn't have gone outside.
Ava, we have to stay in here.
Who did that?
I don't know.
Maybe Andy --
Andy wouldn't do that.
Ava, that line wasn't
broken when I left.
Ava.
What? You
don't think --
I'll tell you what I think. Five months.
You're the only one with all
that time you can't account for.
And that headache you got...
Right when the demon got Lily.
What are you trying to say?
What happened to you?
Nothing!
Had you going, though, didn't I?
Yeah.
I've been here a long
time, and not alone, either.
People just keep showing
up -- Children, like us.
Batches of three or four at a time.
You killed them
-- All of them?
I'm the undefeated heavyweight champ.
Oh, my god.
I don't think god has
much to do with this, Sam.
How could you?
I had no choice.
It's me or them.
After a while, it was easy.
It was even kind of fun.
I just stopped fighting it.
Fighting what?
Who we are, Sam.
If you'd just quit your hand-Wringing
And open yourself up,
You have no idea what you can do.
The learning curve is so fast.
It's crazy, the switches
that just flip in your brain.
I can't believe I started
out just having dreams.
Do you know what I can do now?
Control demons.
Ah. You are quick on the draw.
Yeah, i'm sorry, Sam, but...
It's over.
It looks like the rest
of the way's on foot.
Let's go.
I think we can make it out of here now.
But the achiri demon.
No, no, no, Ava was
summoning it, controlling it.
It shouldn't come back
now that she's dead.
We got to go.
No. Not "we," Sam.
Only one of us is getting
out of here. I'm sorry.
What? I had a vision.
That yellow-Eyed demon,
or whatever it was,
He talked to me.
He told me how it was.
No, Jake, listen. You
can't listen to him.
Sam, he's not letting us go.
Only one.
Now, we don't play
along, he'll kill us both.
Now, I-I like you, man. I
do, but do the math, here.
What good's it do for both of us to die?
Now, I can get out of here,
I get close to the demon,
I can kill the bastard.
Come with me. We can kill him together.
How do I know you won't turn on me?
I won't.
I don't know that.
Okay, look.
Just come with me, Jake.
Don't do this.
Don't play into what it wants.
Okay.
Ugh!
Sam!
Dean.
Sam, look out!
No!
No. Sam.
Whoa, Sam. Sam.
Sam, hey.
Hey, come here.
Let me look at you.
Hey, look. Look at me.
It's not even that bad.
It's not even that bad, all right?
Sammy?
Sam!
Hey, listen to me. We're
gonna patch you up, okay?
You'll be good as new.
Huh?
I'm gonna take care of you.
I got you. That's my job, right?
Watch out for my
pain-In-The-Ass little brother.
Sam?
Sam.
Sam!
Sammy!
No. No, no, no.
Oh, god.
Sam!