Dad wants us to pick up
where he left off --
Saving people,
hunting things.
The family business.
You still running
credit-Card scams?
You think credit-Card fraud
is easy?
Okay, mr. Burkowitz.
Federal marshals.
Environmental study majors.
I'm father simmons.
U.S. Wildlife service.
Nigel tuffnel.
Dr. Jerry kaplan.
Reporters.
Rangers.
Fraternity brothers.
Homeland security?
Pretty illegal, even for us.
Man: s.W.A.T. Team discovered
a local woman bound and gagged.
Her attacker, a white male
Approximately 24
to 30 years of age,
Was discovered hiding
in the home.
Shapeshifter?
Every culture has
a shapeshifter lore --
Legends of creatures
who can transform themselves
Into animals or other men.
Hey!
Cops are blaming
this dean winchester guy
For emily's murder.
Sorry i'm gonna miss it.
???
How many chances am i gonna have
to see my own funeral?
Supernatural 207
www.1000fr.Com present
Under what name?
Oh, yeah,
that's my favorite so far.
Possible i.D.S in three states
that we know of.
I got to call you back.
First i thought you were
just stepping up your game.
Credit-Card fraud,
breaking and entering.
This one, a puzzle --
Grave desecration.
But still, these are
a long way from murder.
Then we get a fax
from st. Louis...
...where you're suspected
of torturing and murdering
A young woman.
However, no one could
prove anything, of course,
Because supposedly
you died there.
But i got to
tell you something.
You look pretty healthy
to me.
So, now we know
karen giles
Wasn't the first person
you murdered.
Going somewhere, sam?
But i guarantee you
she's the last.
capture:frm@donale
sync:frm@linda
Thought you might
be thirsty.
Okay,
so you're the good cop.
Where's the bad cop?
He's with your brother.
Okay.
And you're holding us why?
He's being held
on suspicion of murder.
And you? We'll see.
Murder?
You sound
genuinely surprised.
Or are you that good
of an actor?
Who is he supposed to
have murdered?
We'll get around to that.
You can't hold us here
without formal charges.
Actually,
we can for 48 hours.
You, being a prelaw student,
would know that.
I know all about you,
sam.
You're 23 years old.
No job, no home address.
Your mother died
when you were a baby.
Your father's whereabouts
are unknown.
And then there's the case
of your brother, dean,
Whose demise was, well,
just a little bit exaggerated.
Feel free to jump in
whenever you like.
Shy? No problem.
I'll keep going.
Your family moved around a lot
when you were a kid.
Despite that, you were
a straight-A student.
Got into stanford
th a full ride.
Then about a year ago,
Therwas a fire
in your apartment.
One fatality -- Jessica moore,
your girlfriend.
After she died,
you fell off the grid,
Left behind everything.
I needed some time off...
to deal.
So i'm taking a road trip
with my brother.
How's that going for you?
Great.
I mean...
we saw the second-Largest
ball of twine
In the continental u.S.
Awesome.
We ran dean's fingerprints
through iafis.
Got over a dozen
possible hits.
"Possible" hits,
which makes them worthless.
But makes you wonder,
What are we gonna find
when we run your prints?
Yeah, well, uh...
you be sure to let me know,
all right?
May i?
Please.
Great.
Sam, you seem like
a good kid.
It's not your fault
dean's your brother.
We can't pick our family.
Right now detectives
in st. Louis
Are exhuming a corpse.
They're trying
to figure out
How your brother
faked his own death
After torturing
all those young women.
Dean's a bad guy.
His life is over.
Yours doesn't have to be.
You want me to turn against
my own brother?
No.
We already caught him cold,
Red-Handed at
the karen giles murder scene.
We just need you to fill in
some missing pieces.
Why would i do that?
Because i can talk
to the d.A.,
Make a deal for you.
You can get on
with your life.
Dean's as good as gone.
My dad and tony giles
were old friends.
They were in the service
together.
We've known him
since we were kids, you know?
So we came as soon
as we heard about his death.
Here you go.
Anthony giles.
Who's anthony giles?
The baltimore lawyer.
Working late in his office.
Check it out.
His throat was slit
but the room was clean.
Huh.
No dna, no prints.
Keep reading.
It gets better.
"Security cameras failed
to capture footage
Of the assailant."
Either somebody tampered
with the tapes...
or it's an invisible killer.
My favorite kind.
What do you think,
scully?
I'm not scully.
You're scully.
No, i'm mulder.
You're a redheaded woman.
So [chuckles]
It would've been hard
for an to kill tony,
Considering we weren't in town
at the time.
So, tell me
what happened next.
Okay, uh, that's when
we went to see karen.
She was barely
holding it together.
We just wanted to be there
for her, you know?
Insurance.
I totally forgot
about the insurance.
We're very sorry
to bother you right now,
But the company
is required
To conduct
its own investigation.
Sure.
Well, if you could just tell us
anything you remember
About the night
your husband died.
Tony and i were supposed to
have dinner.
He called and said that he was
having computer troubles
And that he had to work late.
That was it.
Do you have any idea
who could've done this to him?
No. No.
It's like i told the police.
I -- I have no idea.
Did tony mention
anything unusual to you
In the days
before his death?
Unusual?
Yeah, like strange.
Strange?
You know, karen, weird.
Weird noises, visions,
anything like that?
He had a nightmare
the day before he died.
What kind of a nightmare?
Uh, he said that he woke up
in the middle of the night,
And there was a woman
standing at the foot of the bed.
He blinked.
She was gone.
I mean,
it was just a nightmare.
Did he say
what she looked like?
What difference does it make
Uh, it's just our company
is very thorough.
He said she was pale,
and she had dark, red eyes.
So i gave karen a hug,
Told her to call me
if she needed anything,
And that was it.
End of story.
Sam, i am trying
to help you here,
But you have got to
be honest with me.
Now,
we have an eyewitness,
Someone who saw two men
Fitting your
and your brother's description
Breaking
into giles' office.
Karen called us later.
There was some stuff she wanted
from tony's office,
But the police
weren't letting her in.
Like a picture
of the two of them in paris
And some other stuff.
It was wrong to enter
a crime scene,
But she gave us the key.
Hey.
Anthony giles' body was found
right about here.
"Throat slit so deep,
Part of his spinal cord
was visible."
What do you think?
Vengeful spirit?
Underline "vengeful"?
Maybe.
He did see that woman
at the foot of his bed.
Look at this.
"Dana shulps."
What's that, a name?
I don't know,
but it's everywhere.
"All work and no play
makes jack a dull boy."
I'd say we've officially
crossed over into weird.
Maybe giles knew her.
Maybe it's the name
of our pale,
Red-Eyed mystery girl.
Well...
let's see what we can see.
There's not a single mention
of a dana shulps anywhere.
There's not a d. Shulpsor any ot
Great.
What do you got?
???
No dana shulps has ever lived
or died in baltimore
In the last 50 years
at least.
So, what now?
I think i'm pretty close
to cracking giles' password.
Maybe there's something
in his fil.
By "close" you mean...
30 minutes maybe.
Awesome.
So, i guess i just get to,
uh, hang out.
That's awesome.
Dude, seriously.
I'm gonna go talk
to karen again,
See if she knows anything
about this dana shulps, huh?
Great.
Keep going, sparky.
Then dean went back
to karen's place
To check up on her.
I mean, you know,
She had been
pretty upset earlier.
Why didn't you go
with him?
I just went back
to the motel.
How did you know i was there,
by the way?
We found the motel matchbook
on your brother
When we arrested him.
Let's quit fooling around.
You were with your brother
The whole time
you were in baltimore.
Why separate now?
Because your brother left you
to go murder karen.
He didn't kill anyone.
I heard the 911 call!
Karen was terrified!
She said someone
was in the house.
Woman:
emergency services.
Hello?
I think i saw somebody
in my house.
What is your address,
ma'am?
It's 421 clinton avenue.
Please --
Hello?
Karen, you in there?
Oh, god.
Seriously, what the hell?
Freeze.
Stay on your knees.
Hands where
i can see them.
Now!
Cuff him.
You getting anywhere
with him?
No. Just a lot
of wiseass remarks.
You?
Sam's story matches dean's
to the last detail.
Yeah, well,
these guys are good.
I'll give them that.
If we don't get sam
to flip,
We have nothing but a lot
of circumstantial evidence.
We got dean at the crime scene
with blood on his hands.
Juries have convicted
for less.
Yeah, but, i mean,
where is the murder weapon?
What's the motive?
You talk about
reasonable doubt.
Diana...
do you have
reasonable doubt?
We keep leaning on these guys,
one of them will tumble.
And don't forget about
st. Louis.
I'm telling you,
this dean guy is our guy.
I know tony giles
was a friend of yours.
Yeah, he was.
He was a good friend.
I know you want to clean
this mess up quick,
But come on.
Tony knew a lot
of criminal types.
Maybe we just --
"Criminal types"?
He was a defense lawyer,
for god sakes.
Of course he knew
criminal types.
Okay. All right.
Let's get back at them.
No. You know what?
Let them stew in their juices
for a bit.
Come here.
Dana shulps, dana shulps,
Dana shulps, dana --
Dana shulps.
Maybe it's not a name.
Anagram maybe?
Mr. Winchester?
Yeah.
I'm jeff crouse.
I'm with the public
defender's office.
I'm your lawyer.
Oh, thank god.
I'm saved.
Can i, uh, steal a pen
from you and some paper?
Sure.
Well, the police haven't found
a weapon yet,
So that's good.
But, uh,
they got your prints
And literally blood
on your hands.
And with your police record,
uh...
mr. Winchester,
what are you doing?
I think it's an anagram.
A what?
An anagram.
Same letters,
different words.
Could you do me a favor?
See if you recognize any
of these words --
Local names, places,
anything like that.
Do you understand
how serious these charges are?
I'm handcuffed to a table.
Yeah. I get it.
Humor me.
Take a quick look.
Well, s-U-P?
I don't know about that,
but...
ashland is a street name.
It's not far from here.
Street?
Let's start
with where you were
The night
that anthony giles died.
Can you get in
to see my brother?
Mr. Winchester...
you could be facing
the death penalty here.
Hey, thanks for the law review,
matlock.
But if you want
to help me...
...i need you to see
my brother.
I hope that was meaningful.
But i'd like to discuss
your case now.
Sure thing, matlock.
You two really are brothers,
aren't you?
Now...
as you know, the d.A.
Might be interested in --
We need you
with the other one.
This should be nice.
Counselor...
your boy decided to confess.
Mr. Winchester,
I would advise against that
strongly.
Talk directly
into the camera.
Start by stating your name
for the record.
My name is dean winchester.
I'm an aquarius.
I enjoy sunsets,
long walks on the beach,
And frisky women.
And i did not kill anyone,
but i know who did --
Or rather what did.
Of course,
it can't be for sure
Because our investigation
was interrupted.
But our working theory
Is that we're looking for
some kind of vengeful spirit.
Excuse me?
You know,
casper the bloodthirsty ghost.
Tony giles saw it.
I'll bet you cash money
karen did, too.
See, the interesting thing
is the word it leaves behind.
For some reason,
It's trying
to tell us something.
But communicating
across a veil ain't easy.
And sometimes the spirits,
they get things jumbled.
You remember "redrum."
Same concept.
You know,
it could be word fragments.
Other times...
...it's anagrams.
At first we thought
this was a name --
Dana shulps.
But now we think
it's a street --
Ashland.
Whatever is going on,
i'm betting it started there.
You arrogant bastard.
Tony and karen
were good people,
And you're making jokes.
I'm not joking, ponch.
You murdered them
in cold blood
Just like that girl
in st. Louis.
Oh, yeah, that wasn't me,
either.
That was a shapeshifter
that only looked like me.
Pete, that is enough!
You asked for the truth.
???
Pete:
what the hell?
?????
How did he do it?
The fire escape's
way over...
what?
These two guys.
Hilts and mcqueen?
What is that?
Hilts is steve mcqueen's
character in "the great escape."
Can we make this quick?
I'm really tired.
It's been a long day,
you know,
With your partner
assaulting me and all.
I want to know more
about that stuff
You were talking
about earlier.
Time life,
"mysteries of the unknown."
Look it up.
Let's pretend
for the moment
You're not entirely insane.
What would one of these things
be doing here?
Vengeful spirit?
Well, they're created
by violent deaths,
And then they come back
for a reason --
Usually a nasty one,
Like revenge on the people
that hurt them.
And, uh, these spirits...
...they're capable
of killing people?
Where did you get that?
I don't know.
It wasn't there before.
You've seen it,
haven't you?
The spirit.
How did you know?
Karen had the same bruises
on her wrists.
I'm willing to bet that
if you look at giles' photos,
He's got them, too.
It's got something to do
with the spirit.
I don't know what.
I know.
You think
you're going crazy.
But let's skip that part,
shall we?
Because the last two people
who saw this thing
Died pretty soon after.
You hear me?
You think i'm gonna die.
You need to go to sam.
He'll help.
You're giving
your brother up.
Go to the first motel
listed in the yellow pages.
Look for jim rockford.
That's how we find each other
when we're separated.
You can arrest him,
if you want,
Or you can let him
save your life.
The showed up
after you saw it?
Yeah, i guess.
All right.
You're gonna have to tell me
exactly what you saw.
You know,
i must be losing my mind.
You're a fugitive.
I should be arresting you.
All right,
well, you know what?
You can arrest me later
after you live through this.
But right now,
you got to talk to me.
Okay?
Okay. Great.
Now, the spirit,
what did it look like?
She was, um,
really pale...
and her throat was cut.
And her eyes, they were
like this deep, dark red.
It appeared like she
was trying to talk to me,
But she couldn't.
It was just...
a lot of blood.
You know what?
Here.
I've been researching
every girl who has ever died
Or gone missing
from ashland street.
How did you get those?
Those are from crime scenes
and booking photos.
You have your job.
I have mine.
Here. I need you
to look through these.
Tell me
if you recognize anyone.
This is her.
I'm sure of it.
Claire becker?
28 years old.
Disappeared about eight
or nine months ago.
But i don't even know her.
Why would she come after me?
Well, before her death,
She was arrested twice
for dealing heroin.
You ever work narcotics?
Yeah, pete and i did
before homicide.
You ever bust her?
Not that i remember.
Says she was last seen
entering 2911 ashland street.
Police searched the place,
didn't find anything.
Guess we got to check it out,
see if we can find her body.
What?
Well, we got to salt
and burn her bones.
It's the only way
to put her spirit to rest.
Of course it is.
So, what exactly
are we looking for?
I'll let you know
when we find it.
Sam!
Hey, i'm here.
What is it?
What happened?
Claire.
She was here.
Did she attack you?
No.
No, she was just
reaching out to me.
She was over there
by the window.
Here, help me move this.
All right.
I got you.
Our little mystery word.
Now the extra letters
make sense.
What is that?
Spirits and certain remains
Give off
electromagnetic frequencies.
So, if claire's body was here,
that would indicate that?
Yeah.
Well, that's the theory.
Yeah, there's definitely
something in there.
You know,
this is bothering me.
Well, you are digging up
a corpse.
No, not that.
That's, uh, pretty par
for the course, actually.
Then what?
It's just...
i mean, no vengeful spirit
I've ever tussled with
wanted to be wasted,
So why the hell would claire
lead us to her remains?
Doesn't make any sense.
All right. Here.
Give me your hand.
Okay.
Her wrists.
Yeah, they'd be bruised
just like yours.
That necklace mean something
to you?
I've seen it before.
It's rare.
It was custom-Made
over on carson street.
I have one just like it.
Pete gave it to me.
Now this all
makes perfect sense.
I'm sorry?
You see, claire is not
a vengeful spirit.
She's a death omen.
Excuse me?
Claire's not killing anyone.
She's trying to warn them.
Sometimes spirits,
they don't want vengeance.
They want justice,
which is why she led us here.
???
She wants us to know
who her killer is.
How much do you know
about your partner?
Oh, my god.
What?
About a year ago,
Some heroin went missing
from lockup.
Obviously it was a cop.
We never found out
who did it.
But whoever did it
Would need someone
to fence their product.
Somebody like
a heroin dealer.
Somebody like claire.
So, i'm being extradited
to st. Louis, huh?
You just decided to transfer me
yourself 800 miles
At 2:00 in the morning?
This can't be good.
All right. Thanks.
What is it?
Pete just left the precinct
with dean.
??
He said the prisoner
had to be transferred,
And he just took him.
Dispatch has been calling,
but he won't answer the radio.
Radio?
He took a county vehicle?
Then it should have
a lojack.
You got to get it turned on.
Pee break so soon?
I think you might want to get
your prostate checked.
Son of a bitch.
Hey, i'm cool in the van.
You go do what you got to do.
You're a cocky
son of a bitch.
You think those people
in st. Louis
Are gonna buy that crap?
Here's the thing.
You're not gonna make it
to st. Louis.
You're gonna die
trying to escape.
Wait! Wait!
Let's talk about this.
You don't want to do something
that you're gonna regret.
Or maybe you do.
Pete!
Put the gun down.
Diana?
How'd you find me?
I know about claire.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Put the gun down!
No, i don't think so.
You're fast.
Pretty sure i'm faster.
Why are you doing this?
I didn't do anything,
diana.
It's a little late
for that.
It wasn't my fault.
Claire was gonna turn me in.
I had no choice.
And tony? Karen?
Same thing.
Tony scrubbed the money.
Then he got skittish.
And then he wanted
to come clean.
I'm sure he told karen
everything.
It was a mess.
I had to clean it up.
I just panicked.
How many more people
are gonna die over this, pete?
There's a way out.
This dean kid
is a friggin' gift.
We can pin the whole thing
on him.
Okay?
No trial, nothing.
Just one more dead scumbag.
Hey!
No one will question it.
Diana, please.
I still love you.
Thank you.
Then why don't you buy me
another necklace, you ass?
Don't do it.
Sam:
you doing all right?
Not really.
The death omen, claire,
what happens to her now?
It should be over.
She should be at rest.
So, uh, what now,
officer?
Pete did confess to me.
He screwed up
both your cases royally.
There's a good chance
That we can get
your cases dismissed.
You could take care
of that for us?
I hope so.
But the st. Louis
murder charges?
That's another story.
I-I can't help you.
Unless i just happened
to turn my back
And you walked away.
I could tell them
that the suspects escaped.
Wait. Are you sure?
Yeah, she's sure, sam.
You could lose your job
over something like that.
I just want you guys out there,
doing what you do best.
Trust me.
I'll sleep better at night.
Listen,
you need to watch your back.
They're gonna be looking
for both of you right now.
Get out of here.
I got to radio this in.
Hey, uh...
you wouldn't happen to know
where my car is by chance?
It's at the impound yard
on robertson.
Don't even think about it.
It's okay. It's all right.
Don't worry.
We'll just improvise.
We're pretty good at that.
Yeah. I've noticed.
Nice lady.
Yeah, for a cop.
Did she look familiar
to you?
No. Why?
I don't know.
It's nothing.
Hey, you hungry?
I could go for some pea soup.
welcome to www.1000fr.Com