Dean,you're not gonna go to hell.
Sic him,boy.
Somebody help me!
Getting pretty slick there,Sam.
What the hell is going
on around here,ruby?
Who are you?
Castiello.
I'm the one who gripped you tight
and raised you from perdition.
I mean  what  are you?
I'm an angel of the lord.
Why would an angel
rescue me from hell?
Because god commanded it.
Because we have work for you.
Hey,it's olivia.I'm
not in. Leave a message.
Olivia,it's Bobby.
Call me back,would you?
I got something big.I
could use your help.
You!
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Supernatural season 4  episode 2
Well,then tell me
what else it could be.
Look,all I know is I was
not groped by an angel.
Okay,look,Dean.
Why do you think this castiello
would lie to you about it?
Maybe he's some kind
of demon. Demons lie.
A demon who's immune to salt
rounds and devil's traps...
And ruby's knife?
Dean,lilith is scared of that thing!
Don't you think that
if angels were real,
That some hunter somewhere
Would have seen one...
at some point...ever?
Yeah. You just did,Dean.
I'm trying to come
up with a theory here.
Okay? Work with me.
Dean,we have a theory.
Yeah,one with a little less
fairy dust on it,please.
Okay,look. I'm not
saying we know for sure.
I'm just saying
that I think we --
Okay,okay. That's the point.
We don't know for sure,so
I'm not gonna believe
That this thing is a
freaking angel of the lord
Because it says so!
You two chuckleheads want
to keep arguing religion,
Or do you want to come
take a look at this?
I got stacks of lore --
Biblical,pre-Biblical.
Some of it's in damn cuneiform.
It all says an angel can
snatch a soul from the pit.
What else?
What else,what?
What else could do it?
Airlift your ass out of the hot box?
As far as I can tell,nothing.
Dean,this is good news. How?
Because for once,
This isn't just another
round of demon crap.
I mean,maybe you were saved
Okay. Say it's true.
Say there are angels.
Then what? There's a god?
At this point,vegas money's on yeah.
I don't know,guys.
Okay,look.
I know you're not all
choirboy about this stuff,
But this is becoming
less and less about faith
And more and more about proof.
Proof? Yes.
Proof that there's a god out there
That actually gives a
crap about me personally?
I'm sorry,but I'm not buying it.
Why not?
Because why me?
If there is a god out there,why
would he give a crap about me?
Dean -- I mean,I've
saved some people,okay?
I figured that made
up for the stealing
But why do I deserve to get
saved? I'm just a regular guy.
Apparently,you're a regular guy
That's important to the man upstairs.
Well,that creeps me out.
I mean,I don't like getting
singled out at birthday parties,
... much less by...god.
Okay,well,too bad,Dean,
Because I think he wants you
to strap on your party hat.
All right. What do
we know about angels?
Start reading.
You're gonna get me some pie.
Yes,Dean,I'll get the chips.
Dude.
When have I ever forgotten the pie?
Exactly.
I got to go.
Yeah,all right. Bye.
-
- Ruby. So,is it true?
Is what true?
Did an angel rescue Dean?
You heard.
Who hasn't?
100% we're not 100%
sure,but I think so.
Okay. Bye,Sam.
Whoa,whoa,whoa,whoa.
Wait. What's going on?
Sam,they're angels. I'm a demon.
They're not gonna care
if I'm being helpful.
They smite first,and then
they ask questions later.
What do you know about them?
Not much.
I've never met one,and
I don't really want to.
All I know is that they
scare the holy hell out of me.
Watch yourself,Sam.
I'm not scared of angels.
Keep the engine running.
Why? What's going on?
I got a friend one state
over -- Olivia lowry.
I've been trying to reach her for
three days on this angel thing.
It's not like her to
ignore this many calls.
Olivia lowry --
A hunter,right?
Yeah. We're gonna go check
on her. You guys follow me.
Scoot over. Yeah.
Dude? Yeah?
Where's the pie?
Olivia?
Bobby?
Salt line.
Emf olivia was rocking the emf meter.
Spirit activity.
Yeah -- On
steroids.
I never seen a ghost
do this to a person.
Boy,you all right?
I called some hunters nearby...
Good. We can use their help.
...except they ain't
answering their phones either.
Something's up,huh?
You think?
Yeah,this is jed. I'm not
around. Uh,leave a message.
Jed,Dean
winchester again --
Friend of Bobby singer's.
Look,we think something's happening.
We think it's happening to hunters.
Just want to make sure
you're okay. Call me back.
It's not pretty.
He looks even worse than
olivia. What about you?
R.C. I checked on carl
bates and r.C. Adams.
They've redecorated... in red.
What the hell is going on here,Bobby?
Why did a bunch of ghosts
Suddenly want to
gank off-Duty hunters?
I don't know,but until we find out,
You guys better get
your asses to my place.
We're on our way.
Hi,Sam. It's been a while.
Hi,guys. It's been a while.
So,how do we survive?
Henriksen. Are
you -- Did you...
I didn't survive...
If that's what you're asking.
I'm sorry.
I know you are.
Look,if we'd known
lilith was coming --
You wouldn't have left
half a dozen innocent people
In that police station
to die in your place.
You did this to me.
It was your fault.
She was after you,and
I paid the price.
You left us there to die!
Damn it,Bobby! Pick up!
How you feeling,huh? How
many fingers am I holding up?
None. I'll be fine,Dean.
Henriksen? Yep.
Why? What did he want?
Revenge 'cause we got him killed.
Sam. Well,we did,Dean.
All right. Stop right there.
Whatever the hell is going
on,it's happening to us now,okay?
I can't get ahold of Bobby,so
if you're not thinking answers,
Don't think at all.
Bobby?
I'll go. You check outside.
Come out,come out,whoever you are.
Dean winchester. Still so bossy.
You don't recognize me?
This is what I looked like
Before that demon cut off my hair
And dressed me like a slut.
Dean.
Meg?
Hi.
It's okay
I'm not demon
You're the girl the demon possessed.
Meg masters.
Nice to finally talk to you
When I'm not,you
know,choking on my own blood.
It's okay.
Seriously,I'm just a college girl.
Sorry
-- Was.
I was walking home one night
And got jumped by all this smoke.
Next thing you know,I'm a prisoner...
In here.
Now,I was awake.
I had to watch while
she murdered people.
I'm sorry.
Oh,yeah?
So sorry you had me
thrown off a building.
-Well,we thought --
- No,you didn't think!
I kept waiting,praying!
I was trapped in
there screaming at you!
"Just help me,please!"
You're supposed to help people,Dean.
Why didn't you help me?
I'm sorry.
Stop saying you're sorry!
Meg. Meg...
We didn't know.
No...
You just attacked.
Did you ever think
there was a girl in here?
No.
You just charged
in,slashing and burning.
You think you're some kind of hero?
No,I don't.
You're damn right.
Do you have any idea what it's like
To be ridden for
months by pure evil...
...while your family has no
idea what happened to you?
We did the best we could.
Are you scared,Bobby?
We were scared,Bobby.
When the monster came for
us... and grabbed us tight.
And we couldn't even scream.
You were right there,Bobby.
You were in the house.
You were so close.
Bobby?
You could have saved us nBobby.
We're here   Bobby?
You walked right past nthat door.
The monster had us.
Nand you didn't find us.
And now nthey won't find you.
It wasn't just me
Dean. Ni had a sister.
A little sister. She worshiped me.
You know how nlittle
siblings are   right?
How they'll do anything for you.
She was never the Same
nafter I disappeared.
She just...
She just got lost.
And when my body was
lying in the morgue
Beat-Up,broken... meg.
...do you know what that did to her?
She killed herself!
Nbecause of you   Dean!
Because all you were thinking
about was your family,
Your revenge,and your demons!
50 words of latin a little
sooner,and I'd still be alive.
My baby sister would still be alive.
That blood is on your hands,Dean!
You're right.
Bobby!
Hold on,Bobby! I'm coming!
Come on,Dean.
Did your brain get
french-Fried in hell?
You can't shoot me with bullets.
I'm not shooting you.
Iron.
So,they're all people we know?
Not just know. People
we couldn't save.
Hey,I saw something on meg.
Did she have a tattoo
when she was alive?
I don't think so.
It was like a-A mark on her
hand -- Almost like a brand.
- I saw a mark,too,on henriksen.
- What did it look like?
Uh,paper? Thanks.
That's it.
I may have seen this before.
We got to move. Whoa.
- Follow me. Okay.
- Where are we going?
Some place safe,you idiot.
Bobby,is this
Solid iron. Completely
coated in salt.
100% ghost-Proof.
You built a panic room?
I had a weekend off.
-Bobby.
- What?
You're awesome.
See,this is why I
can't get behind god.
What are you talking about?
If he doesn't exist,fine. Bad
crap happens to good people.
That's how it is.
There's no rhyme or reason --
Just random,horrible,evil --
I get it,okay. I can roll with that.
But if he is out
there,what's wrong with him?
Where the hell is he while
all these decent people
Are getting torn to shreds?
How does he live with himself?
You know,why doesn't he help?
I ain't touching this
one with at 10-Foot pole.
Yeah.
-Found it.
-What?
The symbol you saw - - The
brand on the ghosts... yeah?
Mark of the witness.
Witness? Witness to what?
The unnatural.
None of them died what
you'd call ordinary deaths.
See,these ghosts --
They were forced to rise.
They woke up in agony.
They were like rabid dogs.
It ain't their fault.
Someone rose them... on purpose. Who?
Do I look like I know?
But whoever it was
used a spell so powerful
It left a mark,a
brand on their souls.
Whoever did this had big plans.
It's called "the rising
of the witnesses."
It figures into an ancient prophecy.
Wait,wait.
What -- What book is
that prophecy from?
Well,the widely distributed version's
Just for tourists,you know.
But long story
short -- Revelations.
This is a sign,boys.
A sign of what? A sign of what?
The apocalypse.
Apocalypse?
The apocalypse,apocalypse?
The four horsemen,pestilence,
$5-A-Gallon-Gas
apocalypse?
That's the one.
The rise of the witnesses
is a mile marker.
Okay,so,what do we do now?
Road trip.
Grand canyon,star trek experience.
Bunny ranch.
First things first.
-
- How about we survive our friends out there? Great.
Any ideas aside from staying
in this room until judgment day?
It's a spell
To send the witnesses back to rest.
Should work...
Should. Great.
...if I translate it correctly.
I think I got everything
we need here at the house.
Any chance you got everything
we need here in this room?
So,you thought our
luck was gonna start now
All of a sudden?
Spell's got to be
cast over an open fire.
The fireplace in the library.
Bingo.
That's just not as appealing
As a ghost-Proof
panic room,you know?
Cover each other. And aim careful.
Don't run out of ammo until
I'm done,or they'll shred you.
Ready?
Hey,Dean. You remember me?
Everybody on the floor now!
He's got the laser eyes.
Ronald,huh? With the laser eyes?
I wish I could say
it's good to see you.
I am dead because of you.
You were supposed to help me!
If you're gonna
shoot,shoot. Don't talk.
Upstairs,linen closet --
Red hex box. It'll be heavy.
Got it.
Bobby.
Kitchen. Cutlery drawer.
It's got a false bottom.
Hemlock,opium,wormwood.
- Opium?
- Go!
Bobby.
You walked right by us while
that monster ate us all up.
You could have saved us.
You know what really
pisses me off,Sam?
You saw how I suffered for months.
I thought you must
have learned something.
I thought I died for something.
Meg.
But what you're doing
with that demon,ruby...
How many innocent bodies has
ruby burned through for kicks?
How many girls just like me?
And you don't send her back to hell?
You're a monster!
- Dean?
- I'm all right,Bobby! Keep working!
Victor.
Dean.
I know.
No. You don't.
It's my fault you're dead.
I left you behind.
And the minute I heard about
that explosion,I thought,
"I should have known."
I should have protected you.
Unh-Unh. Not so fast.
You think you left and lilith came
And we all died in a beautiful
blast of...white light?
... if only.
45 minutes.
What?
Over 45 minutes.
Lilith said she wanted
to have some fun.
The secretary was first.
Remember her? Nancy,the virgin.
Lilith filleted nancy's
skin off piece by piece
Right in front of us,made us watch.
-
- Nancy never stopped screaming. No.
That was the last.
Victor...
Tell me how it's fair.
You get saved
from hell -- I die.
Why do you deserve
another chance,Dean?
You all right?
No.
Let's go.
Ronald. Hey,come on,man.
I thought we were pals.
That's when I was breathing.
Now I'm gonna eat you alive.
Well...come on,I'm
not a cheeseburger.
No!
-Sam!
-Cover Bobby!
Bobby!
Dean!
Fireplace!
Bobby?
Excellent job with the witnesses.
You were hip to all this?
I was,uh,made aware.
Well,thanks a lot for
the angelic assistance.
You know,I almost got my
heart ripped out of my chest.
But you didn't.
I thought angels were
supposed to be guardians.
Fluffy
wings,halos --
You know,michael landon. Not dicks.
Read the bible.
Angels are warriors
of god. I'm a soldier.
Yeah? Then,why didn't you fight?
I'm not here to perch
on your shoulder.
We had larger concerns.
Concerns?
There were people getting
torn to shreds down here!
And,by the way,while
all this is going on,
Where the hell is your
boss,huh,if there is a god?
There's a god.
I'm not convinced.
'Cause if there's a god,
What the hell is he waiting for,huh?
Genocide? Monsters roaming the earth?
The freaking apocalypse?
At what point does
he lift a damn finger
And help the poor bastards
that are stuck down here?
-The lord works
- If you say "mysterious ways,"
So help me,I will kick your ass.
So,Bobby was right...
About the witnesses.
... this is some kind of a...
Sign of the apocalypse.
That's why we're
here. Big things afoot.
Do I want to know
what kind of things?
I sincerely doubt
it,but you need to know.
The rising of the witnesses
is one of the 66 seals.
Okay. I'm guessing that's
not a show at seaworld.
Those seals are being
broken by lilith.
She did the spell.
She rose the witnesses.
Mm-Hmm. And not just here.
-20 other hunters are dead.
-Of course.
She picked victims that
the hunters couldn't save
So that they would
barrel right after us.
Lilith has a certain sense of humor.
Well,we put those
spirits back to rest.
It doesn't matter.
The seal was broken.
Why break the seal anyway?
You think of the seals
as locks on a door.
... okay. Last one opens and...
Lucifer walks free.
Lucifer?
But I thought lucifer
was just a story they told
At demon sunday school.
There's no such thing.
Three days ago,you thought
there was no such thing as me.
Why do you think we're
here walking among you now
For the first time in 2,000 years?
To stop lucifer.
That's why we've arrived.
Well... bang-Up job so far.
Stellar work with the witnesses.
That's nice.
We tried.
And there are other
battles,other seals.
Some we'll win,some we'll lose.
This one we lost.
Our numbers are not unlimited.
Six of my brothers died
in the field this week.
You think the armies of heaven
Should just follow you around?
There's a bigger picture here.
You should show me some respect.
I dragged you out of hell.
I can throw you back in.
You all right?
What's wrong,Dean?
So...
You got no problem believing in...
God and angels?
No,not really.
So,I guess that means that
you believe in the devil.
Why are you asking me all this?