You chose a demon
over your own brother,
and look what happened.
I did it. I started the apocalypse,
and I set, Lucifer free.
I'm sorry.
I would give anything...
anything
to take it all back.
I know you would.
If we're gonna be a team,
you and I,
It has to be
a two-way street.
We got to just grab on
to whatever's in front of us,
Kick its ass,
and go down fighting.
I can get on board
with that.
Jimmy?
I told you
to go to bed.
I can't. I'm dead.
What is this..?
ketchup?
Gross!
Ow! you're mean.
Yeah, that's what your parents
pay me for... to be mean.
Bed... now!
Okay, okay.
Just wait. wait.
I'll go to bed
if you let me touch your boob.
Oh! go!
I'll, uh,
take, Amber home.
Don't wait up.
Amber.
Amber?
Francine!
Agents, Page and Plant,
FBI.
Gentlemen, what brings you by?
We need to see
Amber Greer's body.
Really? what for?
The police report said something
clawed through her skull?
You didn't read
the autopsy report
That I, e-mailed out
this morning?
W-we had, uh,
server issues.
When they brought her in,
We thought she was attacked
by a wolf or something.
Or something.
But we were wrong.
Is that a...
It's a press-on nail.
We found it
in her temporal lobe.
is that even possible?
wait, are you... you saying
that she did this to herself?
Uh-huh. She scratched
her brains out.
It'd take hours,
and it'd hurt like hell,
But sure... it's possible.
How?
Pick your acronym...
OCD, PCP.
It all spells, "crazy."
My guess...
some kind of phantom itch.
I mean, an extreme case, but...
Phantom itch?
Yeah.
All it takes is someone
talking about an itch...
or thinking about one, even
and suddenly you can't stop scratching.
Thanks, doc.
Okay.
Okay, now, some of these
questions might seem a bit odd,
but please
just bear with me.
Have you noticed
any cold spots in the house?
Uh... no.
Okay, uh,
what about strange smells?
Whatcha lookin' for?
Don't know yet.
It's, uh... Jimmy, right?
So, Amber was
your babysitter?
Yes, sir.
Yeah, most of
my babysitters sucked,
especially Ms. Chancey.
She only cared
about two things...
"dynasty" and bedtime.
Did you, uh, you see
anything strange that night?
No, sir.
You sure about that?
I-I would tell you
if I knew something.
I promise... 100%.
Cross my heart.
Well, Jimmy, I, uh...
...I happen to know
you're lying.
I'm not.
We gonna start talking truth,
or are you and me gonna have to
take a little trip downtown?
Kid said he put this
on the babysitters hairbrush.
Dean, there's no way
itching powder
made that girl
scratch her brains out.
It's just ground-up maple seeds.
If you have any other theories,
I'm open to 'em.
Yeah?
Yeah, we'll be right there.
Dr. Morris, please dial 1-1.
What happened?
Guy got electrocuted.
Any idea how?
Eh, maybe a loose wire
or a piece of equipment
shorted out.
So far, we haven't found anything.
Witnesses?
Yeah, guy in there,
Mr. Stanley.
He says he saw it,
but he's not making
a lick of sense.
Senile.
Thanks.
Um, Mr. Stanley?
It was just a joke.
I didn't know
it would really work.
What would work?
All I did,
was shake his hand.
You ready?
Hit it, Mr. Wizard.
That'll do, pig.
What the hell?
that crap isn't supposed to work.
This thing doesn't even have batteries.
So... so, what?
are... are we looking
at cursed objects?
Sounds good.
Maybe there's a powerful witch in town.
Is there any link
between the, uh,
The joy buzzer
and the itching powder?
Uh, one was made in, China,
the other, Mexico,
but they were both bought
from the same store.
Hmm.
Sam!
Welcome to the Conjurarium,
sanctum of magic and mystery.
You the owner?
Yep.
You sold any itching powder
or joy buzzers lately?
Yeah, a grand total of one of each.
They aren't exactly
big-ticket items.
Look, you boys here
to buy something
or... what?
So, you get
many customers?
Kids come in.
They don't buy much,
but they're more than happy
to break stuff.
These days, all they care about
are their, iPhones
and those, kissing-vampire movies.
The whole thing
makes me just...
Angry?
Yeah.
Yeah, I am angry.
This shop has been
my life for 20 years,
and now it's wasting
away to nothing.
Which is why
you hate them.
I suppose.
You wish there was something
you could do about it.
Yeah, I guess I do.
So you're taking revenge...
...with this.
Aah! no!
Oh!
Oh.
something tells me this guy
is not a powerful witch.
Yeah.
Sorry.
I'll just slip this tooth
under your pillow,
and while you're asleep,
the tooth fairy will float down
and swap it out for a quarter.
So some freak is gonna come
in my room while I'm sleeping
and take my tooth?
Sounds scary.
No, thank you.
Come on.
Good night, sweetie.
Shh!
Hold still.
You might feel just a little...
Pinch.
Well, I, uh,
appreciate that,
Nurse... Fremont.
Please... call me "Jen."
Oh. "Jen" it is.
What's up with toothless?
cavity creeps get a hold of him?
Yeah. close.
He wrote up a description,
5'10", 350 pounds,
Wings, and a pink tutu.
Said it was
the tooth fairy.
So he's obviously
whacked out on painkillers.
Maybe.
whatever it was got past
locked doors and windows
Without triggering
the alarm.
Come on, the tooth fairy?
And it left 32 quarters
underneath his pillow,
one for each tooth.
Well, I will see your crazy
and raise you some.
There's a couple of kids
upstairs with stomach ulcers,
say they got it from
mixing pop rocks and coke.
Another guy...
his face froze that way.
What way?
He, uh, held it too long,
and it... it stuck.
They're flying in
a plastic surgeon.
So, I mean,
if you add all that up...
I got nothing.
I thought
sea-monkeys were real.
They are, they're brine shrimp.
No, no, no,
I mean like in the ads.
You know, like the sea-monkey
wife cooks the pot roast
for the sea-monkey husband,
and the sea-monkey kids
play with the dog
In a sea-monkey castle, real.
I mean, I was 6,
but I believed it.
Okay.
Point is...
maybe that's
the connection.
The tooth fairy,
the pop rocks and coke,
The joy buzzer
that shocks you,
they're all lies
that kids believe.
and now, they're coming true.
Okay, so whatever's doing this
is... is reshaping reality.
It has the powers
of a god.
Or... of a trickster.
Yeah, with the sense of
humor of a 9-year-old.
or you.
Dude, seriously...
still with the ham?
We don't have a fridge.
Well, I found something.
Here.
Um, tooth fairy attack was here,
pop rocks and coke was here,
then you've got itching powder,
face freeze, and joy buzzer...
All located within a 2-mile radius.
So, we got
a blast zone of weird,
and inside, fantasy becomes reality.
Looks like.
and what's the a-bomb at its center?
Four acres of farmland...
and a house.
Our motel isn't in that circle,
by any chance?
Yeah.
Why?
Oh, d-dude...
That's not what I think it is, is it?
I got bored,
that nurse was hot.
You know you can
go blind from that, too.
Give me five minutes.
we'll go check out that house.
Yeah.
Hey, do not use my razor!
Can I help you?
Hi. uh, what's your name?
Who wants to know?
The, uh...
...FBI.
Let me see that.
So, what,
you guys don't knock?
Are your parents home?
They work.
Well, you mind
if we ask you a few questions,
Maybe take a look
around the house?
I don't know.
Come on.
you can trust us.
We're the authorities.
What's that?
It's called soup.
You heat it up,
and you eat it.
Right. I-I know.
it's just, um...
I used to make my own dinner,
too, when I was a kid.
Well, I'm not a kid.
Right. no, I-I know.
Um...
I'm, Robert, by the way.
Jesse.
Jesse, nice to meet you.
Did you draw this?
It's the tooth fairy.
That's what you think
the tooth fairy looks like, huh?
Yeah, my dad
told me about him.
Huh.
what, didn't your dad tell you
about the tooth fairy?
my dad?
My dad told me different stories.
Well, the tooth fairy isn't a story.
What do you know
about itching powder, Jesse?
That stuff will make you
scratch your brains out.
Pop rocks and coke?
You mix them, and you'll
end up in the hospital.
Everyone knows that.
You shouldn't have that.
Why not?
It can electrocute you.
actually, it can't.
It's just a wind-up toy.
It's totally harmless.
Doesn't even have batteries.
So, it can't shock you?
Nope, not at all.
I swear.
Oh.
Okay.
I mean, all it does
is just shake in your hand.
It's kind of lame.
See?
What did you say
your name was, again?
Dude, what the hell?
I had a hunch. I went with it.
- You risked my ass on a hunch?!
- You're fine.
Besides, now we know who's turning
this town into Willy Wonka's worst nightmare.
The kid.
Yeah, everything, Jesse
believes comes true.
He thinks the tooth fairy
looks like, Belushi,
Joy buzzers
really shock people.
Boom, that's what happens.
Yeah, but convince him the
joy buzzers don't actually work,
and they go from killing
machines back into crap toys.
He probably doesn't
even know he's doing it.
how is he doing it?
So, dug up what I
could on, Jesse Turner.
It's not much.
Uh, "B" student,
won last year's, Pine-wood Derby.
But get this.
Jesse was adopted.
His birth records are sealed.
So you unsealed them, and...?
There's no father listed,
But, Jesse's biological mom
is named, Julia Wright.
She lives in, elk creek,
on the other side of the state.
Whatever you're selling,
I'm not interested.
Ohh, we're not salesmen.
Agents, Page and Plant, FBI.
Put your badge in the slot.
Your partner's, too.
What do you want?
Thank you.
Um...
We just had a few questions...
about your son.
I don't have a son.
He was born, March
29, 1998, in, Omaha.
You put him
up for adoption?
What about him?
We were just wondering,
um, was it a...
...was it a normal pregnancy?
Was there anything strange?
Stay away!
Mrs. Wright, wait!
We just want to talk!
You're not demons?
How do you know
about demons?
I was possessed.
A demon took control of
my body, and I hurt people,
I killed people.
That... that wasn't you.
But I was there.
I heard a woman
beg for mercy.
I... felt a young girl's blood
drip down my hands.
That's how you knew
about the salt.
Yeah, I picked up tricks.
it was in my head for months.
How many months?
Nine.
So your son...
Yeah... the whole time
the pregnancy, birth...
all of it.
I was possessed.
The night the baby
was born, I was alone.
and the pain was...
the pain was overwhelming.
I-I screamed, and
it came out a laugh...
because the demon was happy.
it used my body
to give birth to a child.
When it was over,
something changed
maybe the, the demon was tired
Or if the pain helped
me fight it, but...
...somehow, I took control,
and the demon wailed inside me.
It pounded
against my skull.
I thought,
my head was gonna explode.
But... I knew.
I knew
what I had to do.
and when I was alone
with the baby...
a part of me...
Part of me
wanted to kill it.
But, god help me,
I couldn't do that.
So... I put it
up for adoption...
and I ran.
Who was the father?
I was a virgin.
Have you seen my son?
Is he human?
His name's, Jesse.
He lives in, uh, Alliance.
He's a good kid.
so, now what?
We need help.
I take it you got our message.
It's lucky you found the boy.
Oh, yeah, real lucky.
What do we do with him?
Kill him.
Cass.
This child is half demon
and half human,
but it's far more powerful than either.
Other cultures call this hybrid
Cambion or Katako.
You know him
as the Anti-Christ.
That wasn't me.
Who put that there?
Anyway, I don't get it.
Jesse is the devil's son?
No, of course not.
Your bible gets more
wrong than it does right.
The Antichrist
is not, Lucifer's child.
It's just a demon spawn.
but it is one of the devil's
greatest weapons
in the war against heaven.
Well if, Jesse's
a demonic howitzer,
then what the hell's
he doing in, Nebraska?
The demons lost him,
they can't find him
but they're looking.
and they lost him, because...?
Because of the child's power.
it hides him from
both angels and demons
for now.
So he's got, like,
a force field around him.
Well, that's great,
problem solved.
With, Lucifer risen,
this child grows strong.
Soon, he will do more
than just make a
few toys come to life.
Something that will
draw the demons to him.
the demons will find this child.
Lucifer will twist this boy to his purpose
and then, with a word,
this child will destroy
the host of heaven.
Whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa. wait.
You're saying that... that
Jesse's gonna nuke the angels?
We cannot allow that to happen.
Wait.
We're the good guys.
We... we don't
just kill children.
A year ago,
You would have done whatever
it took to win this war.
Things change.
Okay. hey, look, we are not
going to kill him, all right?
But we can't leave, Jesse here
either, we know that.
So...
We take him to, Bobby's.
He'll know what to do.
You'll kidnap him?
What is going on
in this town,
It's what happens
when this thing is happy.
you cannot imagine
what it will do if it's angry.
Besides, how will you hold him?
With a thought, he could be
halfway around the world.
So we...
So we tell him the truth.
You say, Jesse's destined
to go dark side... fine.
But he hasn't yet.
So if we lay it all out for him...
what he is, the apocalypse, everything...
He might make
the right choice.
you didn't.
and I can't take
that chance.
damn it.
Oh.
Sorry, I'm sorry.
It's... it's no worries. you okay?
Yeah, it's just today...
a little... shaky.
Ah well, talking to the
Winchesters will do that to you.
Don't you recognize me, sweetheart?
huh?
we had some great times
together, didn't we?
and then you stole something
from us, hid it away.
That was very,
very naughty of you.
So we watched,
and we waited
and now...
They told you where he is, didn't they?
I think it's time we go
and visit our son.
Don't be afraid.
I won't hurt you.
Mom! dad!
Your mother and father are sleeping.
I assure you, they won't
wake until morning.
I'm sorry.
Was there a guy here?
In a trench coat?
Was he your friend?
Him?
No.
I did that.
but how did I do that?
You're a superhero.
I am?
Yeah.
Yeah. I mean, who else
could turn someone into a toy?
You're superman...
Minus the cape
and the go-go boots.
See, my... my partner and I,
We work for a secret
government agency.
It's our job to find kids
with special powers.
In fact, we're here to take you
to a hidden base
in, South Dakota,
Where you'll be trained to fight evil.
Like the, X-Men?
Exactly like the, X-Men.
In fact, the, uh, guy
we're taking you to...
He's even in a wheelchair.
You'll be a hero.
You'll save lives,
you'll get the girl.
Sounds like fun, right?
They're lying to you.
Stay right there, dreamboat.
Can't hurt you.
Orders.
You, on the other hand?
Hurting you's encouraged.
Leave them alone!
Jesse.
You're beautiful.
You have your father's eyes.
Who are you?
I'm your mother.
No, you're not.
Mm-hmm.
You're half human...
Half one of us.
she means demons, Jesse!
Those people you call your parents,
they lied to you, too.
You're not theirs... not really.
My mom and dad love me.
Do they?
Is... is that why they
leave you alone all day?
because they love you
so much?
these people...
these imposter's...
They told you that the
tooth fairy was real
and that your toys could hurt you
and a hundred other
things that aren't true.
they love you so much,
they made your whole life a lie.
Look into your heart, Jesse.
You've always known
you weren't theirs.
you were different
everyone has lied to you.
They're not, FBI agents,
and you're not a superhero.
Then what am I?
You're powerful.
You can have
anything you want.
you can do
Don't listen to her, Jesse!
They treated you
like a child.
Nobody trusted you,
everybody's lied to you.
doesn't that make you angry?
See? it does make you angry.
But, I'm telling you
the truth, Jesse.
Wouldn't it be better
if there were no lies?
Come with me...
and you can
wash it all clean.
Start over.
Imagine that...
A world without lies.
She's right,
we lied to you.
but I'll tell you the truth.
I just went... to tell...
Stop it.
I want to hear
what he has to say.
You're stronger
than I thought.
We lied to you.
and I'm sorry.
So here's the truth.
I'm, Sam Winchester.
That's my brother, Dean.
W-we hunt monsters.
except when you are the monster.
Right, Sammy?
And that woman right there,
her name is, Julia.
She's your mother.
But the thing inside of her,
The thing that you're talking to...
- It's a demon.
- A demon?
He's done nothing but lie to you
since the moment you met him.
Don't listen to him.
Punish him.
Sit down and shut up.
There's, uh, kind of a...
a war between, angels and demons
and... you're a part of it.
I'm just a kid.
You can go with her
if you want.
I can't stop you, no one can.
But if you do...
Millions of people will die.
She said I was half demon.
is that true?
Yes.
But you're half human, too.
You can do
the right thing.
You've got choices, Jesse.
But if you make
the wrong ones,
It'll haunt you
for the rest of your life.
why are you telling me this?!
because I have to believe someone
can make the right choice,
even if I couldn't.
Get out of her.
How did you do that?
I just did.
Kid...
...you're awesome.
Ahh.
Is she gonna be all right?
Eventually.
Look, uh, truth is,
He's kind of a buddy of mine.
Is there any way
you could turn him back?
He tried to kill me.
Right, uh...
But he's a... he's a good guy.
He was just confused.
Okay.
It's been a long night.
we'll... talk about it later.
What now?
Now we take you
someplace safe,
Get you trained up.
You'd be handy
in a fight, kid.
what if I don't want to fight?
Jesse.
You're powerful.
More powerful than...
Pretty much anything we've ever seen.
- That makes you...
- A freak.
To some people, maybe
but not to us.
See, we're kind of freaks ourselves.
I can't stay here, can I?
No.
The demons know where you are,
and more will be coming.
I won't go without my
mom and dad.
There's nothing more
important than family.
We get that
and if you really want
to take them with you,
We'll back your play.
But you got to understand...
it's gonna be dangerous for them, too.
What do you mean?
Our dad...
He would take us with him
wherever he went.
- Where is he now?
- Dead.
A demon killed him.
Look, Jesse...
Once you're in this fight...
...you're in it till the end,
Win or lose.
What should I do?
We can't tell you.
It's your choice.
It's not fair, I know.
Can I go see my parents?
I, um...
I need to... say goodbye.
Sure.
He's been up there
a long time.
He's gone.
Where?
I don't know.
Jesse put everyone in
town back to normal...
the ones still alive.
then he vanished.
Hey.
What does it say?
That he had to leave
to keep his parents safe,
That he loves them,
and he's sorry.
How do we find him?
With the boy's powers, we can't.
not unless he wants to be found.
You think, Jesse's gonna be okay?
I hope so.
You know, we destroyed that kid's life
by telling him the truth.
We didn't have a choice, Dean.
Yeah.
You know, I'm starting to get
why parents lie to their kids
you want them to believe
that the worst thing out there
Is mixing pop rocks and coke...
protect them from the real evil.
You want them going
to bed feeling safe.
If that means lying
to them, so be it.
The more I think about it...
the more I wish
dad had lied to us.
Yeah, me too.
Sync by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
Edited by scooby