You did it.
What, what did I do?
You opened the door.
Lilith was the final seal.
I killed her and I set, Lucifer free.
# it was a Monday #
# day like any other day #
# I left a small town #
# for the apple in decay #
# it was my destiny #
# it's what we needed to do #
# they were telling me #
# I'm telling you #
Jonesing for another hit
of bitch blood or what?
# I was inside #
you're the, Michael sword.
- What do you mean, I'm the sword?
- You're, Michael's weapon.
- I'm a vessel?
- You're the vessel.
Rufus turner, he's a hunter.
I'm what you've got to look
forward to if you survive.
# paying a penance #
# I was longing for home #
Need some help here!
# I'm looking out for the two of us #
What the hell was that?
An enochian sigil.
It'll hide you from every angel
in creation, including Lucifer.
Ellen... it was my fault.
But, Jo did good out there.
You're angry. I understand.
Angry? "Angry" doesn't
begin to touch it!
Is this about me hunting
or something else?
You chose a demon, over your own brother.
I just don't think I can trust you.
What's it been... like, three days now?
We got to cheer him up.
Maybe I'll give him a back rub.
Dean.
Well, what then?
Look...
We might have to wrap
our heads around the idea
That, Bobby might not just
bounce back this time.
What's in the envelope?
Went to radiology
got some glamor shots.
Let's just say the doctors are baffled.
Holy crap.
Yeah well, Cass carved you one too.
Hello?
Castiel?
Speak of the devil.
Uh... St. Martin's hospital.
Why? what are you...
Cass?
Cellphone, Cass? really?
Since when do angels need to
reach out and touch someone?
You're hidden from
angels now... all angels.
I won't be able to simply...
Enough fore-play.
Get over here and lay
your damn hands on.
Get healing... Now.
I can't.
Say again?
I'm cut off from heaven
and much of heaven's power.
Certain things I can do,
certain things I can't.
You're telling me you
lost your mojo just in time,
to get me stuck in this
trap the rest of my life?!
I'm sorry.
Shove it up your ass.
Well, at least he's talking now.
I heard that.
I don't have much time, we need to talk.
Okay.
Your plan to kill, Lucifer.
Yeah, you want to help?
No, it's foolish. It can't be done.
Oh well, thanks for the support.
But I believe I have the solution.
There is someone besides, Michael
strong enough to take on, Lucifer.
Strong enough to stop the apocalypse.
Who's that?
The one who resurrected me
and put you on that airplane.
The one who began everything.
God.
I'm gonna find god.
- God?
- Yes.
- God.
He isn't in heaven.
he has to be somewhere.
Try New Mexico. I hear
he's on a tortilla.
No, he's not on any flat-bread.
listen chuckles, even if there is a god,
he is either dead and
that's the generous theory.
He is out there, Dean.
...or he's up and kicking
and doesn't give a rat's
ass about any of us.
I mean, look around you, man.
the world is in the toilet.
We are literally at
the end of days here,
And he's off somewhere
drinking booze out of a coconut.
- All right?
- Enough.
This is not a theological issue.
It's strategic.
With god's help, we can win.
It's a pipe dream, Cass.
I killed two angels this week.
My brothers.
I'm hunted, I rebelled
and I did it, all
of it for you.
And you failed.
You and your brother
destroyed the world.
And I lost everything, for nothing.
So keep, your opinions to yourself.
You didn't drop in just
to tear us a new hole.
What is it you want?
I did come for something.
An amulet.
An amulet?
What kind?
Very rare, very powerful.
It burns hot in god's presence.
it'll help me find him.
Ah, a god EMF?
Well, I don't know what
you're talking about.
I got nothing like that.
I know, you don't.
What... this?
May I borrow it?
No.
Dean, give it to me.
All right, I guess.
Don't lose it.
Oh great, now I feel naked.
I'll be in touch.
When you find god,
tell him to send legs!
Your belt, your belt!
Here, hold this.
Aaah!
Hello?
Bobby, Bobby,
damn it can you hear me?
Ruf...
I can't hear you.
Listen, I need a little help.
Seems I'm up to my ass in demons,
whole damn town's infested.
Where are you?
pass... rado.
- Coloro...
- Colorado?
River pass, Colorado?
River pass!
Rufus?
You there? Ruf... Rufus
Bobby, it's...
This is the only road in or out.
No signal.
Rufus was right, demons
got this place locked down.
Looks like we're hiking in
and the hits just keep on coming.
# when I die and they lay me to rest #
# gonna go to the place that's the best #
# when I lay me down to die #
# goin' up to the spirit in the sky #
# spirit in the sky #
# that's where I'm gonna go when I die #
# when I die #
# when I die and they lay me to rest #
# I'm gonna go to the
place that's the best #
# prepare yourself #
# you know it's a must #
# got to have a friend in Jesus #
# so you know that when you die #
Ellen?
Hello, boys.
Ellen, what the heck's going on here?
We're us.
Real glad to see you boys.
The can of whup ass I
ought to open on you.
Ow!
You can't pick up a phone?
What are you, allergic
to giving me peace of mind?
I got to find out that
you're alive from, Rufus?!
Sorry, Ellen. Yeah you better be.
You better put me on speed dial kid.
Yes ma'am.
What's going on, Ellen?
More than I can handle alone.
How many demons are there?
Pretty much... whole town,
Minus the dead people and these guys.
So... this is it, right?
End times?
It's got to be.
Seems like it.
It's me.
This is, Sam and Dean.
They're hunters, here to help.
You guys hip to this whole demon thing?
Yeah, are you?
My wife's eyes turned black,
she came at me with a brick.
Kind of makes you
embrace the paranormal.
All right, catch us up.
I doubt I know much more than you.
Rufus called, said he was
in town investigating omens.
All of a sudden, the
whole town was possessed.
Me and Jo were nearby.
You're hunting with, Jo?
Yeah, for a while now.
We got here and the place,
well, the place was like you see it.
Couldn't find, Rufus then
me and Jo got separated.
I was out looking when I found you.
Don't worry, we'll find her.
Either way, these people
cannot just sit here.
we got to get them out now.
No, it's not that
easy, I've been trying.
We already made a run for it once.
- What happened?
- There used to be 20 of us.
well, there's three of us now.
You don't know what it's like out there.
Demons are everywhere.
We won't be able to cover everybody.
What if we get everyone guns?
What, are you gonna arm
up baby bump over here?
More salt we can fire at once,
more demons we can keep away.
There's a sporting-goods store
we passed on main on the way in.
I bet they got guns.
All right, you stay.
- We'll go.
- What about...
If Jo and Rufus are out
there, we'll bring them back.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. hold on.
Why don't I just go?
What? alone?
Well, yeah. somebody's got to stay
here and start giving them shotgun 101.
- Yeah... Ellen.
- No, no, no.
It's gonna go a lot faster
if you stay and help, okay?
while you go get guns and
salt and look for, Jo and Rufus?
That's stupid.
I can handle it.
You don't want me going out there.
I didn't say that.
- Around demons.
- I didn't say that.
Fine then let's go.
I'll get the salt, you get the guns.
We'll go together.
Dean, it's right there.
Can we at least do
this like professionals?
Exorcizamus te, omnis immundus.
Sammy?
Okay, Roger, try again.
Then snap it in.
You know your way around a gun at all?
Hmm.
Where'd you serve?
Fallujah, two tours.
Got back a little over a year ago.
Takes one to know one.
Where'd you serve?
Hell.
No, seriously.
Seriously.
Hell.
Hey.
What's wrong?
Just... at the store.
Those demons were possessing teenagers.
I mean, I had to slit some kid's throat.
come on, Sam you had to.
I know, I just it used to be like...
I just wish I could save
people, like I used to.
What... you mean when you were
all hopped up on demon blood?
I-I didn't say that.
I'll be back.
Where you going?
I can't sit here on my ass.
My daughter's out there somewhere.
I'm not back in half an hour, go.
Get these people out of here.
No, wait.
I'll go with you.
Whoa, hold on. Can I
talk to you for a second?
You're gonna go out there again?
Well crap doesn't hit
the fan with coffee breaks.
I'll go.
It's fine, just stay here get
'em ready I'll cover, Ellen.
Why's it got to be you?
Oh, that's right, I forgot.
You think I'll take one look at a demon,
and suddenly fall off the wagon, as if
after everything, I
haven't learned my lesson.
Well, have you?
If you actually think I...
So, where'd you see her last?
Up ahead.
So, what's up with you and Dean?
It was hard not to notice,
how different things are
between you guys these days.
Lot of bad road there, huh?
What happened? some girl
come between you or something?
Just... stresses of the job
you know how it is.
Kind of surprised,
you and Jo hunting.
Weren't you always saying
she couldn't hack the life?
She can't.
But if she's gonna do it anyway...
You want to keep an eye on her.
Hey.
Is that a chimney going?
Looks like it.
Huh.
Come on.
Guess we found base camp.
Demons don't get cold.
Makes you wonder what they're burning.
Don't move, you evil skank!
Don't you hurt
her, don't you.
Give me my mom back,
you black-eyed bitch!
Ellen, Run!
Got you now, you bastard.
Unh-unh.
No way you're getting out of those.
Did you up myself.
You're stuck right where I want you.
You evil son of a bitch.
No.
W-wait, wait, wait.
Just, just wait.
Exorcizamus te.
Stop!
omnis satanica.
Please!
the lord is my shepherd. I shall not want.
He layeth me down in green pastures,
and he raiseth me up again.
Yea, though I walk through the
valley of the shadow of death,
I shall fear no evil.
Where's Sam?
They took him?
Demons took him?
Oh, my god.
What if they're in
here, the demons?
Could they get in?
No.
Everybody sit tight.
I gotta...
Okay, we need to get a plan
together, tell me everything.
Please! come on!
Omnis immundus.
Look, something's not right.
Do you see that?
Geez!
Come on!
Stop, listen to me.
Wait a second.
- Why isn't it working?
- I don't know.
Look, listen to me
something's not right.
But he's not as strong
as he thinks he is.
You can see that.
Please, please.
Just listen to me.
Dean one of them's in, Jo.
We got to get it out
without hurting her.
It called me a bitch.
Bruise a little easy, don't you think?
No, that's not what I meant.
It called me a black-eyed bitch.
What kind of demons are these?
Holy water and salt roll right off.
My daughter may be an
idiot, but she's not stupid.
She wears an anti-possession charm.
It's all kind of weird, right?
The whole thing's off.
What's your instinct?
My instinct?
My instinct is to call, Bobby
and ask for help or Sam.
Well tough, all you got's
me and all I got's you.
So let's figure it out.
All right.
Do you know why, Rufus came to town?
Was there a specific omen?
He said something about water.
That's all I know.
Padre, you know what she's
talking about, the water?
Uh, the...
The river, ran polluted all of a sudden.
When?
Last Wednesday.
And the demon thing
started up the next day.
Anything else? anything.
Maybe, but it's pretty random.
Good, random's good.
Shooting star, does that count?
Real big, same night Wednesday.
That definitely counts.
So uh, you think that all
this comes from outer space?
This isn't "x files," pal.
"and there fell a great star from heaven,
"burning like a torch,
and it fell upon the river,
"and the name of the star was worm-wood.
And many men died."
Revelation 8:10.
Are you saying that this
is about, the apocalypse?
You could say.
And these specific omens,
they're prelude to what?
The four horsemen,
and which one rides the red horse?
War.
That cherry mustang parked on main?
You can't think, that a car.
It's the way I'd roll.
I mean, think about it.
It all makes sense.
If war is a dude and he's here,
Maybe he's messing with our heads
turning us on each other.
You said, Jo called
you a black-eyed bitch.
they think we're demons.
we think they're demons.
What if there are no demons at all
and we're all just killing each other?
Wait, just back up.
It's the apocalypse?
Sorry, padre.
Who the hell are you?
what are you?
You caught me, popped in to watch.
I can hustle like that.
so, the Roger everyone around
here knows, the real Roger?
Buried in a ditch.
Mm-hmm.
so, who are you?
Here's a hint.
I was in, Germany.
Then in, Germany.
Then in the, middle east.
I was in, Darfur when my beeper went off.
I'm waiting to hook up with my siblings.
I've got three.
We're gonna have so much fun together.
I know who you are.
There aren't any demons
in town, are there?
Nope.
Just frightened people ripping
each other's throats out.
I really haven't had to do too much.
Take out a bridge here, lay in
a little hallucination there,
sit back, pop some corn, watch the show.
Frankly, you're really
vicious little animals, Sam.
No.
you're doing this.
Please.
Last week, this was Mayberry.
Now these people are stabbing
each other's children.
'cause you made them see demons!
Honestly, people don't need
a reason to kill each other.
I mean, you seen the Irish?
They're all Irish.
You think I'm a monster.
I'm Jello shots at a party,
I just remove inhibitions.
I'm gonna kill you myself.
Oh that's adorable,
considering you're my poster boy.
What's that supposed to mean?
You can't stop thinking about it,
ever since you saw it dripping
off the blade of that knife.
You're wrong.
Save your protests for your brother.
I can see inside your head
and man, it is one-track city in there.
Blood, blood, blood.
Lust
for power.
Same as always.
You want to be strong again,
but not just strong.
stronger than everybody.
Good intentions, quick
slide to hell, buddy boy.
you feel bad now?
Wait till you're thigh-deep in warm corpses.
Because my friend, I'm
just getting started.
Show-time for the meat suits.
Watch this.
Aaah!
- He did it!
- No
He said they're coming, he
said they're coming to get us!
Stop Jo, Rufus he's lying.
You shut your mouth.
Please Jo! he's lying!
So now you're saying
that there are no demons
And that war is a guy.
You believed crazy before.
Open up, Let me in!
It's me!
I saw them, the demons.
They know we're trying to leave.
They said they're gonna
pick us off one by one.
Wait, wait, wait. what?
I thought you said there were no demons.
There's not, where did you go?
I thought someone should go
out and see what's going on!
Where did you see the demons
and what did they say exactly?
We just sit here, we're gonna be dead.
No, we're not!
They're gonna kill us,
unless we kill them first.
Okay hold on, hold on.
No man, we got people to protect.
All right, the able-bodied
go hunt some demons.
Whoa, whoa, whoa slow your roll.
this is not a demon thing.
Look at their eyes!
they're demons!
Go, go!
Hope those are real.
Those two could have been
demons the entire time.
All this salt and holy-water talk,
as far as I'm concerned, it's all crap.
Are you sure?
It's them or us.
I think I saw some
knives in the kitchen.
Great.
Go.
Hey, Rufus.
Yeah.
Pipe bombs won't kill a demon.
Right.
But in my experience...
Demons come at you slower
If they're in a body with no limbs.
One of them is in my mother.
Jo, listen to me, you know
I'm gonna do everything I can.
Your mom's gonna be okay.
Unless she comes through that window.
All right, let's move.
Stay low, move fast.
Rufus!
Now, you listen up
Joanna Beth Harvelle.
Listen to me, I'm not a demon.
Think, Rufus all those omens.
You go to hell.
Rufus!
The polluted water, the shooting star,
the red mustang it's war.
I'm telling you, it's war.
You're damn right it is.
The horseman!
Horseman?
Yes, he's turning us against each other.
You're hallucinating.
The horseman.
War.
Yes.
Did you figure this out
all by yourself, genius?
Whoa. whoa.
We all on the same page?
Good.
Hi, Jo.
Hey.
Okay... we got to find war
Before everybody in this
town kills each other.
Damn it!
- Where's, Sam?
- Upstairs.
Take this.
All right, you three go around back.
Take the alley.
Dean, It's not demons.
- It's war.
- War.
I just can't figure
out how he's doing it.
The ring.
The ring, the ring that's right.
He turned it right before
he made everybody hallucinate
- and go hell-bitch.
- Right.
We got to move, come on.
People, cease fire!
Stop shooting!
Stop!
I'm getting too old for this.
I'm not what you think honey.
come on, keep this right here.
"Stop firing" usually
means "stop firing."
Oh!
Whoa, look.
That's a sweet little knife.
But come on.
You can't kill war, kiddos.
Oh, we know.
Aaah!
So, pit-stop at mount doom.
- Dean.
- Sam, let's not.
No, listen, this is important.
I know you don't trust me.
Just... now I realize something.
I don't trust me either.
from the minute I saw that blood,
Only thought in my head,
and I tell myself it's
for the right reasons,
my intentions are good,
and it... it feels true, you know?
But I think, underneath...
...I just miss the feeling.
I know how messed up that sounds,
which means I know
how messed up I am.
Thing is, the problem's not
the demon blood... not really.
and what I did, I can't
blame the blood or, Ruby
or... anything, problems me.
How far I'll go. There's
something in me, that
...scares the hell out of me, Dean and
the last couple of days I caught a little glimpse
- So what are you saying.
- I'm in no shape to be hunting.
I need to step back,
'cause I'm dangerous.
Maybe it's best we just,
go our separate ways.
- Well, I think you're right.
- I was expecting a fight.
Truth is I spend more time worrying about you
than about doing the job right,
I just can't afford that,
you know. Not now.
- I'm sorry, Dean.
- I know you are, Sam.
- Hey, you uh... wanna take the Impala?
- It's okay.
- Take care of yourself, Dean.
- Yeah you too, Sammy.
Sync by honeybunny www.addic7ed.com
Edited by Scooby