Dad wants us to pick
up where he left off
Saving people, hunting
things, the family business.
My dad had a partner on his last hunt.
The guy screwed up, got my dad killed.
What does this have to do
-It was your father, Dean.
Maybe that's what the demon's doing
-Pushing us, finding ways to break us.
I'm Meg.
She's possessed --A human
possessed by a demon.
Key of Solomon --You get a demon
in one, they’re trapped, powerless.
Before dad died, he told
something -Something about you.
He said that I had to save you, and
if I couldn’t, I’d have to kill you.
Did he know the demon's plans for me?
Am I supposed to go dark side?
I never said that.
You're not careful; you will
have to waste me one day, Dean.
Ellen, it’s me again.
Any chance you've heard from him?
I swear, it’s like looking
for my dad all over again.
I'm losing my mind here.
I've called him a thousand times.
It's nothing but voice mail.
I don't know where he went or why.
Sam's just gone.
Hang on.
Sammy, where the hell are you?
Are you okay?
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Calm down.
Where are you?
Don't move.
I'm on my way.
Sam, it’s me.
Sam!
Sam?
Hey.
Hey, Dean.
Are you bleeding?
I tried to wash it off.
Oh, my god.
I don't think it’s my blood.
Whose is it?
I don't know.
Sam, what the hell happened?
Dean...
I don't remember anything.
What did you find out?
You checked in two days ago
under the name Richard sambora.
I think the scariest part about this whole
thing is the fact that you're a bon jovi fan.
Dean.
Your room's been quiet.
Nobody's noticed anything unusual.
You mean no one saw me walking
around covered in blood?
Yeah, that’s what I mean.
Then how the hell did I get here?
What happened to me?
I don't know, but you're
okay, and that's what matters.
Everything else, we can deal with.
Oh, really?
'Cause what if I hurt someone or worse?
Sam.
What if this is what
dad warned you about?
Come on, man.
Let's not jump the gun here.
We don't know what happened.
We got to treat this like any other job.
What's the last thing you remember?
Me and you in that
motel room in west Texas.
We went out to grab some burgers.
West Texas -That was over a week ago.
That's it.
Next thing I knew, I was sitting here...
Bloody.
I felt like I had been
asleep for a month.
Okay, retrace your steps.
Manager said you left yesterday
afternoon and never saw you come back.
Hey.
Recognize anything?
Not really.
Wait.
What?
I think I was here.
You remember?
Not really. It just...
Feels familiar, you know?
Try that one.
Yeah.
Okay.
Wait.
Please tell me you didn't steal this.
More blood.
Sam, backseat.
You think I used this on someone?
I'm not thinking anything.
Okay, now, this is disturbing.
Come on, man.
This couldn't have been you.
It could have been someone else
-Somebody who, uh, smokes menthols.
Hey, a gas receipts, a few towns over.
All right, receipt’s for10
gallons at pump number 2.
You getting any goose bumps yet?
"God, this looks familiar,"déjavu vibes?
Maybe someone inside will remember you.
Come on.
You -Out of here.
Now.
I'm calling the cops.
You talking to him?
Yeah, I’m talking to him.
Jerk comes in yesterday, stinking drunk,
grabs a 40 from the fridge, starts chugging it.
This guy?
You're drinking malt liquor?
Not after he whipped the
bottle at my friggin' head.
This guy?
What, am I speaking Urdu?
I'm really sorry if I did anything
tell your story walking, pal, okay?
Popo will be here in five.
Wait.
He's leaving.
Put the phone down.
Sam, go wait in the car.
But, Dean  go wait in the car!
Okay, look, I just want to
talk to you that are it, okay?
When he took off yesterday,
which way did he go?
Why don't you ask him?
'Cause I'm asking you.
Please, you’d be doing
mea huge favor, okay?
Oh, do you a favor.
Well, that is what I live for.
You know, your buddy didn't pay for the booze
or the smokes, which he also illegally lit up.
You saw him smoking?
Yeah, guy’s a chimney.
This, uh...
Ought to cover it.
Hmm, it’s, uh, it’s
coming back to me now.
He took two packs.
Of course he did.
Heent north on route
71, straight out of town.
What's going on with you, sam, hmm?
The smoking, throwing bottles at people
-That sounds more like me than you.
Dean, wait.
Wait. Here.
Turn down that road.
What?
I don't know how I know.
I just do.
Whoever lives here, I’d say
they don't like surprises.
Should we knock?
Yeah, I guess.
Hey, Dean.
I'm surprised the cops didn’t show -Place
like this you'd think would have an alarm.
Yeah, you would.
Hit the lights.
Dean, I did this.
We don't know that.
What else do you need?
How else do you explain the
car, the knife, the blood?
I don't know, man.
Why don't you tell me?
Even if you did do this, I’m sure you had a reason -You
know, self-Defense, he was a bad son of a bitch --Something.
He doesn't have any I.D.
I need your lock pick.
What?
Either this guy’s a
Unabomber -Or a hunter.
Dean, I think I killed a hunter.
Let's find out.
Here we go.
How do you erase this, huh?
Sam, come on.
I need your help.
I killed him, Dean.
I just broke in and killed him.
Listen to me.
Whoever this guy is, he’s a hunter, which means
other hunters are gonna look for his killer,
Which means we got to
cover our tracks, okay?
His name was Steve Wandell.
This is a letter from his daughter.
Wipe your prints. Then we go.
All right, we get a couple hours' sleep, and
then we put this place in our rearview mirror.
I know this is bad, okay?
You got to snap out of it.
Sam, say something.
Just get some sleep and
leave in the morning?
Murder, Dean
--That's what I did.
Maybe, okay?
Hey, we don't
--Shapeshifter.
Oh, come on.
You know it wasn’t.
You saw the tape.
There was no eye flare, no distortion.
But it wasn't you, all right?
Yeah, it might have been
you, but it wasn't you.
Well, I think it was.
I think maybe more than you know.
What the hell does that mean?
For the last few weeks,
I’ve been having...
I've been having these feelings.
What feelings?
Rage...
Hate.
And I can't stop it.
It just gets worse.
Day by day, it gets worse.
You never told me this.
I didn't want to scare you.
Well, bang-Up job on that.
Dean, the yellow-Eyed demon
-You know he has plans for me.
And we both know that he’s turned
other children into killers before, too.
No one can control you but you.
It sure doesn't seem like that, Dean.
It feels like no matter what I do, slowly
but surely, I’m just becoming --What?
Who I'm meant to be.
You said it onceyourself, Dean.
I got to face up to who I am.
I didn't mean this!
But it's still true.
You know that.
Dad knew that, too.
That's why he told you
if it ever came to this
Shut up, Sam.
Dean, you promised him.
You promised me.
No.
Listen to me.
We're gonna figure this out, okay?
I mean, there’s got to be a way, right?
Yeah, there is.
I don't want to hurt anyone else.
I don't want to hurt you.
You won’t.
Whatever this is, you can fight it.
No, I can’t...
Not forever.
Here. You got to do it.
You know, I’ve tried so
hard to keep you safe.
I know.
I can’t.
I'd rather die.
No.
You'll live.
You'll live to regret this.
It's past your checkout.
What?
It's past checkout, and I have a
couple here that need your room.
Yeah, I’ll bet they do.
What time is it?
12:30.
The guy that was with
me --Have you seen him?
Yeah, he left before dawn in your car, and you should have
gone with him because now I'm gonna have to charge you extra.
Oh, son of a bitch.
It's just policy, sir.
I need to use your computer.
Why would I let you use my computer?
Hi.
Uh, so sorry to bother you, but, uh, my
son snuck out of the house last night and,
Uh, went to a Justin Timberlake concert.
What?
Yeah.
Justin is quite the triple threat.
Uh, anyway, he’s not back
yet, and I'm starting to worry.
Right, yeah, boys will be boys.
But, see, Sammy is a...
Diabetic, and if he doesn't get his
insulin, then I just --I have to find him.
Please, I’m begging you.
No, no, no, I’m on
the website right now.
I just need to activate
the GPS on his cellphone.
Yeah, right there.
Duluth, Minnesota.
Yeah, that is a long
way to go for a concert.
I appreciate your help.
Night.
Thank you.
Sorry, we’re closing up.
How about just one for the road?
Well, you’re about the last
person I'd expect to see.
Well...
I guess I'm full of surprises.
So, can I get a beer?
Sure.
One beer.
So, how’d you find me?
Well, uh, it’s kind of
what we do, you know?
Speaking of "we,?Where’s Dean?
Couldn't make it.
So, what are you doing here, Sam?
We didn't exactly part
on the best of terms.
Right.
That’s why I'm here.
I kind of wanted to see if we
could square things, you know?
That looks like it hurts.
No.
No, just...
Had a run-In with a hot stove.
So, you were saying something
about squaring things?
Yeah.
Look, I know how you feel about my
dad, and I can't say I blame you.
He was obsessed, consumed with hunting, and
he didn't care who got caught in the crossfire.
And I guess that included your dad.
But that was my father.
That's not me.
What about Dean?
Well, Dean’s more like my
father than I am, but he...
Boy...
You’re really carrying a
torch for him, aren’t you?
I'll take that as a yes.
It's too bad.
'Cause, see, Dean, he
likes you, sure, but...
Not in the way you'd want.
I mean, maybe as kind of a little sister,
but romance -That's just out of the question.
He Kind of thinks you’re
a schoolgirl, you know?
I'm not trying to hurt you, Jo.
I -I'm telling you ‘cause I care.
That's real kind of you, Sam.
I mean it.
I care about you a lot.
Sam, what’s going on?
I can be more to you, Jo.
Maybe you should leave.
Okay.
Sam, get off me!
Let go.
Jo, Jo, Jo.
Sam, no, pleases!
Please.
It didn't have to be this way.
Maybe it did.
What the hell's going on?
What are you doing?
So, what exactly did your mom
tell you about how your dad died?
You're not Sam.
Don't be so sure about that.
Answer the question....
Come on.
It's me.
You can tell me anything.
You know that.
Answer the question.
Fine.
Our dads were in California
-Devil's gate reservoir.
They were setting a trap
for some kind of hell spawn.
John was hiding, waiting,
and my dad was bait.
That's just like john.
Oh, I bet he dangled
bill like meat on a hook.
Then what?
The thing showed up.
John got too eager, jumped out too soon,
and got my dad exposed out in the open.
The thing turned around...
And killed him.
Not quite.
What?
See, it hurt him.
It didn't kill him.
You really don't know the truth, do you?
I bet your momdoesn't, either.
Know what?
You see, bill...
Was all clawed up.
He was holding his insides in his hands.
He was gargling and...
Praying to see you and
Ellen one more time.
So my dad...
Killed him.
He put him out of his
misery like a sick dog.
You're lying.
I'm not.
It's true.
My daddy shot your daddy in the head
How could you know that?
I hear things.
Why are you doing this to me?
Like daddy, like daughter.
You're bait.
Open up.
That's a girl.
Sam!
I begged you to stop me, Dean!
Put the knife down, damn it.
I told you I can't fight it!
My head feels like
it’s on fire, all right?
Dean, kill me, or I'm gonna kill her.
Please.
You'd be doing me a favor.
Shoot me.
Shoot me!
No, sammy.Come on.
What the hell’s wrong with you, Dean?
Are you that scared of being
alone that you'd rather let Jo die?
That's holy water, you
demonic son of a bitch!
He was possessed?
Dean!
So, who are you? I got lots of names.
You've been in Sam since
he Disappeared, haven’t you?
Should have seen your face when you
thought He murdered that guy. Pathetic.
Why didn't you kill me?
You had a dozen chances.
No, that would have been too
easy. Where's the fun in that?
See, this was a test. I wanted to see If
I could push you far enough to waste Sam.
I should have known you
wouldn't have the sack.
Anyway, fun’s over now.
Well, I hope you got your kicks
'cause you're gonna pay hell for this.
How? You can't hurt me
- Not without hurting your little brother.
See, I think you're gonna die, Dean
- You and every other hunter I can find.
One look at Sam’s dewy, sensitive eyes,
And they'll let me right in that door.
This is Dean. Leave a message.
Dean!
Take it easy.
Where's Sam? I don't know.
I’ve been looking for you.
Come on. Get up.
Okay. Don’t be a baby!
God.
All right, almost. All
right, got it. Got it.
God, you’re a butcher. You're welcome.
All right, are we done? Would you
give me two minutes to patch you up?
You can't help Sam if
you're bleeding to death.
So, how did you know
that he was possessed?
I didn’t. I just knew that
It couldn't have been him.
Hey, Dean. Yeah.
I know demons lie, But do
they ever tell the truth, too?
Yeah, sometimes, I guess, especially
If they know it'll mess with your head.
Why do you ask?
Nothing. It doesn't matter.
So, do you have any idea?
Where he's headed to next?
So far, he’s been going after the nearest hunter,
So, the closest one I know is in South Dakota.
Okay, good. I’m done. Let’s go.
You're not coming. The hell
I'm not. I’m a part of this now.
I can't say it more plain than this you try and
follow me, And I'll tie you right back to that post.
This is my fight. I’m not
getting Your blood on my hands.
That's just how it's gonna be.
Wait. Here.
Take these. They’ll help with the pain.
Thanks.
I'll call you later, okay?
No, you won’t.
Damn it.
Sam. Hey, bobby.
It's been a while. Come on in.
So, what brings you? Working a job nearby,
and I thought I'd stop in and say hey.
Where's Dean?
Holed up somewhere with
a girl and a 12-Pack.
Oh, yeah? Is she pretty? You ask
me, he’s in way over his head.
Well, it’s good to see you.
To john.
To dad.
What'd you do? Little
holy water in the beer.
Sam never would have noticed,
But, then, you’re not Sam, are you?
Don't try to con a con man.
Ugh!
Dean. Back from the dead.
Getting to be a regular
thing for you, isn’t it?
Like a cockroach.
How about I smack that smart-Ass
Right out of your mouth?
Careful now.
Wouldn't want to bruise this fine packaging
Oh, don’t worry. This isn't gonna hurt Sam much.
You, on the other hand...
Feel like talking now?
Sam's still my meat puppet.
I'll make him bite off his tongue.
No, you won't be in him long enough.
Bobby.
Ee, whatever bitch-Boy master plan you demons Are
cooking up, you’re not getting Sam, you understand me?
'Cause I'm gonna kill
every one of you first.
You really think that's what this is about
- The master plan?
I don't give a rat's ass
about the master plan.
Oops.Doesn't seem to be working.
See, I learned a few new tricks.
This isn't going like I
pictured. What's going on, bobby?
It's a binding link!
It's like a lock. It’s locked
Itself inside Sam’s body.
What the hell do we do? I don't know!
There. That’s better.
You know when people want to
describe The worst possible thing...
They say it's like hell?
Well, there’s a reason for
that. Hell is like, uh...
Well, it’s like hell, even for demons.
It's a prison made of bone
and Flesh and blood and fear.
And you sent me back there.
Meg. No...Not anymore.
Now I'm Sam.
By the way...
I saw your dad there. He says "howdy."
All that I had to hold on to was that I would
Climb out one day and that I was gonna torture you,
Nice and slow, like pulling
the wings off an insect.
But whatever I do to you, it’s nothing
compared To what you do to yourself, is it?
I can see it in your eyes, Dean.
You're worthless. You
couldn't save your dad
And deep down, you know that
You can't save your brother.
They'd have been better off without you.
Sammy?
Did I miss anything?
By the way, you really
look like crap, Dean.
Yeah, right back at you.
What is it, bobby?
You boys ever hear of a
hunter Named Steve Wandell?
Why do you ask?
Just heard from a friend, wandell’s dead
- Murdered in his own house.
You wouldn't know anything about that.
No, sir.Never heard of the guy. Dean.
Good. Keep it that way.
Wandell's buddies are looking for
Someone or something to string up.
They're not gonna slow
down to listen to reason.
You understand what I'm saying?
We better hit the road...
If, uh, you can remember
where we parked the car.
Here. Take these.
What are they? Charms.
They’ll fend off possession.
That demon's still out there. This will
Stop it from getting back up in you.
That sounds vaguely dirty,
but, uh, thanks. You're welcome.
You boys be careful, now. You too.
You okay?
Sam?
Is that you in there?
I was awake for some of it, Dean.
I watched myself kill Wandell with my own
two hands. I saw the light go out in his eyes.
It must have been awful.
That's not my point.
I almost carved up jota.
But no matter what I
did, you wouldn't shoot.
It was the right move,
sam.It wasn't you.
Yeah, this time. What about next time?
Sam, when dad told me that I might have to
kill you, It was only if I couldn't save you.
Now, if it's the last thing
I do, I'm gonna save you.
What?
Nothing.
Dean, what?
Dude, you, like, full-On had a girl
inside you for, Like, a whole week.
That's pretty naughty.