The radio
around here sucks.
Come on man.
Jobs don't get much t1der
than this, you know?
Dead vic with a gnawed-On neck,
body drained of blood,
And a witness who swears up
and down that it was a vampire.
No, I agree.
It's a hell of a case.
A little more gusto,
please.
It's just...
The world
is coming to an end.
Things are a little complicated,
you know?
Yeah, well, we can't save the world,
not today anyway.
But what we can do
is trup off some vamps' heads.
Come on, man,
it's like the good old days.
An honest-To-Goodness
monster hunt.
It's about time the Winchesters
got back to tackling
A straightforward,
black-And-White case.
We still got to see
the new "raiders" movie.
Saw it.
Without me?
You were in hell.
That's no excuse.
Big pretzel!
Thank you.
Guten tag.
"Guten tag" yourself.
Looks like
that's our man.
Sheriff Dietrich.
Are you the boys
from the fed?
Angent anges and Young.
We called ahead about your,
uh, problem.
Right. Um...
I'll tell you what,
Why don't we talk this out
away from the crowd, huh?
Marissa wright, 26,
Just up from lockhard
for the 'fest.
Terrible.
Just terrible.
It's the last thing is town needs
at peak tourist season.
Definitely the last thing
Marissa wright needed.
What the hell?
Yeah, you got me --
I mean,
This killer's some kind
of grade-"A" wacko, right?
I mean, some satan-Worshipping,
anne rice-Reading,
Gothic,
psycho vampire wannabe.
Sheriff, in your report,
you mentioned a witness.
Yeah,
I wished I didn't.
But our witness insisted.
That's Ed Brewer.
Not exactly
what you'd call reliable.
I remember you.
And I remember you...
"Jamie."
I never forget
a pretty...everything.
We're looking
for Ed Brewer.
What do you want
with Ed?
Well,
we are, uh...
...federal agents.
Mr. Brewer was witss to
a serious crime.
-We just --
-Wait a minute.
You're a fed?
Wow, you don't come on
like a fed.
Seriously?
I'm a maverick, ma'am.
A rebewith a badge.
One thing I dot egay
by -- The rules.
Okay, maverick.
So, where can we
find mr. Brewer?
I told the cops
everything I saw.
No one believes me.
Why should you
be any different?
Believe me, mr. Brewer,
we're different.
Psycho ????
And now,
the town is a joke.
Marissa wright's murder
is no joke to us.
And we want to
hear everything,
No matter how strange
it may seem.
We have a lot of experience
with strange.
It was just
after midnight.
I just left here,
and like I do every night,
I cut through the park
on the way home.
At first, I thought it
was a couple kissing.
But she was...
struggling too much.
And this man,
He was -- Well,
he was biting her neck.
Can you describe
her assailant?
Oh, he was a vampire.
Okay, right.
And by that, you mean --
You know,
a vampire.
-Uh-Huh.
-Yeah.
So, he looked like --
He looked like
a vampire,
You know, with the fangs
and the slicked-Back hair
And the fancy cape
And the little medallion thingy
on the ribbon.
You mean
like a dracula?
Exactly.
Like a dracula.
Right down
to the accent.
-The ac.
-Yep.
What did he say?
You know,
something like..
"Stay away, mortal!
The night is mine!"
You do believe me,
don't you?
They must be here following up
on that murdered woman.
Crazy Ed
and vampire story.
He might be weird,
but he's not crazy.
Look,
you're just saying that
'Cause the guy has a crush on you
and he tips you in $20s.
Lucy.
So, you got a beer
back there for me?
I don't know, agent Young.
You off duty?
And then some.
So, what do you think?
Goth, psycho
vampire wannabe, right?
Definitely not
our kind of case.
Agreed.
But who cares?
Room's paid for,
and it's oktoberfest.
Come on, brother.
Beer and bar wenches.
Pretty sure women today don't react well
to the whole "wench" thing, Dean.
Hey, bar wench,
where's that beer?
Coming up,
good sir!
Dude, oktoberfest.
There you go.
What can I get you?
Oh, he doesn't drink.
He's a christian scientist.
Doesn't even take aspirin.
He's a real drag
on stakeouts.
You're funny.
I'm a re than that.
I'd love to get a chance
to show you the rest.
What time you
get off?
Ha ha.
Like I said, "funny."
Man, it is time
to right some wrongs.
Come again?
Look at me.
I came back from the furnace without
any of my old scars, right?
You know, bullet wounds,
knife cuts,
None of the off-Angled fingers
from all the breaks.
I mean, my hide is as smooth
as a baby's bottom,
Which leads me
to conclude,
Sadly...
That my virginity is intact.
What?
-I have been re-Hymenated.
-Re--
Please.
Dean, maybe angels
can pull you out of hell,
But no one
could do that.
Brother,
I have been re-Hymenated.
And the dude
will not abide.
All right, dude.
Well, you go do
whatever you got to do,
And I'm gonna go back
to the room
And get some sleep.
So?
How about tonight?
Oh, sorry.
I promised Lucy
a girls' night out.
Besides,
no self-Respecting bar wench
Lets herself get picked up
by a customer on the first try.
Well, I'm not a customer.
I'm a federal agent.
Try again tomorrow,
g-Man.
I wish I could.
I don't think
we're staying on the case.
What?
Is it too weird for you?
Not weird enough.
Rick.
Did you hear that?
What?
It sounded
like a wolf.
Come on, marie,
don't change the subject.
I told you what could happen
to a man if he doesn't --
Those stories aren't true.
They are.
Baby,
If a man doesn't get the stuff
out of his system regularly,
It can back up and cause
all kinds of...
Medical-Type problems.
Shh,
do you hear that?
Anne marie, there aren't
any wolves in pennsylvania.
And then it just -- It just tore
Rick into little pieces.
Ma'am, we understand
how hard this is,
But can you describe
the creature?
Oh.
It was a werewolf.
A werewolf?
You're sure?
Oh, yeah.
With the furry face
and the black nose
And the claws and the torn-Up
pants and shirt,
Like from
the old movies.
Um, well...
Okay, so...
Thank you for your time.
First a dracula and now
a full-On movie-Time wolf man?
What the hell is going on
in this town?
-Ohh.
-Whew.
Damn!
All right.
Whatever did this
wasn't a psycho wannabe.
Look at
those bite marks.
Right down
to the bone...
And deeper.
Strong enough to tear a healthy man
apart limb from limb.
Could be a werewolf.
Yeah,
except, look.
The heart's still there
in one piece.
They never leave
the heart behind.
Thus I reiterate --
What the hell is going on?
Well, I was hoping you boys
could tell me.
I just got a rush job
back from the lab
On those fibers
we found on the body.
Canine.
Wolf hairs.
I'm getting a headache.
I don't know, man.
Looks like we've stumbled on
To a midnight showing of
"dracula meets wolf man."
Is that it?
I don't know.
I mean, wolf man
seems real enough.
It makes dracula seem
a little less impossible, I guess.
Yeah, but werewolves
don't grow wolf hair.
-That's just a myth.
-Yeah.
So, what?
We've got a vampire
And a werewolf
monster mashing this town?
Looked like you guys
are staying a while.
I heard
about Rick Deacon.
Yeah, this case
just got weird enough for,
Our department.
Well,
beers are on me.
And, just so you know,
I get off at midnight tonight.
Oh, it's not another, uh,
girls' night out?
Doesn't have to be.
Okay, then.
I'll see you tonight.
Hey, you think this dracula
could turn into a bat?
That would be cool.
That's right.
Yeah, an egyptian kind
of deal.
No, it was just sitting there
on the loading dock.
No, doctor,
there's no shipping invoice.
There's no nothing.
I don't know
any was deliver
They was chill
one o'clock in tonight.
I thought you wouldn't to do
You think Helen has
any record of it in her files?
Holy mother of crap!
No!
This sarcophagus
isn't ancient.
It's from a prop house
in philly.
Well...
It goes well with
the bucket of dry ice
He was keeping
in it.
Is he making
his own special effects?
Yeah, a mummy with a good sense
of showmanship.
This is stupid.
Oh, damn it. Jamie.
I'm late.
You're good here
with the mummy and the...crazy
-Yeah.
Your loss,
g-Man.
Good evening.
I have watched you
many nights from afar.
My passion knows
no bounds??!
You are the reincarnation
of my beloved,
And I must have you.
Mary,
son of a...
Jamie!
Son of a bitch.
You should not use
such language
In the presence
of my bride.
Okay.
Jamie, run!
You have no choice
in the matter, mr. Harker.
???
Hey.
You guys all right?
Yeah, I think so.
And I think I know
what's going on.
Yeah?
Part of it
at least.
Uh, the ear part?
Ripped it off
of dracula's head.
Touch it.
Feel familiar to you?
Oh, man.
The skin
of a shapeshifter,
Just like st. Louis
and just like milwaukee.
Of course this one's all
holding buckets of crazy.
Oh, and, uh...
This must have fallen off
during the fight.
Look at the label
on the ribbon.
It's a costume rental.
All three monsters - The dracula,
wolf man, and the mummy --
All the same critter,
Which means we need to
catch this freak
Before he "creature from
the black lagoon's" somebody.
So, you guys are like mulder
and scully or something,
And the x files
are real?
No, "the x files"
is a tv show.
This is real.
Oh.
Okay, so, the stagecraft,
the costuming --
It's like he's trying to reenact
his favorite monster-Movie moments,
Right down
to the bloody murders.
Wait a second.
Who the hell is Mina?
-Mina?
-Yeah.
That's what he called Jamie.
And he called me mr. Harker.
Jonathan Harker?
They're characters from
the movies and the novels --
Mina,
dracula's intended bride,
Harker, the fianc ???
Seems like
he's fixating on you,
Like he sees you
as his bride.
Wow.
Lucky me.
But to fixate on you,
My guess is that the shifter has to
have seen you before or been around you.
Jamie, has anybody strange
come to town,
Somebody that has taken
a specific notice of you?
I don't know, Dean.
It's oktoberfest.
I'm a bartender.
There's lots of people.
I...
Wait a second.
There is Ed.
"Ed Brewer" Ed?
Yeah.
He moved here
about a month ago.
Lucy swears
he has a crush on me.
He comes in
almost every night.
But, you know, I don't think
he's the type of guy --
Where does Ed live?
I don't know.
But he works
at the old movie theater.
I think
he's a projectionist there.
-Take care of Mina?
-Yep.
So, monsters are real.
Some of them, yeah.
And the shapeshifter,
He can turn
into different people.
Yeah.
Yeah,except this one's turning into
the great monstersof screenland,
Which is a new one
for me.
You're not really fbi,
are you?
Not so much.
So,
this is what you do?
You and your partner
just tramp across the country
On your own dime
Until you find some
horrible nightmare to fight?
Some people paint.
What?
That must suck.
I mean, you're giving up
your life for this terrible...
I don't know,
responsibilit
Last few years,
I started thinking that way,
And, uh, it started
sort of weighing on me.
Of course,
that was before...
A little while ago,
I had this --
It's called
a near-Death experience.
Very near.
And, uh...
...when came to...
Things were different.
My life's
been different.
I realize
that I help people.
Not just help them,
though. I save them.
I guess it's --
It's awesome.
It's kind of like
gift...
Like a mission.
Kind of like a...
a mission from god.
So, does that make you...
Some kind of monk
or something?
You know, celibate?
Man, I hope not.
Holy crap.
Oh, my god. Jamie.
Guys,
I'm -- I'm sorry.
I thought you guys
were going out.
Lucy,
it's -- It's okay.
-Uh, listen --
-You know what?
I just -- I came to
borrow a bottle.
I kind of got something
going back at my...
Anyway, uh,
you guys look really busy,
So I'm just gonna get out
of your hair.
Seriously, Lucy,
it's been a crazy night.
Stay for a drink.
Yeah. Stay for a drink.
Whoa!
You, fbi man --
What did I --
Shut up, okay,
you know what you did.
What?
I know what you are.
I'm not anything.
I just like to play the casio.
Had time to grow
the ear back, huh?
What?!
Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow!
It's supposed to come off.
No, it's not!
Oh, that sounds awful.
Jamie, honey, are you okay?
Oh, I am fine.
He didn't even touch me.
Dean, he just blew right in
and fought him off.
Well,
I didn't actually fly,
But I'm sure it seemed
that way at the time.
It was really,
really something.
Jamie
So, Dean, are you like
a black belt or what?
Well,I guess they train you to fight
at the academy or whatever.
Dean,
what are you doing?
It's you,
isn't it?
Oh, damn it!
What did you put
in the drinks?!
That's all right.
I'll skin you myself.
And...scene.
Oh, come on.
She is beautiful,
No?
Bride number three
from the first film.
She never got the acclaim
that she deserved.
Which is why
I chose her shape,
Her form to move
among the mortals unnoticed,
To listen to the cricket songs
of the living.
That is when I discovered
my bride had been reborn
In this century.
I can't get over
what a pumpkin-Pie-Eyed,
Crazy son of a bitch
you really are.
You're not dracula.
You get that, right?
Or even if you think
you are dracula,
What the hell's up
with the mummy?!
I am all monsters!
Life ain't a movie,
you sorry sack of --
Aah.
Life is small.
Meager messy
The movies are grand,simple,elegant.
I have chosen elegance.
You think "elegance" is really the word
For what you did to Marissa or Rick Deacon
Or any of the others?!
But of course.
It is a monster movie,after all.
You do realize what happens
At the end of every monster movie?
Ah. But this movie is mine.
And in it,the monster wins.
The monster gets the girl.
And the hero,he's...electrocuted.
And tonight,jonathan Harker,
You will be my hero.
Wait,wait,wait,wait.
Please,excuse me.
Good evening.
Uh...pizza delivery.
Ah,you've brought a repast.
Excellent.
Continue to be of such service
And your life will be spared.
Uh-Huh.
That'll be $15.50.
Tell me... yeah?
...is there garlic on this pizza?
I don't know. Did you order garlic?
No!
Then no.
Look,mister,I got four other deliveries to make.
You want to just pay me e money so I can go?
Yes. C
But I have a coupon.
Dean,hey,listen,uh,Ed is not our guy.
Um,I'm guessing you're at home with Jamie,
So just give me a call,okay?
Lucy.
You wake.
The gown -- It suits your beauty.
Please,put it on.
Where am I?
What have you done with Dean?
Harker is resting elsewhere.
Please,put on the gown and you may dine.
We are having pizza.
What?
What is wrong with you?
You made up Lucy,right? Pretended to be my friend.
I needed to know if you were the one.
You could try talking to people!
But instead you become this?
the gown.
I don't want to play your stupid game,okay?
I just --I just want to go home.
Put on the gown!
I scared you.
You were the only one I don't want to scare.
I used to love the movies.
They aren't real.
You can't make them real.
"Real" is being born this way.
Different.
"Real" is having your dad call you "monster" --
It's the first time you hear the word --
And he tries to beat you to death with a shovel.
Everywhere I ran,everywhere I tried to hide,
People found me,n dagged me
Called me "freak," called me "monster."
Then I found them.
The great monsters.
In their movies,they were strong.
They were feared.
They were beautiful.
And now I am like them.
Commanding.
terrifying.
Lonely.
was lonely.
Now I --
I have you.
Ever think that maybe you're lonely
Because you kill people?
Or I kill people because I'm lonely.
Did you hear that?
What?
Dean?
Dean!
Oh,thank god. Just in the nick of time.
That guy was about to frankenstein me.
Hey there,handsome.
Shut up!
Let's go.
Aah!
[ Hungarian accent ] you will never be van helsing!
And you,Harker,now you die.
How 'bout now you shut the hell up?
Silver?
It was beauty that killed the beast.
No,Mina,do not weep.
Perhaps this is how
The movie should end.
Well,thank you,g-Man.
You have been a great service to your co
Oh,yes,I'm very,very patriotic.
Bye.
You guys saved my life,you know?
So,thanks.
I like her.
Feels good to be back on the job,doesn't it?
Yeah,it does.
The hero gets the girl,
Monster gets the gts all in all,happy ending --
With a happy ending,no less.
[ Chuckles ] real classy,Dean.
Hey,all I'm saying is
The shifter man had a point,you know?
It would be nice if life was movie simple.
Although,if I was turning life into a movie,
I wouldn't do this "abbott and costello meet the monster" crap.
Yeah. No,I know what you'd pick.
no,you don't.
,do.
No,you don't.
You don't. "Porky's ii."
What? You heard me.
Lucky guess.