You think Adam's okay?
No! No!
Dean!
Doubt it.
Cass either.
The cage you sprung
Lucifer from...
you can shove his ass back in.
The key to the cage...
four rings from The Horsemen.
Well, we got War's.
We nicked Famine's.
That's two rings down.
Collect all four.
I can give you Pestilence.
Do you want The
Horsemen ring's or not?
What are we dealing with?
Do you know?
Croatoan. It's a virus of
Plague and Pestilence.
More like demonic germ warfare.
They want our vaccine.
They need our vaccine.
It's called "demand,"
people. Now, supply!
Sir, great news.
The vaccine trials...
the results have been...
really quite grotesque.
I think you'll be pleased.
Oh, hello, Death.
You make a wish.
I can give you
anything you want, mate.
Up to and including
Death's coordinates.
All I need is...
My soul.
Say we can open the cage.
But then what?
What if you guys
lead the devil to the edge
and I jump in?
Dr. Green,
how was your trip?
Oh, very productive.
And how are we tonight,
Celeste, my favorite patient?
The nurse says you can't sleep.
Oh, I just feel
worse and worse.
Well, that's because you're
suffering from a combination
of the common cold...
Dengue fever...
and a nasty, nasty case
of Japanese encephalitis.
What are you...
I'm sorry. I...
Oh, you heard me.
Oh, and look at that.
You never had
chicken-pox as a child.
Oh, this is gonna be fascinating.
But I...
h-how could I...
Have all those diseases at once?
Well, it's a proprietary blend.
I mix it up in a petri dish.
The petri dish being... you.
Try and relax.
It'll be all right.
Are you... gonna c-cure me?
No.
You're going to die.
In four, three...
Two...
Interesting.
Season 5 Episode 21
"Two Minutes to Midnight"
What the hell
is wrong with you?
- Dean...
- No, don't "Dean" me.
I mean, you... you have had
some stupid ideas in the past,
but this...
Did you know about this?
- What.
- About Sam's genius plan
to say yes to the Devil?
Well, thanks for the heads up!
Hey, this ain't
about me.
You can't do this.
That's the consensus.
All right. Awesome.
Then, end of discussion.
This isn't over.
Hello?
- Dean?
- Cass?
Is he okay?
We all thought you were Dead.
Where the hell are you, man?
A hospital.
Are you okay?
No.
You want to elaborate?
I just woke up here.
The doctors
were fairly surprised.
They thought
I was brain-dead.
S-so, a hospital?
Apparently, after Van Nuys...
I suddenly appeared,
bloody and unconscious,
on a shrimping boat
off Delacroix.
I'm told it upset the sailors.
Uh, well, I got
to tell you, man...
you're just in time.
We figured out a way
to pop Satan's box.
How?
It's a long story, but, look...
We're going after Pestilence now.
So if you want to
zap over here...
I can't "zap" anywhere.
What do you mean?
You could say my batteries
are... are drained.
What do you mean,
you're out of angel mojo?
I'm saying that I am thirsty
and my head aches.
I have a bug bite that itches no
matter how much I scratch it,
and I'm saying
that I'm just incredibly...
Human.
Wow.
Sorry.
Well, my point is... I can't
go anywhere without money
for... an airplane ride.
And food.
And more pain medication, ideally.
All right.
Well, look, no worries.
Uh, Bobby's here.
He'll wire you the cash.
- Dean, wait.
- I will?
You said "no" to Michael.
I owe you an apology.
Cass...
I-it's okay.
You are not the burnt
and broken shell of a man
that I believed you to be.
Thank you.
I appreciate that.
You're welcome.
Be careful.
So this is
Dr. Evil's lair, huh?
It's kind of more
depressing than evil.
It's like a four-color
brochure for dying young.
Of course, to Pestilence, it's
probably dolly-wood in there.
Great.
A whole building
full of people.
We don't know who's human,
who's demon,
and who's Pestilence.
So what do we do?
Hang on.
Hey. Hi.
Uh, I'm looking for my Nana.
Uh, her name is Eunice Kennedy.
Go around front
and see the nurse.
You mind just
helping me out, sir?
Uh, she's about, uh,
about that small
and gray hair, wears diapers.
Eunice Kennedy?
That's the beauty
about improv, Sammy.
You never know what's gonna
come out of your mouth.
So, what are...
Hey.
What are we even looking for?
Well, he's Pestilence,
so he probably looks sick.
Everybody looks sick.
Hey.
Oh, now we're talking.
Dr. Green,
how was your trip?
Oh, very productive.
And how are we tonight,
Celeste, my favorite patient?
Sir...
the Winchesters are here.
We should go.
Are you kidding me?
They have a track
record with Horsemen.
You mean my brothers.
What they did to my brothers.
No.
The only reasonable thing
to do here is to...
take it out of their
healthy young asses.
We're under strict orders
not to kill the vessels.
Oh, if Satan wants them so bad,
he can glue them back together!
Come. Come.
Now then.
- Page me if she's dying.
- Yes, Doctor.
Ugh...
Must be getting close.
You think?
Dean?
Get up.
The doctor will see you now.
Sam.
Dean.
Come right in.
Hmm.
You boys don't look well.
It might be
the, uh, Scarlet fever.
Or, uh, the meningitis.
Oh!
Or the syphilis.
That's no fun.
However you feel right now?
It's gonna get so
very, very much worse.
Questions?
Disease gets a bad rap,
don't you think?
For being filthy, chaotic.
Uh, but, really, t-that just
describes people who get sick.
Disease itself...
very... pure...
single-minded.
Bacteria have one purpose...
divide and conquer.
That's why, in the end...
it always wins.
So, you've got to wonder
why God pours all his love
into something so messy...
and weak.
It's ridiculous.
All I can do is
show him he's wrong.
One epidemic at a time.
Now...
on a scale of 1 to 10,
how's your pain?
Cass.
How'd you get here?
I took a bus.
Don't worry, I...
Well, look at that.
An occupied vessel, but powerless.
Oh, that's fascinating.
There's not a speck of
angel in you, is there?
Oh!
Maybe just a speck.
It doesn't matter.
It's too late.
Well, it's nice to
actually score a home run
for once, ain't it?
What?
Last thing Pestilence said.
"It's too late."
He get specific?
No.
We're just a little freaked out
that he might have
left a bomb somewhere.
So please tell us
you have actual good news.
Chicago's about
to be wiped off the map.
Storm of the millennium.
Sets off a daisy chain
of natural disasters.
Three million people
are gonna die.
Huh.
I don't understand
your definition of good news.
Well...
Death, The Horsemen...
he's gonna be there.
And if we can stop him before
he kick-starts this storm,
get his ring back...
Yeah, you make
it sound so easy.
Hell, I'm just trying to
put a spin on it.
Well...
Bobby, h-how'd you put
all this together, anyways?
I had, you know... help.
Don't be so modest.
I barely helped at all.
Hello, boys.
Pleasure, et cetera.
Go ahead. Tell them.
There's no shame in it.
Bobby?
Tell us what?
World's gonna end.
Seems stupid to get all precious
over one little... soul.
You sold your soul?
Oh, more like pawned it.
I fully intend to give it back.
Well, then give it back!
- I will.
- Now!
- Did you kiss him?
- Sam!
Just wondering.
No!
Why'd you take a picture?
Why do you have to use tongue?
All right. You know what?
I'm sick of this.
Give him his soul back now.
- I'm sorry. I can't.
- Can't or won't?
I won't, all right?
It's insurance.
- What are you talking about?
- You kill demons.
Gigantor over there
has a temper issue about it.
But you won't kill me...
as long as I have that soul
in the deposit box.
You son of a bitch.
I'll return it.
After all this is over,
and I can walk safely away.
Do we all
understand each other?
Let me guess.
We're about to have a talk.
Look, Dean, um...
for the record...
I agree with you
about me.
You think I'm too weak
to take on Lucifer.
Well, so do I.
Believe me, I know exactly
how screwed up I am.
You, Bobby, Cass...
I'm the least of any of you.
- Oh, Sam...
- No, it's true. It is.
But...
I'm also all we got.
If there was another way...
but I don't think there is.
There's just me.
So I don't know
what else to do.
Except just try to do
what's got to be done.
And...
scene.
There's something
you need to see.
Niveus pharmaceuticals
is rushing delivery
of its new swine-flu vaccine,
to quote, "stem the tide of
the unprecedented outbreak."
Uh, shipments leave Wednesday.
Niveus pharmaceuticals.
Get it?
You two are lucky
you have your looks.
Your demon lover, Brady?
V.P. of distribution... Niveus.
Ah, yes, that the sound
of the abacus clacking?
We all caught up?
So, Pestilence was
spreading swine flu.
Yeah, but not just for giggles.
That was step one.
Step two is the vaccine.
- And you think...
- I know.
I'll stake my reputation...
That vaccine is chock-full
of grade-A,
farm-fresh Croatoan virus.
Simultaneous, countrywide distribution.
It's quite a plan.
They don't get to be
Horsemen for nothing.
So, you boys
better stock up on...
well, everything.
This time next Thursday...
we'll all be living
in zombie-land.
Watch where
you're walking, pal.
What's your problem?
This is what they mean
by "the 11th hour," right?
Pretty much.
Well, it's the 11th hour,
and I am useless.
All I have is this.
What am I even
supposed to do with it?
Point it and shoot.
What I used to be...
Are you really gonna
bitch... to me?
Quit pining
for the varsity years...
and load the damn truck.
All right, well...
good luck stopping
the whole zombie apocalypse.
Yeah.
Good luck killing Death.
Remember when we used to just...
hunt Wendigos?
How simple things were?
Not really.
Well, um...
you might need this.
Keep it.
Dean's covered.
Death's own.
Kills, golly, demons
and angels and reapers
and... rumor has it,
the very thing itself.
How did you get that?
Hello... king of the crossroads.
So, shall we?
Bobby, you just
gonna sit there?
No, I'm gonna river-dance.
I suppose if you want
to impress the ladies.
Bobby, Bobby, Bobby.
Really wasted that crossroads deal.
Fact... you get more if
you phrase it properly.
So, I took the
liberty of adding
a teeny little sub-a-clause
on your behalf.
What can I say?
I'm an altruist.
Just gonna sit there?
Son of a bitch.
Yes, I know.
Completely worth your soul.
I'm a hell of a guy.
Thanks.
This is getting maudlin.
Can we go?
"Yes" to Lucifer,
then jump in the hole.
It's an interesting plan.
That's a word for it.
So?
Go ahead and tell me it's
the worst plan you ever heard.
Of course.
I am happy to say that
if that's what you want to hear.
But it's not what I think.
Really?
You and Dean have a habit
of exceeding my expectations.
He resisted Michael,
maybe you could
resist Lucifer
But there are things
that you would need to know.
Like?
Michael has found
another vessel.
What?
It 's your brother, Adam.
You must have considered it.
We were trying not to.
Sam...
if you say yes to Lucifer
and then fail...
This fight will happen.
And the collateral...
it'll be immense.
There's also the demon blood.
What? What are you
talking about?
To take in Lucifer, it would be
more than you've ever drunk.
But... why?
It strengthens the vessel.
Keeps it from exploding.
But the guy he's in now...
is drinking gallons.
And how is that not
the worst plan you ever heard?
Yup, they're loading up hotshots
of Croatoan in the trucks.
Okay. First truck
don't leave for an hour.
We get in,
we plant the C-4 every 25 feet,
then we pull the fire alarm.
That truck is leaving.
Balls!
Okay, new plan.
It's the Winchesters.
Well, then, let's bake
them up a little treat.
- Help!
- Side door!
- Get back.
- Help me, please!
Get back!
Go. Come on. Go.
Help me! Please, help!
There's still people here.
Sam, no!
Wait here.
Damn.
Hey, let's stop for pizza.
Are you kidding?
Just heard it
was good, that's all.
Up ahead.
Big, ugly building.
Ground zero.
Horseman's stable, if you will.
He's in there.
How do you know?
Have you met me?
'Cause I know.
Also, the block is
squirming with reapers.
I'll be right back.
Boy, is my face red.
Death's not in there.
You want to cut the cute
and get to the part
where you tell me where he is?
Sorry. I don't know.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Wait a minute.
You don't know?
Signs pointed.
I-I'm just as shocked as you.
Bobby sold his soul for this!
Relax.
All deals are soul back
or store credit.
We'll catch Death
in the next doomed city.
Millions, Crowley.
Millions of people
are about to die any minute.
True.
So I strongly suggest
we get out of here.
You okay?
Go! Go!
So, what?
Call in a bomb threat?
1,000 bomb threats?
I men, how the hell
am I supposed to get
three million people out of
Chicago in the next 10 minutes?
Come on!
What?
I can't hear you!
I said I found him.
Death...
he's in there.
You coming or...
not.
Go! Go!
All clear.
Sam!
Actually,
these things can be useful.
Can we commit our act
of domestic terrorism already?
Let's go.
Thanks for returning that.
Join me, Dean.
The pizza's delicious.
Sit down.
Took you long enough
to find me.
I've been wanting
to talk to you.
I got to say...
I have mixed feelings about that.
S-so is this the part where...
where you kill me?
You have an inflated sense
of your importance.
To a thing like me,
a thing like you, well...
think how you'd feel
if a bacterium sat at your table
and started to get snarky.
This is one little planet
in one tiny solar system
in a galaxy that's barely
out of its diapers.
I'm old, Dean.
Very old.
So I invite you to contemplate
how insignificant I find you.
Eat.
Good, isn't it?
Well, I got to ask.
How old are you?
As old as God.
Maybe older.
Neither of us
can remember anymore.
Life, death, chicken, egg.
Regardless... at the end,
I'll reap him, too.
God?
You'll reap God?
Oh, yes.
God will die too, Dean.
Well, this is way
above my pay grade.
Just a bit.
So, then why
am I still breathing...
sitting here with you?
Uh... w-what do you want?
The leash around my neck... off.
Lucifer has me bound to him.
Some unseemly little spell.
He has me where he wants,
when he wants.
That's why I couldn't go to you.
I had to wait
for you to catch up.
He made me his weapon.
Hurricanes, floods,
raising the dead.
I'm more powerful
than you can process,
and I'm enslaved to a bratty
child having a tantrum.
And you think...
I can unbind you?
There's your ridiculous
bravado again.
Of course you can't.
But you can help me
take the bullets
out of Lucifer's gun.
I understand you want this.
Yeah.
I'm inclined to give it to you.
To give it to me?
That's what I said.
But what about... Chicago?
I suppose it can stay.
I like the pizza.
There are conditions.
Okay. Like?
You have to do
whatever it takes
to put Lucifer in his cell.
Of course.
Whatever it takes.
That's the plan.
No. No plan. Not yet.
Your brother.
He's the one
that can stop Lucifer.
The only one.
What, you think...
I know.
So, I need a promise.
You're going to
let your brother
jump right into that fiery pit.
Well, do I have your word?
Okay, yeah.
Yes.
That had better be "yes," Dean.
You know you can't cheat Death.
Now, would you like
the instruction manual?
Well, how'd it go
at the Rockettes audition?
Well, high kicks... fair.
Boobs need work.
I walked up and down stairs
all night for no damn reason.
I'm sore.
Feels so good,
I'm scared it's a dream.
But then I remember that
the world's dying bloody...
so, drink?
Check it out.
Hmm.
Oh.
So Death told you
how to operate those?
The whole deal?
Yeah. It's nuts.
Of course,
I got bigger problems now.
Really? Like?
What do you think Death does
to people who lie to his face?
- Nothing good.
- Yeah.
What'd you say?
That I was cool with Sam
driving the bus
on the whole Lucifer plan.
So death thinks Sam
ought to say yes, huh?
I don't know. Yeah.
Hmm.
But, I mean...
of course he'd say that.
He works for Lucifer.
Against his will,
I thought he said.
Well, I'd say, take his sob
story with a fat grain of salt.
I mean, he is Death.
Exactly, he's Death.
Think of the kind of
bird's-eye view.
Seriously?
- I'm just saying...
- Well, don't.
I mean, what happened
to you being against this?
Look, I'm not saying Sam
ain't an ass-full
of character defects.
- But...
- But what?
Back at Niveus...
I watched that kid pull
one civilian out after another.
He must have saved 10 people.
Never stopped.
Never slowed down.
We're hard on him, Dean.
We've always been.
But in the meantime...
he's been running
into burning buildings
since he was... what, 12?
Pretty much.
Look, Sam's got a...
darkness in him.
I'm not saying he don't.
But he's got a hell of a lot
of good in him, too.
I know.
Then you know
Sam will beat the devil...
or die trying.
That's the best
we could ask for.
So I got to ask, Dean.
What exactly are you afraid of?
Losing?
Or losing your brother?
Edited by Scooby