Underworld Evolution -
Action 2006 [H264-mp4] English
My God. Brother, what have you done?
Yet again we arrive to witness
this monster's aftermath.
I will not tolerate this
any longer, Marcus.
Your brother must be stopped.
It ends tonight.
We must move quickly, before they turn.
Is he still here?
Yes.
Viktor, he must not be harmed.
I gave you my word, did I not?
But William must be controlled.
Burn the bodies.
Search the outbuildings.
Form two groups. You,
douse them with fuel...
Marcus.
Stay with me.
Give me the torch.
They're turning!
Retreat to the woods.
I'll stay and fight. You need my help.
I need you alive.
If you die, we all die.
Now, go.
Go!
We found him.
And?
We need more men.
Find Amelia.
Amelia, we found William.
Surround him!
Take him down.
No.
Leave him be.
Stop this, you're killing him.
More!
William.
Marcus!
He was not to be harmed.
Place him in my charge as we agreed
or you will pay for your deceit.
And you will learn your place.
Your sympathy for this beast is foolish.
Your brother is entirely beyond control.
It will be done my way.
You know well the consequences
if you murder me or William.
If you so much as speak his name again
you will have chosen that future for him.
What is thy will, my lord?
Imprisonment for all time.
Far from you.
For six centuries I was a loyal
soldier of the Vampire clan.
But I was betrayed.
The war was not as it had seemed.
In one night,
the lies that had united
our kind had been exposed.
Kraven, our second-in-command
had formed a secret alliance with Lucian
ruler of the Werewolf clan
to overthrow Viktor, our leader.
But Kraven's lust for power
and domination had failed.
Viktor was not the saviour
I had been led to believe.
He had betrayed us all.
Soon the hunt will be on for his killer.
I have but one ally left.
Michael
the human descendant of Corvinus.
Neither Vampire nor Lycan
but a hybrid.
It's only a matter of
time before we're found.
Underworld: Evolution.
My only hope now is to awaken Marcus
our last remaining elder
and expose the truth
before Kraven tries to murder him
while he's still in hibernation.
Kraven knows he's no match for him awake.
Perfect.
This thing's been dead for weeks.
I thought Lycans went back to
their human form when they die.
They do.
This one's been given a
serum to stop regression
so it can be studied.
How can you tell?
Not quite your department, I guess.
I just killed them.
I didn't pay much attention
to their anatomy.
How long can we stay here?
Not long.
These safe houses are all linked
together on one mainframe
with motion sensors revealing
which ones are active.
Someone could have picked us up already.
There's only about an hour till daylight.
Can you even make it back to
the mansion before sunrise?
Just.
Okay, let's get what we need and go.
No.
I'm going alone.
Open it.
Marcus?
The blood memories of
this wretched creature,
have shown me that your
treachery knows no bounds.
My lord, I can explain.
Why would I listen to your lies
when the journey to the truth
is so much sweeter?
I kept his secrets,
cleaned up the mess.
You'll go before Viktor
and tell him exactly what I tell you to!
You just concentrate on your part.
Please.
I can assist you.
Oh, you already have.
If I can plead my case,
there's a chance you'll
be granted sanctuary.
Right now, you'll be killed on sight.
I'm not prepared to risk it.
So what am I supposed to
do, sit and wait for you?
No, Kraven may still have his men with him.
You're not going alone.
You're not as strong as you might think.
What?
Michael, you're unique.
There's never been a hybrid before.
However ambivalent you might feel about it,
the truth is your powers
could be limitless.
But you depend on blood.
You need to feed.
Without it, you'll be growing weaker,
by the second. Use the time for that.
Jesus Christ.
And what if I don't?
What if I can't?
Normal food could be lethal.
If you don't anticipate your
cravings, you will attack humans.
And believe me, you don't
want that on your conscience.
There really is no going back, Michael.
I'm sorry.
Look, I understand what you did.
I'm grateful.
You saved my life.
I wasn't ready to die.
I don't know.
Every thing's changed.
I probably need just a minute
to make it all fit in my head.
It's a lot to process all at once.
Look, go.
I'll be here.
You just make sure you come back.
Sir.
The innocent who witnessed...
they've been silenced?
But otherwise unharmed, as ordered.
Show me what you have.
Yes, sir.
Two Death Dealers were killed.
We found no Lycan bodies.
Apparently they were using
a new kind of ammunition,
some sort of UV round.
Amelia?
No one survived.
It seems Kraven's men
might have been present,
but they did nothing to prevent it.
And Viktor?
And no trace of Marcus amongst the ashes?
It seems he destroyed his own coven, sir.
It was never his coven.
We need to go.
Give me a moment.
There you are.
How you doing?
Thank you.
[ Speaks In Hungarian ]
You've got to get away from me.
Get away from me!
[ Speaks In Hungarian ]
There.
Get the men up there. Now.
[ Speaks In Hungarian ]
Get the fuck away from me.
Shit.
[ Speaks In Hungarian ]
Michael.
Here. Take it.
No.
Michael, you'll die.
Shit.
Can you move?
We need to go.
Marcus.
I know what you've done, Selene.
Viktor deserved his fate
and Kraven was no better.
Kraven has already reaped the
rewards of his own misdeeds.
And Viktor,
Viktor deserved his fate, many times over.
A terrible business,
the slaying of your family.
Yet so much effort was spent to
conceal this matter from me.
What do you suppose Viktor had to hide?
Or perhaps it is you, Selene
as the last of your wretched family
who has something to hide.
Go!
Get in.
Dead or alive, you will
give me what I want.
You okay?
He's a hybrid, isn't he?
Yes.
He wanted this. Why?
I don't know.
But we have another problem.
Turn off up here.
Shit.
All right, get down.
Keep your foot on the gas, but stay down.
Hold on.
Stay down.
Come on.
Give me your hand.
Jesus Christ.
There's really no need.
I'll be right back.
All right, let me see.
See?
No need.
[ Speaking In Hungarian ]
Area secure, sir.
Sun's setting.
What's wrong?
The supplies were taken. Used
weapons were left behind.
The tavern events occurred
just before dawn,
so they couldn't have got very far.
Remain airborne for the moment.
I'm sure they'll reappear in good time.
Yes, sir.
I've seen this before, when I was a child.
I've held it.
When it was open, like this.
How is that possible?
I don't know.
But I know someone that might.
Andreas Tanis.
He was the official
historian of the covens.
He fell from favour after documenting what
Viktor considered malicious lies.
Of course, as it turns out, he
was probably telling the truth.
What happened to him?
He was exiled over 300 years ago.
300 years?
What makes you think we're
gonna find him now?
I was the one who exiled him.
Looks like a monastery.
It used to be. More like a prison now.
Tanis has been hiding there
since Viktor's order.
We'll be the first people
he's seen in centuries.
That's odd.
What?
I don't remember this
gate being here before.
Take this.
Shit.
Go back!
Gotcha.
Fuck.
I knew it was you, Selene.
The stench of Viktor's blood
still lingers in your veins.
Tanis.
I see your aim hasn't improved.
You haven't changed.
You don't scare me, Selene.
Well, we're gonna have to work on that.
We need to talk.
Your exile seems a bit more
comfortable than I remember.
How does a Vampire have Lycan bodyguards?
A gift.
From a most persuasive client.
Lucian.
Why would Lucian wanna protect you?
Because he was trading with them.
UV rounds.
How long have you been in the
business of killing your own kind?
I've done what's necessary to survive.
My decision was made easy the day
your precious Viktor betrayed me.
Betrayal was something he did very well.
Viktor's dead. I killed him.
You?
Kill Viktor?
No, I think not.
Oh, unless you've learned the truth.
Ah...
So your eyes are finally open.
Isn't it interesting how the truth
is even harder to absorb than light?
You know, I tried to stop him, of course.
A travesty, committing
such a horrible crime.
And then turning you.
That was too much to take.
My protests are why he put me here.
Careful with that, dear.
Makes a terrible bang.
Open the blades and they're active.
Good to know.
Viktor put you here for a reason,
but I doubt it was because
you had moral qualms.
What do you know?
Very little of anything, I'm afraid.
Well,
then, perhaps I'm mistaken and
there's no use for you at all.
Marcus was after this. Why?
Some history is based on truth
and others on deception.
Viktor was not the first of our
kind, as you were led to believe.
He was once human
the ruler of these lands.
Marcus
he's the one.
The source.
The first true Vampire.
So the legend is true.
Toward the end of his ruthless life,
when the next breath meant more
to Viktor than silver or gold,
Marcus came
with an offer,
a reprieve from sickness and death.
Immortality.
And in return, Viktor was to use his
army-turned-immortal to help him.
To do what?
To defeat the very first Werewolves,
a dangerous and infectious breed
created by Marcus' own flesh and blood.
His twin brother, William.
But these weren't the Lycans we know.
Disgusting though your brethren may be,
they at least are evolved.
No, these were raging monsters.
Never able to take human form again.
It was only later generations that
learned to channel their rage.
And William's appetite for destruction
and rampage was insatiable.
He had to be stopped.
And so once Viktor's army was turned,
the legions of Vampires under his control
tracked down and destroyed the animals,
then captured William
and locked him away.
Viktor's prisoner for all time.
Why let him live?
For the very same reason that Viktor
never conspired against Marcus.
Fear.
He was warned that, should
Marcus ever be killed,
all those in his bloodline
would follow him to the grave.
So in Viktor's mind,
William's death would mean
the end for all Lycans,
his slaves.
Yes.
Yes, a clever deception,
but one Viktor was hardly
willing to put to the test.
And so Marcus was protected
at all costs.
Ah, yes, here we are.
Vampires?
Mortals.
Men loyal to Alexander Corvinus.
The father of us all.
What's this?
You should know.
It's William's prison.
The prison your father was
commissioned to build.
So you've been the one keeping a
watch over this for me, have you?
I've been searching everywhere
for this, my darling.
What is it?
What's wrong?
She now understands why
her family was killed.
But that was many years later.
The winter of Lucian's escape.
Your father knew too much.
Or too much for Viktor to risk,
especially when Lucian
had the key to William's cell.
And I'm the map.
Yes.
The only one still living
who has seen its location.
Oh, Viktor realized you'd be too
young to remember explicitly,
but Marcus knows that the memory,
and therefore the exact
location of William's prison
is hidden away in your blood.
Why is Marcus looking for him now
after all this time?
That I cannot answer.
But I do know someone who could stop him.
Perhaps I could arrange a meeting.
In exchange for your discretion, of course.
Of course.
Tanis.
You seem anxious.
Why do you flee the very sight of me?
Please...
sit.
There's no need for this to be unpleasant.
I've always rather enjoyed your company.
Now you're being rude.
Sorry.
Viktor struck two keys.
What do you know of them?
Keys?
I don't know of any keys.
Oh, yes.
Yes, those keys.
Yes.
Well, one was...
One was kept in plain sight,
draped around his daughter's neck,
right there for you to see.
And the other?
Kept with Viktor at all times.
Where?
Within him.
Beneath the flesh.
Please. Please. I beg you. Please.
Who could stop him. Perhaps
I could arrange a meeting.
Go to pier 17.
Ask for Lorenz Macaro.
How do we know Tanis isn't setting us up?
He's not brave enough to set me up.
You can go.
You're familiar with this, then?
Intimately.
You're Alexander Corvinus.
There was a time that I
was known by that name.
By any name, I am still your forefather.
How have you stayed hidden all these years?
For centuries I've stood
by and watched the havoc
my sons have wrought upon each other
and upon humanity.
Not the legacy I prayed for
the morning I watched
them enter this world.
And a tiresome duty
keeping the war contained,
cleaning up the mess,
hiding my family's unfortunate history.
Couldn't you have stopped it?
Yes.
Could you kill your own sons?
You know what Marcus will do.
If he finds me, he finds William's prison.
You need to help us stop him.
You are asking me to help you kill my son.
You?
A Death Dealer?
How many innocents did you
kill in the six-century
quest to avenge your family?
Spare me your self-righteous declarations.
You are no different from Marcus
and even less noble than William.
At least he cannot control his savagery.
Anything I've done can
be laid at your feet.
Hundreds of thousands have died because of
your inability to accept that
your sons are monsters.
That they create monsters.
You could've stopped all of this.
Do not come grovelling to me simply
because you are weaker than your adversary.
You know the devastation William caused
before he was captured.
He cannot be set free.
No, wait.
You're no match for him.
Soon, brother.
No.
Father.
They've gone. There, my child.
You are safe now.
No. Michael.
Look at me.
Michael.
Shit.
Please.
Come on.
Fuck.
Hello, Father.
You are unwelcome in my presence.
Ah.
The predictable heart that never thaws.
Pity it beats within such a fool.
The eldest of the immortals,
yet you have made no attempt
to seize your destiny.
We are oddities of nature, you and I.
Nothing more.
This is a world for humanity.
And that petty sentiment explains
why you rejected your sons?
Why you stood by for over half a millennium
as William suffered alone in darkness?
No, Father.
I have no respect for your petty sentiment.
Viktor's key.
Where is it?
Whatever plan you have
for William is futile.
You cannot control your brother.
Oh, I am stronger now.
And our bond is
greater than you have ever
wanted to acknowledge.
You're wrong.
Soon you'll be drowning in
Lycans, just like before.
Oh, not Lycans, Father...
or Vampires.
A new race,
created in the image of their maker
their new god.
Me.
And a true god
has no father.
You will fail.
Get the kit.
No.
Please, sir,
let us help you.
The time has come, my friend.
Find the girl.
Bring her to me.
No, wait. Wait.
If you want Marcus, you'll
need Alexander's help.
Don't leave him here.
Did he get the pendant?
Yes.
He's too powerful for you alone.
You are the only one older than he is,
the only one stronger.
You could have killed him yourself.
No matter what he's become...
he is my son.
You are the last hope left.
There is only one way to defeat him.
Quickly, now,
before there is no more
legacy left in my veins.
What will I become?
The future.
Go now.
We're getting close.
Head back around towards the river.
I don't see a way inside.
There used to be a river
entrance just there.
It must be submerged now.
Looks like we're getting wet.
Closer.
Selene.
William.
Wait.
No, William. Stop.
Be still, brother.
It's me.
I'd no sooner harm you than myself.
Which way?
Is this it?
He's already here.
What is that?
Nothing.
Let's go.
We're too late.
After him. Get behind him.
Impressive.
Michael, you're unique.
There's never been a hybrid before.
Your powers could be limitless.
Hold it!
Oh, fuck.
Where is he?
He went right through there.
All we have are UV rounds.
They won't take him down.
No, but they'll slow him down.
Let's go.
You all right?
Jesus Christ!
But these weren't the Lycans we know.
No, these were raging monsters.
Unable to take human form ever again.
What are you waiting for?
Shoot them.
I can't. Not without taking her out.
I can't get a shot.
Michael.
Take her down.
Cut us loose!
We're going down!
William!
I knew Viktor made a mistake
by keeping you as a pet.
He should have killed you
with the rest of your family.
An unknown chapter lies ahead.
The lines that had divided the
clans have now been blurred.
Chaos and infighting are inevitable.
All that is certain is that
darkness is still ahead.
But for now,
for the first time
I look into the light with new hope...